MMM
ACCHI KOCCHI TYPESETTING TESTS
Level 1 - Static signs or very simple movement
simple stuff for beginners, expected to look really good
Level 2 - Movements, perspective, masking etc.
nothing too difficult, should be done decently
Level 3 - Difficult stuff... motion tracking expected
non-linear movements, scaling etc.
preferably should be properly tracked [mocha or by hand]
if that's beyond your skills, at least try to make it look decent
Level 4 - Insane stuff... most typesetters wouldn't even do it
signs doing all kinds of weird things
if done properly, one sign may take an hour to do
NOTE: Signs are only rough-timed to a few frames - fine-time them properly first!
Notes & Tips
There are a few things you can change about the signs...
- you can split them into more lines as needed
- many of them could be in UPPER CASE, if it makes them look better
Try to maintain some consistency
if you use a certain font, you should keep using it for all signs that use the same japanese font/style
Try to match fonts well especially for the kind of signs that repeat often...
if you're gonna have the same style used 30 times in one episode,
you'd better make it look good, otherwise it's 30 shitty signs right there
Let's begin preparing for the school festival!
School Festival
Events to Organize (Please form groups)
Café
Game Arcade
Haunted House
Theater
Curry restaurant
School Festival
Register your stand ASAP.
They tried them on
Several days later...
Preparations for the festival are still underway.
Tsutsumin!
And so...
On the day of the festival...
Tsutsumin!
Best Stand Award
Fully Electronic
Equipped with eco-friendly system
Rechargeable Sodium Cell
Under Development
Tsutsumin!
Rechargeable Sodium Cell
Do what you want.
The preparations continue...
Home Economics Room
Waiting room
Anteroom
For students
Ah...
I can't tell her it's a mascot suit...
Tsutsumin!
Mayoi
It's made from leftover wood.
Stab
Mayoi
VENA CAVA
RIGHT ATRIUM
LEFT ATRIUM
Mayoi
To the nurse's office!
Neko  High School Festival
Shocked
Still not ready for the festival.
Home Economics Room
Waiting room
Anteroom
For students
It's obvious
Whaaaat?!
Depressed...
Twitch
Roar
Just as Planned
Putting it on...
Meo~w
Aloof
Pat  Pat
Empty Can
ALL OVER the PLACE
Nekoge High School Festival
Tsutsumin!
The taste will blow you away!
Crêpes
Tsutsumin!
Various Toppings
Crêpes
Tsutsumin!
Strawberry Cream
Marron Custard
Chocolate Banana Cream
The taste will blow you away!
Tsutsumin!
Home Economics Room
Waiting room
Anteroom
For students
Throb
Stopped
Just Curious
Still Half-Asleep
Splash
He woke up.
Point
Getting changed...
Tsutsumin!
Romantic!!
Definitely isn't
Grrrrr
Chomp
Romantic
Sulking
Ta-da!
Apron
Cat Mascot Costume
Gloom
Tsutsumin!
It's almost time to begin!
Shocked
Desperately trying her absolute hardest not to smile
Tsutsumin!
So good!
Feeding Complete
It's almost opening time!
Chatter Chatter
Pass?
Crash
On Air
Let the festival begin!
YEAH!
Nekoge High School Festival
Tsutsumin!
Cat
Business is booming!
The taste will blow you away!
Crêpes
Tsutsumin!
Strawberry Cream
Marron Custard
Chocolate Banana Cream
Giggle
That was delicious...
Tsutsumin!
Hime
Waiting in line
Tsutsumin!
Thanks! We're all sold out!
The taste will blow you away!
Crêpes
Tsutsumin!
Strawberry Cream
Marron Custard
Chocolate Banana Cream
Stretch
Lots
ALL OVER the PLACE
Acchi Kocchi Kindergarten
Special
School Festival
Next Episode Preview
So, in next week's episode... On a snowy day, Otonashi and Miniwa encounter a strange individual wearing a bear suit. When they ignore it as always, the easily spooked Ms. Kikue becomes its next target!? Next up, it's Christmas time! What happened to everyone who dressed up as Santa as part of their work at Hatch Potch? Next time: "Bear Encounters of the Close Kind <=> Lovelymas!" Should I get a cake to go?
Going down...
See you next time!