May 4, 1648 Testament Era
10:03 A.M., Alley 6, Tama
Members of the Vermillion Grounds
INARI
Kitano Tenmangu Shrine
Musashi transport cable connection status
Connected
Kitano Tenmangu Shrine
Musashi transport cable has been released
Approve
Kitano Tenmangu Shrine
Censored
Individual Expression of Emotions Super-Drive
Output : 60
Censored
This test is intended to teach you to play with details.
Most of these signs may be easy to do somehow,
but the point here is to do them perfectly.
That means no \an8 and no "good enough, I guess."
All signs should have precise positioning and aligning,
correct colors, borders, shadows, blur, \fax, rotations, fades,
\move should be perfect, clipping too, everything should blend in.
Using multiple layers is a given.
If possible, the signs should look like they're a part of the video.
Try to replicate as many effects as possible.
A few of the signs are very difficult but at least all the shrines should look perfect. Things shouldn't lag though...
This test is intended to teach you to play with details.
Most of these signs may be easy to do somehow,
but the point here is to do them perfectly.
That means no \an8 and no "good enough, I guess."
All signs should have precise positioning and aligning,
correct colors, borders, shadows, blur, \fax, rotations, fades,
\move should be perfect, clipping too, everything should blend in.
Using multiple layers is a given.
If possible, the signs should look like they're a part of the video.
Try to replicate as many effects as possible.
A few of the signs are very difficult but at least all the shrines should look perfect. Things shouldn't lag though...
Kitano Tenmangu Shrine
Asama Shrine
White Sand Plinth
Danger
Please evacuate immediately.
Next Episode
Herald on the Stage