This is the Tasogare Episode 1 timing test. Its purpose is to determine your ability as a timer, whether you can competently split lines, frame-time signs, shift in OPs and clean up the script.
The timer for this show was presented with a script almost exactly as you see it now, complete with translator notes and extraneous blank lines.
You need to identify what lines are subtitles and what lines should be deleted.
Teiichi!
Ghost Maiden
Mystery 1
Welcome!!
Investigation Brigade
Come join us!
Contact me if interested.
Investigation Brigade Journal.
Okonogi Momoe on duty.
I organized the rumors surrounding the mysterious events that happened at school.
Oops.
Heh?
Oh, here it is.
Although there are some that are really doubtful...
There are some that are really doubtful...
but there are also a number of testimonies that seem to be credible.
What?
I could've sworn I put it here a second ago!
It definitely moved!
Could a poltergeist be around?
Could there actually be a ghost in this very room?
Nah, that's crazy.
I must need more sleep.
But these might really be true. **
We have so many testimonies.
There's definitely something in this school.
There might be a ghost roaming around campus right this second.
As a member of Investigation Brigade, I have to solve this mystery!
I can't really sense ghosts though...
This kind of stuff is probably best left to Niiya.
After all, Niiya's really talented.
He's really active, can actually sense ghosts, and isn't afraid of them either.
And he's pretty handsome to boot.
I should do my best to not be a burden for Niiya.
I might not be able to solve mysteries, but I can at least gather up information for him.
Heh?
What?
When did...
When did my keychain fall down?
Could it be?!
Is there something here?!
Hi, Okonogi.
Niiya!
Is there something wrong?
Is there a new scoop?
Get this, Niiya!
I just had a brush with the paranormal!
What?
Open and be cursed!
My keychain moved on its own!
It must be a poltergeist!
Oh... I had duties to take care of.
No, I didn't say anything!
You must have been dreaming or something.
But I'm sure there's something in here...
Hey, cut it out!
Niiya's scared of it?
There must be something here!
No, no, it's not like that!
It's fine, Okonogi!
There's nothing scary here!
Really?
Niiya can speak to those on the other side, so I'm sure he's just lying to make me feel better.
I'm not lying!
What?
How did you know what I was thinking?
You really do have the sixth sense!
M-Maybe so.
Niiya, you're amazing!
You have a wonderful talent!
I wish I could be you!
Please, cut it out already.
Oh, okay...
If Niiya can really read people's minds,
then he may already know about what I think about him!
I do know.
What?
He can really read my mind?
Then...
Niiya, let me ask you a question.
Where is the name of the place where the Mesopotamian civilization emerged?
...Hell if I know.
He received my question? Wait, no he didn't get it.
Damn it, I should have asked an easier question!
Geez.
Screwing around, you two?
Hey, Kirie.
It's so embarrassing. You two are flirting already.
I'm sorry...
No worries, just talking to myself.
Oh, okay. I thought you were talking about me.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Stop it!
Niiya, it's all your fault!
What? Me?
But it was my fault for being too familiar with him.
No, it's not my fault!
Again?!
He is speaking to the other side!
What?
What's wrong, Niiya?
Why do you ask?
I couldn't possibly know that!
Niiya's communicating with the other side!
Niiya, what the hell are you doing?
No, you shouldn't, Kirie!
He's communicating with the other side!
If you interfere, you'll get cursed!
As always, let's start the meeting for Investigation Brigade.
Is the president not coming in again?
Um, yes...
Pres is...well...
Oh, someone's calling me.
Hello, Niiya speaking.
Hello, Pres...
But you're always playing around.
Come to think of it, I haven't met the president yet.
I hope president will show up here soon.
It's fine with just us here. Don't worry.
Pres is down with a cold, so it'll just be us today.
If you will, Okonogi.
Yes, okay.
I organized the testimonies.
It seems certain that there are various cases of paranormal activity occurring in this school.
The most suspicious one of all is...
this!
This is an elevator for carrying school lunches.
Although the school no longer provides lunches, people still say that, on occasion, it moves...
all on its own.
You don't say...
The story is the spirit of a student who died with his neck stuck in here is the culprit for the elevator's autonomous movement, and if you pass by it alone, the spirit will lure you into the elevator, dragging you over to the other side.
I call this...
The Autonomous Haunted Elevator!
No way!
Is this...
Is there paranormal activity happening right before our eyes?!
While the elevator is indeed moving, I'm fairly certain it's not what you're thinking.
Well, it's certainly a ghost's doing, at the very least.
W-What's going to happen now, Niiya!?
Boom!
Niiya!
Oh no, Niiya's....
Let's go, Okonogi!
O-Okay!
Investigation Brigade Journal.
Okonogi Momoe on duty.
I organized the rumors surrounding the mysterious events that happened at school.
Oops.
Heh?
Oh, here it is.
Although there are some that are really doubtful...
There are some that are really doubtful...
but there are also a number of testimonies that seem to be credible.
What?
I could've sworn I put it here a second ago!
It definitely moved!
Could a poltergeist be around?
Could there actually be a ghost in this very room?
}Oh, you noticed, did you?
Nah, that's crazy.
I must need more sleep.
}Of course, you didn't.
But these might really be true.
We have so many testimonies.
There's definitely something in this school.
There might be a ghost roaming around campus right this second.
As a member of Investigation Brigade, I have to solve this mystery!
I can't really sense ghosts though...
This kind of stuff is probably best left to Niiya.
After all, Niiya's really talented.
He's really active, can actually sense ghosts, and isn't afraid of them either.
And he's pretty handsome to boot.
I should do my best to not be a burden for Niiya.
I might not be able to solve mysteries, but I can at least gather up information for him.
}Look here! It's a ghost!
}I'm gonna curse you!
}Oh geez, she's boring.
Heh?
What?
When did...
When did my keychain fall down?
Could it be?!
Is there something here?!
}You just got it?
Hi, Okonogi.
}Teiichi!
Niiya!
Is there something wrong?
Is there a new scoop?
Get this, Niiya!
I just had a brush with the paranormal!
What?
Open and be cursed!
My keychain moved on its own!
}Teiichi, you're late.
It must be a poltergeist!
Oh... I had duties to take care of.
Open and be cursed!
No, I didn't say anything!
You must have been dreaming or something.
But I'm sure there's something in here...
}Kitty ears!
Hey, cut it out!
Niiya's scared of it?
There must be something here!
No, no, it's not like that!
It's fine, Okonogi!
There's nothing scary here!
Really?
Niiya can speak to those on the other side, so I'm sure he's just lying to make me feel better.
}Are you really late because you had things to do?
}I'm sure you were just out flirting with another girl.
I'm not lying!
What?
How did you know what I was thinking?
You really do have the sixth sense!
M-Maybe so.
Niiya, you're amazing!
}Spirit Antenna!
You have a wonderful talent!
I admire you for it!
Please, cut it out already.
Oh, okay...
If Niiya can really read people's minds,
then he may already know about what I think about him!
}It was pretty boring since you were late.
}You have no idea how I felt.
I do know.
What?
He can really read my mind?
Then...
Niiya, let me ask you a question.
Where is the name of the place where the Mesopotamian civilization emerged?
}Why's she glaring at you?
...Hell if I know.
He received my question?
Wait, no he didn't get it.
Damn it, I should have asked an easier question!
Geez.
Screwing around, you two?
Hey, Kirie.
It's so embarrassing. You two are flirting already.
I'm sorry...
No worries, just talking to myself.
Oh, okay. I thought you were talking about me.
}Hey smile more!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Stop it!
}Wow, what a bully!
Niiya, it's all your fault!
What? Me?
But it was my fault for being too familiar with him.
}Maybe she's right.
}It is your fault for not understanding girls' feelings.
No, it's not my fault!
Again?!
He is speaking to the other side!
}Hey, Teiichi, would you look at this?
What?
}Do you think this bra is cute?
What's wrong, Niiya?
Why do you ask?
}You understand how girls feel, right?
}I want to hear what you think of this.
I couldn't possibly know that!
Niiya's communicating with the other side!
Niiya, what the hell are you doing?
No, you shouldn't, Kirie!
He's communicating with the other side!
If you interfere, you'll get cursed!
}Yeah.
}I'll curse you!
As always, let's start the meeting for Investigation Brigade.
Is the president not coming in again?
Um, yes...
Pres is...well...
Oh, someone's calling me.
Hello, Niiya speaking.
}Hello, Pres here.
Hello, Pres...
} The club meetings are boring, so why don't you skip it and come play with me instead?
But you're always playing around.
}You're so mean, Teiichi.
Come to think of it, I haven't met the president yet.
I hope president will show up here soon.
It's fine with just us here. Don't worry.
Pres is down with a cold, so it'll just be us today.
}Oh well...
If you will, Okonogi.
Yes, okay.
I organized the testimonies.
It seems certain that there are various cases of paranormal activity occurring in this school.
The most suspicious one of all is...
this!
This is an elevator for carrying school lunches.
Although the school no longer provides lunches,
people still say that, on occasion, it moves...
all on its own.
You don't say...
The story is, the spirit of a student who died with his neck stuck in here is the culprit for the elevator's autonomous movement, and if you pass by it alone, the spirit will lure you into the elevator, dragging you over to the other side.
I call this...
"The Autonomous Haunted Elevator"!
}It moves just fine. You didn't know?
No way!
Is this...
Is there paranormal activity happening right before our eyes?!
While the elevator is indeed moving, I'm fairly certain it's not what you're thinking.
Well, it's certainly a ghost's doing, at the very least.
W-What's going to happen now, Niiya!?
Boom!
Niiya!
Oh no, Niiya's....
Let's go, Okonogi!
O-Okay!
Could it be?
Was this rumor started all because of you?
Yep. It's pretty convenient, after all.
That's why you drag people in like this?
No way.
You're the first person I rode the elevator with.
What about the part where people would be dragged off to the other side?
Where exactly is this "other side"?
Sounds like the rumor had a life of its own.
Hey, stop fidgeting!
But it's so cramped in here.
Yuuko, it's touching me.
It's all right if you touch me.
What? No, it's not all right at all!
Oh? You don't like touching me?
No, it's not that.
But I like touching you, Teiichi.
And you're the only one who can touch me.
Yuuko...
Other people don't even notice if they touch me.
When I talk, they can't hear.
They don't try to see me. My existence. My actions.
To the living, they are all nonexistent.
I'm like a pebble beside the road, a completely insignificant, inconsequential existence.
That sounds really lonely.
Lonely?
Don't you feel lonely?
I don't know. I don't know what it means to be lonely.
But, I do know what it means to be happy.
Yuuko?
I like touching too, Yuuko.
It's a bit embarrassing though.
Thank you, Teiichi.
But, that's...
What?
Niiya!
I-It was just an accident! It's not my fault!
Inc-c-c-c—
Creep.
—credible!
You solved the mystery by yourself!
I knew you could do it!
I'm in awe!
Well, how are you feeling?
Well, that's...
Did you get a glimpse of the other side?
I saw heaven and hell.
Oh my.
It really was like an encounter with a poltergeist, huh?
It's actually an evil spirit.
It's the evil spirit haunting Niiya that's been doing the bad deeds.
Now that I think about it, this may have all been Yuuko's doing.
W-Why is that?
Because, a lot of the mysteries in the school have to do with her.
Well, I guess you're right.
I don't know about that.
It's not right to blame everything on Yuuko.
But it would make so much sense if she was the culprit...
That reminds me,
I found a pretty big story on that Yuuko.
What is it?
The thing is, I heard that Yuuko's grave is actually on a hill behind the school!
At the highest point on campus, beside the chairman's room, is a location called Maple Hill.
At the center of the hill should be a grave.
From what I heard, the name Yuuko should be inscribed on it.
If there is a name on it, then that means...
I don't know if that's true or not.
It's my first time coming here too.
But then why...
I found it!
This is it!
That's true.
Yuuko
It really says Yuuko.
I'm not sure about this.
You know that, right?
Because my body should be in the clubroom's basement.
Yeah, that's right.
But then, whose is this?
Niiya?
Oh, nothing.
I just don't think Yuuko's body would be buried here.
Well, I guess you're right.
But...
I figured that since Yuuko was alive at one point in time, maybe someone built this in honor of her.
When I imagine scary mysteries to be not rumors, but reminiscences of days long past, they become pretty romantic.
Oh my god!
The grave moved on its own!
Hey, calm down, Okonogi!
It was just...
Look, I just stumbled on it.
No way!
You didn't do squat to it!
I saw it with my own eyes!
The grave fell on its own!
It's a curse!
It's a curse, I tell ya!
Okonogi, wait!
Teiichi.
Can you come here for a second?
Isn't it beautiful, Teiichi?
It is.
I did say I didn't know this place earlier,
but I think there's a chance I've been here before.
Yu...
Is this...
a bell?
One of the mysteries passed down in Seikyou Academy is that of Yuuko.
She is a ghost without a single memory remaining of her past, and the Investigation Brigade's phantom president.
Before I knew it, I was possessed by her.
I just didn't know it was true literally as well.
The heart that can be seen.
The figure that can't be seen.
The illusion resting upon your eyes
is whatever you'd like it to be.
2nd Mystery
Maiden and the Accidental Meeting
Your first task, and one which you will do every time you get given a script to time, is to import the styles.
For the first episode of a show, the typesetter will create the styles, so you do not need to worry about them then.
But, in future episodes, you must import the styles from the previous episodes (mainly the Default, OP and ED styles. Usually NOT the sign styles, unless the typesetter has requested you do so.)
The Tasogare Episode 1 Test OP script contains the styles you are to import (in addition to the OP, more on that later).
Apart from timing every line perfectly, you should be aware of a few things.
1) There are several lines which overlap others (when two characters are talking). The "foreground" lines are to be left as is. The "background" lines should be aligned to the top of the screen using \an8.
2) The resolution of the file must be set accordingly to 720p. Make sure you know how to do this.
3) Lines must be split appropriately. Avoid three-line subtitles at all costs. If I see a three-line subtitle at any point, it is an instant fail.
4) All signs must be frame timed. Signs should be timed for as long as they appear on-screen. After they are timed, comment them out.
5) The OP must be shifted in correctly. Around line 455 there is a line with <OP>.
This is roughly the positioning of the OP (by the time you get down there you should have an idea of where it starts).
DO NOT RETIME THE OP.
It is provided to you in the OP/Style script. You copy those lines and paste them in to this script.
You then shift them to the correct starting position which is the FIRST FRAME OF THE OP ANIMATION. Make sure you know how to do this. Also ensure you have imported the OP style.
6) Clean up the script. You do not need to remove the translator notes, but make sure random shit doesn't appear on-screen. Also delete useless lines.
7) Finally, make chapters for this episode. You need MKVtools version 4.1.1 (Not the latest one because Haali is a faggot). Ask if you do not know how to make chapters.
You will be graded on your ability to follow these instructions, your competence as a timer and your capability to think for yourself.
And for fuck's sake, don't have these instructions show up in your submission.