This is a test in fine timing, shifting, timing signs... and other stuff.
As you may know, Commie does little translating and steals scripts wherever possible uses scripts from simulcasts.
Some of them have to be typed (that's why we have Jukey), while others,
like from Crunchy(T)roll, are ripped including timing & everything.
The timer's task then is to shift the script to our raw and fine time it.
"Cool, that sounds easy!" you may think but fuck! it's not!
Firstly, just shifting won't do. You're timing in milliseconds, not frames, so even if after shifting the script seems generally fine, plenty of start/end times may actually be half a frame off, which in some cases will happen to be ok while in other cases will cause a 1-frame bleed.
We're not ok here with 1-frame bleeds because we're not crunchy trolls.
There may also be additional shifting after OP/eyecatch/ED.
So you have to figure out how to not have any bleeds or I'll kill you. No, srsly...
As you may also know, Crunchy(T)roll employs a bunch of incompetent niggers, so along with imprecission of shifting you will encounter shitloads of timing derps, bleeds, mistimed lines, more bleeds, things that don't make sense and other weird crap.
In other words the shifted script is not nearly as good as your rough timed would be.
So you have 2 choices. Either you can try to work with this, or you can just erase the times and start from scratch. Option 2 is obviously the same as regular timing then.
I use option 1 but still do 2 passes. In the first one [after it's shifted in the right place] I go through the lines quickly pressing G and looking at audio, fixing obvious bleeds and whatever seems odd - bad lead in/outs, bad linking etc.
Shifting alone is unreliable and your fine timing will take longer, fixing all the derps. This is at least a bit faster than starting from scratch.
2nd pass is regular fine timing.
There are a few more things that you need to pay attention to.
The editor will edit the translation but otherwise the script is handed to you as HS released it. That means it has their styles and possibly, like here, their songs.
So unless you're as useless as MisterX, you're gonna nuke the HS styles, import our styles from previous episode, nuke the songs, and import and shift our OP/ED.
Should you happen to be as useless as MisterX then please GTFO.
Styles can be nuked/imported either in the Styles Manager, or in notepad. Same with the songs.
Use whichever method you want but I recommend to at least check what .ass files look like in notepad to be familiar with the headers and everything in the raw form.
After importing our styles, make sure to also adjust the script resolution [in Properties]. Normaly we use 1280x720 for everything, Un-Go just happens to be 1024x576. Dunno, ask RHE.
Along with making chapters, importing styles and changing the resolution should be a part of your routine for all shows, not just CR rips.
I chose Un-Go for this test because it also has plenty of signs and you need to be able to time lots of signs as well.
Signs, as you should know, are timed to the exact frames of appearance/disappearance, so you use those blue icons above rather than the audio track.
Aside from the Styles Manager you also need to change the styles in the script.
Going to Subtitles - Select Lines... might help you with that,
like select all Main Dialog lines and change them to Default etc.
If you also want to learn typesetting, TS the signs as well. You can just use the imported styles, but do at least the positioning, fading, and make sure the colors, borders etc match.
So remember all the things you need to do...
• nuke CR styles/songs
• change the styles & adjust script resolution
• shift script [or zero times & start from scratch]
• if you shift, pay extra attention to fine timing
• time the signs [and typeset if you want]
• import & shift OP/ED and make chapters
...and comment/delete things like these instructions cause you don't want actual releases to have weird things on screen
It wasn't supposed to be like this, head in my hands
Struggling to escape from this saturated world
Time passes like whispering sand
These circumstances, unchanging
gazing out at a dreamless tomorrow
Wanna say goodbye to the confusion of yesterday
I try reaching out, as if to resist
We cry millions of times and then get born again
Let's go with these red eyes
to that pictured future
Come here right by me, I'm clapping my hands
Where are you? Who are you?
Strain my eyes in the darkness
Can't see anything, don't know anything, but I'll still go
To the place of shining light in which you wait
Episode Five
The Statue of Illusion
Inspired by Ango Sakaguchi’s Meiji-era Ango Detective Stories "The Statue of Illusion"
I believe the war has brought the human race a number of benefits.
The development of civilization, the exchange of cultures,
House Representative Shimada Hakurou's Rising Sun Rally: A Call to Action
the advancements in science and technology.
Through our mastery of nuclear power, have we not acquired
the privilege to use air conditioners in the midst of summer,
and the right to watch late-night TV?
I stand before you to relate the happenings of that day.
One that will live on forever.
My supporters and I were the targets of a terrorist bombing.
Suzuki said...
"If an explosion goes off here,
glass will rain from the sky, and chaos will erupt.
Let us move the explosives to another location."
It was only a few days earlier that they were ordinary students,
but they supported me and did their part for the Rising Sun Party.
With nary a sliver of hesitation,
they drove off with the truck, loaded with explosives.
The outcome was as reported.
I'm not here to just beg you to praise the dead.
They did what needed to be done.
But speaking of those three after the war brings
Screwing around, are we?
I just wanted to try on a formal dress...
on a feeling of hesitation that we just cannot afford.
Sasa Kazamori
Artificial Intelligence (R.A.I.)
Inga
Detective's Assistant
It's adorable!
Yuuki Shinjurou
Detective
Komamori... You freak.
Even if the recent war was a detestable farce,
You're not pleased?
T-There's no reason for you to please me.
those three young men performed a miracle.
Well, I know, but...
And there is a piece of that in each and every one of our hearts.
Shimada Jirou
Actor, son of Mr. Shimada
Thank you.
That was actor Shimada Jirou, the oldest son of Shimada Hakurou,
reading from his father's work.
Mr. Jirou has also been appointed honorary director of the memorial hall...
Don't let yourselves be fooled by Shimada Hakurou!
He has made back room deals with allied nations and lined his own pockets
Yamamoto Teishin
Former bodyguard of Hakurou's
with financial support collected on behalf of the dead youths!
Mr. Yamamoto! Thank you for making your way down here!
Ootsubo Tetsuya
Rising Sun Party member, Hakurou's bodyguard
What's he doing?! Is he spouting that bullshit again?!
Those three youngsters will remain with me for an eternity.
One day, we'll bring about a miracle too.
That's why the symbol of this memorial hall is...
Shimada Hakurou
Rising Sun Party Leader
Souls...
I commissioned this statue
from a young friend of my son's, one much like those young men.
It was finally delivered late last night.
Um, excuse me...
Where's the bathroom?
The bathroom's over...
The Defeated Detective, Yuuki Shinjurou!
It seems you're challenging JJ Systems' Kaishou.
I commend you.
Rumor has it that you have some connection to
the young people who were the first victims in the war.
Oh? Are you the one who invited me here?
There's only one thing I cannot stand for.
What's this "Defeated Detective" business?!
There is no defeat! This is merely a ceasefire!
I. Gotta. Piss!
Wha...?!
Pardon me, but I'm about to wet myself.
Why are you angry?
You're a detective.
It's your duty to reveal the truth.
Yet, when it comes to yourself, you hide it?
All I want to expose are dirty lies.
Hirato Youko
Jirou's Friend, sculptor
Fancy place to take a nap.
I was up working 'til late into the night...
...you see.
She created the statue and brought it here.
This is my good friend, Hirato Youko.
This is Detective Yuuki.
Oh. It was worth coming just to look at the statue.
"The story is that they willingly gave up their lives for someone else?
It wasn't as heroic as that.
There had to have been at least one tear shed."
That's what I felt when I looked at it...
I apologize for my father back there.
To be honest, even as his son, I must say he's a bit overbearing.
That bit about not losing the war too...
...Is he in the National Service Restoration Front or something?
Don't forget money-grubbing.
Youko!
That's how that yakuza and ex-bodyguard, Yamamoto, feels.
He claims that the story of the three heroes is a sham,
Wipe Out the Allied Nations' Puppet Government
Patriotism Justice Victory
and that the donations were turned into gold bricks and hidden away.
Yamamoto is demanding that the money be returned.
Gold bricks? That's low.
Even though he just left the House of Representatives? I don't buy it!
Oh!
You used the dead to make a profit!
And this...
Jirou, sir, don't!
Shinjurou!
Jirou, sir?
Ootsubo, what is this?!
Gomi
Former member of the Rising Sun Party, works for Yamamoto
Mitsuhisa
They've been murdered... haven't they?
It seems that things have gotten interesting.
Because it involves Shimada Hakurou?
I couldn't care less about Mr. Shimada.
I'm talking about the Defeated Detective.
Both of the dead were former members of the Rising Sun Party.
Mitsuhisa! Gomi!
They recently joined Yamamoto Sadanobu's
opposing political organization.
How peculiar. Why were those two murdered and put inside the statue?
Kaishou Rinroku
Chairman of JJ Systems
Koyama Izumi
Public Prosecutor of the Joint Coordinating Dept. Public Prosecutor's Office
The Trojan Horse.
Why were they inside that thing?!
They were your men! What are you plotting?!
Wait a moment! That statue has no real need for an access panel.
In other words, no one but the creator knew that it could open and close.
Y-You killed those two?!
Are your men so frail that a mere girl can snuff them out?!
What's that, asshole?!
How dare you insult my men?!
It wasn't Youko, Father!
I asked Youko to do it...
I told her to get those two into the statue
and smuggle them into the memorial hall.
You knew about it too, Mr. Yamamoto!
Apparently, under Yamamoto's order,
the two of them went to find the gold hidden somewhere in the memorial hall.
Oh, the rumored gold bricks.
I see. With a newly-built memorial hall, they could be hidden anywhere.
But why would Jirou help?
Shimada Jirou was repulsed by the way his father used the young men
who sacrificed their own lives to publicize himself.
Gomi and Mitsuhisa both knew how I felt.
That's why they asked for my help in stealing the gold and making it public.
I asked Youko to sneak them in with something akin to a Trojan Horse.
Last night, the two of them got inside the statue at my studio,
and I transported it here like that.
The whole thing is my responsibility.
Jirou, you little shit... You took that business about the gold bricks seriously?!
In the meantime, I'll need statements—
That's not the issue!
They say the victims were carried here with the statue.
And then?
The question is, who killed the two of them?
The plan was for them to get out of the statue before sunrise
and look for the gold bricks.
But they were both murdered, and their bodies were stuffed back into the statue.
Last night, Ootsubo and several others were at the memorial hall,
but they were at the security checkpoint in front of the gate,
so no one could have gone off on their own.
But there was one more. Shimada Hakurou was there, no?
You're accusing me of killing Mitsuhisa and Gomi?!
You were here alone last night.
You discovered the two of them slipping out of the statue,
murdered them to protect the gold, and, knowing there'd be a lot of trouble,
stuffed their corpses back into the statue.
I don't believe it...
He's capable of anything...
After all, you killed three young men without even blinking!
What does that mean?
Hayami Seigen
Security Bureau Director, Metropolitan Police Dept.
It's a well known story.
On the day of the terrorist attack,
this man ordered those three to drive the truck away in no uncertain terms.
He did it to create a sense of obligation for the supporters who were right there,
but the truck blew up all too soon.
Bastard! Do you have proof?!
No.
Even if that terrorist bombing was staged, there's no proof.
Are you implying that I used terrorism to murder Suzuki and the others?!
I can't say anything for certain.
But, if you did this to protect the money you made by setting them up as heroes...
If you took lives just for that, you will never find redemption.
Y-You again?!
She's like my boss.
You're in high spirits today.
I know that pointless deaths litter the battlefield.
There are no heroic tales.
There are no heroes.
People have no choice...
...but to answer her question.
You must have been worried about whether those two would find the gold bricks.
Hey, I get the pleasure of asking.
Shimada Jirou, you came back here last night, didn't you?
Well, what did you see?
Tell me...
You mean he was a witness to the two being murdered?!
We'll find out soon.
What...
...did you see?
I... returned here when it was still dark...
I told Ootsubo and the others I was concerned about the statue...
But there was nothing out of the ordinary.
What did you see?
Father was...
Shimada Hakurou was...
...sleeping. Just like we planned.
I put a sleeping drug in Father's usual tea.
Just so he wouldn't wake until morning.
The plan was to find the gold bricks before then...
You said he was sleeping?!
That's what I was going to say!
That's why I couldn't have killed them!
It's the son's testimony. Perhaps he's trying to protect his father...
If we analyze the remains of the tea...
Humans can't lie when they answer Inga's question.
Shimada Hakurou didn't murder those two.
Then who did?!
Who killed them, Defeated Detective?!
How unlike Shinjurou to jump to conclusions!
And for him to decide his innocence based on mere testimony...
We still don't know the real killer.
What if I said it was friendly fire?
Huh?
The two victims killed each other.
They probably squabbled over their shares,
and by the time they arrived,
they had already breathed their last.
Inside the statue...
This way, Mr. Shimada doesn't get hurt, either.
This is how you want it?
Maybe after this, Mr. Shimada will settle down a bit.
That idiot!
Come on, Shinjurou!
Buy me ice cream! Ice cream!
A soul like that can't fill me up!
Shut up!
There are no tales of heroism on the battlefield.
That's why you think I killed them?
You either threatened them... or you planned the whole thing.
Oh... Then let's assume I did.
They died... but they saved a great number of lives.
Aside from that, what more is necessary?
Maybe they were terrified of death.
Screamed their lover's names, and pissed their pants.
But did the driver take his foot off the gas pedal?
Everyone wants to live. It's only natural.
Yet, in that instant, they chose to save the lives of the people there.
The option to escape was there...
But they didn't take it!
I believe that they acted without an ulterior motive.
From the bottom of my heart,
I wish to pass that through the generations as a heroic tale.
Youngster, you don't know the true beauty of humanity.
Kaishou Rie
Kaishou Rinroku's daughter, lives at home
According to my father, the murder was a result of friendly fire.
What do you think?
I'm sure it's just another lie!
Shimada Hakurou has pull in the military.
Father just wants to put him in his debt!
You're not going to do anything about it?!
You thought Mr. Shimada was the culprit from the beginning, didn't you?
You couldn't forgive him for being the kind of person who claims that
"war is the right thing to do" and "giving up your life is wonderful".
But you were wrong.
Yeah. That's right. From the start,
I couldn't picture anybody but him being the killer.
But afterwards, I couldn't even think of one word to refute him.
Refute him?
To what he said about people being able to die for the sake of others.
I didn't believe in stuff like that.
People live with things they don't talk about hidden in their heart.
I thought my job was to bring those things to light...
...but now, I...
You really are the Defeated Detective, Yuuki Shinjurou.
I... had expectations for you.
I thought maybe it would be you
who would tear down that invisible wall around us.
Well don't count on me!
I know myself!
I'm a fool, and powerless, and... I can't do anything for anyone!
Shinjurou, what's wrong?
You're not gonna quit being a detective, are you?
After all, you're gonna let me eat lots of souls, right?!
Shinjurou...
It's odd, isn't it?
Humans really are peculiar.
With all the data in the world, you still don't get it?
You thought that Shimada's heroic legend was a made up fairy tale.
But it was the truth.
The essence is unchanged.
It's just something beautiful that's been sullied.
Why are you with Inga?
So he can feed me souls!
Inga!
Without having to kill anyone!
I heard about how you and Inga met.
I'm me!
It would seem that in exchange for Inga not murdering anyone,
you provide people's souls, their truths.
But that means Inga will haunt you.
So what?!
Well then, aren't you giving up your life for the sake of others?
I'm not that noble...
In my mind, it's just about the same thing.
Shall I give you the percentage?
The real culprit?
Those two didn't kill each other?
It was actually quite simple.
As long as I wasn't looking at the illusion...
The real murderer's illusion is the idea
that those two snuck in so they could steal the gold bricks.
That's true.
Before the statue was transported, before even they got inside of it,
they were already murdered.
You're the only one...
...who could have done that.
Why would I do something so heinous?
Y-Yes, exactly!
She has no motive!
As I said, it's simple.
Her purpose was the gold bricks.
Oh, give me a break!
During yesterday's party, you were the only one in the building.
I was tired!
Even with all the ruckus outside, you didn't leave the building.
Even though bodies fell out of the statue that you created?
I didn't want to... be wrongly accused!
From where you were lying, you could clearly see Shimada Hakurou's back.
My back?
Corpses from a statue.
A person with good sense would suspect robbery.
And so, it's only natural that you would look
right at the place where your precious item was hidden, right?
You kept an eye on Mr. Shimada to see which way he would face.
But he didn't move at all.
Youko...
You knew that the gold bricks hadn't been stolen yet...
...since you'd already killed those two.
I don't want any gold bricks!
I don't think that the three who died were any kind of heroes!
They cried and screamed that they didn't want to die!
They were just ordinary kids!
That's why I helped with your plan!
That's the only reason!
I thought so as well.
That wasn't in the design.
I thought it was a message from the artist.
But...
It's human blood.
If the police check it out,
I'm sure they'll find it belongs to one of the victims.
If they'd murdered each other inside the statue,
there's no way there would be a splash of blood on the outside.
They were murdered outside of the statue, before it was transported.
The interior of the statue heats up throughout the day.
Thus, figuring out the exact time of death would be impossible.
The tear that I saw was also an illusion.
What should we do?
I'll leave it to you.
But I can't afford to let Mr. Shimada come off unscathed now.
To be fooled by a beautiful woman... Some detective he is!
I suppose I owe you my thanks.
I just came here to sully something that was beautiful.
Are you calling that woman beautiful?
Or do you still doubt the beauty that is their sacrifice?
Certainly, they died.
But I'm alive. And so are you.
What are you trying to say?
People have given up their lives for others.
But that doesn't say a damn thing about either one of us.
The only ones who are admirable... who are beautiful...
...are the guys that died!
The rest of us are petty, stupid, vulgar...
...and flail on the ground as we desperately try to stay alive!
That's all.
You little...
The reason you didn't panic, even after finding out about the thieves...
Inga.
Really?
It was in front of you the whole time. No need to panic.
In the pale morning mist, a whispered prayer
I'm gonna follow this twisted landscape with you
Looking for the "truth", "a 'lie' will do" is it?
Tracing it as if we can see through
Looking for, beyond words
Like a falling feather
Looking for, find it
So we can cuddle close together here
Looking for, unravel it
Like a tattered cloud
Looking for, find it
So we can cuddle close together here
The next episode is inspired from "Meiji-era Ango Detective Stories"...
Huh? It's not?
The original work is a short story called "Angou"?
The title has a double meaning, both "angou",
which means a code to hide secrets and then, of course, the author's name.
But who cares about that? I'll give it a read.
It's a great story! I've got tears coming from my eyes!
I can't believe Shinjurou and I
are going to tamper with a wonderful story like this!
Next time on UN-GO, "The Code Too Simple"!
What a great feeling...