I'm so excited about the
High School Airsoft Tournament.
Me too! I came prepared with tons of snacks.
Oh, good thinking.
Advance.
Halt.
Fire...
The one for snipers is...
This is the signal for snipers.
R-Right!
We're here, guys!
That's where the tournament will be.
High School Airsoft Tournament
Ruthless Capture the Flag
Exit
Wow, there are tons of people here!
Seems like a lot more girls
are into airsoft than before.
Oh, I wish we had this many airsofters at our school!
So this is what an airsoft field is like.
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
Enemy Fire Brings Me Down?
There's a hot spring near here?
Yeah.
They've got a great view too,
so soaking outdoors there is amazing.
Natural Hot Springs
Tsurumi
Resort
Natural Hot Springs
Tsurumi
Resort
We must ask you to bring your own
Please mention any special necessities
or requests when you submit your form.
We thank you for your cooperation.
Straight from the source!
Only a 15-minute walk from venue.
Shuttle to and from nearest station.
Come heal your aching body
after the tournament!
Wow...
Okay.
Here are your markers, guys.
Markers?
In order to help players
tell their allies from their opponents,
every team wears armbands like these.
Here you go, Yura-pyon.
Oh. Thank you.
Today's Airsoft
Game
All right, everyone,
let's review the rules for
today's tournament while we've got time.
To win, we must either seize the enemy flag
Game
or eliminate the opposing team.
It's a Capture-the-Flag knockout tournament.
Game
By the way, Yurara-chan,
this is your first time at a major tournament like this, right?
It might be better to tie up your hair
and get it out of the way.
Oh, I hadn't thought of that.
How about this?
Nah, it's gotta be like this.
This isn't bad, either.
I think we got a winner!
This one's much better.
Uh, you guys...
Yurarin.
If you don't wanna tie it up,
you can just leave it as it is.
Can you put this on for me?
Sure!
We will soon commence the first round.
All participating teams are to assemble at the gate.
Hell yeah!
Let's break a leg, everyone!
Are you jinxin' us?!
U-Um...
Then, how about "Explode a leg"?
That sounds like fun.
We'll go with that, then.
Let's go, C3 Club!
Explode...
a leg!
I'm so nervous.
I wonder if I can even shoot properly.
Relax.
I'll be defending the flag,
so go have fun, and give 'em hell!
Five.
Four.
Three.
What the...
Two.
A grenade?!
One.
Hell yeah!
That flag is mine!
U-Uh...
Yura-pyon,
time to move out!
I'm under attack!
Request backup!
You're mine now!
H-Hit.
Way to go, Kari-chan.
All right.
Hey, over here!
Damn it!
Karila's got them distracted.
Now's our chance!
Yurara-chan, advance!
They're going after Kari-chan-senpai.
No, no, Yurara-chan!
Karila's just the decoy!
Wai—
Hit.
N-No way.
Yesss! I did it!
Oh! I'm so sorry I shot you!
Now she's apologizing to the enemy...
This is a match, Yurara-chan.
You don't need to apologize
for shooting your opponent.
I-I'm sorry!
All's well that ends well, I guess.
Three on one, eh?
This'll be fun.
H-Hit.
From this distance,
even Yurara-chan can get to the flag.
Go on! The flag's there for the taking!
The flag...
But am I really the right one for the job?
This guy's really good.
Get going, Yurara-chan!
I'll draw their fire.
Hono-chan-senpai...
Ch-Charge!
Go!
We did it!
I think my airsoft debut went pretty well!
You did it, Yurarin.
Yes! I did it!
Bet there was plenty of
beginner's luck involved, though.
Come on now.
I think she was pretty light on her feet.
She did great for a first-timer.
I did a lot better than I thought I would!
Okay. Next round's starting soon.
Make sure you reload your mags
and rehydrate, okay?
O-Okay!
Club
We will now have a scheduled
one-hour recess for lunch.
Finally! A break.
That took forever.
Each match is only fifteen minutes long, though.
But that was a whole year's worth of exercise.
Homemade
Curry
Participant
Lunch
Curry sure hits the spot after airsoft!
It's spicy but so good!
Here's some tea and snacks, too.
I just went to check the matchups,
and our next opponent is Meisei Women's Academy.
Say what?!
Are they a strong team or something?
"Strong"? They're more like monsters.
Monsters?!
We've faced them four times already,
and every match ended in a draw.
We've never once beaten them.
And their leader, Haruna Rin-san, is on a whole other level.
Haruna Rin-san?
And that's not all.
That Rin chick was Sono-chan's
airsoft partner back when she was in the US.
Really?
I've never beaten her, either.
She's good and all,
but it's no fun playing with her.
Personally, I'd never wanna team up with her.
Haruna Rin-san.
I wonder what she's like.
I'm gonna go get some water.
I'll go too!
Lockers
Water Fountain
Cafeteria
Lavatory
Lemme use the bathroom real quick.
O-Okay.
Th-Thanks, Sono-chan-senpai—
Huh?!
Long time no see.
Huh?
"Long time no see"?
Hey.
That's our new member.
Cute, isn't she?
So are you.
But be it the past, the present, or the future,
I'll never forgive you.
Huh?
U-Uh...
Was that...?
This time, we'll all attack the same point in our enemy's defense.
A blitz, basically.
"B-Blitz"?
Yay!
I haven't been an attacker in a while!
This strategy is just so us.
Normally, you'd leave a group to defend the flag,
splitting all members evenly
between offense and defense.
But frankly, a small offense with a beginner like Yurara-chan
Meisei
wouldn't stand a chance
using that tactic against Meisei.
Meisei
If we go on an all-out attack, though,
we might pull this off even if we get surrounded.
Meisei
So this time, we're banking on
a quick and focused breakthrough.
That is all.
I'll be sure to kick their asses nice and fast!
I don't know if I can do this right...
Don't worry about winning or losing.
"Explode a leg," right?
I've got to advance—
An enemy?!
What're you doing, Yurako?
Move it!
No, listen!
I spotted an enemy!
Kari-chan, look out!
Hit.
Hacchan!
I'm hit.
Ren-chan too?!
This is...
Yurara-chan!
Just focus on what's in front of you.
Let's go.
R-Roger!
Charging the flank...
So, they plan to wage all-out war while babysitting a novice, huh?
Karila!
Hit.
Not bad.
What now?
They'll get to our flag any minute now.
I'll take care of Rin. You guys hurry up.
She just told us to hurry up, but...
This is impossible! How can we get past them?!
Let's go.
W-Wait!
Bring it on, Sonora.
Yurara-chan!
This is all my fault.
I didn't keep up, so now...
even Sono-chan-senpai...
This is strange.
Meisei should've captured our flag by now.
No way...
I can't do this alone!
I'm too scared!
Rin-san,
Stella only has one member left.
Let's capture the flag and finish this.
Thank goodness.
It'll be over soon.
I don't want the flag.
Huh? But...
I plan to annihilate every last member of the C3 Club.
Now go.
Right away!
It's not over yet.
They're searching for me.
I've gotta hide!
Oh no! They found me!
I-I give up.
I surrender.
It's over?
Stella Women's Academy has surrendered.
Meisei Women's Academy wins.
Huh? Did he just say "surrender"?
Yeah, that's what I heard too.
You there.
Why didn't you fight till the bitter end?
You're playing airsoft without any resolve.
That attitude of yours
pisses me off.
Why do you fight?
I...
You are not fit to play airsoft.
Hey, Rin!
What're you sayin' to our girl?
Excuse me.
H-Hey!
Ugh.
Don't let her get to you, okay?
Yeah.
There's always next time!
Don't worry about it.
Come on, Sono-chan, say something!
Sono-chan-senpai.
Rin hit the mark.
Today, Yurarin ran away,
putting her teammates' sacrifices to waste.
Someone who can't fight alone
can't fight in a group either.
Keep smiling till the bitter end.
You don't have to be afraid of losing.
But don't you ever do something like this again.
Natural
Hot Springs
Ladies
Anyway, time to hit the hot springs!
This is the only time you'll see
Hono-chan without her glasses.
Hono-chan-senpai is truly bewitching when naked.
On the other hand, there's another one of us too tiny to even notice.
What?!
The hell are you calling tiny?!
Olé!
Stop it!
Yahoo!
Karila,
it's rude to just jump in!
Quit bein' such a stiff.
What do we do about them?
Act first, think later!
Action is the only course of action!
Hey, check out my medals from today!
Yurara-chan.
Yes?
You'll probably be upset about today even if we tell you not to be,
but "don't do it again" means
that you've got another chance.
She's right.
Don't worry about it!
Yup!
I'm sorry I made you guys worry about me.
Putting her teammates' sacrifices to waste...
I ran away.
I thought I could change if I went somewhere new.
I was sure I could change if I joined the C3 Club.
But that just means
I wasn't trying hard enough!
What was I thinking?!
If you don't wanna tie it up,
you can just leave it as it is.
I just wanna be myself
and be with everyone,
and that means
I need to
change right now!
Yurara-chan?
Thanks for all your hard work!
The hell?!
Yuracchi, what happened?!
Hi there, Yuranosuke-kun.
I'm going to give airsoft everything I've got!
I won't run away anymore!
H-Huh?
It looks adorable, Yurarin!
You're too cute!
Thank you!
All right!
We're going to work you
like a horse from now on, Yurako!
Oh, guys.
Enough with the nicknames!
From now on, please call me Yura.
Roger that, Yura.
I'll...
do my best!
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Making eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will beat faster the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's time to go
Next Episode
Your hair looks great on you, Yura-chan.
Thank you!
Maybe I should cut my hair too.
That'd be such a waste!
You're a natural blonde!
A waste, huh?
Guess I won't, then.
In that case, I'll cut mine!
What?! Your hair's really pretty too, Ren-chan!
It's so long and silky.
Makes me jealous!
I cut it every day, though.
What?!
Next Episode: Real Gunslingers Don't Need Guns.
Real Gunslingers Don't Need Guns.
What about you, Sono-chan?
My hair doesn't grow.
What?!