I'm Yamato Yura.
I'll be playing with you from today on.
Nice to meet you.
I'll be operating in a two-man cell with her.
You guys take up Formation Bravo.
Let's go.
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
Comrades-in-Arms
Will Always Leave You.
Hey, what do you make of that girl with the short hair?
Leave it to you to notice the cute girls before anything else.
You gotta take this seriously, man.
Well, she certainly is cute,
but that's not what I meant.
Huh?
Isn't she from Stella?
Ack! You're right!
If I remember correctly,
that's Yamato Yura.
What's she doing here at Meisei?
Did your sister mention anything about this, Aira?
No, nothing.
I'm as surprised as you.
Where's our support?
Clear.
Hit!
Listen up.
Keep me covered.
Roger.
From both sides, huh?
Here I go.
Wait! Stay where you are!
Hit!
I got hit.
Three enemies dead ahead.
I might get taken out in the process,
but I'll take two of them with me!
A suicide attack?
Hit.
The match on Field B has ended in victory for Meisei Women's Academy.
We did it.
We won, Rin-san.
Looks like it.
We've got big trouble!
Oh, it's just you.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Anyway, this is trouble.
Take a look at this.
We thought Yura-chan was back.
This photo...
What's up?
It's Yura-chan!
But isn't that Meisei's...
Haruna Rin?!
I heard about it from Aira.
Apparently she's a member of Meisei's Airsoft Club now.
What's going on?
Why Meisei?
Yura-chan moved out of the dorms, right?
Seems so.
You think they headhunted her?
They might have done it to spite us.
No way...
Does it matter?
We can just hear it straight from the horse's mouth.
Mom
Incoming
Call
Hey, Sono-chan. Let's bring her back!
Nah, let her be.
What? Why?
Hey, Sono-chan!
We're playing Medic War on home ground today,
but don't get complacent.
Let's review the rules.
If you get hit, call for the medic.
Once you receive a bandage from her,
you can continue playing.
At the end of the game, whichever team has used fewer bandages wins.
Taking our last match into account,
we'll be going with Formation Echo this time.
Um, in that case, what will my role be?
You're the medic.
Huh?
Why?
I'm better as an attacker.
Like I said, I took our last match into account when choosing this formation.
No objections allowed.
But...
If someone calls for the medic,
run to them with a bandage.
It's all over for us if the medic gets hit,
so be careful out there.
You'll be allowed to attack during the last five minutes.
That said, your role as medic takes top priority.
Understood? Get to your post.
Roger.
Why?
Why do I have to play the damn medic?
Hit!
Medic!
I took down so many enemies last time!
O-Okay!
Coming.
Five minutes to go.
Medics are now allowed to attack.
All right!
Hit!
Medic!
I'm hit too.
Hit!
Medic!
Of all the times to call for a medic...
It'll be more efficient
to take these guys out first.
Hit!
Medic!
Got him.
While I'm here, I might as well take out another...
Hurry the hell up, medic!
Coming!
This girl...
You're late!
I called for you so many times.
I'm sorry.
Thirty-six.
Thirty-seven.
Thirty-eight.
That's all of them.
Thirty-nine,
which means...
We lost by one.
Thanks.
That was a good game.
Why'd you make me the medic?
How many times do I need to repeat myself?
I made that decision based on our last match.
Nothing more, nothing less.
I took down four enemies in the last five minutes!
And I probably could've taken down one more if I hadn't been called for.
What's your point?
If not for that,
we probably could've won today's game.
I'm not interested in what we "probably could've" done.
A loss is a loss.
Then tell me what I did wrong!
I answered all the medic calls,
and I took a few enemies down as well.
But I still lost.
So what should I have done?
Don't expect me to solve every one of your problems.
You need to find the answer to this one yourself.
I understand.
It basically means this still isn't enough, right?
Yeah. I did end up losing, after all.
I need to become even stronger, don't I?
You could've just said so.
Yamato-san!
Yura-chan.
It's me, Rento.
Long time no see.
Yura-chan...
You've lost so much weight.
Are you eating properly?
Are you getting enough sleep?
Are you injured or hurt anywhere?
Let's not waste time on small talk. Could you please get to the point?
The C3 Club...
Aren't you going to rejoin the C3 Club?
You can come back anytime you want.
I'll bake a cake for you.
And all the cookies you can eat!
Oh, if you've gotten tired of sweets,
how does a tuna mayonnaise taiyaki sound?
Or how about...
No thanks.
I don't need it.
I don't need the C3 Club anymore.
No way...
I belong here.
These people recognize my worth.
Yura-chan.
Sorry. I need to practice.
Hail of Bullets
Rin-san.
This week's results are in.
Thanks.
Meisei Women's Academy
Member Data
Yamato-san's amazing.
Her accuracy, speed, enemy detection, and stamina are all exceptional,
but her hit rate is particularly outstanding.
All right, everyone.
We're going with Formation Oscar today.
We'll be launching a surprise attack from the slope—
Please let me be an attacker!
I'll help the team more than I did as a medic.
We'll win this for sure.
Raise your head.
Sorry, but you'll be the medic again.
Did you make this decision based on the last match too?
I did.
Got it.
In that case, I'll win this even as a medic.
Teams participating in the first round,
please assemble at the entry gate to the center field.
Let's go.
Last five minutes.
Hit!
I won.
Even as a medic, I won.
I'm sure I got the most hits in that match.
Please let me be an attacker.
Hits, eh?
I kept count for everyone.
You got fifteen.
I—
Are you fighting for the team?
Or do you simply want to show off?
Let's talk about our formation for the next game.
I won't bring up our hit counts anymore.
I need to clear my mind of everything but winning.
Five minutes to go.
Th-Thanks.
Wait, Yamato-san!
There's someone behind us!
S-Somebody, help!
Someone get over here!
They weren't calling for a medic.
I can focus on taking down another enemy!
Hit.
I won.
Yamato Yura.
Put your gun away.
Huh?
But we won!
It's almost time for the next match!
Put it away.
What the hell?!
Why?!
It wasn't my fault she got hurt!
It's not about that.
Then what is it about?!
Isn't winning everything for you?
That's why I came here! To get stronger!
So why?!
You sought out Sonora and now myself to be your role model.
Through victory and praise, you seek
to validate your worth as a human being.
What's wrong with that?
All you're doing is forcing yourself onto others.
Huh?
The same goes for your acts of self-sacrifice.
Everything has been for your own satisfaction.
No!
It's not like that!
It most definitely is.
At first glance, it may look like you're acting selflessly,
but in truth, you're constantly looking for praise in return.
No!
No! No! No! No! No! No! No!
At the end of the day,
the only person you care about is yourself.
You don't belong on this team.
The third round will begin shortly.
Participating teams,
please assemble at Field A's entry gate.
Participating teams, please assemble...
I just don't understand.
Why did it end up like this?
Someone who lived as she pleased,
and was still accepted by the people around her.
That's the kind of person I wanted to be.
That's why I wanted to change myself.
All you're doing is forcing yourself onto others.
At the end of the day,
the only person you care about is yourself.
It's too late for that.
There's no way I can go back now.
Yeah, it's all good.
You'll be coming to the clubroom today, right, Sono-chan?
I'm fine. Nothing's wrong.
Hey!
You worry too much, Mom!
I'm fine, really.
Oh, the exchange thing?
We got a reply?
Oh, nah.
I was just surprised. That's all.
I'm not really against it.
It's just... I was planning to stay in Japan a bit longer.
All right.
I'll let you know as soon as possible once I'm done with the formalities.
Sweets?
Well, if you send some, I guess I'll eat them...
O-Okay, all right!
I'll share them with my friends.
Not "Nura."
Her name's Yura.
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Making eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will beat faster the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's time to go
Next Episode
I'm kinda bored. Let's play a word game.
Start with the 'e' from Word Game.
Hello.
I'm University Student G-
the guy
Yura-chan
refused
to shake
hands with.
I'm University Student G-
the guy
Yura-chan
refused
to shake
hands with.
E? E, E...
E for Exchange Student A!
Hey, don't bring that up!
Her refusal
hit me hard
in its own right,
Her refusal
hit me hard
in its own right,
Exchange Student A, huh?
A, A... Airport!
but there was
something else
that hit me
even harder.
but there was
something else
that hit me
even harder.
That's off-limits too!
Let's head down a different path, okay?
Since I didn't have
enough credits at
my university,
Since I didn't have
enough credits at
my university,
Okay, a different path it is!
T, T... Traitor!
I was officially told
to repeat the year today.
Traitor...
Next Episode: "We Can't Fight Anymore."
We Can't Fight Anymore.
I'm done.
I've had enough of this game!