Are you serious?!
When do you leave?
The end of the month.
But that's just around the corner!
Well, I gotta make it to the entrance ceremony over there.
This is so sudden...
C'mon! Make your hit call already!
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
What do you mean, you're goin' abroad?
We Can't Fight Anymore.
You can't go to the US!
Karila!
This is her choice.
Still!
Why didn't you tell us sooner?
Do you think of the C3 Club as just a phase?
Of course I don't.
Then what are we to you?!
Don't go!
I don't want you to!
Sorry.
Even now, you're totally nonchalant.
Sorry...
In that case,
you can go if you can
beat us one more time!
Yeah!
We're the champions of the
24-Hour Tournament, you know.
Yeah, an airsoft match is
more like us than a farewell party.
Yup.
Now that we've reached an agreement, let's get to it!
It's still light outside.
Yeah!
Yeah.
Sorry...
I can't. I've still got a lotta stuff to take care of before I move.
Stop. Stop.
You're doing too many useless things.
I guess Kari-chan can't play
the role of Sono-chan after all.
Well, excuse me.
Hmm...
How does Sono-chan play, anyway?
If Yura were here,
she'd already have the answer to that.
Yeah...
More like, it just feels wrong without her.
It really does.
Yeah, I can't deal with this kinda atmosphere.
Me neither.
Wanna call it a day?
Yeah.
Awesome!
Yura-chan?
Oh, Ren-chan.
You sure saw a lame side of me just now.
I didn't know you liked these kinda games too.
Huh?
I don't, actually.
Aww, I lost.
Um, can I talk to you for a minute, Yura-chan?
Go ahead. I'm listening.
Sono-chan-senpai's leaving for the US
at the end of the month to study abroad.
So we've all decided to have one final match during her last weekend here.
Oh?
You're not... interested?
Well, how should I put this?
I already quit, so...
I mean, I've only caused you guys problems, you know?
It'd only be more of the same if I came back.
And frankly speaking, I'm through
with the whole "This is youth!" scene.
What the heck?
It's not like I ever belonged in the C3 Club anyway.
I probably just wasn't cut out for it.
But...
That's how it is, so...
even though it was only for a short while, thanks for having me—
Knock it off!
There you go again, running away by yourself.
Sure, you may be fine with that,
but what about Sono-chan-senpai and the others?
You should think about them once in a while, too!
She totally crossed the line this time.
Yeah.
Did something happen?
We ran into Yura-chan just now.
Hey, Yura-chan!
She's, like, scared of us!
She must be finding it hard to face us, but...
Yeah, she doesn't have to be terrified.
Rento?
What? What's the matter?
I'm so sorry. It's all my fault!
Ren-chan!
Huh? Wh-What?
'Sup.
What is it now?
I see.
I'm sorry.
Nah, you didn't do anything wrong.
But...
If you didn't go, I'm sure one of us would've.
That's true.
At the end of the day, we all want her to come back.
Especially with Sono-chan not acting like herself.
You can say that again.
She was camping outside the clubroom the other day.
I'm positive she came to check if Yura-chan was here.
I saw it too.
"I forgot something here,"
is what she said.
But it was so obviously an excuse.
And after everything she said about being super busy...
We can't let her leave like this.
Not without a proper good-bye.
Sono-chan or Yura-chan.
Then it's obvious what we gotta do!
We just gotta get Yura-chan to join us again!
I think we should use the cake tactic.
That's your favorite, ain't it, Ren-chan?
Then, I'll—
Anything goes! Let's just do this!
Yeah!
I'm home.
Yura
Rice Ball
Yura?
Right. There's no way she'd come in through the window.
Hey, wait!
Here. You can have this salmon rice ball.
You remind me of her.
I should start packing.
Man...
Yura?
That's no way to greet someone.
Thanks for the pickled plums.
They're nothing compared to
how good Master's tasted, though.
Regardless, it still makes me happy.
About that girl...
You mean Yura?
I'm sorry it ended up with me throwing her out.
I had grown conceited.
The strength in which I believe
cannot help that girl.
The strength one gains through victory, I mean.
This isn't like you.
You have tons of juniors who look up to you, you know.
I suppose so.
We've both changed a lot since back then,
but I think you're still amazing.
I, on the other hand, got it into my head that I was fine with everything...
with Master's death,
with you leaving me,
with Yura.
I thought I was keeping my mind clear,
but I was just running away from the chance to face it all.
I'm horrible.
Then, perhaps you should stop
looking so nonchalant all the time.
Are you gonna give me shit for that too?
It's rather unsightly, you know.
I'll walk you out.
She's not close to being a finished product,
but she was making remarkable progress each day.
Greedy, confrontational, and impudent—
she's just like you used to be.
Why don't you try going back to the Kashima Sonora of old?
Rin!
I'll be fine from here.
Take care.
Thanks.
You too.
The "Shove something nostalgic in Yura's face and appeal to her sentimentality" tactic!
How about this?
Champions
I have a feeling that trophy
would have the opposite effect.
Then how about this?
That's wild! I like it!
We also have this.
Nice! I love how it smells all fishy, too.
Huh? What's that?
Oh, Yura's club registration form?
I didn't know she actually submitted one.
Sono-chan probably kept it safe somewhere.
Good job, Rento!
That thing reeks of memories.
Let's not do this.
Huh?
Where'd that come from?
It's just that we're getting excited all by ourselves,
and we're being kinda...
Self-centered?
Yeah.
Something along those lines.
Well, I suppose that's one way of looking at it.
It's not actually like that, though!
Remember when Yura-chan worked so hard to get us ready for the 24-Hour Tournament?
You mean the special training?
Yes, exactly.
Yeah, that was kinda weird.
Champions
Well, that won't do this time!
I mean...
We shouldn't have turned
a blind eye to those small changes.
When my leg was hurting, I should've just said so.
I didn't bring it up,
because I didn't want Yura-chan to leave,
but I was just being selfish!
Ren-chan...
So you're saying it's wrong
to selfishly drag her back here.
Yeah, if we brought her back against her will,
she'd wanna leave even more.
If Yura-chan were to come back on her own,
nothing would make me happier, but...
Inbox
From: Kashima Sonora
To: Mutsu Honoka
Up for some airsoft?
From: Kashima Sonora
To: Mutsu Honoka
Up for some airsoft?
From: Kashima Sonora
To: Mutsu Honoka
Up for some airsoft?
From: Kashima Sonora
Inbox
From: Mutsu Honoka
To: Kashima Sonora
Roger that.
C3 Club
Sono-chan
Farewell
Airsoft Tournament
Take care!
Sorry I'm late.
Done with the farewell party your class threw?
Yeah.
Yura-chan's not here.
I've been waiting here for an hour already.
I even called her.
And I texted her the place and time, just in case.
That so.
It's a shame, but let's keep our chins up, okay?
After all, this is an airsoft farewell.
She's right.
So lemme say this:
you're not gettin' on that flight
unless you beat me.
Roger that.
The time limit is fifteen minutes, and the rules are—
To defeat me.
That'll do.
That's Sono-chan for you!
Okay, then. When the bell rings five minutes from now...
Let the game begin!
I'm sorry, Mom and Dad.
In the end, I couldn't change one bit.
You got into another fight?
Yeah.
Did you make up?
Yup, we did!
Ren-chan?
Are you okay?
I'm sorry!
City Library
Temporarily Closed
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Closed
Out of Order
No Entry
Were you the one who just called me?
N-No!
It's raining...
This weather is makin' it harder to find Sono-chan.
Yeah, it's like even the rain is on her side.
I don't belong anywhere anymore.
Don't cry, geez!
Ow!
This is...
The perfect place to take shelter from the rain, is it not?
Choujirou?
I hope it never stops raining.
Why?
'Cause that way, I'd be able to stay here forever,
and I don't have anywhere else to go.
Unfortunately, all rain ceases eventually.
Can't you make it go on forever?
You're a god, aren't you?
Are you confusing me with some kind of tool designed for your convenience?
But I really, really don't have anywhere to go.
No matter what I do, no matter where I go,
no one accepts me.
Then you do it.
Accept myself?
That's just weird.
It's not weird.
Can you accept someone who can't even accept themselves?
But what would be the point?
It's not like I can go back to the C3 Club now.
You can.
Right now, this is your world
and mine.
Did you forget?
Our worlds are resonating.
The worlds you create are not mere illusions.
Choujirou, look out!
A shooter and his target
are always one and the same.
No! Choujirou!
Come on, Choujirou!
Accept yourself,
and accept others.
Once you do, the entire world...
Choujirou.
The entire world...
...will...
be mine.
Karila!
Don't use just your hands to shoot!
Oh, come on!
Hit!
Yachiyo, your heart's racing, isn't it?
Relax a little.
If you do, knowing where to aim and how to shoot will be a piece of cake.
N-No way is that true!
For real?!
Hit!
Honoka!
If you wanna back Rento up, you gotta
aim at me from a little more to your right.
Aww, darn it.
Hit.
What's with you guys?
Come at me with your guns blazin'!
Isn't this your last chance to beat me?
Is no one gonna attack me?
I'm no match for her.
She's way too strong.
We surrender.
We admit defeat.
I've lost all will to fight.
You could look all over Japan
and still not find a match for her!
Then I guess this is game, set, and match—
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Making eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will beat faster the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's time to go
Next Episode
Everyone, tea's ready!
Sono-chan Farewell Airsoft Tournament
Too good!
Today we have royal soy-milk tea!
Whoa, nice.
Take
care!
There's also some pound cake flavored with plum jam.
Yachiyo
Screw you!
Man, so tasty!
Yachiyo
Cake and tea is the greatest combo ever.
This is kinda relaxing.
Take
care!
Very relaxing.
I wanna stay like this forever.
Yachiyo
Screw you!
I know, right?
Too good!
Sono-chan Farewell Airsoft Tournament
All right! Time to go.
Let's go.
Next Episode: Explode a Leg!
Explode a Leg!