Was Rin-san the sniper after all?
If she was...
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
Flag Drop #1
The 24-Hour Endurance Airsoft
Tournament has finally begun.
Is a Commander
Supposed to Be Heartless?
All teams will start
each round simultaneously.
This time, we'll be using cameras positioned throughout the field
to broadcast each team's fierce battles in real time.
There are fifty-seven squads participating,
but only forty-seven flags will be parachuted in.
Which teams will get their hands on these flags and survive?
Keep up, Ren-chan!
I'm sorry.
Listen, you—
So basically, those who survive will be the teams that
before time runs out,
get to the safety zone carrying flags,
which will be dropped every three hours.
Today's Airsoft
Game
Each time, the number of flags parachuted in
will be less than the number of teams on the field.
This means that every three hours, a few teams will be eliminated, like in a game of musical chairs.
This will be an uphill battle.
But I'm sure we'll be fine, thanks to all those strategies Yura-chan came up with for us.
Yeah!
Plus, we trained really hard,
so things'll definitely work out.
While I'm sure those strategies are all theoretically sound,
this will be our first time using them in an actual match.
We'll be fine.
As long as you all follow my instructions to the letter, we will definitely win this.
We may even beat Rin-san's team.
Yep.
Y-You're right.
Well then, let's review our formations one last time.
Today's Airsoft
Game
Enemy
Opposing team spotted!
Yura-chan was right on the money, wasn't she?
An ambush?!
Damn. Stella, eh?
Running into them right off the bat... It must be fate.
But this is no time to get all misty-eyed.
Aira and I will draw their fire.
Yoichi, Miyagi, flank them.
Hibiki, go back them up.
They seem perfectly in sync.
Attacker team!
While the defender team lures the enemy out,
Enemy
the attacker team will flank them and then capture their flag.
Hit! Damn it!
We're in trouble!
Hit.
They took our flag.
We've gotta get it back!
No.
We have to think this through.
Once the point man has the flag,
Enemy
the defenders will act as a wall
to prevent any enemies from getting close to her.
Hang on. That doesn't look like KGB's camo pattern.
Is there another team here?
Don't worry about it!
Stay in formation.
Hit.
Oh, come on!
That was your plan?
Well, we're used to changing costumes quickly for plays, so we wanted to put that to use.
Only Aira's left now.
Bad news!
They got the flag back!
What?!
Freeze, please.
You're Aira-san, aren't you?
How'd you know?
Because I ordered Kari-chan-senpai to operate in a two-man cell with Ren-chan.
There's no way she'd come back by herself.
"Ordered"?
We've been completely and utterly defeated, huh?
Touchdown!
We're with Stella.
Teams are bringing flags to the safety zone one after the other,
securing their positions in the next round.
We've cleared the first round.
All right!
Man, I didn't expect things to go this smoothly.
This strategy is definitely working!
Ren-chan, you got hurt?
I ran into something.
Oh, but it doesn't hurt too bad.
Ren-chan...
Pull yourself together, guys!
The battle has only just begun.
The judges have announced that during the first round, members of the Blood 13 Team were "playing zombie,"
thus getting their team disqualified.
Continuing to play without announcing that you were hit is a violation of the rules.
Please keep in mind that if even one of its members is judged to have "played zombie,"
the entire team will be disqualified.
I guess there are always people like that, huh?
Why would anyone go that far to win?
Yeah, it's really terrible,
but this just shows how much everyone wants to win.
No Firing during Intermission — Even on the Field!
On top of which, Rin-san's team is out there too.
Let's keep our guards up and keep at it.
Flag Drop #2
Teams Remaining
Now for a look at this tournament's rising stars—
the C3 Club of Stella Women's Academy.
It seems all of the members are currently high schoolers.
Whoa! That's awesome!
Look! It's me!
I wonder if I can get a copy of this video!
Hacchan, you're out of position right here.
And here, Hono-chan-senpai, you're lagging behind.
Also, Ren-chan, you're advancing more and more slowly!
It's not her fault!
On top of carrying everyone's food and water,
she also has the heaviest equipment out of all of us.
Not to mention—
It's okay.
Ren-chan...
Haven't I made myself clear?
The point man's sole backup needs the firepower of the M-60!
I'm all right, really.
Oh, look. They're showing Rin-san live.
The airsoft team of Meisei Women's Academy, led by Haruna Rin-san,
is a favorite, having had great results in numerous tournaments.
Perhaps we can look forward to a high school girls showdown with Stella!
We must beat Rin-san's team.
It's not like I don't wanna win too,
but you know,
this just isn't any fun.
The sun's setting.
Let's prepare for night combat.
Flag Drop #5
The tournament has reached its final stages.
Flags will now have LEDs attached to them.
Flag Drop #6
The remaining teams will be using equipment designed for night combat.
Teams Remaining
Furthermore, players will now have to fight sleep in addition to each other.
This will likely be a tough time for everyone.
Flag Drop #6
Teams Remaining
Before the Final Flag Drop
Intermission
Hang in there for just a little bit longer.
The next flag drop is the final one.
What's the situation like?
There are two teams left:
ours and Rin-san's.
The time has finally come, huh?
Hey there, Stella.
Looks like you made it all the way to the final round.
Oh, it's you guys?
Whoa, you guys are still awake?
But of course. Since we've come all this way,
we want to at least see who wins.
'Sup, guys!
Sorry. We totally ended up losin'.
Aoi-chan!
We were doin' fine up till nighttime, but then we ran into Meisei.
Rin-san...
After that friendly with you guys,
we went home 'n' trained our socks off.
We even prepared some new special moves, y'know?
But we didn't stand a chance!
It wasn't just the Seto Family.
We hear Rin-san even destroyed that team of marines, one of the favorites, in but an instant.
Even the marines?
In an instant? You serious?
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
What Rin-san's team really excels at is the speed at which they achieve their objectives.
Marines
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
They qualified for each round in under twenty minutes
on average, and were the first to the safety zone every time.
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Meisei Women's Academy Airsoft Team
Marines
Team Detectives
Some people try to eliminate more teams
by capturing multiple flags,
but Meisei doesn't waste their time on such things.
The more time you spend on the field,
the higher the risk of you getting hit.
And you waste energy that way too.
Yeah.
Also, every team that has come up against Meisei
has been annihilated by having every one of its members hit.
They probably did it to prevent being pursued and hit themselves.
Annihilating every member would also prevent the opposing team from playing zombie.
Rin-san's team was truly the odds-on favorite to win this tournament, after all.
But since you guys beat us,
we want you to be the champions.
So go avenge us, 'kay?
She's really something else, that Rin-san.
But we're no pushovers ourselves.
I've gotten better,
and we've all been training hard.
If only Sono-chan were here, we could win this for sure.
Isn't that exactly why Rin shot her?
Even if you wanna win, wouldn't that be going too far?
She and I are the same.
No, no way.
I'm not like her.
Definitely not.
But...
Wait here a moment.
What do you want?
U-Um...
I need to ask you something, Rin-san.
What is it?
Um, well...
I don't have much time.
Could you get on with it?
Sonora-senpai taught me everything I know about airsoft.
There's more to airsoft than meets the eye,
and it really helps you reconsider how you want to live your life and all that.
That's just dressing it up.
Definitely sounds like Sonora.
It doesn't matter how much you romanticize airsoft.
At the end of the day, it's just an imitation of war—of destruction.
In a real war, it's all over if you lose.
The same goes for airsoft.
All you need to learn from it
is that winning is all that matters.
But that's not what you came here to ask, is it?
You want to know if I attacked Sonora, correct?
What if it was me?
I believe I asked you this once before...
I asked what you were fighting for.
Did you enter this tournament to avenge Sonora?
Well...
If you were to ask Sonora, she'd probably say,
"Forget about all that.
The most important thing is to have fun."
All I'll say is that as long as you keep following such worthless teachings,
you'll never be able to beat me.
Where the hell did Yura go?
The final flag's gonna drop any minute now!
She said she'd be right back.
Yeah.
It seems too long to be a bathroom break.
More importantly, don't you think she's being egocentric?
This leader thing has gone straight to her head!
Who the hell does she think she is?!
I can't deal with her crap!
Don't be like that.
We're just one step away from victory!
But, Ren-chan...
I'm sure Yura-chan feels the same way.
That's why she pushed herself so hard.
I want us to win too!
I want to go back and tell
Sono-chan-senpai that we won.
Well, yeah...
We've come this far.
Let's hang in there just a little bit longer.
"Just a little bit longer," huh?
Thank you for waiting!
The final round is finally upon us.
Meisei Women's Academy
versus Stella Women's Academy!
Two teams of high school girls will be squaring off
against one another. What a twist of fate!
Which team will emerge victorious?
Where the hell have you been?!
Let's talk about that later.
The match is starting.
I'm sorry.
Let's win this.
Of course.
We must not lose.
Not to her!
The final flag has been dropped!
Knowing Rin-san, she's definitely going to come after us.
Are we being ambushed?
Shit.
They know where we are!
Same here.
Retreat.
Use Formation W.
Dead on, huh?
Well, what else could I expect from Stella?
Hit!
Formation A!
Hono-chan-senpai, form a two-man cell with me.
The enemy's got us pinned down from three directions,
so why aren't they going after the flag?
Because they don't need to.
Against us, she won't aim for the flag. She's aiming to take us all out.
That's how Rin-san does things.
That bitch! I'll teach her to sell us short.
Now that we know that,
we know what to do!
Found them!
Two at the back!
Wait, there's still something—
Rin-san!
You've got the edge in terms of numbers, but too bad.
You think you've won already?
How naïve.
I win again.
Hit.
Goddamn it!
Kari-chan-senpai...
Yura-chan!
You can't take her on alone!
Go, Hono-chan-senpai.
I'll handle things here.
Roger.
I'll give it to you for getting this far.
You're far better than Sonora.
I'll never forgive you!
Out of ammo?
Yura-chan!
Hit.
I see you're just like me.
You'll do whatever it takes to win.
Everyone on the Meisei team has been hit!
Stella Women's Academy's C3 Club has won this long, hard-fought battle!
Stella Women's Academy
Club
Champions
Yura-chan, we took out all of Meisei!
We won!
I...
won, huh?
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Making eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will beat faster the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's time to go
Next Episode
Did anything unusual happen while I was hospitalized?
Lovely Girl
I took your camo fatigues without permission and soiled them.
Don't worry about it.
Lovely Girl
If anything, the camo looks more realistic now.
I ate all your instant noodles, Sono-chan!
What? Everyone's got something to confess?
I did a good thing!
Lovely Girl
What'd you do? Let's hear it.
Danger!
Lovely Girl
There was a box in your locker that had "Danger!" written on it.
Danger!
I threw it away!
Lovely Girl
What?!
Next episode: And Thus the Party Comes to a Close.
And Thus the Party Comes to a Close.
Hey, hey! I did good, right?
My precious swimsuit gravure magazines!