Oh, look.
It's the ocean.
Wait, what?
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
How'd I get here?
Good morning, Yura-chan.
Huh?
Things Heat Up on an Isolated Island.
We're playing an
important friendly today.
Did you forget?
Oh!
That's right!
I overslept!
Well, you did stay up late preparing 'cause you were so excited.
When it was time to go, you wouldn't wake,
Left, right, left, right...
so we decided to just carry you aboard.
I'm sorry!
No worries.
More importantly, check out our line of sight.
That island's gonna be our airsoft field this time,
and those guys...
our opponents!
Speed up!
Man, they're totally leavin' us in the dust.
Yeah, they're wild, all right!
Here.
The amphibious battle starts in three minutes.
Prepare for battle!
Roger!
Let's go, C3 Club!
Explode...
a leg!
Hit!
I decided I wouldn't run away anymore.
I won't ever...
go back to who I was before!
You doing okay?
I'm fine.
I can do this!
So it's down to us two, Karila, and Rento, huh?
All right.
Let's go back 'em up!
Roger.
I'm gonna save everyone!
Whoops.
When you're behind cover,
don't stick your head up to attack.
Attack from the side!
Hit.
Hit!
That was a big help!
Three to go!
I've gotta be faster
and more efficient!
Hit!
Hit.
Amazing, Yura-chan!
Look out!
Yes!
I'm hit.
We did it!
Yura, catch!
Blow the whistle of victory.
Make sure it's loud enough for the whole island to hear.
Looks like it's done!
Man, this is hella good!
Hey...
That was mine!
I'm from Team Seto Family.
I'm here ta socialize with ya guys!
Seto Family?
Seto
Midori
Momoka
Yep. 'Cause our last names're all "Seto,"
Midori
Momoka
Seto
Midori
Momoka
Seto
Akane
Moe
Seto
Akane
Moe
Seto
Akane
Moe
and our bonds're thicker than anything!
Seto
Akane
Moe
Seto
Kinako
Aoi
Seto
She ate them all!
I'd expect nothing less
from the Speedster of the West.
I know, right?
Yer a toothpick!
Ya gotta eat more, ya hear me?
I was trying to, you know.
Despite how they act,
they're one of the top airsoft teams in Kansai.
Why dontcha offer 'em that one thing?
Oh, good thinkin'!
You guys, wait a sec.
No way!
Oh, ya want me ta butcher it for ya too?
N-No!
Let it go.
Aw, man. Just when I finally caught one, too.
Yer fine with takoyaki though, right?
Let's have a takoyaki speed eating contest!
Oh, count me in!
Hey, don't overdo it, okay?
Takoyaki
Speed
Eating
Contest
Takoyaki
Speed
Eating
Contest
Takoyaki
Speed
Eating
Contest
Takoyaki
Speed
Eating
Contest
Takoyaki
Speed
Eating
Contest
Ready?
Go!
Speed
This is a riot!
Nooo!
You were awesome today, Yura-chan.
You got three of their members.
I almost didn't recognize you!
O-Oh, it wasn't...
G-Good night!
Huh?
You usin' the toilet too, Yura?
Oh, no. That's not it.
Good job today, Yura.
Thanks so much!
We've definitely gotta win tomorrow's game too!
It's up to you, Yura.
Roger!
What?
Aim without aiming.
Roger!
That's what I'm doing, but...
N-No way! Why?!
No.
No!
It's over?
I was a fool to count on you.
No, wait...
Don't go!
Wait!
How pessimistic can I get?
I'm a different person now!
Ow!
Looks like you're even more fired up this morning.
Yup!
I'll give it my all!
That's weird...
Huh? Are you looking for something?
Well, it's just that...
I dunno where our flag is.
Have you seen it?
Hmm...
Not that I remember.
Well then,
let's eat!
Let's eat!
Thif hot dog if dewifif!
The soup's great too!
First, I toasted the bun, and then
I used charcoal to grill the wiener.
The soup's just some broth,
and veggies left over from yesterday.
Honoka, I wanna marry you!
Then, you wanna be dominated, I take it?
Oh, that's right.
Sono-chan.
Apparently, we dunno where our flag is for today's match.
Any ideas?
Oh, that's no problem.
I got us a replacement already.
A replacement?
Isn't that... my bikini top?
Kari-chan's is up there too.
Why're Honoka's and my swimsuits our new flag?
Actually,
the hell is up with our replacements?!
Well, you know,
Honoka's is huge and yours is flashy, so they make the perfect flag.
Uh, about yer flag...
I ended up burning it by mistake while heatin' up our bathwater.
It's an accident befitting survival games,
so it's totally okay.
This is totally not okay!
Where's your flag?
Let's use that instead!
Uh, well,
ours met with the same fate.
That's how it is, guys,
so we won't be playing normal Capture the Flag today.
We're gonna switch to Capture the Center Flag.
You know the rules, right, Yura?
Island-Basking Rules
Today's Airsoft
You win if you capture the solitary flag
and take it to your base within the time limit. Right?
Right.
This time, our base is the dock where our boat's anchored.
And our base is the beach where our raft landed.
Now, if the player carrying the flag gets hit,
only that player leaves the field.
The flag remains where it is, and the game resumes.
Man, I feel crappy about burnin' our flags, but I'm not gonna feel bad about winnin'!
Airsoft might be fun whether ya win or lose,
but it's way more fun when ya win!
We aren't gonna lose to you!
We already won the amphibious battle.
I want to keep winning.
Our opponents are fast runners,
so I believe they'll get to the flag before us.
But the flag's heavy,
so it'll be best if we wait for them to lose steam from carrying it,
and then we take them out.
The longer the game drags on,
the likelier we are to win.
That's right.
So in preparation for the latter half of the match,
we'll split up into three teams.
Karila and I will take the middle,
Yachiyo and Rento will go right,
and Sono-chan and Yura-chan will go left.
Pay attention to our formation, okay?
Okay.
Now, recovering the flag in the endgame will be...
you, Karila.
Gotcha.
I'm gettin' my bikini back no matter what!
Okay, looks like everyone's fired up.
We're gonna go in guns blazin', all right?
All right!
You guys ready yet?
Yeah, we're good!
All right, the game starts now!
I'm not gonna let you turn this into a race!
And I'm gonna shake ya off!
An ambush?
Huh?
Something just moved.
There aren't two of them!
There's only one shooter!
I got hit...
One down.
I saw her!
She was pretending to be two people firing at once!
Yeah. But it could still be a setup, so be care—
Hit!
Let's go back them up!
Come on!
Okay.
She's here!
They sent more troops here than I expected.
Four of 'em...
No, wait. All five of 'em are here?!
They're probably thinkin' there's a bunch of us.
Speed ain't everythin' we got, ya know.
Launching the Seto Stream
Attack!
We need to retreat and pull back to a new defense line.
Otherwise, Aoi-chan's gonna shake us off!
Should we regroup with Hachi, or with Sono-chan?
Head toward Yachiyo.
I'll cover you.
Roger that.
Ugh, stay still, damn it!
You okay?
Not really.
Aoi-chan's got, like, three or four teammates with her.
I'm totally pinned.
What?!
Just how fast are these guys?
Launching the Seto Stream Attack:
Dash Turbo!
Hit.
Wait for me, guys.
I can do this!
Hey, Yura!
Be more careful!
I'm fine!
I can do this!
She's not paying attention to her surroundings at all.
Yachiyo!
Your gun barrel's in plain sight!
Get back!
Sorry!
Yura!
They were dual-wielding to make it hard to get a read on their numbers!
I'll take it from here.
Go get the flag, Kari-chan-senpai!
But you...
I'll back her up.
We'll be all right.
Hit!
Seto...
Stream Attack:
Jet—
Seto
Hit!
You're mine now!
The heck?!
I'm hit.
How'd it come ta this?!
You go, Yura!
Go recover the flag!
Roger!
Wow!
I did it!
You did it!
Yura-chan, you're amazing!
That was incredible, Yura!
My body just knew what to do.
You even gave me advice like a pro.
I was totally shocked!
I just blurted out what came to mind.
Nothing wrong with that.
You did great!
We lost!
Let's go one more time!
Just one more match!
Hey, time for a picture, guys!
Everyone, get in real close.
Okay!
Get over here, Honoka!
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep firing even when you barely survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will start racing the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
Three, two, one, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep firing even when you barely survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's about time
Next Episode
Aoi-chan, Aoi-chan!
Moe
Akane
'Sup, Moe, Akane?
Moe
Akane
Aoi
What's it mean when they say
"practically see-through"?
Moe
Akane
What's it mean when they say
"practically see-through"?
Moe
Akane
They're talkin' about optical camo.
Moe
Akane
Aoi
Moe
Akane
Aoi-chan, Aoi-chan!
Moe
Akane
'Sup?
Aoi
Akane
Moe
What's it mean when they say
"A woman's always got somethin' up her sleeve"?
Moe
Akane
What's it mean when they say
"A woman's always got somethin' up her sleeve"?
Moe
Akane
They're talkin' about the M-36 Chief's Special!
Aoi
Akane
Aoi-chan, Aoi-chan!
Moe
Akane
'Sup?!
Moe
Akane
Aoi
Next Episode: Operation "Dripping Wet" Begins.
Operation "Dripping Wet" Begins.
What's a "Dripping Wet" Operation?
What's a "Dripping Wet" Operation?!