Work with your teammates
to secure your victory!
Let this huge field be your playground
as you defeat your opponents!
The 24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
is looking for participants!
Fight and fight!
Looking for participants!
Thank you very much.
Illegally modified guns?
Yeah.
Airguns that were powered up with high-pressure gas.
The guy who made them was arrested,
but apparently, he sold one of them before he got caught.
Did the buyer get arrested too?
Nah.
They say they don't know who it was.
Since it's so dangerous,
I was told to contact the police if I had any leads.
But airsoft players are all good people!
Yura, you're so adorable.
But this is pretty bad timing.
With the 24-hour tournament coming up, I mean.
I hope nothing bad happens.
Yeah, me neither.
I'm really excited about the tournament.
I even bought a high-capacity magazine for Choujirou!
If you're that pumped up, we might have a real chance of winning this thing.
Yup!
That's why I...
Well, take it easy, girl!
These tournaments don't come around too often, so let's have some fun.
But that's exactly why I want to win.
Rin-san's team is going to be there, too.
This time for sure, I want to—
Yura!
BB pellets?
A sniper?!
Are we being targeted?
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
City Library
Second floor, five o'clock.
My Comrade Has
Fallen to an Assassin.
There's the sniper.
We've got a problem. Look.
Judging by the state of the can,
they're using an illegally modified gun.
If we get hit, it'll do some serious damage.
We should run for it.
No. I'm going after them!
This is too dangerous, Yura!
But I can't just let them get away with this.
How dare they misuse airguns!
Come on.
That was close.
Thanks, Sono-chan-senpai.
Somebody, call an ambulance!
You okay?
Sono-chan-senpai?
Are you okay?
No way...
Hey...
Hirakawa General Hospital
Sono-chan!
You doin' all right?
Hey! Thanks for coming, you guys.
Sorry for making you all worry.
I-It's not like I was all that worried about you.
It looks bad, though. You sure you're okay?
It was all good till I fell while trying to avoid the car.
I must've landed badly.
It looks painful.
I've only got a mild concussion, but my ankle's sprained.
Looks like it'll take me three weeks to recover.
Three weeks?
That means you'll miss the 24-hour tournament...
Well, no use crying over spilt milk.
Damn it!
That sniper's gonna get a good ass-whoopin'!
Leave that to the cops.
Don't get so worked up over this, you guys.
Instead, just focus on having tons of fun
during the tournament for me.
That's the most important thing.
Well, I guess you're right...
This is my fault.
She got hurt trying to save me.
I'll assume all responsibility and quit the C3 Club.
What?
Calm down, Yura-chan.
Quitting won't solve anything.
Besides, it's that sniper who's to blame!
Yeah, exactly!
Sono-chan said we should forget about it, but this is too much to overlook.
Why would someone attack Sono-chan-senpai, though?
Maybe they've got a grudge against her?
Could it be...
Haruna Rin?!
C-Come on now.
You all don't really think she'd go that far, do you?
I guess it is against the law and all...
But don't you guys think she's capable of it?
What do you think, Yura?
W-Well...
That'd be too much.
I can't bring myself to think
any airsoft player would stoop so low.
W-Well, yeah.
I guess I went a little too far.
It's unusual for someone to do that, right?
Yeah...
Anyway, we're in trouble for the tournament.
What'll we do?
It's gonna be tough without Sono-chan.
Plus, powerhouse teams from
all over the country are participating.
We don't stand a chance with our current lineup!
I won't even be able to have fun without Sono-chan-senpai.
Yeah, really.
I guess we should just call it quits, then.
Sorry.
Huh?
I forgot something in Sono-chan-senpai's room.
You guys, go on ahead.
Excuse me...
Sono-chan-senpai?
She fell asleep, huh?
I came back to talk to you about the tournament.
They're all saying we should give up on it
because you won't be there with us.
What should I do?
They're not acting like the C3 Club I know and love!
I'm sorry I did this to you.
So I'll take care of this.
I'll take your place.
So please get some rest and leave it up to me.
Kashima Sonora, Senior
Yamato Yura, Freshman
That's right.
I should be able to do this.
Hey, what are you doing for summer vacation?
I'm going abroad!
I'm going on a family trip too.
I'm totally jealous!
Man, what're we gonna do over the break?
Come, Summer Vacation
Well, we never registered for the tournament.
Not like we'd win even if we did apply.
Come, Summer Vacation
By the way, you guys seen Yurako?
She hasn't come by recently.
She's probably focusing on her studies.
Yeah, she's even been reading while walking!
She must've done terrible on her finals.
Come, Summer Vacation
Maybe I should take a summer class...
since it's not like we'll be in the tournament.
I signed us up for the 24-hour tournament.
Come, Summer Vacation
Huh? Weren't you studying, Yura-chan?
No. I was making these.
Confidential
"The C3 Club Surefire Strategy"?
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Confidential
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Top Secret
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
The C3
Club
Surefire
Strategy
Yes.
Let's see...
Strategy pattern A for forest battles.
This is a tactical formation, isn't it?
Lemme see.
You made plans for all different sorts of battles?
Urban warfare, various offensive strategies, base defense,
parachute operations, amphibious tactics, antitank and anti-aircraft tactics—
Wait. These have nothing to do with airsoft!
I came up with battle formations based on our combat style
so that we can deal with all kinds of fields and strategies.
Whoa now...
They all look so interesting.
Way to go, Yura-chan.
Huh?
That's right. We've always left the planning to Hono-chan till right before the battle.
Yeah, there are some ridiculous ideas in here,
but there are some good ones too.
If we use them properly,
we might be able to win this tournament!
Let's put Yura-chan in charge, and give this a shot.
Agreed!
Still, we need Sono-chan around for stuff like this...
Let's do this!
Let's work together and win this tournament!
For Sono-chan-senpai!
Yeah!
Well, whatever.
24-Hour Endurance
Airsoft Tournament
Blitz Go! Go!
Attack Strategy
The 24-hour tournament is basically a scramble to capture the limited flags on the field.
As we're short one member, we're at a disadvantage in terms of finding the flags first.
Attack Strategy
Therefore, our strategy will focus on capturing a flag from another team.
That's where Yura-chan's plan comes in.
First, we'll split our team into attackers and defenders.
The attacker team will be Kari-chan on point,
with Ren-chan backing her up.
The two of you will try to link up and capture a flag from the opponent.
At the same time, we defenders will try
to divide the enemy and keep them at bay.
This strategy hinges on quickly switching formations depending on what our opponents do.
We need to be perfectly coordinated.
Let's give it our all!
10 days
until the
tournament
Here I go!
Oh, I'm sorry!
You're moving too early, Kari-chan-senpai!
Get in sync with Ren-chan!
You two are too in sync!
Everyone's totally uncoordinated.
Kari-chan-senpai keeps jumping the gun,
Hono-chan-senpai and Hacchan aren't on the same page,
and Ren-chan's not being cautious enough.
You're all good individually,
but you're wasting your abilities like this!
Also, you take too much time to move into formation.
Average
Target: under 30 seconds!
You should take at most thirty seconds to reach each objective.
Easy for you to say.
This is impossible!
Well, make it possible!
We should be able to move as a unit.
Yeah, just like Rin-san's team.
If we can't do that, we'll never be able to beat her.
Don't you want to win?
You know...
we all wanna win, but isn't this going too far?
Yeah, I had no idea Yura could be like this.
I'm sure she's just feeling desperate right now.
She's got a strong sense of responsibility,
and she thinks it's all her fault Sono-chan got hurt.
But you know...
she could stand to back off a little.
Yeah.
For real.
I'm sure they'll come to understand why I'm doing this.
That's just another reason we have to win!
9 days
to go
1 week
days
to go
Karila
days
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Only
1 day
to go
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
_will be the championship trophy!
Bang!
Club
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
will be the championship trophy!
Bang!
Club
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
will be the championship trophy!
Bang!
Club
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
will be the championship trophy!
Bang!
Club
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
will be the championship trophy!
Club
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
will be the championship trophy!
Club
Sonora's hospital discharge gift
will be the championship trophy!
Club
Hirakawa General Hospital
It's that time of year again!
The summer festival for airsoft players:
the Fifth 24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament!
This battleground spans the area of five Tokyo Domes.
Queue
In total, fifty-seven teams will be—
Please refrain from shooting when outside the field!
Attention please. To the parents of Fujiwara Yoshikazu-chan,
your daughter is waiting for you in front of the main office.
Safety checks will be performed over here!
Please speak to the nearest staff member immediately.
So this is the 24-hour tournament?
Wh-What is it?
Nothing. Just thinking that you're back to your old self.
Yeah, for real. You're way better like this, Yurako.
I bet you're surprised by how hectic things are here!
Well, this is the largest festival for the airsoft world.
There are plenty of shops and stalls here.
There are also gun manufacturers' shops
and exhibits of their new products.
Hey, they're selling Sixteen merchandise over there!
Sixteen
Sixteen!
I also spot a doujin corner.
Better hurry up, or they'll sell out!
Gotcha!
Wait for me!
Aren't you gonna buy something too, Yura-chan?
It's a festival, after all.
No...
I'll pass.
Come on, Ren-chan. Hurry up!
We're back!
We bought lots of stuff!
You guys are too laid back!
Did you forget we have a match soon?
What's the big deal?
We told you this was a festival.
You're missing out if you don't have some fun.
How could I have fun without Sono-chan-senpai here?!
Oh, come on...
C-Calm down, you two.
Hey there, Stella girls.
Oh, you're Seikou Academy's...
KGB.
Finally showed up in full strength, eh?
But what's with all that stuff you've got?
Well, we brought equipment befitting this big stage.
Oh, it's your first time here, isn't it?
This is Tsubaki Hibiki, our sniper.
I'm Mochizuki Miyagi.
I'll be attending Stella next year!
Nice to meet you, senpai!
Oww...
Hey, knock it off.
Please excuse my little sister.
She's a huge Sonora fan.
Anyway, I'm Mochizuki Yoichi.
You're the rising star they say beat Sonora-san, right?
I've heard a lot about you.
Who cares? They were just water guns.
By the way, I heard about what happened to Sonora-san.
I heard it was pretty rough.
Oh, don't let that bother you.
No need to hold back with us today.
But without your star, I think
you'll have a tough time today.
Even excluding Meisei Academy, you've got teams like...
Hokkaido's Team Grizzlies.
And over there, made up of a certain
gun manufacturer's staff, is the Team Detectives.
And like all good detectives, they only carry handguns
and play airsoft in those clothes.
But apparently, they're good with airguns,
what with them being gun makers and all.
Whoa! Look at those guys!
An overseas team comprised of active-duty marines.
They're one of the favorites.
Speaking of favorites, there's another team you should know already.
Seto Family, led by Seto Aoi, is participating as the Kansai representative.
Rumor has it that they're hell-bent on getting revenge on you guys.
I'd like to see 'em try!
You all seem well informed.
We are the special intelligence unit,
Seikou Academy's
KGB!
Rumble
Our name's not just for show!
We've analyzed and come up with
countermeasures for you guys too!
Let's both give it our best shot!
Definitely.
Bring it on.
All right. Why don't we get ready, too?
First, we should sort out the paperwork.
Oh, I'll go put our luggage away, then.
I'll help!
Participants, please check in here!
Those who have finished checking in,
please collect your supplies over there.
Supplies?
Water, food, and BB pellets.
Oh, and each team will also be given a PDA so they can stay on top of proceedings.
That's pretty generous of 'em!
Reception
Haruna Rin!
I hear Sonora's going to be hospitalized for a while.
What on earth was she thinking, getting hurt at such a place?
Say what?!
Wait... "At such a place"?
You say that like you were there.
I just happened to be passing by, that's all.
But I never imagined I'd see Sonora looking so unsightly.
What do you mean by "unsightly"?!
I hope for your own sake that was all you did.
What else could I have done?
Come on, Karila!
Who knows?
Either way, Sono-chan not being here is convenient for you guys, isn't it?
I'll crush Stella, whether Sonora's here or not.
By any means necessary.
"By any means necessary"?
Try to put up a fight this time, will you?
You bitch! How can you be like that?
Karila!
Weren't you and Sono-chan friends?!
That's exactly why I can't forgive her.
That's all.
Maybe she really was the sniper.
Knock it off!
It really might've been a coincidence that she was there.
Was it Rin-san after all?
Either way, I'm gonna kick her ass!
Fighting Meisei will be quite the uphill battle, you know.
Yeah, I know!
But we've been training hard too, haven't we?
Hey!
We put our stuff in the lockers.
Huh? Did something happen?
No, it was nothing.
At any rate, now that we've come this far,
we'd better prepare ourselves.
Let's fight until the bitter end!
All right. Let's do this!
Of course!
I'll do my best too!
Explode...
a leg!
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Making eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will beat faster the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's time to go
Next Episode
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
Oh no! I forgot my sunscreen!
Sixteen
24-Hour Endurance Airsoft Tournament
Wanna use mine?
Can I really? Thanks!
Here. Have
some sunscreen.
Sixteen
What's the SPF of the one you brought, Karila?
I accidentally bought, like, a super low one.
"SPF"?
Click
Coffee
Yeah, not to be confused with "FPS."
Yeah, I dunno, but I've never gotten sunburned using this.
Here.
What's with this pot? It's full of mud.
So tired.
Huh? Nah, that's sunscreen.
It's in a pot? How cute.
Is a Commander
Supposed to Be Heartless?
I know, right?
Seriously?!
Next Episode
Is a Commander Supposed to Be Heartless?
Next Episode: Is a Commander Supposed to Be Heartless?
I'm gonna go check the stalls for sunscreen.
Me too.