Keep your head down!
I can't!
Will Sono-chan-senpai's squad
actually come this way?
Of course.
It's Sono-chan we're talkin' about.
Just concentrate on digging.
What's this hole for?
For stuffing in enemy grenades before they go off.
Oh...
Let's go.
Charge!
Roger!
Senpai!
Don't let 'em close in!
Give 'em all you've got!
Ren-chan! Kari-chan-senpai!
Stella Jogakuin
Koutouka C3-bu
jibun dake de kimeta
Any limits
kanousei nante mou
That I place on myself
waracchau kurai ate ni naranai kara
are laughably mistaken
tojita me de tsukuridashite ita
This illusion of safety I've created
anzenken oitekebori ni shite yukou
I'll leave it behind and forge ahead
mirai ga mada reticle no
It doesn't matter if I can't capture the future
mannaka toraerarenakute mo
Dead center in my crosshairs
kao wo agerun da
I'll hold my head high
itsumo no basho mo
I'm going to shape my world
nibiiro no rule mo
And all of its gray rules
tsumazuite mo kaete iku kara
Even if I stumble in the process
te wo torare nagara
And have to be dragged by the arm
demo aruite iku
I'll keep walking
ashiato wa takusan no iro de
And leave behind
afureteru no
Many colorful footprints
Club
I'm serious!
The scenery changed right before my eyes!
And before I knew it,
I was in the middle of a desert battlefield.
There was a tank, and then hundreds of people ran by!
Real Gunslingers Don't Need Guns.
Oh?
Guess that's that.
The three of us in the garrison squad
heroically suffered a crushing defeat!
Wah... Boom!
I'm weird, aren't I?
Would you like some more?
I guess so.
Me too!
You managed to "see it," Yura.
I believe you saw it too, whatever it was.
I mean, I'd love to have seen it myself.
Yeah, seeing something like that
sounds like it'd be fun.
Yeah.
Thank you!
Oh, Yurako's revived!
There we have it, then. Yura wins today's game.
Huh?
The one who has the most fun wins, you see.
You win if you have fun?
Yeah.
There are plenty of
different ways to enjoy airsoft.
We may look like we're
all doing the same thing,
but we each have
our own unique experiences.
You've got your own airsoft too, Yura.
My own airsoft?
Yeah.
The airsoft that only you can see.
An airsoft just for you.
And since you had so much fun playing that airsoft, you won.
Except she didn't.
Hey!
But I'd still like to
get better enough to really win.
That so?
You free after this?
Y-Yeah.
Then, it's time for some training!
You're going to teach her that, aren't you?
You guessed it.
How about it?
Count me in!
I could probably take one more person too...
Me!
I win!
Scissors!
Sorry I'm late!
There was something I wanted to give you,
but it took a while to find.
Isn't this...
A Škorpion vz. 61.
It's a famous Czechoslovakian submachine gun.
Try folding out that part.
Doesn't it look like a scorpion's tail?
That's why it's called a "Škorpion."
Wow...
You close it by squeezing here.
Just like that.
Small but deadly, like a scorpion.
It's a great gun.
Take good care of it.
But...
Relax.
I'm only lending it to you.
What? Really?
Well, my master left me that gun.
I'll give you an even better one, Yura.
If you pass, that is.
Wait for me!
You're almost there.
Yachiyo and Rento didn't break a sweat, you know.
Both of us went through this training last year.
The goal's right over there.
What's the matter?
A fox! Look, a white fox!
It's gone...
Come on, Yura-chan.
Sure, this may be an Inari shrine,
but there aren't any foxes around here.
Did you, by chance,
"see" something again?
Nah, must've been my imagination.
Aside from the main god of this shrine, another deity is worshipped here.
It's a god of war from the Heian period,
a soldier from the Heike clan.
We're all set!
Thank you!
Nobody even knows his name.
According to legend,
he was a handsome and unparalleled
genius at archery from the young age of fifteen.
That's gotta be Nasu-no-Yoichi.
But he was a Minamoto...
So it's gotta be Taira-no-Yoichi.
I just said nobody knows his name!
How come?
Beats me.
Maybe it's 'cause he was so young when he died in the Genpei War.
Oh, Yura-chan.
What if you were to see him?
Wouldn't you like to talk to him?
Y-Yeah, I guess so.
I'd at least want to find out his name.
Yura, be careful what you wish for.
You might get spirited away and never come back.
Th-That's not funny!
I bet he never even had
the chance to find a girlfriend.
Those kinds of deities can be pretty wild.
Be careful you don't get abducted.
Now, let's get started, Yura.
O-Okay.
I will now teach you one of the arts of airsoft:
Japanese Gun Fu.
I-I would be honored.
5 Yen
What?!
That's your target?!
Yep.
But it's so tiny!
And probably out of airgun range, too...
Just watch.
What?!
Bull's-eye...
It's not really all that difficult.
What?!
Wanna give it a go too, Rento?
Ren-chan, you can do this too?
I wonder.
Bull's-eye.
It's thanks to that god of war
that we can do this,
so you can do it too, Yura-chan.
Really?
Come on, didn't I say it wasn't difficult?
Yeah!
Put on your shoes.
Let's try it from up close first.
5 Yen
Can you hit it at this range?
Probably.
Huh?
Why? Why can't I hit it?!
Yura, this isn't shooting practice, you know.
We're aiming to get you to grasp airsoft.
In truth, airsoft has got
nothing to do with marksmanship.
Why do you suppose that is?
I don't know.
Because airsoft isn't that simple.
Tons of people participate,
and the flow of battle constantly changes direction
depending on the distance to your enemy,
the distance to your allies,
and your own position.
So forget about hop-up,
precision barrels, and all that jazz.
There's no surefire method to land your bullets.
So, how do you suppose we hit our enemies?
Hmm...
Shoot them from point-blank range, maybe?
Exactly. A zero-centimeter range will do the trick.
But in order to get that close, the shooter and her target must become one and the same.
Get it?
The target you need to hit
is none other than yourself.
Enemies,
allies,
and the entirety of the airsoft field...
Make them all one and the same.
That way, you and your target will be zero nanometers apart!
It's okay, Yura-chan.
I have no idea what she's saying either.
My bad.
Master—uh, I mean, the person who taught me all this...
I didn't know what he was talking about at first either.
But... well, you'll see once you give it a shot.
Give it another try, Yura.
I'll do my best!
5 Yen
First, keep an unblinking eye on your target.
Okay!
Don't target it. Look at it.
This is what we call "aim without aiming."
"Aim without aiming."
Yeah. And don't shoot. Wait.
This, we call "shoot without shooting."
"Shoot without shooting."
"Look" and "wait"...
until the target
comes to you of its own accord.
Okay.
It will "come," right?
You fail because you search for success.
But to truly succeed, you must first
make everything one and the same.
If a shooter is in the perfect frame of mind,
her shots will hit the target.
5 Yen
There's no need to rush.
Just wait for the target to shoot itself for you.
Here it comes!
Yay!
Whoa! It came to you already?
Yeah, I think so!
Then, take three steps back, and try it again.
Three steps, right?
Guess I can let the
cat out of the bag now.
Huh?
To be honest, you've already completed 99% of this training with that step alone.
If you keep it up while
gradually increasing the distance,
you'll be at our initial shooting line in no time.
Yura-chan, you're amazing!
It took us days to do that!
We're gonna finish this with time to spare.
Wanna go get some cake after this?
Yay! Thanks!
Stay focused.
Okay.
Try it again.
O-Okay!
That's weird...
Maybe we should call it a day, Sono-chan-senpai.
Yeah, you're right.
All right—
I can keep going!
Nah, we're supposed to leave the shrine before it gets dark.
We'll come back another day.
Yeah.
Time to get some of that cake! It's on me.
I can't believe you ate the whole thing.
What're you gonna do when your boobs get even bigger?
You have a point...
Then, I'll start limiting myself to
one lump of sugar with my tea!
I don't see how that's gonna help.
Oh, Sono-chan-senpai, I have your gun—
Just give it back later.
Don't take it out on a train!
What's the matter?
Oh no... it's gone!
So it's at the store we just left, huh?
But I didn't open my bag there!
It must be at the shrine.
But I'm sure you put it in your bag, Yura-chan.
I was in a daze, so I don't really remember...
I'm gonna go check!
I'll call you!
Hey, it's too late to—
You've finally come.
You're Yura, yes?
How do you know my name?
Choujirou.
Huh?
It's my name.
You said you wanted to know what it was, right?
Oh...
I'm just seeing weird things again, huh?
Weird?
Yeah...
I may have perished,
but as an Ise Heike, my glory is still intact.
So don't you think you're being a bit rude?
I'm a god, you know!
Sorry, Choujirou-san.
There's something important I have to find,
so I'll see you later.
What exactly do you think I am?
A figment of my imagination?
I must be really tired...
You're mistaken!
You set foot into a god's domain—into my domain!
A god, eh?
Very well.
Yura.
I'll teach you what it means to be truly powerful.
That is the reason I summoned you here.
What?
It begins now...
Your world, that is.
And along with it, the world you shall create for me.
Where are we?
Didn't I tell you already?
This is your world, Yura.
Your world and my domain are resonating.
This is the era I lived in,
on the last day of my life...
My very last moment.
Huh?
I've been fighting forever...
Fighting an endless battle
that I can never, ever win.
You're going to lose?
Yes,
I will lose, and then I will die.
N-No! You can't!
Will you save me, then?
Can I?
You can.
You only have to shoot.
But this is just an airgun!
Does that look like a toy gun to you?
I believe you already know
that this world will make
everything you want come true.
And whenever you run from reality,
this world will be right here,
waiting to fulfill your every need.
Hasn't it been doing so
since you were a child?
Stop saying all these weird things!
Yours is an amazing power
able to swallow the world whole!
So don't hide behind your illusions.
Instead, turn them into reality.
Then, the entire world will be yours.
Nothing you're saying makes any sense!
I thought you of all people would help me...
We're out of time.
Welcome back.
You had me worried.
Sorry I didn't take your calls right away.
It was at the shrine.
Oh! Welcome back, Choujirou.
Senpai, what'd you just say?!
Choujirou?
It's the name my master gave that gun.
Nice and exotic, ain't it?
Yura, what's wrong?
H-Hey, Yura!
Kashima Sonora, Senior
Yamato Yura, Freshman
Are you sure that young warrior called himself Choujirou?
I'm sure.
Sounds like you saw something incredible.
Sono-chan-senpai, what should I...
Hmm?
What should I do?
If you really wanna know the answer to that,
go back tomorrow.
Either choose to let him die,
or choose to kill his enemy.
My master was an American soldier.
He was good at what he did,
so he was sent to the frontlines.
Okay...
So one day,
I got the call that he'd been killed in action.
What?!
After hearing that, I just couldn't play airsoft.
Of course you couldn't.
But after a while,
I realized that that's simply the nature of
facing off with guns and shooting people,
so I started playing again.
What? Why?!
That's strange! It's too weird!
Huh?
Did you forget what you said?
You said you win if you have fun.
Doesn't that mean you lose if you don't?
I guess so.
So, aren't you losing
by playing airsoft that way?
You can't play like that! You just can't!
I believe I also said
that although we look like
we're doing the same thing,
we each have our own airsoft.
I'm no exception.
I enjoy my own airsoft
from the bottom of my heart.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
O-Okay.
If, by chance, you don't find airsoft fun
after today or after tomorrow,
you can just quit, can't you?
5 Yen
Wasn't Yura-chan acting a little strange?
Will she be okay?
She'll be fine.
Yura's just gone to visit
a world that only she can see.
She'll be all right by herself.
H-Hey!
Forgot to give her this!
Wh-What?!
What is this place?
Yura-chan?
Yours is an amazing power able to swallow the world whole!
So don't hide behind your illusions.
Instead, turn them into reality.
Then, the entire world will be yours.
Okay.
If this is my own airsoft,
then...
Club
Whaaat?!
I'm serious!
The scenery changed right before my eyes!
And before I knew it, I was in the middle of a Tale of the Heike battlefield.
Well?
What did Choujirou say then?
"You have my praise!"
But you know, I never woulda thought Yura had a thing for old men!
What? Choujirou was a
ridiculously handsome young man.
It's a shame he died so early
during a battle with the Minamoto...
Huh? Are you saying he kept fighting even when he was old and gray?
Huh?
Having your own little world is all well and good,
but don't go getting history wrong.
What?
Oh, right.
You got perfect marks,
so here's a memento for the occasion.
Choujirou!
But you said—
If you've fallen for it that badly, I gotta give it to ya.
Thank you!
All right! We've got Darjeeling tea today.
It's this year's premier second flush!
command
Command!
control
Control!
communication
Communication!
shikyubu
The C3 Club!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
egao ni nacchatte tanoshinde nanbo jan
Put a smile on your face and enjoy yourself
nakama to eye contact de
Making eye contact with your friends
terechaun dakedo ii kamo
might make you blush, but that's okay
shinjiatte hajikemashou ready
Believe in each other and get ready
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go, go!
nakama to mezase flag get
Look to capture all the flags together
susumeba kanjiru dokidoki
Your heart will beat faster the further you get
atatte hajikemashou
Let's explode a leg
dane
Yeah
three two one go-go
3, 2, 1, go-go!
kanashii mo kurushii mo norikoetara
Once you get over your pain and sorrow,
ima yori mo zutto zutto zutto egao ni naru
you'll have a much, much bigger smile on your face
zenin haichi ni tsuke
Battle stations, everyone!
hai hai hai hai hai
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
survival chatte mo gangan utte
Keep on shooting, even if you think you won't survive
flag tocchatte sou banban hit!
Keep capturing flags one after the other
namida ubachatte mo seishun hashire
Keep chasing your teenage dream through the tears
ban ban ban whoo
ishin denshin
One for all and all for one
ippou zenshin
Take a giant leap forward
utsumuku na mae wo nuke
Look on the bright side
harikicchatte
Pump yourself up
omatase
It's time to go
Next Episode
What's wrong, Hono-chan-senpai?
Well, it's not really a big deal.
I'm here for you, if there's anything I can do!
Me too!
If it's money problems, you can count on me!
I was simply worrying about fitting into last year's swimsuit,
since my breasts have gotten even bigger—
Okay, dismissed!
Dismissed!
Hey, come on!
Next Episode:
Things Heat Up on an Isolated Island.
There's nothing wrong with a little muffin top, in my opinion.
Cleavage is fine too!