Now it's time for me to return the favor.
Let's go catch that runaway crow!
But they're in the air.
We'll need a projectile of some kind.
Ibara!
Maybe this'll help.
I got it from that warehouse over there.
Sweet, a Hand Arrow!
Nice find, Aoi!
All right! We're going after...
that monstrous crow!
hey men koko de kiken
Hey men, danger lurks here,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men mori no oku de
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
setting for the forest's end
shougai arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni ketsuen inai
you will find no kin
angai doro darake kizu darake kono tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Pretty words will not calm me
anshin nante shitenai
kyokou kara
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
will you have faith?
yes or no?
kirisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama ni naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 4:
Sunset
It's heading due south!
It's gonna pass the river!
Do you know how to use that thing?
Yeah! I learned it in gym class.
Damn it!
They want to attack us from behind!
They seem pretty mad! What now?!
Make a turn when you can!
They'll probably follow us!
You were right!
It's right on our tail!
What's with that thing?
Why can't they leave us alone?
Probably 'cause they've got something to hide.
Hurry up and do something, Ibara!
To hell with it.
Here goes nothin'!
Damn it!
I can't hit it from this angle!
It'll just get taken out by air-to-air missiles!
Ibara! This is pointless!
We're no match for that thing!
Wait.
Even the most sophisticated radars always have a blind spot.
I learned about it in school.
Hang on!
A bunch of golfing supplies?!
This is insane!
We're out of options.
I'll try hiding us in a tunnel.
On the count of three, slam on the brakes!
One.
Two.
Three!
Take this!
You did it!
You're the best, Ibara!
The blind spot was right beneath it.
Huh?
They're getting away.
No big deal.
They'll just crash-land in the riv— Huh?
Oh no! It's headed for the speedboat racing pool!
Speedboat racing pool?
It's similar to a rainwater reservoir.
If they manage to put out the flames, they'll get away!
After it! Hurry!
Uh-oh! Stop the jeep!
This is where the danger zone begins!
I'm just going to slow you down, aren't I?
Go after that monstrous crow.
You girls are able to proceed past this point.
I'll return to base.
The helicopter will be here in another two hours.
Just hold on until then.
See you later!
Stay alert.
They'll be armed.
Ibara!
L-Look...
We're too late.
Wh-Who are these people?
Mercenaries, most likely.
I screwed up again.
I let people die.
There it is!
It hasn't sunk yet.
I'm so tired...
If you can get through this,
I'll take you out for ice cream.
Ibara! There's something in the water!
What?!
Yellow canisters. Like a million of them.
What are they?
This is...
high-level waste!
What?
W-Waste?
That answers our question.
This is what's causing the abnormal levels of contamination.
The waste leaked out from here and spread to the surrounding areas.
But who brought them here, and how?
Wait a minute...
The stealth aircraft!
Damn.
Just as we suspected.
They just dumped it here,
completely unregulated.
All possible thanks to this stealth aircraft.
High-level waste?!
Yes.
Seems like our intruder was dumping it in the speedboat racing pool.
We're looking for clues right now.
Ibara!
Check this out!
What does this sticker mean?
It's got a yellow cake on it.
What?! A yellow cake?
Do you know what it is, sir?
If I recall correctly,
there's supposed to be a back-end company called "Yellow Cake" in Japan.
"Back-end"?
It's a business that deals in the disposal of used fuel and hazardous waste.
So you're saying that they're the ones who brought this refuse here?
Yes. Probably from abroad.
High-level waste is very dangerous.
There aren't really any places to dispose of it.
But isn't it fine as long as we properly bury and supervise it?
And shrug off our responsibilities to future generations?
You girls should know better.
That mountain of waste is a symbol of mankind's greed. A cross that we must all bear.
But every nation is now in over their heads
and desperately looking for somewhere to get rid of their dregs.
And that would be...
No way!
Yes. The old capital.
No matter how much waste you dump here,
you can't contaminate this place any further.
Fully knowing that,
Yellow Cake probably accepted hazardous waste from around the world for exorbitant fees,
and then came here to relieve themselves of that cross.
They wanna turn this city into a dumpin' ground for hazardous waste?
Who do these morons think they are?!
Ibara! Calm down!
How low can they stoop?!
Have they already forgotten
what happened here?!
What do they think this city is?
What are we to these people?!
This is Kamata.
I overheard your discussion.
Is the professor with you?
He isn't back at the base yet?!
Huh?
No. I figured he was still with you guys.
Where is he then?
Professor, where are you?
I know you can hear me.
Professor Shiba, come in!
Where are you?!
I am responsible for all that has happened.
I opened Pandora's box
before I knew how to close it.
You're wrong!
We all opened it together!
She's right, Professor!
There's no reason to shoulder the entire responsibility by yourself!
Professor, stop being silly!
Can't you see how worried we are about you?!
Um, I don't think you should be so hard on yourself.
Thank you.
Thanks to all of you, I've made up my mind.
I will assume responsibility for the accident here and now
and clear the name of science.
Kamata, I'll leave the rest to you.
P-Professor?!
It was a mistake to leave him by himself!
Damn it!
I screw up everything I do!
If sacrificing this city
could save the world...
Then I'd destroy the world!
Remember how that apple tasted?
Is that what you want your future to taste like?!
It's not too late.
Never give up, no matter what!
Professor, where are you?
Please come out!
Damn it!
Do we have any clues where he might be?
This is Kamata!
Granny's been rambling constantly over here.
About what?
Put her on.
He might be at the shrine south of the row of zelkova trees.
He often used to take me there to pray.
It has quite the sunset view.
The delivery man was very fond of it as well.
We're heading for the shrine!
Naruse!
The helicopter's ETA is 30 minutes.
Roger that!
Land at the Air Self-Defense Force base.
Listen to me!
Don't you dare let the Professor die!
Make sure you capture him alive!
"Capture him alive"?
That's a terrible way to put it.
The vice-principal lost his family in that accident.
Both his wife and his young daughter.
That delivery man would always escort me to the shrine.
He would even help me up the stairs.
He never once complained,
even though he was no spring chicken himself.
I felt bad for him.
He's already atoned more than enough.
I forgive him.
You should tell him that yourself.
Good.
This place ain't as contaminated as I feared.
The professor's hazmat suit oughta be enough to keep him safe.
Let's split up and search the area!
Right!
Professor!
Professor! Please answer!
The worship hall...
Seems like it's still in pretty good shape.
Lovely, isn't it?
I tend to it every day.
Professor! Thank goodness—
What a pleasant breeze.
And the sunlight...
I'd forgotten how warm it felt.
It's so beautiful.
Your mask...
When did you take it off?
Just now.
I heard the footsteps of an angel.
We've got ten minutes!
Ibara! Oh my god...
What are you doing?
He doesn't have his mask on!
I gave him a shot of Aether.
The contaminants haven't penetrated the ion exchanger yet.
We're going back to base! Stat!
What's happening?
Did you find him?
You have to get back to
base within ten minutes!
The Professor took off his mask!
He has less than ten minutes until his last dose of Aether wears off!
No, less than nine now!
Get that thing going!
Step on it!
Ibara, shouldn't we put his mask back on?
The mask is useless at this point!
This is how it should be.
I can feel death slowly approaching.
It's an end befitting a foolish man.
Don't say such things!
You're going to make it!
You can't just give up on living like that!
Aren't we there yet?!
He only has seven minutes left!
I can see it!
We're nearing the old capital!
We're on the main road now!
We're nearly there!
Damn it! C'mon...
What's taking them so long?!
Oh! There you are!
Professor, why the hell
would you do that?!
Where's the helicopter?
Huh?!
It's not here yet!
Say what?!
B-But we're nearly out of time...
It's all up to the vice-principal now.
Your vice-principal...
The accident affected him too, did it not?
I heard you talking about it.
He lost his wife and daughter.
I may as well have killed them myself.
How I wish I could turn back the hands of time,
back to the golden days of the past.
I implore you... Let me die.
I couldn't bear to face him.
The vice-principal isn't that kind of a person.
He's a Self-Defense Force member.
A Self-Defense Force member's job is to protect the people.
That's why he's headed this way:
to extend a helping hand.
It's too late.
He has less than a minute left!
Damn it...
The helicopter's here!
Stay with him!
Here's the Aether!
Catch!
Ibara!
Hurry!
Yes!
Just in the nick of time!
His readings are normal.
We made it, Ibara!
Thank goodness.
Thank goodness...
Ibara!
Let me help you.
You think I don't have legs?!
Easy, Granny!
I got it. Just... get in.
You seem exhausted.
Please take my hand,
Professor Shiba.
Thank you.
Would you stop crying already, Aoi?
Miss Ibara.
Yes?
Not only have the mistakes of my generation brought great sadness upon yours,
but now we are forcing you to clean up after us.
Please forgive us for making the world this way.
I...
I don't get all those complicated things.
But there is one thing that I do get.
And that's...
that this world is a place worth living in.
That's why I'm not really all that sad.
Take care, everybody!
Bye-bye!
This is a list of the people who
stayed behind in the old capital.
Please...
Use your abilities to save them.
Save this beautiful city.
Mr. Vice-principal.
I can see in those girls the very essence of mankind.
Yes.
I couldn't agree more, Professor.
Aw... They're gone.
Now it's just us three again.
Dang it!
I forgot to ask them for an RV!
With this list,
we won't have to go walkin' around, searchin' every little place.
Oh well, a little exercise'll do us good.
We'll just take our time and do some sightseein'.
Next stop: downtown!
Um, Ibara.
You don't have to try so hard anymore.
Huh? What do you mean?
I got no clue what you're talkin' about.
Whatever!
Let's just go!
The two of us are Coppelion too.
We may not be as useful as you, Ibara,
but I realized something today.
You're not superhuman.
Even you need help sometimes.
You don't have to keep it all bottled in.
We'll always be there for you.
You two...
Much obliged.
Okay then. Let's go!
Our amazing school trip's only just started!
Hey, Ibara, let's go on a tour!
Be my guest.
What?
Taeko, you wanna go too, don't you?
Me? Not really...
She's just human
aitsu wa tada hito
She doesn't ask herself what she is
shiritagaru mon ja nai
I'm just human
watashi wa tada hito
I'm not a doll
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku darou
Nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki kono setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku toukeiteki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku darou
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no okusoko made
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
Only sadness is real, and philosophy a waste of time
kangaeta hou ga katachi da kujiketa hou ga genjitsu da
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Dawn will break on our blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni ake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of the vanity of grief,
kurushimi no munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
The final class roll call.
Territory.
Ghosts.
A lead barrier wall.
A pregnant woman.
The cleanup staff.
The planet.
An indoor garden.
Next time on Coppelion: "Life."
Episode
Life