Shit! It's the Iron Spider!
The Iron Spider?
The 1st Division's secret weapon!
They're gonna use the flamethrower!
Run! They're firing!
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 11:
Awakening
They mean to reduce the whole city to rubble.
Why do you all try to hurt each other?
Weren't you all created equal?
Miss Aoi!
M-My sweater's stuck!
Nice landing!
Ibara!
The Iron Spider's coming!
Step on it, Haruto!
We have to figure out a way to destroy it before it kills us.
The hatch underneath its belly is vulnerable!
That's where its motor is located!
There it is!
Eat this!
I've lost control!
No good! The hatch's barely scratched!
Wait a minute! That building!
Is that where you locked up the man in white?!
Thank you for your assistance.
This isn't looking good at all.
You have to hit the switch!
There's an override that opens the hatch.
It's at the tip of its abdomen!
How are we supposed to climb up there?!
It's them!
The Ozu Sisters!
Ibara! They're gaining on us!
What are we gonna do?!
We've already got our hands full just running away from the Iron Spider!
We'll use this wire gun!
We'll aim for that spike that's pokin' out from the Iron Spider's abdomen and climb our way up!
What if the Ozu Sisters get in the way?!
I'll keep 'em busy.
In the meantime, one of you
needs to push the switch!
I'll do it!
I want to help.
I want to do something, anything...
to help make this world a better place!
It's hooked on!
I see it!
That must be the switch to the hatch.
Now, Sis!
She's electrifying her own sister?!
Electric Attack!
Stop it, Shion!
Made it!
Once I push this, the hatch will open.
Ow, my finger!
What the heck?!
Stupid, stupid reinforced glass!
Why, you little...
I'm in trouble now!
Shit, I used up too much power!
Damn you, Haruto!
God, you're so stubborn.
Why go this far just to help humans?!
Sis!
Show this bitch how Fukasaku Aoi meets her end!
It's over!
Aoi!
She absorbed my electricity?!
Hey!
Stop right there!
That's enough! Die already!
She's floating?!
What kind of monster is she?!
Take this!
Now!
Where's Naruse?
She destroyed...
the Iron Spider?!
Fukasaku Aoi...
Just what are you?
Did you know, Naruse?
About what?
Science has both positives and negatives.
Positives and negatives...
Naruse.
Positives and—
Hey, snap out of it!
Where's Aoi?!
Fukasaku Aoi's condition is stable.
What was that power Aoi used, Haruto?
No clue.
Hey!
No luck. We couldn't find their bodies anywhere!
The Ozu Sisters and the man in white
must still be on the loose.
If we don't lure them to us, our plan will be exposed!
Naruse,
we have a bigger problem.
It's already 4 p.m.?!
Where did the time go?
Passing out tends to have that effect.
And yet...
No way!
That's right. The train hasn't come.
The Maintenance Team must have run into trouble.
Then I'll go and help them!
You're in no shape! You have broken bones.
I'm fine, really...
Your lying skills haven't improved.
Stay here and rest.
I'll go check what happened.
Haruto...
See you later, Naruse.
Haruto!
W-We'll see each other soon, right?
Science has both positives and negatives.
You're definitely on the positive side.
Don't look so sad.
Haruto...
We did it!
The armored train is complete!
It's amazing how you did all this in half a day.
Hey!
How's the Diversion Team doing?
We had some issues.
Anyway, we don't have much time left.
Has Miss Ibuki gone into labor?
I have no idea what's happening inside there.
All we can do is pray for a safe delivery.
The train's ready, but there was a problem at the transformer substation.
Gojirou went to fix it.
If we don't get that train started in the next 40 minutes,
you people won't survive.
What?!
I should've known letting Gojirou take care of it was a mistake!
We don't really know anything about his past!
I'm going to the transformer substation!
We Coppelion were born because of the mistakes humans made.
So why?
Haruto,
you still want to believe in humans, don't you?
Damn it! Why?!
Why isn't it getting any power?!
I'm running out of time,
and I don't have anyone to help me.
Ibuki...
Ibuki, your dad's run out of options.
Then I guess I'll just have to give you a hand.
You worked at that company, didn't you?
Damn that blabbermouth Kurobe!
There's no point in hiding it anymore.
If we don't hurry, we'll be
swallowed up by the storm!
Let's split up to find the break!
During those days, I experienced
feelings of powerlessness so many times.
The country spent huge amounts of money every year,
but most of the funding that should have gone to safety measures was cut.
In the end, even facility management was contracted out
and company employees left their now-dangerous workplaces.
That's when I thought:
"This is how this country works."
The wheels fell off a long time ago.
But everyone acted like nothing was wrong.
That accident was the price we ultimately paid.
That's right. I was one more cog in the machine.
It cost money to do regular inspections.
That's why I followed company orders and slashed the number of inspections.
Over here!
Because of what I did, a terrible thing happened.
You stayed until the very end, didn't you?
The only one left in that treacherous workplace.
If the wheels fall off,
we just have to fix them!
The power's back!
Way to go!
Wh-What was that sound?
This is bad! We're losing power!
Don't tell me that sound was...
...an electrical pole falling?!
Haruto, why do you help humans?
Please tell me, Haruto.
Are humans even worth saving?
If you think so, then you should help them.
Me?
No matter how dangerous the workplace is,
you face the problem without running away.
As long as there are brave people like you,
that sort of accident will never happen again.
This time, I want you to make sure you save mankind, Mr. Gojirou!
Is it fixable, Gennai?
Gunshots! Something must've happened!
Haruto!
Stay with me, Haruto!
What a shame.
You were so close.
What is it that you want?
Why are you so driven?
I devoted myself to the sole purpose of serving this country and its people.
We gave our lives to protect them.
That's the pledge my men and I made back then.
Why do we need these things?
I thought this was an earthquake rescue.
That day, we headed out to rescue the city's denizens.
Listen up!
Protect this land!
That is our mission as the 1st Division!
I went to look for the then-Minister of Defense.
He was a long-time friend of mine:
Defense Minister Natsume.
You know him as the current Prime Minister.
You idiot!
How can someone entrusted with the country's security forsake its citizens?!
That you, Kunikida?
We lack sufficient information!
What the hell's going on?
I wish I knew!
Anyway, right now,
our top priority is ensuring the safety of the Prime Minister.
Understood. We have this area covered.
The country is in your hands, Natsume.
By the time I realized the truth, it was already too late.
The government abandoned the citizens and ran away to save their own necks.
It's always the weak and the brave
who get left behind in Hell.
A future with a cost that high is no future at all!
Then why didn't you take action sooner?
What?
All this time, like ghosts, you people watched what was happening to the world.
My theory is that, like me, you still believe in people.
And now you want to see how far they can go.
Those girls have landed into this dark world.
And now, they're trying to light the way as they walk alongside mankind.
You want them to complete their journey.
I have comrades who share my mission.
There's no turning back!
Don't!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Retreat.
Hold your fire!
He's a human being.
Please, let him go.
Are you serious?
After everything he's done to you?!
Shit!
You guys hurry and get on the train!
You're not coming with us?
We had a slight problem with the power line near the south exit.
Gennai is repairing the pole as we speak.
What? Is there enough time?
Don't worry about it!
But if we don't make it back before time's up,
go on without us.
I'm not shaking your hand until you make it back alive!
Yeah, I hear you.
Didn't Naruse give you the Aether?
We gave it all to Ibuki.
As long as she can safely give birth to her baby,
then it doesn't matter what happens to us.
Sorry. I only have one dose left.
Thanks. I'll make good use of it.
Okay! See ya later!
Gennai!
Kurobe, where's Gojirou?
He's okay. Is the power back yet?
You bet it is!
Hell yes!
Hooray!
Let's get back to the station!
Th-This can't be!
The wind wasn't supposed to come from the south!
It's no use. We'll never make it!
Gennai!
Inject yourself with this. It'll keep you alive.
I already gave myself a shot. Now, hurry!
All right, Kurobe.
Gennai!
Come on. Let's get this thing moving.
I-Is that... Gennai?!
It was just a little wind...
Do you know how to drive this thing?
Yeah. I've done it a bunch in video games.
Switching all buttons to on!
Wh-What was that buzzer?
I-It's telling us the batteries are dead...
The batteries haven't finished charging.
The train won't budge until it's fully charged.
Shit! Right on cue, just like Bomber Boy said it would.
The wind's coming!
All we can do is pray now.
Dammit! C'mon! Move!
We can't let it end so close to the end!
Every one of us worked our guts out.
Move. Please move!
C'mon!
I... We can't die here!
Yes!
It's moving!
What do you think of that, Haruto?
Your dad did it, Ibuki!
The railway signal!
What?!
Haruto?!
What are you doing?! You're hurt!
Naruse...
Follow through on the path you believe in!
God dammit!
I've got your back.
Thank you, Commander Kunikida.
Haruto!
Don't stop!
Speed up! The wind's coming!
Go!
Naruse Ibara...
That girl looked into my grotesque face
and told me my eyes were those of a human.
I want to thank you people.
Thanks to you,
I can die a human being.
Naruse—
She just says:
aitsu wa tada iu
"Don't worry about it"
shiritagaru mon ja nai
All I say is:
watashi wa tada iu
"I'm not a doll"
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku no nara
There nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki you de setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku tooku toki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku no nara
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no oku no okusoko made wa
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
It's easy to despair, simple to give up
nayamu hou ga kantan de kujikeru hou ga kanketsu de
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Men will grow tired of their blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni iyake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of grief and vanity,
kanashimi ya munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Words left behind.
The final battle.
An angel.
Your smile.
The blink of an eye.
A world covered in white.
Living dolls.
Next time on Coppelion: "Promise."
Episode
Promise