Ground Self-Defense Force 3rd Division
Technical School
All rise!
Bow!
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Send-Off
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Ceremony
Be seated!
Coppelion
Congratulations!!
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Dear students,
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
tomorrow, you will begin service on the field.
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
Congratulations!!
Coppelion
Send-Off
Ceremony
I will now do the final class roll call.
It was just a dream...
You know...
This place reminds me of our school.
I wanna go home already.
Time to get going!
Now, get ready!
hey men koko de kiken
Hey men, danger lurks here,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men mori no oku de
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
setting for the forest's end
shougai arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni ketsuen inai
you will find no kin
angai doro darake kizu darake kono tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Pretty words will not calm me
anshin nante shitenai
kyokou kara
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
will you have faith?
yes or no?
kirisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama ni naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 5:
Life
"JASA Headquarters"?
What's JASA?
Never heard of it.
It's an organization that does
space station and rocket R&D.
Sounds like they'd have all sorts of scientific equipment.
Guess that's why they'd want to stay there.
Okay! Let's get going!
Those are shelter choppers,
a new tool developed by Tristar Industries.
For now, we're going to use them
to store the high-level waste
from the speedboat racing pool.
Gotcha, Vice-principal!
We can see them from here.
They'll hold the containers until we can find a proper waste collector.
There won't be any further waste leakage, so there's nothing to worry about.
I'll remain here for a while.
You three continue searching for survivors.
Roger.
Is the Professor... doin' okay?
Yes.
He's undergoing some tests.
Naruse.
Yes?
Thank you for saving Professor Shiba.
I may have been wrong about him.
Copy that, Vice-principal!
High-level waste containment completed.
You sure it's okay to set this stuff down in the middle of an intersection?
It's not like anyone's gonna pass through here.
C'mon, let's head back.
What's that?
What are these tracks?
Ibara! Over there!
Hey!
Is anyone in there?
Are you okay?
I'll get you out right now.
Get Ibuki first!
My daughter! She's in the back.
Okay, got it!
She's pregnant?!
We have to get her out!
Right.
Naruse!
Come in!
What is it, Vice-principal?
One of our shelter choppers was shot down.
Every one of the containers we used was stolen!
They stole the waste?!
Why would anyone do that?
Find the people who did this immediately!
What's going on?
They're coming.
The ghosts of the
Self-Defense Force roam this place.
The Self-Defense Force?
Ghosts?
What's that sound?!
Here they are.
The 1st Division!
Wh-What do you mean by
"ghosts of the Self-Defense Force"?
They're the ones
who attacked us.
I fired a smoke bomb.
Now's our chance to get out of here!
Use the ambulance as cover, and make a run for it!
Sorry about that.
Found them!
Open fire!
See ya!
Was that one of the new land mines from the Ministry of Defense?
They've made some improvements.
Who were those guys back there?!
I never signed up for this!
They belong to the 1st Division.
They show up in the city from time to time.
But they've never tried to harm us until today.
Why the sudden attack?
Is your baby okay?
Yes.
Thank you for saving us.
I'm Kajii Ibuki.
This is my father, Gojirou.
I know who you girls are.
I listened in on your conversation yesterday
with a radio that Professor Shiba gave me.
Coppelion.
What?
The 1st Division?!
Are you sure that's what you saw?
We saw them!
We so saw them!
This is totally insane!
Hurry up and get us out of here!
The 1st Division...
If I recall correctly, the 1st Division...
...was wiped out, or so they say.
Immediately after the accident,
the mass of people trying to escape from the city paralyzed traffic,
and the trapped citizens died one after another.
Some chose to remain behind, thinking it would be better to seek shelter in the city's safe zones
and wait for the government to rescue them.
But no matter how long they waited, no one came to their rescue.
That was because the Self-Defense Force
sent to rescue them
also suffered many casualties.
And that was the 1st Division?
They were the core of the forces
protecting the metropolitan area.
The government, fearing more losses,
stopped sending any troops.
Further rescue efforts were canceled,
and the old capital was sealed inside a high lead wall.
Supposing those people were sealed
inside the old capital for all these years...
Hurry and get to a secure location.
I'll send a helicopter immediately.
Roger.
Hurry up and get here already!
I can't stand this place anymore!
If I'm not mistaken, there's housing at the JASA Headquarters up ahead.
There is.
That's our hideout.
Ibara!
Damn, they're persistent!
This way.
While we still can.
Not a peep, Aoi.
Oh no. She's having contractions again.
Contractions?
Targets found!
They found us! Run!
Take them out!
Damn it!
The cavalry has arrived, Ibuki!
Foreman!
Wh-Who's that?
He's one of us.
Quit dawdling!
The ghosts will get you!
Okay! Get inside the armored car!
Take that!
I'll wash you all the way to the ocean!
Hurry!
Easy.
I know.
Taeko! Look out!
I'm almost out of water!
Are you all in yet?
Hurry!
R-Right!
Everybody's inside.
Get us out of here, Gennai!
Got it!
Is everyone okay?
Aoi's not taking it well.
How about you, Taeko?
Taeko!
Vice-principal.
We're the Self-Defense Force,
not security guards, you know?
Why the heck are we doing security for a conference?
They can't possibly be this short on people.
Prime Minister's orders.
There you are, Mishima.
Thanks for all your hard work.
I traveled quite a way to meet you.
Prime Minister Natsume, the air
we maintain here is extremely clean.
There is no need for that mask.
We're rather close to the contaminated zone.
There's always the possibility.
There is no contamination here.
Besides, if you're worried,
a protective mask alone would be useless.
How about this, then:
let's talk inside my limousine.
Guess he's not going to take that thing off, is he?
The Prime Minister is ignorant,
just like most people.
Thank you for taking the risk
to get those pictures the other day.
The international conference begins tomorrow.
Leaders from around the world will meet in Japan's capital.
I intend to use this golden opportunity
to seek the entire world's understanding
regarding the issue of environmental pollution.
By the way, Vice-principal Mishima.
How are the dolls doing?
"Dolls"?
Oh yes! I've heard of them.
Those new weapons called Coppe-something, right?
It's "Coppelion," sir.
Vice-principal, I'm sorry to interrupt,
but Taeko's been shot.
Excuse me.
Is her condition critical?
No, she'll survive.
But even with our regenerative abilities,
she'll need a week of bed rest.
I'm not sure we can keep
dodgin' those guys for that long.
You mean the 1st Division?
D-Did you say the 1st Division?!
Vice-principal.
Can you at least evacuate
the pregnant woman and Taeko?
Me too!
I'll send a helicopter there right away.
Wait!
Eliminating the enemy takes priority!
Hey!
Who was that?
I thought we were a rescue unit, not a fighting unit!
I am the Prime Minister,
the most important man in Japan!
You are my subordinates and soldiers!
Effective immediately, you're promoted from rescue unit to fighting unit!
You're welcome!
Prime Minister, there is a limit to what three people can do.
I don't care if you're the Prime Minister.
That's just not gonna be possible!
Idiot!
Idi—?!
This is a direct order from your Prime Minister!
There are still tons of people I need to rescue first!
Have it your way, stupid girl!
I'm afraid the Self-Defense Force will be tied up until tomorrow with conference security.
Wipe out the 1st Division!
I'm not sending a single helicopter until you do!
End of discussion!
Just a minute, Prime Minister!
Prime Minister?
Hello?
Oh, c'mon!
Ibara, you big dummy!
Sorry, Aoi.
That just slipped out.
What's with that racket back there?
You're not little girls.
No use crying over spilled milk.
Who's that scary old dude?
That's Foreman Kurobei, our leader.
"Foreman"?
I'm Gennai, the fix-it guy.
Pleased to meet you.
Same here.
We're—
We know.
You're that special unit they call Coppelion, aren't you?
You came down here from
the far west to rescue us.
That was what we were supposed to do,
but we're sorry.
We can't really do much for you unless that heli gets here.
Foreman, I'm worried about my daughter.
Maybe we should go back to JASA for now and regroup.
This is exactly why I told you not to go walking outside on your own.
You know how the ghosts have been lately.
But Ibuki is full-term.
She could go into labor at any time.
I'm well aware of that.
Now let's get the hell back to our hideout!
Prime Minister Natsume.
Please rescind that last order!
We should at least get the pregnant woman out of there immediately!
Chief Cabinet Secretary Ougai.
Right now, nothing you say will get through to him.
The moment I mentioned the 1st Division,
the Prime Minister's face paled.
Does it have something to do with that, Ougai?
I'm a very busy man myself.
I'm sorry, but I'm going to make the conference my priority.
The dolls will need to hang in there a bit longer.
After all, we spent quite a bit of money creating them.
That bony old bastard!
I've known Ougai a long time.
He can be like that,
but without him, Japan probably
would've gone to the dogs by now.
Oh?
Yet even such a great patriot doesn't give a rat's ass about the former capital.
We have no choice.
If we cannot send additional help,
our only option is to rely on the personnel already in the area.
What?
We'll call in the Cleanup Crew.
We're here.
Look at all those strange-looking buildings!
Most of them are so contaminated even cockroaches won't live there.
The prized fruits of science are now nothing but clumps of rusting steel.
We just passed Gate One.
It can be opened and closed only from the inside.
When intruders approach, a siren sounds,
and the gate is electrified
with high-voltage current.
Naruse. Come in.
I'm here, Vice-principal.
How did things go afterward?
Can't say I have good news.
We have to head to the conference to provide security.
No way!
What are we supposed to do by ourselves?
Don't worry.
The conference will be over in three days.
Three days...
I hope it won't be too late by then.
For now, you'll just have to sit tight.
I can gut it out for three days.
Did you hear that, sir?
I'm worried that you're by yourselves.
I'll do something from this end.
Huh?
What's that?
That's our home.
It's the biggest safe zone in this place.
We call it "The Planet."
Welcome to the Planet.
This is the entrance to the science of the future.
Wow!
Awesome!
It's like a space station!
When you've lived here as long as we have,
it's no different from a prison.
First-time visitors,
please register in the lobby to become a member.
Check it out!
It's a humanoid robot!
Hey, introduce yourself.
I am a robot guide to JASA. I am called No-sense.
Master Gennai gave me this name
because I possess a heart rich in emotions.
Really?
I think you'd be better off pickin' your own name next time.
He possesses artificial intelligence,
but he needs to be told every little thing.
Cool!
I'm the beautiful Aoi!
Nice to meet you!
Beautiful Miss Aoi.
Registration complete.
So?
How're you going to treat that girl with the glasses?
If you have a room that's like a rich oxygen chamber, it'll speed up the healing.
How about that oxygen capsule?
I use it all the time for anti-aging.
Better clean it up first.
It's got that old man smell.
Ibara.
I'm sorry.
I've become a burden to you when you need me most.
Don't worry about it, Taeko.
Think of your wounds as a badge of honor for savin' a pregnant woman.
She's right!
And besides, now I get the chance to kick some butt while you're out!
So take it easy and get some rest!
O-Okay.
That's very reassuring, Aoi.
Are you okay, Ibuki?
The pain's stopped, so I'm fine.
Hey, thanks again for saving us back there.
I really owe you girls.
You saved me and my baby.
It wasn't anything.
I just acted on instinct.
Now that things have cooled down,
I feel kinda hungry.
Okay!
Then let's go get some lunch.
That's what I want to hear, Foreman!
Gotta say,
you guys don't skimp on electricity here, do you?
To provide this much electricity,
we need a steady energy source.
You mean solar power generation?
That wouldn't be enough.
We use water power to make up the difference.
Water power?
The river.
We built a hydroelectric power plant upstream.
Wow!
Water power is awesome!
You can't get stable energy from water.
Uh... no... Nothing.
We have arrived.
This is the multi-purpose hall.
Wow!
What is this place?
There's even grass growing here.
Oh, and look!
The stream even has fishes!
This was a massive project.
They tried to stuff everything into this indoor garden.
The entire world—no, the entire universe.
But...
Ironic, isn't it?
I never imagined the outside world would be the first to wither away.
What?
I can't hear you very well, Mushanokouji.
Does it look like you can connect me with the Cleanup Crew?
As I was trying to tell you, Vice-principal Mishima,
this is in clear violation of the law!
Presently, your jurisdiction is solely limited to the Coppelion Medical Unit headed by Naruse Ibara.
Contact with any other member
requires the approval of the Prime Minister.
Mushanokouji,
would you like to eat the most delicious sukiyaki in Kyoto?
Yes. I would.
This is Vice-principal Mishima.
Channel 3, Cleanup Crew, come in!
What can I do for you, Vice-principal?
I want you to rendezvous with the Medical Unit immediately.
The Medical Unit?
The one led by Class President Naruse Ibara?
Roger that, Vice-principal.
I'm on my way.
She's just human
aitsu wa tada hito
She doesn't ask herself what she is
shiritagaru mon ja nai
I'm just human
watashi wa tada hito
I'm not a doll
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku darou
Nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki kono setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku toukeiteki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku darou
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no okusoko made
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
Only sadness is real, and philosophy a waste of time
kangaeta hou ga katachi da kujiketa hou ga genjitsu da
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Dawn will break on our blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni ake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of the vanity of grief,
kurushimi no munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
The 1st Division.
The ghost's lair.
A man in a white coat.
A heavy responsibility.
A curse.
Pitiful creatures.
A carefully thought-out plan.
The simplest things.
Next time on Coppelion: "Planet."
Episode
Planet