This is Vice-principal Mishima.
Cleanup Crew, do you copy?
This is Cleanup Crew.
What can I do for you, Vice-principal?
I want you to rendezvous with the
Medical Unit immediately.
The Medical Unit?
The one led by Class President Naruse Ibara?
Roger that.
I'm on my way.
hey men koko de kiken
Hey men, danger lurks here,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men mori no oku de
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
setting for the forest's end
shougai arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni ketsuen inai
you will find no kin
angai doro darake kizu darake kono tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Pretty words will not calm me
anshin nante shitenai
kyokou kara
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
will you have faith?
yes or no?
kirisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama ni naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
So, what's the plan now, little miss Kansai?
Our vice-principal's stuck at a conference,
Episode 6:
Planet
so he won't be available for another three days.
Three days, you say?
We've been stuck in this hole for years.
We're long past hoping
someone will come and rescue us.
No need to be so rude.
It's not their fault.
I know that!
Just saying all we can do now is stay holed up like we always have, ain't that right?
Not quite...
If the 1st Division's gone rogue,
we'll need weapons as well.
How're you feeling, Taeko?
Sorry for all the trouble, Mr. Gennai.
I put your glasses on the desk.
If anything happens,
please wake me up immediately.
Fear not, citizen!
Aoi is here to save the day!
This is our armory.
Wow... You've got quite an arsenal.
This is my collection!
I started with air guns back in the day.
Now schoolgirls are running around, spraying bullets all over the ruins.
What's the world coming to?
I mean, aren't there any male Coppelion?
There are boys, yes.
Then where are they, and what are they doing?
One of them is with the Cleanup Crew.
He's cleanin' up the contamination.
Cleanup Crew?
You mean you're only just now
beginning to clean up this mess?
The truth is,
I don't really know the details
of the other Coppelions' duties.
Huh?
What? What is that?
An alarm?!
An intruder is approaching Gate One.
Hey!
Hmm...
Nothing's showing up on the surveillance camera.
It must be Mr. Wolf!
He must've caught Taeko's scent and followed us here!
But...
I'll bring him here!
Shouldn't you wait for the others?
I'm coming, Mr. Wolf!
Mr. Gennai!
I was just watching the monitor.
It's the 1st Division!
Did you say the 1st Division?!
They're definitely here for us.
Where's Aoi?!
Oh no! She's gone to open the gate!
What?
She'll be all right.
She's a Coppelion—
Ibara!
Ibara! You gotta save me!
What the hell is she doing?
No! No! No!
They've gone though the gate!
We're doomed!
No, wait!
They stopped in front of the Planet!
What do they want with us?
Could it be?
Ibara! Please listen carefully!
I'm going to give you their statement!
Please join these great people, no questions asked!
D-Do what, now?!
These people are not our enemies!
They're just trying to protect their city!
It's their right to govern the old capital!
So please make a decision now!
Will you cooperate with the 1st Division,
or will you abandon this beautiful and innocent young girl?!
It ain't you that they're after.
It's us, the Coppelion.
Huh?
What makes you think that?
It would explain why they
suddenly attacked your group.
If someone got hurt,
they knew we'd come to their rescue.
So that's it...
We were bait.
What makes you so special that they'd
go through all this trouble to get to you?
I don't know.
But...
Ibara!
You're not abandoning me, are you?!
That's enough.
We got what we came for.
Withdraw.
Yes, sir!
Wait...
No, wait, wait!
Wait! What are you gonna do to me?!
What's going on?
That was an awfully quick retreat.
I'm followin' them!
Wait!
I know where their hideout is.
I'll take you there.
Foreman!
Channel 2, do you copy?
Come in, Medical Unit!
This is Cleanup Crew.
Are you there, Class President Naruse?
Greetings. You've reached the Planet.
Miss Ibara and her party departed 5 minutes and 38 seconds ago.
The 1st Division's hideout is in this park?
See for yourself.
Let's go!
What is that mountain of junk?
It's where the ghosts hang out.
It only got bigger over the years.
Hey!
Freeze!
One move, and I shoot the guy in the white coat!
Ibara, run!
These people don't fear death at all!
Threatening them won't work!
Shoot me.
What's the matter?
I'm unarmed.
Go right ahead and kill me.
Shit!
Why didn't you shoot, you idiot?
Stop it!
Oh boy...
Our class president sure is a handful.
Who are you?!
Wait, isn't that the guy from the Cleanup Crew?
Open fire!
Blast off!
Hey, young fella!
Quick, open up the back!
We're getting out of here!
This way, Fukasaku Aoi!
Get your ass over here!
I'm saved—
The hostage is getting away!
Run faster, you dunce!
They're right on your heels!
C'mon! I got you!
Reach for my hand! C'mon!
Haruto!
Didn't you hear the bell?
Don't break it.
That head of yours is hard enough to split the tank in two.
You're—
Kurosawa Haruto from the Cleanup Crew?!
The vice-principal ordered us to assist your Medical Unit.
Oh! You've come to.
Foreman Kurobei!
I'm glad you're okay.
Sorry about that.
The rescue party ran a little late.
No, it was my fault for runnin' off on my own.
By the way, where's Aoi?
We left her behind.
What?
You've gotta be kidding me!
How could they forget about me?!
Morons!
Let me out of here!
Why does this keep happening to me?!
It ain't my fault.
He messed up and made me drop her!
Then we have to hurry and rescue her!
Calm down, Naruse.
I stuck a transmitter on
Fukasaku Aoi that detects life signs.
Hey, you guys!
It has a sensor that'll keep sending a signal as long as she's alive.
What good is a helpless and beautiful young girl like me to you?!
We'll be able to see what they're doing that way.
Are you tellin' me you left Aoi behind
just so you could monitor the 1st Division?!
Doesn't it bother you?
Not knowing what the 1st Division wants with us?
That doesn't justify sacrificin' one of our own!
I don't recall "sacrificing" anyone, Naruse.
At the very least, they'll keep her alive until they have no further use for her.
You'll see.
The explosion rendered their base in that mountain of junk useless.
They'll have no choice but to relocate.
We'll use that opportunity to rescue Fukasaku Aoi.
So you're saying all we can do
is wait until the ghosts start moving?
Exactly.
Aoi's probably wallowin' in despair right now.
Oh my gosh, it's so good!
Gimme some of that miso soup!
Is lightin' a bonfire on the roof of
a department store really a good idea?
The 1st Division's probably got their hands full preparing for their move.
I'll keep watch here.
Go get some rest.
My wounds healed a long time ago!
Drop the act.
You always were a lousy liar.
While you were asleep, I checked your body from head to toe.
These past few days have completely worn you out.
At any rate, with your recuperative abilities,
you'll probably recover completely with a full day's rest.
From head to toe?
Seriously...
They keep talking about rescuing us,
but before the accident,
we were stuck in a recession.
Now, at least, we don't have to work or pay taxes 'n stuff!
I ain't going back to that bullshit society!
Kurobei, look at it this way.
Those children came here bearing a heavy responsibility that's been decided since their birth.
They will be bound by that curse until they complete their mission.
Wow...
The stars sure are pretty tonight!
Do you know why we're able to see the stars here in this metropolis, Naruse?
It's because there are no electric lights around.
Technology destroyed this city in the blink of an eye.
Don't you think human beings are pitiful creatures?
I've been meaning to ask, Haruto.
What sort of work does the Cleanup Crew do?
The transmitter's moving.
What?
Looks like the 1st Division's on the move.
Are you good to go, Naruse?
You bet!
Okay! Is everybody on board?
Why're you dragging me along?
We're short on manpower! Suck it up, Gennai!
I'm worried about Aoi!
Hurry up, Haruto!
Hold it, young fella.
See this?
It's a map of the Zones,
the heavily contaminated areas.
They're here too?
It's okay for you two, but it's
too dangerous for us ordinary humans.
We'll need to take a detour around the Zone if we're going after those ghosts.
Maybe it's best if Haruto and I go in on our own—
Let's get this show on the road!
The contamination must've affected his brain.
The 1st Division is heading northwest in straight line.
It suggests they have a specific destination.
Where are we right now?
The train station?!
That's right!
A train, huh?
By now, it must be a heap of rusted metal.
Not at all.
We were using it until just recently.
We transport all sorts of goods from downtown.
What? It's still runnin'?
Well, it was.
We ran electrical lines from the
hydroelectric plant to power the train.
But it's out of commission now.
The power line has a break somewhere,
but the Zone is preventing us from doing repairs.
Don't be frightened.
You'll just have to help us out for a bit.
Once we're done, I promise I'll send you back home.
He's so lying!
I'm so going to die!
The 1st Division made a right turn.
The road leads to a massive Zone.
That one's not so dangerous.
See the "low level" written here?
Low level?
That area's been gradually getting worse over these past few years.
Something may be causing the pollution to gather there.
What's in that area?
It'll take too long to explain.
Just see for yourself!
What's with all the pools?
It's a water treatment plant.
Back in the day, this is where tap water came from.
Nowadays, it's just a reservoir of contaminated water.
I found the 1st Division!
Slowly, now!
What the hell?
They're loading yellow drums onto the truck!
That's low-level waste!
Wait.
Does that mean those drums are at the bottom of all these pools?!
What's your plan, Naruse?
Rescuin' Aoi comes first!
Just a minute!
Now what?
We were about to get the ball rolling.
I have an idea.
An explosion!
Enemy attack!
Ibara?!
Hey! Over here, guys!
After him!
Here they come!
Come on, ya dumb ghosts!
Good!
The diversion's workin'!
Now to clean up.
Hey, wait, Haruto!
If you shoot them, they'll die!
Exactly.
You intend to kill them?!
You and I are puppets.
There is no benefit for us to be compassionate.
Now leave the dirty work to the Cleanup Crew.
Haruto!
Enemy spotted!
It's the enemy!
Haruto, you moron!
Are the drums loaded?
There's a firefight over there! Return fire!
Commander, I think we should leave.
Agreed.
Ibara! I'm over here!
I'm right here!
Hey! Shut up!
Help me, Ibara!
Ibara!
Hang on, Aoi!
I saw through your every move!
Because like you, I was trained to protect our country.
You and I are nothing alike!
He's not wearing an oxygen tank?!
Do you see now?
We do not fear death.
You apparently came here to rescue people.
In that case, you need to learn more about them.
It is very easy for people to lose their humanity.
Thank goodness.
Your eyes are still human.
Now stop this and come with me.
Now! Fire at me!
Naruse?!
Get in, young fella!
Did the shell hit the target?!
Confirm!
I-It's not what you think...
I have to use the bathroom.
Hurry and run!
Now!
Keep going straight ahead!
We're going to help Naruse!
You dimwit!
Don't jaywalk while it's dark!
Where's Naruse?!
Naruse!
She's just human
aitsu wa tada hito
She doesn't ask herself what she is
shiritagaru mon ja nai
I'm just human
watashi wa tada hito
I'm not a doll
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku darou
Nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki kono setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku toukeiteki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku darou
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no okusoko made
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
Only sadness is real, and philosophy a waste of time
kangaeta hou ga katachi da kujiketa hou ga genjitsu da
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Dawn will break on our blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni ake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of the vanity of grief,
kurushimi no munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Resuscitation.
A life worth saving.
The third-year students.
Pointless words.
Next-generation energy.
The sound of a beating heart.
Yellow Cake.
Next time on Coppelion: "Haruto."
Episode
Haruto