Sis...
I'm a doll.
I was never human from the very beginning.
I'm a living doll!
Is that it?
That's right.
In a little while,
the setting sun will paint the skyscrapers
of the downtown area crimson red.
I hope I can see it with all of you.
We will! I promise!
No way!
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 13:
Angel
Wh-What the hell is that?!
There's a giant spider chasing us!
That's the Iron Spider!
No way!
I thought we destroyed it!
Ozu Kanon!
How is it still moving?
Even if its power systems are functional,
it doesn't have an energy source.
It's her.
Kanon is using her ability to generate electricity to power it directly.
This is bad!
Time to pull out all the stops!
We need weapons!
Right!
What's that noise?
Somebody tell me!
You what?!
You gotta be kidding!
I-I'm afraid so, Lieutenant Ibuse.
Shit! Well, that's just great.
We're short on time already,
and now this happens.
Mayday! Mayday!
That you, Fukasaku Aoi?
Come in, Vice-principal!
Things are going crazy here!
This is Ibuse.
The Vice-principal's occupied with something else.
Ibusecchi!
You have to come and save us right now!
Right now?
Hey, what's going on over there?
It's a real pandemonium here because of the conference,
so this isn't a good time to—
J-Just hurry up and come get us!
We can't hold out much longer! Help us!
But even if we left right now,
the soonest we could get to you is in twelve hours.
We'd get there around sunrise tomorrow!
That's fine! Just hurry up and come!
Please don't abandon us!
Of course we won't, you blockhead.
We're moving out!
Better hurry up, Vice-principal.
It caught up to us!
Huh?
Where'd Ibara go?
Good, you're here!
This'll be our final showdown.
Naruse Ibara!
Stop it already, Ozu Kanon!
What good is this gonna do?!
Why?
Why do we have to hurt each other?!
Because you side with humans!
I won't ever forgive them for what they did!
They dumped us into this place!
Into this contaminated city.
I can see things clearly from up here!
An endless labyrinth of concrete,
but there's nothing here. Nothing!
This empty world...
Is this where we're supposed to live out our lives?
Thanks, but no thanks!
Eat this!
Dammit! She's trying to derail the train!
Kanon!
Shit! My blood...
Stupid blood!
Please stop, Sis.
You'll die.
You stay put and rest, Shion!
I'll put an end to this.
Don't worry.
Once it's all over, I'll die with you!
After that, you won't have to see them anymore.
Those nightmares that torment you...
They'll all go away.
Hey, Class President!
How are we supposed to stop that thing?
Are you listening to me?!
Ibara, what's the matter?
Kanon's prepared to die.
If I don't help her quickly, it'll be too late!
Help her?!
Before those steel wires wrapped around Kanon's fingers drain the life out of her.
I have to sever them myself!
You fool! Stop that chopper!
Go ahead and try!
Take off!
Ibuse!
Let me on!
Vice-principal!
Oh, to hell with it!
The 3rd Division is committing treason!
Ignite boosters!
Set a course for the old capital!
Here it comes!
It's catching up again!
Slam on the brakes!
Now!
Damn you!
I missed!
Ozu Kanon!
Hang on, Shion!
Just a little longer...
It'll all be over in a minute.
Hey, Class President!
You only have one shot left!
If you miss, it's all over! You got that?!
Everybody, look up ahead!
That building is about to fall down!
C-Can we get past it?
Is that a reservoir tank?
Looks like the train will be able to make it through.
Hang tight, everybody!
Now for the finale!
Die, Naruse Ibara!
Now!
What the hell?!
Here's something to help you cool down!
That's...
Enjoy your shower!
In your dreams!
I win, Naruse Ibara!
You can't even move!
Now to finish you off for good, Miss Class President!
I'm so exhausted.
Haruto.
I want to join you...
Haruto's...
It's over!
Ibara!
Kanon! Give me your hand!
Hurry! You're going to fall onto the tracks!
Save my sister. Save Shion!
I will! I'll pull her up now!
I can't do it.
Aoi?!
I hate these two!
But...
But I don't want any more people to die!
Screw it!
Here, lemme help you!
Ready... pull!
Shion's safe!
You're next, Kanon!
I don't deserve to get on that train.
See you, Class President.
You idiot! Let go!
Just forget about me!
I already lost, Class President!
Let go of my hand!
Please!
Please...
I...
can't take it anymore.
I don't have the will to go on living in this world.
What is there for me if I go on living?
Will we find a single good thing by staying alive?
I don't know the answer to that, either.
But you know what, Kanon?
One good thing did happen!
You and I became friends.
Gennai, you still awake?
Hey, Kurobe...
Is everyone still with us?
We're almost there.
You can see the skyscrapers from the window.
Miss Aoi, help me out of this hazmat suit.
Okay, this should stop the bleeding.
Uh... Th-Tha... Than...
Thank you, Naruse.
The city's turning bright crimson.
Mr. Gennai?
Good-bye.
And thank you.
Kanon.
We're going outside for a bit.
We need to find a spot for
the rescue chopper to land.
Hopefully, we'll find an
open area somewhere close.
Want to come?
Sorry, Class President.
I have my hands full right now.
Oh, okay.
Hope she's having a nice dream.
Well, I'll see you later.
If you're looking for open space,
go down to the underground level, and go out the east exit.
We received word from the Coppelion, sir.
The plan is to land around 6:30 a.m. tomorrow in an open area in front of the station.
Is something bothering you?
The birth.
I was thinking about that child who's about to be born.
It might have to live through
even harsher times than we have.
Can we promise the children who'll succeed us
a world where they'll be
genuinely happy to be alive?
What're you talking about, Vice-principal?
Isn't that precisely what we've been working our tails off for?
Right, guys?
Yeah!
It's a healthy pair of twins!
Miss Ibuki's doing fine too.
Hooray!
We did it!
We sure did, Father!
Taeko!
You're amazing! You did great!
I knew we could count on you, Taeko!
I'm so relieved.
Hello?
This is Granny Ayame from Nagoya!
Come in!
Good grief, did you all forget who deserves the most credit here?
You did great, everybody.
Hey, guys!
Over here!
I am Mishima, the commander of this rescue team.
I apologize for our lack of support.
So you're the vice-principal, eh?
You're just the kind of straight-laced guy I imagined you'd be.
This fellow here is Gennai.
Put him on the chopper with us, will ya?
I want to show this old geezer
what my new life will be like.
Roger that!
We'll take care of the rest.
We surrender!
What the hell?
What's the matter, 1st Division?
We give ourselves up!
Restrain us and take us away!
Get up!
We didn't bring any handcuffs.
Now shut up and get in the chopper!
Guess this really is goodbye.
Aoi.
This is for you.
It's the photo we all took together yesterday.
Yesterday, huh?
It seems like so long ago.
It's been just four days since we first met,
but it feels like we've been together for decades.
Time flows in mysterious ways.
We've paid a heavy price in all the years we've lost,
but I feel like we were able to get them back in these four days.
Dad.
Well then, I'm gonna go ahead and excuse myself.
I hate these touchy-feely moments.
See you!
Foreman!
I will be on my way as well.
Thank you for everything, Miss Aoi.
No-sense...
I have found a new job as a babysitting robot.
Miss Aoi, from a biological perspective you are a full-fledged adult.
As an adult, you must get your act together.
Right.
I didn't know robots could cry.
I won't ever forget what you taught me:
that the world can change with a single thought.
We will strive to live here in this city.
Well, I guess we'd better get going too.
Don't want to keep the chopper waiting.
Taeko, I'd like to ask you a favor.
A favor?
What is it, Miss Ibuki?
I want you to be my children's godmother.
What?!
I-I'm sorry, but this is too sudden.
Then I'll name them!
This little boy will be Riku.
And this little girl, Sora. Well?
What kind of names are those?
They sound like branches of the Self-Defense Force!
Riku and Sora...
Great names, both of them.
Agreed! I like them!
Riku, Sora, take a good look.
This is where you were born.
Take care!
Thanks, girls!
Thank you, everybody!
I'll do my best to raise these children!
Please do that.
That would be the least you could do for those girls.
Huh?
What's that supposed to mean, Vice-principal?
So they didn't tell you.
The truth is...
Riku and Sora are your children, too!
Promise you'll come and see us sometime!
We'll be waiting.
We'll always be waiting for your return!
Gonna find out just where we're going
I don't wanna cry anymore
Here it is, here it is, we're all right
I have to understand everything
Guess it's back to just the three of us again, huh?
Please come take my hand
I am standing at the lookout
There are supposed to be some people still living around here.
Gonna find out just where we're going now
I wanna hold this world's every hand
Which way was it now?
When is this school field trip going to end?!
It's only lies they told me
I'm still weak and falling over
Somebody said to me
Somebody said that's right
Yes, yes, yes, yes, Jesus Christ
kangaeru na mou iku shika nai no?
Don't think, we have to keep going
Yes, yes, yes, yes, Jesus Christ
And we can now all ready anew
Bye bye days, good bye days
sariyuku daichi wo kaete
Let's change this dying land
By myself, by myself
riyuu wo sagashitekuru
Hold on, I'll tell you why we live
Bye bye days, good bye days
shikkari kinou ni sayonara
Let's kiss yesterday goodbye
Oh my god, all right
All right, all right
Bye bye days, good bye days
annojou mata hi wa noboru
Don't you worry, the sun will rise again
By myself, by myself
isshun saki no mirai kirihiraite
A brighter future is at hand
Bye bye days, good bye days
massugu tsuranukitoose
Let the world see your dreams
Oh my god, all right
All right, all right
Don't look back