God dammit!
I've got your back.
Naruse—
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 12:
Promise
H-Haruto?
Huh?
Where am I?
Aoi!
Thank goodness you've come to!
Ibara...
Where are we?
You don't remember anything?
W-Wait, you mean...
Did I screw up again?
I'm so sorry!
I'm sure I didn't mean to do it!
Please forgive me!
I'm such a useless scatterbrain!
That's not true!
It was your heroics that saved the day!
Believe in yourself!
Really?!
B-By the way,
how'd that plan of ours go?
As you can see,
we're waiting for the train to get here.
That means our mission is nearly complete!
Hooray!
Yeah.
The train will definitely come!
Haruto will make sure it gets here. I know it!
Haruto...
I'll never forget the words you said to me.
I will save the world with these hands.
I don't know what one old man can do,
but I will try!
What's keeping the train?
Miss Aoi, you have awoken.
No-sense!
Thanks for patrolling.
Anything unusual?
For the time being,
everything seems to be under control.
The 1st Division must've lost their will to fight.
They've resigned themselves to being swallowed by the wind.
What was that?!
That sounded like shattering glass!
Aoi, you stay here!
What? Wait! Don't leave me!
Shit!
They just won't stay dead!
The Ozu Sisters!
Damn it! When will they give up?!
What do we do now?
Sis, this is a train station!
They're here, all right.
My antenna's picking them up, loud and clear!
They're headed this way!
To hell with it already!
See? I told you so!
Yeah, but we can't get near them!
Keep them cornered!
Don't let them get any closer to the platform!
Roger that!
I've got bullets to spare!
It's already past 5 p.m.!
How long do they intend to keep the world's leaders waiting?!
Why haven't we reconvened?
All we need is a clear position from Japan for the talks to move forward!
Ibuse, have a rescue chopper on standby.
Huh?!
But our 3rd Division is on security duty
until the conference concludes tomorrow!
We're not security guards!
Our real duty is to save lives.
We'll leave for the old capital tonight.
I don't care what anyone says!
Oh boy.
Well, there goes my salary.
Shion, Kanon, listen to me!
Give yourselves up!
I know you're both badly hurt!
We'll treat your injuries, so come on out!
"Give ourselves up"?
Do we look like the type who'd surrender?
Besides, what are we supposed to do after we join you?
Work together and save lives?
That's what pisses me off about you!
We'll die before we do what the school tells us!
S-Sis?
Class President Naruse Ibara...
You're able to say shit like that because you don't know anything!
I don't know anything?
What do you mean?
I'm talking about "saving lives"!
Do you seriously believe that's the reason we Coppelion were created?!
They're deceiving you.
The adults are manipulating you like a puppet!
I-I don't understand anything you're saying.
You're doing it again!
That's how you run away from every predicament!
There isn't a single difficult issue you've ever understood!
Well, go right on following the rules, Miss Class President!
If you can defeat us, that is!
Sis! If you use any more of your power,
your body will—
We don't have a future.
Oh no!
It's the 1st Division!
Well, shall we begin...
our final battle?
That sound...
It's the train!
The train's here!
We have to get on quickly, or we'll be left behind!
We can't!
The Ozu Sisters know our plans!
If we don't stop them somehow, they'll destroy the train!
But how can we fight so many people at once?
Tell me you have a plan!
I do. Our final ace in the hole, given to us by Haruto.
If you don't hurry up, I'm gonna leave without you!
Okay!
We're approaching the station!
Slow her down, Kurobe!
K-Kurobe?!
What's wrong? You look pale!
I-It must be the Aether.
It wears off after ten minutes, I'm told.
Oh my God!
Get inside the shelter before the Aether wears off!
I'll do the driving!
Got it...
Thanks, Gojirou.
I'll be right back!
Ow! It hurts!
Hang in there!
Keep your breathing steady!
I can't!
Granny Ayame!
The baby might be caught on something inside the womb!
Something? Like what?
Wait a minute!
Earlier, you said she'd been anemic since her first trimester, correct?
Y-Yes.
Ibara!
Hurry! Hurry!
The train is arriving at the platform!
Hey! The Maintenance Team has arrived!
Where is everybody?
The train's here!
You damn monster!
Don't shoot!
Retreat to the platform!
Hurry! The train's going to leave!
Never mind me! Just get on!
You're getting on a train?
That train, Class President, is headed straight for Hell!
Ow, ow, ow!
Damn you! I'm gonna trash that train!
The only thing that's getting trashed is the ceiling!
What?
A bomb?!
Th-The ceiling's caving in!
Shion...
Ibara!
Hurry!
Everybody else is already on board! You're the only one left!
I can't slow down any more!
I need to accelerate to break clear of the Zone!
Hurry and get on!
Shion?!
I'm gonna smash everything to smithereens!
Stop this recklessness, Shion!
Put that down!
I'm losing... my strength...
Shion!
S-Shion...
Ibara!
Get on the train!
Please! Hurry!
Foreman Kurobe!
Yes!
Way to steal the show!
Ibara!
What're you looking at, Ibara?
The 1st Division?
Come with us!
Let's all get out of this alive!
Jesus... She brought along the entire gang with her!
It's an angel...
Mr. Gennai!
This can't be real!
Why did this have to happen?
Don't die, Mr. Gennai!
It's not your fault.
How does he look?
Can Gennai be saved?
How long does he have left?
I don't know.
This is Gojirou in the cab car.
The train will be passing the station soon!
You all know what that means, right?
This is where things get serious!
There's a Zone with heavy fog five kilometers ahead of us!
Breaking through that fog is the reason we've worked so hard up until now!
Everyone inside the shelter!
I will take over the driving.
Roger that!
Haruto! Where'd you go?
This is no time to slack off!
Haru—
I'm sorry, kid...
Haruto!
No!
You can't have died!
Haruto!
All right, listen carefully.
As things are now, the baby is obstructed!
If we make a mistake, both mother and child might not survive!
B-But why is this happening?
You'll find out soon enough!
Right now, we have to make a decision!
Do we save the mother, or the child?
Haruto, you dummy...
You promised we'd see each other again soon.
Ibara, please pull yourself together.
You can't be crying now.
We've almost entered the Zone!
Hey! Are you listening, Coppelion?
We're almost past the five-kilometer point!
Hurry up and take over for me!
On your feet, Ibara!
Aren't you the one who brought us this far?
If it hadn't been for you,
we would've given up a long time ago.
In this sad world,
people lose sight of what it means to go on living.
Everyone has felt that way at one time or another.
That there's no future in sight. That we'd be better off just...
I felt the same way too!
But you know what, Ibara?
When we all saw your smile,
it gave us the courage to keep on living.
That's the power your smile has!
Don't look so sad, Naruse.
Haruto...
I'm sorry, Aoi.
Let's do this. We're breaking through the Zone!
Hurry up, Coppelion!
I'll take over from here!
Everyone, inside the shelter!
What are you talking about?
Please explain, Granny Ayame!
The baby is suffocating because the umbilical cord
has wrapped around its neck.
But don't worry! It's not all that uncommon.
But now, the problem is
that we'll have to do a C-section to bring the baby out safely!
A C-section?!
Do you understand?
It means that if someone inexperienced like yourself does the surgery,
there's no way to guarantee that the mother will survive.
That's why...
You want me to choose which one I want to save?
Ibara!
The counter readings are rising rapidly!
889, 895... They're off the scale!
White cloud ahead!
Is that the Zone barrier we have to get past?
God, it's so cramped in here!
This is the cab car.
We are about to enter the Zone fog.
Those of you in the shelter are not to open the doors until I tell you to!
Regardless of what happens, it'll all be over soon!
We risked our lives for this single moment!
We're going to make it alive.
We came this far thanks to our beliefs!
So let's keep going without any hesitation!
Believe in the power of life, everyone!
Taeko, I was prepared for the worst from the very beginning.
I beg you,
cut me open and save this child!
No, Miss Ibuki.
I paid close attention when we learned surgical techniques in class.
Let me show you by saving you and your baby both!
Here we go, Aoi!
Yes, Ibara!
A white...
world...
Make it through...
Make it through!
Birds...
It's a flock of birds!
Ibara!
We made it through! We made it through the fog!
Shelter! Come in, shelter!
Please respond!
We're here! Can you hear us?
We've already begun the celebrations!
Okay! The readings have fallen within safe levels.
Okay, everyone! You can come out now!
You did it, Miss Class President!
Mission accomplished! We showed 'em!
Ouch! My bones!
Oops. Sorry about that.
Is everybody okay?
Yeah. Thanks to you!
We made it right past the thick Zone fog!
The plan was a huge success!
Put me down!
What's the matter? You don't seem happy.
We owe him our thanks as well.
This is a grenade Haruto left behind.
I've been meaning to give it to you.
Ibuki! It's me! Please answer!
I'm the baby's father!
Was it born safely?
What's happening in there? Hey!
"The baby's father," you say?!
So you're the one!
You're the bastard who laid hands on my daughter!
You piece of shit! Explain yourself!
Calm down, Gojirou.
Father! This isn't the time for that!
Father, my ass!
Taeko!
You won't get away with this, you bastard!
What's happening over there?
This is Granny Ayame in Nagoya!
Will somebody answer?
Hello?
This is the lovely Aoi speaking!
Tell us how Miss Ibuki's childbirth is going.
Who is this?
Never mind. Just put Taeko on!
We were debating whether or not to go ahead with a C-section!
If we don't do something quickly, the baby will suffocate to death!
Did she just say C-section?!
Are Ibuki and the baby all right?
Everyone, please be quiet!
This is Taeko.
I'm operating right now and can't step away.
But don't worry!
I promise I'll save both Miss Ibuki and her baby!
So please proceed with taking this train to a safe location!
Granny Ayame,
please continue with your guidance.
Okay, Taeko!
Downtown, here we come!
You alive, Sis?
Th-That you, Sis?
Why?
I was crushed by rubble.
Any ordinary human being would be dead by now, right?
Why?
Why am I still alive?
It hurts, Sis.
My whole body hurts so badly it's killing me.
So why won't I die?!
Sis.
Kill me.
Please?
I don't want to live like this anymore!
We're just going to drop dead one day without warning anyway, right?
What does it matter if I vanish right here?
You idiot.
You're lucky that you can even feel pain.
Look at me. I can't feel a thing.
My body is constantly tingling from the electricity.
I don't even know what pain feels like anymore.
Sis...
I'm a doll.
I was never human from the very beginning.
I'm a living doll!
Is that it?
That's right.
In a little while,
the setting sun will paint the skyscrapers of the downtown area crimson red.
I hope I can see it with all of you.
We will! I promise!
No way!
She just says:
aitsu wa tada iu
"Don't worry about it"
shiritagaru mon ja nai
All I say is:
watashi wa tada iu
"I'm not a doll"
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku no nara
There nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki you de setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku tooku toki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku no nara
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no oku no okusoko made wa
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
It's easy to despair, simple to give up
nayamu hou ga kantan de kujikeru hou ga kanketsu de
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Men will grow tired of their blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni iyake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of grief and vanity,
kanashimi ya munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Beyond the memories.
Haruto's memento.
Tears.
Friends.
The skyscrapers.
The sky and the land.
Daybreak.
Goodbyes.
The final episode of Coppelion: "Angel."
Episode
Angel