This is where our plan begins!
Central
Akatsuki
The Diversion Team will set out first to draw out the 1st Division.
Once we're about a kilometer away from the Planet,
we'll set off a smoke flare.
That'll be the signal for the Maintenance Team
to head towards the station where the train is.
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Central
Akatsuki
West
Hey, why not just tell us when to go through the radio?
We can't.
The Ozu Sisters are on the same frequency.
Central Akatsuki
When the train nears the station we're at,
give the horn a loud blast.
Central Akatsuki
Our Diversion Team will defeat the Ozu Sisters,
jump onto the train,
and escape from the Zone with everyone on board.
That includes Miss Ibuki's husband too.
We're counting on you, Ibara.
All right, then!
Let's move out!
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Don't go too fast, Haruto!
The whole point is to have
the Ozu Sisters see us.
Episode 10:
Human
Is there any history between
Fukasaku and the Ozu Sisters?
Well,
The Ozu Sisters...
you see...
Ground Self-Defense Force 3rd Division
Technical School
Give it back!
Give me my lunch back!
If you want it back, go do a lap around the schoolyard naked!
She was bullied, eh?
Hey, it traumatized her!
Where are we?
Proceed with caution. Life signs detected.
That's No-sense's voice!
There he is!
Heya! How's it going?
Hey!
I thought I recognized that voice.
Long time no see, Fukasaku Aoi.
We're now a kilometer away from the Planet!
Charge, Haruto!
Here they come!
Fire!
I see white smoke!
Armored vehicle down! Direct hit!
You rats won't get away!
Let's go after them!
Aye, aye, sir!
White smoke! That's our signal to move out!
About time!
Nice move, Haruto!
Looks like they took the bait!
Hang in there, Miss Ibuki.
Has her water broken yet?
No, but she seems to be in a lot of pain.
It's the pain of childbirth! Remember that!
Hey, why are we getting off the armored vehicle?
We can lure the Ozu Sisters
closer if we run around on foot.
Let's go.
Okay, we're here.
Hurry, Gennai!
Found it!
That's the break!
Wh-What was that sound?
That was her water breaking, silly!
Okay, time to deliver the baby!
Miss Ibuki.
Taeko,
I'm counting on you.
Let's both do our best, Miss Ibuki!
The enemy has entered the park.
Thank you, No-sense.
With Kanon's ability,
it won't take them long to find us.
I hope you have a plan in mind.
Oh boy...
Who voted you class president, anyway?
This is a new type of bomb.
I stayed up all night making it.
Um, Haruto.
That looks more like a missile than a bomb.
Just watch.
Wow! It split up!
It worked. Let's move.
There we go!
Hang in there, Ibuki.
Oh, no!
Dark clouds are gathering in the western sky!
W-Will we make it in time?
We have to.
Where'd you go?!
You can run, but you can't hide!
They're in those bushes.
You sure? Isn't it dangerous?
Don't worry!
I've got your back!
Sis!
I'm gonna pulverize you guys with my iron fists!
Fooled you! It's a kick!
Sis, there's a strange ball thingy down here.
Hey!
It exploded!
I call them Electric Mines.
I modified them to emit electrical signals very similar to bioelectricity.
I've scattered these bombs throughout the park.
They should hinder Kanon's ability to detect us.
Ibara, look over there!
Halt! Where are you going?
I'm bored of hide-and-seek.
We're heading for the sarcophagus.
We've got a problem!
They're heading towards the sarcophagus!
What?!
What're we going to do?
We need to attract the Ozu Sisters' attention...
Huh?!
What?
Why are you looking at me?
No way, Ibara!
I'll get killed!
You used to get bullied by the Ozu Sisters.
If they see you, they'll come after you for sure!
Go, No-sense!
W-Wait a second!
They're so gonna kill me!
Stop! You stupid robot!
You finally stopped.
Hey.
Good timing. I needed to
blow off some steam.
Let's beat the crap out of this nerd
before heading for the sarcophagus.
It's working!
The Ozu Sisters stopped!
The wind...
See that, Naruse?
The wind is starting to pick up.
But it was so sunny just a minute ago!
We have another seven, maybe eight hours at most.
Seven or eight hours...
That means we need to get the train fixed and moving before then.
Damn it!
Come back here, twerp!
You won't get away, you stinking rat!
Haruto, what time is it now?
It's 9 a.m.
We have until sunset.
Damn that Fukasaku Aoi.
Where's she hiding?
Aw, geez. I knew I should've stayed indoors today.
I want to go back to the Planet's storeroom!
Miss Aoi, that would not solve anything.
You must overcome the obstacles in front of you on your own.
Stop lecturing me!
There are things in this world
that are out of my hands!
I sense ions on the opposite bank. Could be her.
No matter what I do, there's no way I could defeat the two of them!
Okay, let's go get her.
Look up at me.
The world is a dark place
because you have a gloomy look on your face.
Run, No-sense!
Dumbass toaster.
I'll turn you into scrap!
Piece of junk!
You're just trash!
S-Stop it!
Just looking at you pisses me off!
You human wannabe!
Stop it!
Girl,
do you know who you're talking to?!
Now you've gone and done it.
I'll take you on!
Now that's a surprise, Fukasaku Aoi.
You want to fight me?
Please... get away... Miss Aoi...
Playtime is over.
I'll pound you straight down to Hell!
Huh?
I-I'm falling!
Please get away, Miss Aoi.
Let go of me, you piece of junk!
That hurts! Dammit!
Screw that!
You're not getting away!
I can fly too!
Sorry we took so long!
Get away, Aoi!
Hey, Sis!
What're you just standing there for?!
Shoot your electricity!
Looks like I was right.
Huh? What're you talkin' about, Haruto?
Ozu Kanon's weakness is water.
If she unwittingly releases her electricity near water,
she'll electrocute herself.
Now that's useful info!
C'mon!
You're not helping, Sis!
Wait a minute. This pond stops at the bridge!
Stupid park! Really?!
Hold it, swan!
I destroyed the bridge!
Slip on through, Aoi!
This is no way to spend time at a park!
I'll leave the rest to my sister.
No-sense!
Are you okay?
H-How is Miss Aoi?
She's headed west.
I'm worried about leaving her by herself though.
No-sense will protect Miss Aoi!
Hey!
Wait!
He's acting of his own free will...
This is no time to dawdle, Naruse.
The wind is getting closer by the minute.
We're here to rescue the
pregnant woman's husband, right?
That's right.
According to Miss Ibuki, he's with the 1st Division.
Hey, what've you got there?
It's one of those transceivers the Coppelion were using.
What?
Keep the channel open!
Anyone there? This is Granny Ayame in Nagoya.
Is she dilating yet?
N-No, not at all.
Should I give her some labor-inducing drugs?
Fool! You young people are
too quick to rely on medicines!
Hey, what the hell is this about?
Hang in there.
She'll be fine, so don't worry!
It sounds like someone's having a baby.
Y-Yes, ma'am!
What nonsense! Let's go!
What did you just say?
Miss Ibuki is terribly anemic,
even though she says she's been taking medications to build up her blood.
How long has she been on them?
Since the first trimester, she says.
The fetus must be absorbing
a huge amount of the mother's nutrients!
I'll bet the baby's going to be a big one!
I found him!
You're Miss Ibuki's husband, aren't you?
Please come with us.
What are you waiting for?
You're the one who saved Aoi, aren't you?
Damn! Did we get the wrong guy?
Will Ibuki...
and the baby be all right?
We're about to blanket the area
with concentrated contaminants.
We promise to rescue your family.
And you too, of course.
Can't ignore a request from Miss Ibuki.
Ibuki...
Hey! Is she a Coppelion?!
Well done, comrade!
Bring the handcuffs!
Don't press your luck, humans!
Don't shoot, Haruto!
Did you just say Haruto?
So we meet again, Class President Naruse Ibara.
I know you're hiding there, Kurosawa Haruto!
I advise you not to try anything reckless.
Our class president might just lose her life.
Drop your weapons and come on out.
You don't have to be afraid.
After all, you don't reek of humans like she does.
You still possess the nobility of a Coppelion.
Don't listen to her, Haruto!
I can take her down myself!
Enough, Kanon!
What is it that you want?
He was carrying this many weapons?
H-Haruto...
Run!
Here's the deal!
You have two options, Kurosawa Haruto.
Either you join us and stick it to the humans,
or you get to trade places with our lil' missy here for a lesson in electricity and magnetism.
Come to your senses, Kanon.
If you're seeking revenge on humans,
you're wasting your time.
You need only look at
their history to understand why.
They're likely to repeat this tragedy all over again.
They'll destroy themselves
without you having to do a thing.
Like I care!
You used to despise humans.
So what the hell happened to you?
You're right about that,
but my DNA just won't do as I say.
Haruto...
You've disappointed me for the last time!
You bastard!
Now's your chance! Run!
Traitor!
Get going!
Roger!
Stop, you!
Dammit! I said stop!
No way!
Caught up with you, Fukasaku Aoi!
Miss Aoi!
I'm sorry I took so long.
No-sense...
You're alive!
I wonder if Aoi got away safely.
Pullin' off a diversion ain't easy.
Haruto, you okay?
I lost all my weapons.
All I have is this.
Ibuki and I met here in this park.
A cramped shelter was the only place
we could see each other.
We both knew that our relationship was forbidden.
Why?
Why was it forbidden?
I'm a member of the 1st Division.
I forgot what it means to be human a long time ago.
I'm a ghost... A ghost that haunts this city.
This is the only place where I fit in, but...
Ibuki is different.
She shouldn't be in a place like this.
You changed, didn't you?
After you met Miss Ibuki.
That makes you an ordinary human being.
Okay!
The electrical cables are fixed!
Hey!
I finished repairing the electrical cables!
Huh?
The way it's shaping up,
we'll be swallowed by the storm.
Are you sure we'll make it in time?
We're racing against nature!
Good god...
We could be contaminated at any time!
We're doing this to save Ibuki.
She's never seen the outside world.
And now, Ibuki is about to give birth to a child here.
I want that child at least to live a life
that doesn't involve wearing a hazmat suit!
That will be my final act of repentance.
Gojirou, what are you on about?
Let's check the current flow!
R-Right, we have a device for that.
It'll signal when an electrical current is flowing though the cables.
Huh? That's odd.
Must be a mistake.
I swear I repaired the cables.
Something must've gone wrong at the electrical substation.
Then get over there and fix it, Gennai!
Do you have any idea how big the substation is?
Just finding where the fault lies is a task in itself.
Let me worry about the substation.
What?
But, Gojirou,
electrical repairs aren't
something amateurs should—
I can do it.
I used to work for the power company.
H-Hey! Wait, Gojirou!
Power company?
Don't tell me...
We want to brighten up your world
Hey!
Where'd you go, Aoi!
Man...
We completely lost her.
The wind is getting stronger.
This isn't good.
If the weather keeps getting worse, I don't know if the cables will hold.
Found them!
Kanon!
Run!
They're running away!
Attack!
You! Activate that thing.
Yes, sir!
"Thing"?
Here I am.
This must be the substation.
Hang on, Ibuki.
Damn.
They have us outgunned!
Ibara! This way!
Good work, Aoi!
Hurry!
We're getting out of here!
What's that rumbling noise?
It's...
It's a giant robot!
She just says:
aitsu wa tada iu
"Don't worry about it"
shiritagaru mon ja nai
All I say is:
watashi wa tada iu
"I'm not a doll"
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku no nara
There nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki you de setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku tooku toki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku no nara
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no oku no okusoko made wa
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
It's easy to despair, simple to give up
nayamu hou ga kantan de kujikeru hou ga kanketsu de
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Men will grow tired of their blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni iyake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of grief and vanity,
kanashimi ya munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
The Iron Spider.
It destroys everything in its path.
Aoi's power.
The two sides.
Limitations.
A feeling of powerlessness.
The broken wheel.
The path to believe in.
Next time on Coppelion: "Awakening."
Episode
Awakening