What are you looking at, Taeko?
That.
Ibara?
She's been staring at the city like that all morning.
Now that you mention it,
she does seem to zone out from time to time.
I think she's just exhausted.
hey men koko de kiken
Hey men, danger lurks here,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men mori no oku de
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
setting for the forest's end
shougai arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni ketsuen inai
you will find no kin
angai doro darake kizu darake kono tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Pretty words will not calm me
anshin nante shitenai
kyokou kara
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
will you have faith?
yes or no?
kirisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama ni naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 3:
Hope
Mr. Tanizaki Heiji.
How are you feeling?
Well. What pressing question brings you to me today?
There is a man who delivers relief supplies to the people in the old capital.
Who is he?
Why are you trying so hard to keep his identity hidden?
Is he a death-row inmate like you?
Captain Mustache,
why can't we have a normal conversation for once?
For example... Oh, I don't know...
Do you have any family?
Didn't go too well, I presume.
You went to interrogate that old man again, didn't you?
It wasn't an interrogation.
Who do you suppose this delivery man is?
Probably the leader of the people who stayed behind.
I don't know if he's just trying to be charitable,
but judging from the fact that he's produced clean air and delivers water and food,
he's not just some eccentric.
Channel 1. This is Coppelion.
We've reached the prison.
The prison?
The wolf that Taeko tamed found
a car key and then brought us here.
A car key?
It might lead us to the delivery man.
We're going in.
Wait. They may not welcome you with open arms.
Stay on your guard.
Yes, sir.
What's he doin'?
Is that the one who stole the key, Kamata?
Yes, Professor.
Kawabata Miku
Ah! If it isn't Vice-principal Mishima!
If you're here to interrogate Miku,
I'll have to ask you to come back another time.
I just want her to answer a few questions.
That's not going to happen, sir.
She's been staring out the window since she arrived here.
Gazing toward the old capital.
This isn't pleasant for me either.
Yes, I know.
What is it, Naruse?
Are you inside the prison?
Two men are in sight.
They're armed.
Permission to open fire.
I'll have 'em subdued in ten seconds.
Wait.
You said you found a car key, correct?
Yes.
There's no mistake. It belongs to them.
What kind of key?
Any distinguishing characteristics?
Let's see.
It's attached to a strange keychain.
Tiger stripes with three stars in a row.
Tiger stripes and three stars?!
Make sure you capture them alive.
I'm heading there right now!
Don't shoot!
I have your car key.
If I die, you'll never find it!
H-How can she not be wearing a hazmat suit?
We are Coppelion, a special unit from the JGSDF 3rd Division.
We are immune to this environment.
Say what now?!
We're here to help you.
No one asked for your help!
Give us the key!
You sent out an SOS, right?
An SOS?
Just as I feared.
They probably ran out of supplies.
It's our fault for being late with our deliveries.
Wait a minute.
You're the guys makin' deliveries?!
That's right.
We kept at it until last month, but...
over the past few months,
new Zones have been appearing in this area.
Because of that, we haven't been able to move around.
"Zones"?
Areas that are especially contaminated.
That's what we call them.
You came all this way despite knowin' the risks?
It is my mission.
Taeko, Aoi!
Bring me the key!
Immune to contamination...
It's frightening how far science has come.
First the hazmat suits, and now modified humans.
I suppose people couldn't live in this city otherwise.
That's the kind of world we have created.
Please, tell us who you are.
You stayed behind and served as a lifeline to the people, didn't you?
This was cultivated underground.
Try it.
Yes! Dessert after a hot shower!
Man, you sure are quick when it comes to food.
It doesn't taste like anything!
Huh?
This is the best we can produce.
Life can only thrive out in the open.
Artificial sunlight won't do.
It's no good, Professor.
I'm not getting anything from her radio.
This is bad.
What's wrong?
It's Granny Ayame.
There used to be a lot more elderly people,
but now, they all rest at the racetrack,
leaving Granny Ayame all alone.
Is she the sole survivor?
No.
The Kawabatas are still around.
There's also an old man named Heiji who lives in this area.
But everyone has gone missing.
Those people have been rescued.
That old lady is the only one left.
I see!
So they're all safe?!
Mr. Kawabata Mitsuo and his wife, Yukiko,
have passed away.
I'm to blame.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault, Ibara!
She's right!
Things just didn't work out the way we had hoped.
Is their daughter, Miku, safe?
Yes.
She's somewhere safe.
That's good.
She's my last hope.
She was born in this city after the accident.
This is her hometown.
Professor, you know how
Granny is. We should hurry.
Take us out, Kamata.
Where are we going?
We're heading towards the shrine.
We often took Granny to pray there.
Sentou
It's north of the racetrack.
The racetrack?!
That whole area is highly contaminated!
It's inside a Zone?
Hazmat suits ain't gonna cut it!
Step on it, Kamata!
Hurry to the shrine!
What could be causing all of this?!
This kind of contamination just doesn't come out of nowhere.
Something must be behind it.
And what would that be?
I don't know.
But whatever it is,
it's not a natural phenomenon.
Only something man-made
could generate this level of toxicity.
You said you were trying to find out about this delivery man, yes?
The one who's distributing
relief supplies in the old capital.
And you say he's also the one
who developed the hazmat suits we refer to as the Advanced Barrier Suits?
That's right.
Only a senior scientist from Tristar Industries would be capable of a feat like that.
A senior scientist, huh?
I'd say he's far beyond that.
What?!
Hey, who are you talking about, Mushanokouji?
His name is Shiba Denjirou.
He went missing after the accident.
He was a top atomic physicist
who worked for Tristar Industries
and developed the theory behind the Barrier Suit over three decades ago.
And that's not all.
Professor Shiba was the one in charge of
designing the plant where the accident occurred.
What did you say?!
He built that plant.
Th-This is bad, Professor!
The area is contaminated all the way to the tree line along the north.
If we continue in this direction,
there's no telling what'll happen.
Damn it!
We'll go on our own.
Please wait right here.
Take this radio with you.
If you need anything, just let me know.
Oh yeah.
Please stick out your shoulder.
What's this?
It's a cure-all known as Aether.
Well, we call it a cure-all,
but it's only good as a preventive.
And it's only effective for ten minutes once you're exposed.
That was my last dose, so try not to do anything rash.
It's like a magic potion.
What exactly is it made of?
It's made of cells extracted from our bodies.
Cells?!
A Coppelion's somatic cells
carry special ion exchangers.
How can you be okay with this?
The government used you as guinea pigs.
Why do you still choose to live as their puppets?!
I just wanted to see this city with my own eyes.
If that accident hadn't happened,
we'd never have been born.
So even a place like this has a connection to us.
We've never been here before,
but when I gaze out at the city,
I sometimes feel nostalgic.
Maybe it's 'cause this is my hometown.
Such strength these girls possess.
They've accepted their cruel reality,
but they haven't abandoned their pride.
I, on the other hand...
Shiba Denjirou.
He led the industry in energy engineering.
People strongly opposed his plan to build a plant in the old capital,
but his technical brilliance ended up swaying the government.
But then the accident happened.
He probably feels responsible for it.
I suppose that's why he remained here doing volunteer work.
Naruse.
Yes?
How are things on your end?
Have you restrained the delivery man?
What? You knew about him?
Professor! They're communicating with someone!
Naruse.
He is no ordinary person.
He's the one who designed the plant where the accident occurred,
Shiba Denjirou—
a scientific genius who worked for Tristar Industries.
They know who you are, Professor!
We'll be there in two hours.
Listen. Don't let him escape.
Roger that. We will take him into custody.
Um, Ibara?
Doesn't the professor have his radio on?
Yes, I heard everything.
There's no need to worry.
I won't run or hide.
I plan to atone for my sins.
However, that can wait until after we save Granny.
H-Help me! Someone!
What was that?!
It was Granny Ayame!
Granny! Where are you?!
A crow! A monstrous crow!
A monstrous crow?
I ran away to the art museum! Please save me!
The art museum?
It's in the forest
northeast of your position!
Go on ahead in the truck.
We'll meet up with you shortly!
Okay!
If you head east, you'll hit the entrance to Route 15.
The art museum is just past there.
Roger that!
I think it's about time we retire from this volunteer gig, Professor.
There's only so much a normal human being can do.
We should leave the rest to those girls.
Kamata.
I've relied on you a lot.
When the helicopter comes, I want you to get on it.
You can leave this place behind and start over.
Yeah. A thug like me can live anywhere.
It looks like getting you on that helicopter will be my final job.
Professor, we'll get on that helicopter. Together.
What's that?!
It's coming from the art museum! Let's move!
Wait! What do you think that explosion was?
A murder of crows?
What in the world happened?
I don't know.
I thought I saw a shadow behind me, and then there was this explosion.
The helicopter's almost here.
Please take cover.
Ibara?!
I'm gonna look for Granny.
You two protect the professor!
O-Okay!
Granny Ayame!
Are you there?
Granny Aya—
That radio...
Is this Granny's?
Ibara!
What's wrong?
I told you to wait.
Look at that!
The heck is that?!
That bird's enormous!
I don't know.
But that's probably...
The monstrous crow?
Hey, where's Granny?
She ain't here. But I found her radio.
Damn it!
What's going on?!
Maybe she ran away on her own.
She's an escaped convict too, isn't she?
No.
Granny Ayame was left behind in a nursing home.
How could that happen?!
The elderly were abandoned by their families.
The accident was but a convenient excuse.
They ended up having no choice but to live here.
How could they be so cruel?
It's all my fault.
If I hadn't made that thing,
nobody would have had to suffer like this.
These hands ruined the lives of countless people!
If you're a scientist, then stand proud!
People wanted it to be built.
So as an engineer, you did your best to answer that demand.
You haven't done anythin' wrong!
I love science.
Science... is my mother.
Damn it! Here it comes again!
What in the world is that thing?!
Hold on.
I'll check it out.
Hey, why're you removing your glasses?
Doesn't that make it harder to see?
Other way around, actually.
Taeko's vision is so good
that she has to wear glasses that reduce her eyesight to a tenth of its usual strength.
No fair! I want super powers too!
Ibara, I figured out what that monstrous crow is.
Ah, good work!
What is it?
A B-2 Stealth Bomber.
It's a special bomber plane that can fly undetected by radars.
Wait. It's preparing to land!
What?
But is there even anywhere for it to land in this forest?
Yes, there is!
Behind us lies an Air Self-Defense Force base!
I don't recall the Self-Defense Force
possessing a stealth aircraft like that one.
We don't!
In other words,
that bird belongs to someone from the outside.
An invader?
Who could they be?
That's what you're going to find out,
Class President Naruse Ibara.
Figures.
Will you really be all right by yourself?
Is there anything we can do?
I told you guys, didn't I?
I have ten times the athletic abilities of a normal human.
Just leave it to me.
Whoa, this kinda reminds me of school.
Let me go!
Someone save me!
Now that you've seen us, we have no choice but to take you in!
There they are! Is that Granny?!
What's that?
She's not wearing a hazmat suit?!
She's a monster!
Who're you callin' a monster?!
Boss! We dumped the goods and are on our way back!
Goods?
Shit! It's a smoke screen!
Granny! Run!
Screw it! Forget about her!
Just take off!
Y-You saved me.
They got away.
Ibara!
Hurry up and get in!
Ah! Well done!
Granny Ayame, are you all right?!
You damn delivery man!
What took you so long?!
My apologies.
That solves one of our problems.
Kamata, take care of Granny.
What?
Now it's time for me to return the favor.
Let's go catch that runaway crow!
But what are they doing with such an advanced aircraft?
More importantly, who are they?
We have no choice but to ask them what they're up to in this city.
But they're in the air.
We'll need a projectile of some kind.
Ibara!
Maybe this'll help.
I got it from that warehouse over there.
Sweet, a Hand Arrow!
You can actually be pretty useful sometimes, Aoi!
Are you all ready?
All right!
Coppelion, move out!
We're going after that monstrous crow!
aitsu wa tada hito
She's just human
shiritagaru mon ja nai
She doesn't ask herself what she is
watashi wa tada hito
I'm just human
ningyou ja nai to
I'm not a doll
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
tooku made tooku made aruiteku darou
We shall walk our path to the very end
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki kono setsuna
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
hito toshite
but be the human
hito de are
that you are
tooku toukeiteki ni fusegareta michi wa
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
aruiteku darou
but we will endure
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no okusoko made
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
shihai dekinai kara
and nobody rules over it
kangaeta hou ga katachi da kujiketa hou ga genjitsu da
Only sadness is real, and philosophy a waste of time
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
What are we?
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni ake ga sasu kara
Dawn will break on our blood-stained lives,
tada arukidase
so fear not and walk forward
shiranu mama warau yori
You might have to trade your innocent smile
kurushimi no munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
for knowledge of the vanity of grief,
hito toshite
but be the human
hito de are
that you are
Hired soldiers.
Yellow cake.
The desires of modern people.
A cross that must be carried.
A box that no one knows how to close.
The pride of a scientist.
Next time on Coppelion, "Sunset."
Episode
Sunset