Naruse, the wind is coming.
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 9:
Diversion
You're saying the Zone is shifting over this way?
That's right, Naruse.
And given its trajectory, it'll reach the Planet eventually.
You can't be serious! Damn it!
How long until it gets here?
Another three—no, two days.
That's too soon!
The vice-principal's helicopter might not arrive in time!
The wind is coming from the west.
Let's check what it's like in the other directions.
What in the world?!
The animals are running away from the east!
Are you sure the wind's not coming from the opposite direction?
Oh no...
The wind changed direction.
Head back west!
Wh-What?!
It's coming!
The wind is coming! Get us out of here, Gennai!
It's as though the wind is alive.
It's coming after us.
What're we gonna do now?
The Zone has completely
blocked off the north side as well.
We're out of options at this point.
We're trapped like rats!
Those two sisters are seriously trying to destroy mankind!
Haruto,
isn't there some way we can break clear of the Zone?
Contaminants tend to settle on the ground.
Is there some way of traveling ten meters above the ground at eighty kilometers per hour?
How would we do that? Flap our arms?!
Are you nuts?!
I got it!
Got what?
I just thought of a way we can fly!
The train?
I'm so bored.
What's wrong with me, anyway?
Just wasting time in here...
It's not so different from school, in a way.
The minute anything bad happened,
I'd run away and stay cooped up inside my own fantasy world.
I wanna go outside.
Okay, is everybody here?!
Miss Ibuki is asleep.
Her contractions have eased a bit.
And Aoi's still keeping herself locked up...
So what were you gonna tell us?
Spit it out!
We're going to split up into two groups!
Get ready. We're gonna be busy!
What do you mean by two groups?!
Okay, listen up.
Planet
This is where we are: the Planet.
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
Planet
Zone
Power
Substation
Hydroelectric Plant
Police
Station
West Akatsuki
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Higashigawa
That's one ugly map.
Recognition error. Please re-input.
I just made it easy to understand!
Anyway,
we're going to put the train back into service!
Huh?
Oh!
Have you forgotten?
That thing broke down a long time ago
and hasn't moved since!
If it's broken, we'll fix it.
Have you determined where the breaks are?
Yeah.
The current stops right before
it gets to the electrical substation.
The wind hasn't reached that area yet.
That means we can still go there.
We're counting on you to repair it, Gennai!
I figured it'd be me.
We also need to arm the train as best we can, right?
Leave the construction work to me!
Doing construction work
and repairing power lines...
I just pray the 1st Division doesn't spot us.
So far, I've covered the job of the Maintenance Team.
Now I'll talk about the Diversion Team.
Diversion Team?
The Ozu Sisters will regain consciousness soon.
Our problem is that, at the moment,
we have no real way of stopping them.
Huh?
We're tied up in chains.
Aw man, my uniform's all messed up.
Wait, if those girls see you building things,
they'll blow you up along with the tracks!
Probably, yes.
That's why we need the Diversion Team to draw the Ozu Sisters and the 1st Division away.
Maintenance Team
Diversion Team
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Police Station
Tonoda
Central Akatsuki
Police Station
But will it go as planned?
This won't work if the Ozu Sisters can't find us.
You won't have to worry about that.
Sis!
Is that you, Shion?
Thank goodness, Sis!
I thought you were a goner!
So, where did those bastards go?!
I'm gonna bash their skulls in!
I can feel them.
Ozu Kanon's special abilities
aren't limited to electric discharge.
She's able to sense the ions
in the bodies of living things.
Now I get it.
That's how she knew right away where we were.
However, she's only able to detect electrical fields within a radius of one kilometer.
Which means...
If we hang around inside a one-kilometer radius of the Ozu Sisters,
we can draw them to us!
Granny Ayame!
Why, Dr. Edogawa.
What brings you to see this old lady?
What is it you've been staring at?
Could it be that nursery over there?
I'll get my things together and leave by today.
No matter how long I wait,
no one's going to contact me anyway.
It's a difficult job...
Saving lives, that is.
Listen up, everybody!
What we'll need to make this plan work today is thorough preparation!
Maintenance Team, make sure you bring the coils, ladders,
and tools you'll need to rig the power cables.
Diversion Team, you'll need weapons!
Load every gun and explosive we have onto the truck!
These appear to be high-voltage cables.
Do we have enough to reach the substation?
We don't!
This'll be a race against time.
We're going to apply the high voltage directly to the tracks.
That way, it'll be faster,
and we'll get more power!
Wait, do you seriously not know?
All downtown-area trains use a DC system!
In order to reduce the risks of high voltage,
transformers at the substation convert high voltage from the power cables
to lower-voltage DC all the way down to 1,500 volts!
Otherwise, the train's motors would burn up!
Gojirou.
You seem to know a lot about electrical stuff.
What sort of work did you do before the accident?
Th-That's not important.
I think I'll go and check on Ibuki.
Today's the last day I'll be able to look at this sky, isn't it?
I know it's all fake, but it's strange.
When I think about how this'll be my last time seeing it,
the sky looks more beautiful than ever.
I know that feeling.
On graduation day,
I couldn't stop crying.
Until then, I was dying to get out of that school.
That day, I stood by the school gate watching the sun go down.
I felt like there was a new world
waiting for me outside those gates.
I guess I was afraid to take that first step.
A new world, huh?
Tomorrow, I'm going to take that first step too.
Are you afraid of the world outside the old capital?
No, not a bit!
Because I have this child.
I won't give up, no matter what happens.
Ow... It hurts!
A-Are you having contractions?!
Wh-What should I do?
Ibuki!
Mr. Gojirou! Please do something!
You're asking me?
Aren't you the rescue team?
C'mon, please...
When she goes into labor,
you'll have to deliver the baby!
But... I can't...
Taeko, is that you?
Taeko? Is Miss Ibuki going into labor?
I thought I heard her voice.
You can do it, Taeko.
Unlike me, you're competent.
Everything will be okay!
Stop saying that!
I'm sorry.
It's just that...
I'm afraid of holding a human life in my hands.
I'm afraid of breaking it with those same hands.
Ibuki's having labor pains again?!
She's probably at her limit.
I'll connect us with the hospital in Nagoya.
I'll follow the obstetrician's instructions and deliver the baby myself.
Hey, wait a minute!
You're the key element of the Diversion Team!
You can't do that!
But who else can?
This requires medical knowledge.
If only the head nurse were here.
The former head maternity nurse
from the old capital.
Oh yeah, that old lady!
She was a maternity specialist.
You guys got her out of here, though.
Huh?
Granny Ayame!
Put your things back.
We need your help!
Hello? This is Nagoya.
Who is this?
It's Granny Ayame. You girls rescued me!
I heard all about your childbirth woes.
Now that I'm with you, your worries are over!
But I...
I know. You're afraid, aren't you?
I don't blame you.
No one wants to take responsibility for handling a human life.
But you know what?
As someone who's delivered hundreds of babies,
I can say there isn't a more wonderful job in the world!
I'll help you through it,
so let's do our best together!
Taeko.
Miss Ibuki...
This child...
Please help this child.
Taeko!
I will!
Listen up!
We'll be towing this shelter by train!
If Ibuki goes into labor tomorrow, she'll have to do it inside here!
Hey! Take that side, will ya?!
It weighs a ton! What is this, lead?
We could sure use some help!
Sounds like they're preparing something big out there.
But I don't want to get in everyone's way more than I already have!
Miss Good-for-Nothing Aoi...
Aw, come on! Now you're being mean too!
They will put their plan into motion early tomorrow morning.
Plan?
Haruto.
Oh, it's you, Naruse.
Why the grouchy look?
Are you really on our side?
I want to get that cleared up right now.
To be honest, I'm not sure myself.
I don't understand why you'd go this far to save humans.
What good does saving them do?
If I had to give a reason why I'm helping you despite what I think...
Well, it might be because I want to learn more about human beings.
Wow! Look at all the stars!
Is this a planetarium?
What's all this?!
You've pulled out all the stops tonight, No-sense!
I asked him to, Foreman.
After all, this is our last dinner party at the Planet!
You're right, Ibuki.
Okay then!
Let's eat our fill to prepare for tomorrow!
Yahoo!
Yum!
These rice balls are delicious.
Yeah!
Wh-What?
It's simpler for me this way.
Don't be like that. Try some.
They taste great!
No thanks.
Human food's not my thing.
What did you just say, twerp?!
Okay, hold him down!
I'm gonna shove it down your throat!
Hey, stop it!
Have you lost your mind?!
That'll teach ya!
Come on and eat!
Ya need to grow some more, preppy!
I guess Aoi isn't coming, is she?
It's too bad. We're all having fun.
This isn't bad at all.
What do you think?
Eating with others makes the food
taste pretty good, doesn't it, Haruto?
Those rice balls...
I made them.
Were they okay?
You kiddin' me? They were delicious!
Right.
Rice balls taste the same regardless of who—
Come here and join us, Aoi.
Ibara!
Whoa, careful there!
I missed you!
Are the intervals between contractions getting shorter?
They're around ten minutes apart now.
Her water will break soon.
You need to get her to the delivery room before then.
All right, Naruse.
I'm going to explain the details of the plan.
After the train reaches its destination...
Are you listening to me?
The vice-principal's helicopter will arrive, and we'll all be rescued, right?
Sounds perfect to me!
W-Wait!
Miss Ibuki.
What is it?
I want you to save one other person!
What?!
Get in there! Everyone in the truck!
Mr. Gennai.
Are you taking all of these animals too?
That's right.
If I leave them here, they'll be
swallowed up by the Zone and die.
So I asked Kurobe to build an extra shelter for them.
Isn't that great?
It's like...
It's like Noah's Ark.
Noah's family gathered two of each species aboard a huge ark,
and they became the guardians
of the new world.
Guardians of the new world?
But only living creatures are allowed on the ark.
Robots must remain in the world that will be destroyed.
H-Hey, wait a minute, No-sense!
Are you saying that they're going to leave you behind?
No, don't stay!
Come with us, No-sense!
If I were to go outside, I would only slow you down.
I am a guide robot here at the Planet.
My purpose has come to an end.
That's not true!
You're a living being with a gentle heart!
A 1st Division soldier?!
Just a minute...
You mean the person you want us to save
belongs to the 1st Division?
Yes.
I'm sure he's still somewhere nearby.
Please... He's not a bad person.
Please save him.
What makes you think he's nearby?
Because he is this child's father.
What?!
I think I might have met him.
When I was captured by the 1st Division,
someone there let me go.
I knew it. He's nearby...
Please, will you find him for me?
We owe him for saving Aoi.
Guess we should repay him for that, right?
Okay!
The Maintenance Team is ready to move out!
Roger!
We'll do one last head count!
One... Two... Three...
Huh? Where'd Gennai go?
No-sense isn't coming with us, after all?
I'm sorry to keep you waiting, Miss Aoi.
Is that No-sense?
Oh my gosh, this is so cool! You're, like, a robot soldier!
Surprised?
I scrounged up some parts and gave him a little makeover!
Thank you!
I love you, Mr. Gennai!
Now he can be useful out here too.
So this is the outside world.
That's right, No-sense.
What do you see?
The breeze...
A warm breeze is blowing.
Morning, Sis.
What's wrong?
The enemy is making their move.
Time to move out!
Naruse!
Respond, Naruse!
Damn. What's going on?
Vice-principal, it's only 6:30 a.m.
Maybe you should let your students sleep in for once.
I haven't been able to contact the Medical Unit since last night.
Hey! Channel 2!
Who is this?! You're disturbing us!
We're getting ready to deliver a baby here!
This is Granny Ayame from Nagoya!
I'm taking over this channel!
Delivering a baby?
There's a pregnant woman.
Seems she's on the verge of giving birth.
Vice-principal Mishima, please stop this at once!
Calm down, Mushanokouji.
How can I calm down?!
Some unidentified person in the old capital
is using my satellite communications system to send me strange messages!
That would be Naruse.
I gave her your line to use in an emergency.
Request rescue helicopter to be sent above the old capital city center.
Moving forward, we will send all messages through this line.
Tell me what she said in her message!
Good grief.
It's supposed to be a private line!
But why would she contact us using that fatso's secret line?
This is still working, so why didn't she use this?
She may have some reason not to use the radio.
Something must have happened in the old capital.
Re:    Copy that!
...........Good luck!
Here we go! I got a reply from the vice-principal!
Re:    Copy that!
...........Good luck!
Ibara, why are you talking via e-mail?
Why not use the radio like you usually do?
We can't.
The Ozu Sisters also use this channel.
They'd hear everything we were saying.
O-Ozu Sisters?!
Wh-What's wrong, Aoi?!
Naruse, the Diversion Team is ready.
We can head out anytime.
Okay.
Let's get the ball rolling, then!
We're counting on you, Diversion Team!
Good luck, No-sense!
O-Ozu Sisters...
She just says:
aitsu wa tada iu
"Don't worry about it"
shiritagaru mon ja nai
All I say is:
watashi wa tada iu
"I'm not a doll"
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku no nara
There nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki you de setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku tooku toki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku no nara
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no oku no okusoko made wa
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
It's easy to despair, simple to give up
nayamu hou ga kantan de kujikeru hou ga kanketsu de
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Men will grow tired of their blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni iyake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of grief and vanity,
kanashimi ya munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
The outside world.
The time limit at sunset.
Reinstatement.
One's free will.
The history of mankind.
Their path to self-destruction.
Life.
Next time on Coppelion: "Human."
Episode
Human