Hey! There's someone here!
It can't be!
Hey, Sis.
We've got company.
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Episode 8:
Sisters
Whoa. Who are these girls?!
They're wearing school uniforms!
Are you girls classmates or something?
That's the Ozu Sisters, isn't it?
We need to contact Haruto.
Come in, Channel 3!
This is Kurosawa Haruto.
How is the cleanup mission coming along?
Ozu Sisters, respond!
Could the other members of the
Cleanup Crew he was talking about be...
...those two sisters?!
Hey...
I'm not sure what they're up to,
but this can't be good!
They must've been the ones who blocked the roads.
She picked it up?!
Back up!
Jesus Christ!
Hey! We didn't sign up for this!
What the hell was that?!
Why're your people attacking us?!
I don't know.
We don't know much about the other units.
I'd better tell Haruto about this.
They're after us!
It's out of control!
I can't steer!
We're gonna crash!
Hey!
`
It's a cafe!
What's up with the truck, though?
Dunno.
Time to find out.
Hold it right there!
Do you have any idea what you're doing?!
Answer me, Ozu Sisters!
Oh, so it was you, Naruse Ibara?
Still acting like you're class prez, huh?
Well, guess what...
You're not in school anymore!
Damn it!
Go take a hike!
Hey, did you see that?
Y-Yes.
Each Coppelion's cells incorporate a particular special ability.
As I recall, the younger sister, Ozu Shion,
possesses a vastly enhanced skeletal and muscular system.
A chick with superhuman strength...
But without the brains to go with it, huh?
What's up, Class President Naruse Ibara?
Haven't seen you since graduation.
How's your sightseeing tour of the old capital going?
Having fun?
We're having a blast here.
We finally got to break off
from the boring group tour.
Have you forgotten that we're all on a mission here as part of the Self-Defense Force?!
Self-Defense Force?
Tell you what, then!
As of now, we quit!
Run, Taeko!
My eyes!
A flash grenade! Damn it!
Playing hide-and-seek?
Man, she really pisses me off.
Channel 2, Kurosawa Haruto speaking.
Naruse,
this is just a hunch,
but could it be
that the Ozu Sisters are giving you a hard time?
Are you kidding?! They almost killed us!
My daughter's life is on the line! Hurry up and do something!
A-All right.
I understand the situation.
The Ozu Sisters are twins born via the same clone technology that created us.
They were created by injecting living nuclei from a
certain actress into two enucleated, unfertilized eggs.
A certain actress?
Is she their mother?
No, not their mother. The same person.
We Coppelion are all clones of existing people.
We never had mothers to begin with.
Each clone was altered to resist contamination and possess special abilities
before being placed in an inventory,
as though they were genetically modified produce.
The downside is that much of the original genetic code is passed on as is,
in particular that of the brain, which
determines our personality traits and judgment.
A little-known fact is that the actress Ozu Kuon, the twins' original,
was actually a serial killer.
Wh-What?!
So you're saying
the twins possess the same wicked personality trait?
Let's hope that's all they got from her.
It'd be bad news if they had her knowledge too.
All right, this is it.
I bet you they're hiding in this supermarket.
Seriously, Sis?!
You're kidding me!
How did she know where we were?
Wh-What're we going to do?!
Keep it down, Gennai!
Escape through the emergency exit!
I-Ibara?
Are you ready yet?
Not yet!
Not yet?
Oh hey, canned peaches!
They look tasty!
Damn it!
How'd she dodge that?!
I've got ya now!
Tell me!
Why'd you two block the road?!
Naruse Ibara, I've never liked you.
That's why we decided to side with these guys.
You've got nowhere to run.
We've blocked off the entire area with waste.
Your school trip ends here.
Sorry!
But I'm going to go back and help Ibara.
Hey, wait!
You still haven't fully recovered!
Shit!
Take Gojirou and Ibuki back to the Planet!
You got it!
Hey, young fella!
What is the situation?
Couldn't be worse!
Little miss Kansai's been captured by those crazy sisters and the 1st Division!
Ozu Sisters!
They're usin' you!
Listen to me!
The 1st Division's plan is...
...to gather all the waste and put it in the old capital's sarcophagus.
After that, they'll stuff
the sarcophagus with dynamite
and blow it sky-high!
And then, the entire world will be contaminated, and it'll be the end of mankind!
If you know that, then why are you cooperating?!
Uh, duh.
With humanity out of the picture,
it's we, the Coppelion, who will rule the world.
We are the greatest race the world has ever known!
That sounds like a line from a comic book villain!
Good one! Let's take over the world!
Anyway, we're not in a good mood.
Now you can die with your curiosity satisfied.
Damn it, she's gonna get herself killed!
Wait a minute!
Naruse should have one of my newest grenades with her.
Your newest grenades?
Three.
Two.
One.
Zero!
My ears!
An ultrasonic grenade! Damn it!
She used it on them!
I-Ibara, you're amazing!
Oh yeah!
This way, Ibara!
Is this a game of tag now?!
Now I'm really pissed!
Never mind them!
Once we surround this place with waste,
they won't be able to get far.
Use that opportunity to head for the sarcophagus.
Who do you think you are, chump?
We're not going anywhere until they're all dead!
Hey, what's taking you so long, Gennai?
Hush! Be quiet!
Look over there!
There are still more of them?!
They intend to keep us holed up in here to buy time for themselves!
Ibara!
Dumbass!
Think before you act!
Fire!
Hell yeah!
She took control of the tank!
Way to go, young lady!
Okay, everybody get in!
Hey! Let's play tag this time!
Step on it, Gennai!
It's no use! They're gaining on us!
What should we do?
We have to do something about those sisters!
This armored vehicle gives us a fighting chance!
Wh-What?!
We're taking them down!
"Taking them down"?!
How exactly are we gonna do that?!
Is the cannon functional?
You mean this?
Hey! Hurry up and do something!
Damn it!
I need shells!
Shells?
I don't see any over here, Ibara!
Hey! I found something!
Is this it?
Sis, you steer.
Gotcha.
Rocket Punch!
Don't fight here!
Found them!
I found the shells!
Okay!
Locked and loaded, Gennai!
Let's blow that bike to bits!
Damn, the older sister's aiming for our rear!
Megaton Punch!
What the hell?!
You just punched through
a high-pressure hydrogen tank!
How's that super strength treatin' you now?
Fire cannon toward six o'clock!
You got it!
Serves them right!
They're dust!
Ibara, don't you think we overdid it a little?
Don't worry about it.
The flames last only an instant,
leavin' the Ozu Sisters knocked out.
Did that chick just use her
younger sister as her shield?
Now you bastards have really ticked me off.
Hey, what's her special ability?
I don't know.
Ibara!
What the hell?
Is that her special ability?
She shoots electricity?!
I'm told they wove the genetic code of an electric eel into my DNA.
What the hell was our "beloved" school thinking, anyway?
Messing with my body like this!
In order to get rescue teams
to the site as quickly as possible,
they had no alternative but to push the boundaries of their research.
Their goal was to save lives.
Human experimentation was never their intent!
You know, Class President Naruse Ibara,
everything you said just sounds like wishful thinking to me.
Admit it. You're worried
out of your mind, aren't you?
We're no different than these disposable hand warmers.
Crumpled up until the warmth is gone,
and discarded once we're no longer of any use.
So, how long will we live?
We're not sure.
Now it all makes sense.
The reason why we were named Coppelion.
It's so that when we die,
your people won't have to feel any guilt.
One day, we'll suddenly drop dead like lab mice during a test.
Do you understand what that means, Naruse Ibara?
We Coppelion are all condemned to die sudden deaths!
One day, without warning,
the warmth in our bodies will be gone.
Tomorrow,
or maybe even tonight!
Who knows how long we'll live?
Did the vice-principal...
Did the vice-principal and Haruto really say that?
Do you get it now?
This is war.
We either die first
or take out mankind before that.
Why not join us, Naruse Ibara?
Together, we'll be unstoppable.
You and us, we can kill the vice-principal together!
What do you say?
Not a chance!
What?
Wait.
Are you for real?
Humans are the ones who did this to us!
Living things...
All living things die eventually.
That's just how it is.
Are you daft?
We're not gonna go peacefully in our sleep, you know!
Get real!
On the morning of graduation day,
I don't know why, but I had this feeling I'd never be returning to Osaka again.
Somehow, my DNA must've known.
If it turns out to be true,
then I'll live my life to the fullest here in the old capital.
And I'm fine with that.
Well, I'm not.
Look at this filthy, contaminated city.
This godforsaken place that humans fear.
This is what I want the whole world to look like!
Until I make that happen,
this electricity in me will never disappear!
Ibara! Run!
You're not getting away!
Die!
You break school rules, you get...
punished!
Way to go!
You took her down in one hit!
Just to be safe,
I'm going to give them both an anesthetic.
I don't know if it'll work on them, though.
One thing's for sure:
we can't bring them back to the Planet.
Did you say we're going back to the Planet?!
What did we come all this way for?!
Look, we'll regroup and then set out again, okay?
About that...
What?!
You're saying the entire area is surrounded by waste?!
We're stuck here?!
The wind is picking up.
Miss Aoi, I have brought you your three-o'clock sweets.
Sweets?!
N-Nice try! I'm not falling for that cheap trick!
Leave the sweets there and get lost!
Wait. You're really leaving?
Come back here.
Miss Aoi.
Why do you keep yourself in this storeroom?
I, No-sense, am a robot,
but I possess deep emotional sensitivity.
However, since the day I was created,
I have never even once been outside of the Planet.
I do not know what it means to feel the warm rays of the sun
or the feeling of the breeze caressing my cheek.
You're a robot.
Even if there were a breeze,
I don't think you'd feel anything.
That is correct.
I am a robot.
I am nothing but an imitation modeled after a human being.
That is why I envy you, Miss Aoi.
You are free to go outside and feel the breeze whenever you please.
You're better off not knowing what it's like outside.
I mean, the breeze in this city is contaminated.
Miss Aoi?
Hey, No-sense!
It's me, Gennai!
Open the gate!
Can you really tell from here?
Yes.
I have counters set up all over the city.
If the Ozu Sisters really did spread high-level waste,
I should get a reading in those areas.
Oh my God! Look!
Every counter reading is rising above critical levels!
Observatory
The astronomical observatory?
The sun's disappeared...
Don't move! Put your hands up!
What're you doing here?!
I was taking an afternoon stroll.
I got tired of working at my desk.
Take him in!
This one's also a Coppelion!
Hey, the bird's acting up!
I'm busy now! Shut up!
We're on the north side of the astronomical observatory.
We caught one of the dolls.
We'll rendezvous with you shortly.
You should escape while you can.
What?
That can't be!
The waste is supposed to be
way down south of the observatory!
The wind... The wind is carrying it here!
Pull out!
Naruse, the wind is coming.
She just says:
aitsu wa tada iu
"Don't worry about it"
shiritagaru mon ja nai
All I say is:
watashi wa tada iu
"I'm not a doll"
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku no nara
There nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki you de setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku tooku toki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku no nara
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no oku no okusoko made wa
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
It's easy to despair, simple to give up
nayamu hou ga kantan de kujikeru hou ga kanketsu de
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Men will grow tired of their blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni iyake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of grief and vanity,
kanashimi ya munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Earth's wrath.
No escape.
The train.
The direction of the wind.
Electrical substation.
Internal ions.
Operation Electric Railroad.
The fake sky.
Next time on Coppelion: "Diversion."
Episode
Diversion