Yukiko...
Not good.
These are wolf tracks.
Ibara! Over there!
He's injured!
A bullet wound if I ever saw one.
You mean...
Yeah, someone musta shot him.
Don't move!
Bring me back my child!
Taeko!
What the hell are you?!
How can you not be wearing hazmat suits?!
We are a special unit from the 3rd Division
of the Ground Self-Defense Force: Coppelion.
Our bodies are immune to this environment.
Immune?!
We're here to help you.
Don't give me that!
Give me back my precious little girl!
Taeko!
Move!
Huh?
Ibara! Bring me the first-aid kit!
I gave you a shot of Aether just now. It's a cure-all.
Did it help you calm down a little?
Why are you helping it?!
He protected me.
He's a very good person.
"Person"?
You said your child was missing, right?
That's right.
My daughter disappeared!
If something were to happen to Miku, I...
hey men koko de kiken
Hey men, danger lurks here,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men mori no oku de
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
setting for the forest's end
shougai arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni ketsuen inai
you will find no kin
angai doro darake kizu darake kono tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Pretty words will not calm me
anshin nante shitenai
kyokou kara
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
will you have faith?
yes or no?
kirisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori wa dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama ni naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Ground Self-Defense
Force 3rd Division
Interim  Helipad
Episode 2:
Future
What?
A child?!
Are you saying we've
got a nine-year-old
running around in that
contaminated city?!
We're on our way.
For now, do as the man says
and help search for the child.
Here's our home.
A hospital?
There's a sterilized room in the basement that luckily wasn't contaminated.
We've been able to live here.
Impossible!
How do ya still have lights?!
We brought some solar panels along with us.
More than enough for a single family.
What about food?
A delivery truck comes once a week.
A delivery truck?!
Who runs it?
I don't know.
In any case, they stopped coming last week.
And back to the site we go.
Vice-principal.
You have a call from the research team.
Hello, hello!
This is Mushanokouji,
head of the research team, speaking.
You know that hazmat suit
you retrieved from the site?
Well, apparently it's even more effective than our own Barrier Suits.
What did you say?!
Man...
We look like a buncha prisoners.
I don't want any grumbling, Aoi.
No!
I won't leave this place without Miku!
This is my wife, Yukiko.
And I'm Kawabata Mitsuo.
Excuse me, but you said
your daughter was nine, correct?
Can she even put on a hazmat suit by herself?
I taught her how just the other day.
Why would she leave by herself?
She may have gone to see her mother.
I thought you were her mother!
I remarried.
My first wife—Miku's mother—
died three years ago.
Then what did you mean by
"she went to see her mother"?
There's a grave at the racetrack.
The racetrack?
Municipal Horse Racing Track
Stables
That's where my ex-wife rests.
Please, tell us why you continue to live in this city despite all that's happened.
Because we're criminals!
What?!
Sentou
Sentou Prison
There's a prison to the north.
During the chaos that ensued
after the accident, we escaped.
Yukiko and my late wife were there too.
Please, I'm begging you!
I don't care what happens to us!
But Miku...
Please save my little girl!
I'll take any punishment!
I'd do anything for her.
So please!
Please save Miku!
Don't cry, ma'am.
We'll make sure Miku's safe! Okay?
Aoi!
Y-Yes?!
We're goin' to the racetrack.
You stay here and look after Ms. Yukiko.
What?!
No way!
I don't wanna be left behind!
You're the only one who can do this.
I'm counting on ya!
Wait, I'm coming with you!
You'll need someone to show you the way.
Miku's oxygen tank isn't very big.
It won't last long!
Huh?
Normal humans can't pass this point.
What?!
Are you saying that my daughter's over there?!
It's too risky for you to come with us.
Mr. Kawabata, please head back and wait for us.
Let's go, Taeko!
Okay!
No...
Miku!
How old are you girls?
Are you high school students?
Yep!
Taeko and I are both sixteen. We're first-years.
Ibara's two years older than us.
She's a third-year student,
and the class president to boot!
You're all so young.
Your parents must be worried sick about you.
We don't have any.
We were artificially created
through genetic engineering.
Genetic... engineering?
`
Have you ever heard of "Coppelia"?
It's a French comic ballet.
`
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Coppelia.
She had beautiful eyes and spent her time reading
by the second-floor window of Dr. Coppelius's house.
But the girl was just a doll created by the doctor.
"Coppelion"... We're living dolls.
What the hell?
This place is huge.
No time for chit-chat!
We gotta start looking!
Hey! Miku!
Come out!
Where are you?
Answer us, Miku!
Mi—
There's something there.
What do you think it is?
Let's check it out.
Ibara.
That's...
Memorial
So this is her grave, huh?
Ibara, what about the child?
Yep. Looks like she ain't around.
You see, I was arrested when I was twenty.
Um, you don't have to tell me if you don't want to.
For infanticide.
What?
I killed my own baby.
She was just a newborn!
I thought of her as a doll.
I never should've been allowed to be a mother!
I know that.
But Miku...
I want to protect her.
I'm a bit jealous...
I wonder if my mother
would feel the same, if I had one.
Aoi...
You're not a doll.
Your eyes are too kind to be one.
Um...
I need to use the restroom!
Huh?
Where'd she go?
Ibara!
Aoi? What's wrong?
Ms. Yukiko's gone!
She's what?!
Maybe she went to look for Miku.
Wait a second.
She's the one who led us here.
Huh? What are you suggesting?
Miku isn't her real child.
Wait!
You mean she...
Aoi! Do ya have any idea
where she mighta gone?!
I-I have no idea.
Mister! Hey, mister!
What the hell? Now the dad's gone too!
Were we tricked?
I mean, they never even showed us a picture of this supposed child.
Maybe they just didn't want us to save them,
so they made that whole story up.
Nah, there's a kid, all right.
Aoi!
Ibara!
Wh-Wh-What should we do?!
We're gonna go look for Ms. Yukiko!
She can't have gone far.
But we don't know where to start!
Here, boy. These belong to Ms. Yukiko.
Remember that smell.
They were probably fighting
over whether to send out an SOS.
Ms. Yukiko didn't want her husband to call for help,
so she took the child hostage.
No way.
She's not that kind of person.
She learned to change her ways
after living in this city for so long.
Is this where she went?
Wait, it's that leaning hotel we saw the other day!
Okay.
You two stay here!
Ibara!
It's dangerous!
If rain seeps into their hazmat suits,
they're gonna be in trouble.
There ain't no time to waste!
Ibara!
What?
What is it, Taeko?
Can you hear that sound?
Naruse Ibara!
We have arrived!
Where's the child?
I'm looking for her right now.
Please come to the leaning hotel!
Stand back!
If you come any closer, I'll shoot!
Please!
Don't come any closer!
Where's Miku?
We gotta get out of here immediately.
Th-There never was a girl!
I've been lying to you since the moment we met!
Got you hook, line, and sinker!
Hand over the child!
Auntie...
Miku! I told you to stay inside!
Oh no! She's runnin' out of air!
Stand back!
My precious little girl...
I refuse to lose my child again.
If we go with you, my husband and I will probably be arrested.
And then she'll be all alone!
We can still save her if we hurry.
Just hand her over!
What the hell is wrong with you?!
How can you just ask us to hand over our child?!
You're just like some emotionless doll!
If you do happen to have even
a shred of humanity, then please...
let us go!
People can't live here.
You don't understand, do you?
We stayed here of our own free will.
We can be free here!
So don't interfere with our lives anymore!
I don't get all those complicated things.
I've been training for this mission ever since I was little.
My entire life, just for this
rescue operation in the old capital.
It's all I know.
And I'm fine with that!
I'm just a livin' doll, after all.
But...
if you don't let me,
I'll lose my purpose for living!
Please.
Let me save that child.
Don't let my eighteen years of life go to waste!
Auntie...
Let her save us...
She can save all of us...
Miku!
What have I done?!
Naruse!
My hand's slippin'...
Ibara!
Oh no!
What are you doing?!
Get us closer!
I can't, sir! The rotor will make contact!
Please...
take the child!
Don't worry about me, okay?
Auntie!
The child is going to be okay.
Why? Why'd it have to turn out this way?
You all did the best you could.
Wait, what about her father?!
What?!
She has a father?!
Vice-principal!
There's a smoke flare coming from the racetrack!
He probably went there to look for Miku!
Oh no!
Please be careful, Ibara.
Don't cry, Miku.
You'll get to see your dad soon.
Really?
Yeah!
Ace Detective Ibara's on the case!
I'm not going to be alone?
Nope! Pinky swear!
Yukiko...
Miku.
Oh, it's you.
Did you find Miku?
Yes.
She's safe.
I see.
That's good news.
Come on! We're gonna airlift you outta here.
Hang in there!
No.
Just leave me here.
I can't let my daughter see me like this.
Why?!
How can you be so strong?!
Once you die, that's it!
I just want Miku to smile.
That's good enough for me.
As long as she's smiling,
I'm not afraid of anything.
Miku.
Sorry.
I lied to you.
I'm so sorry.
There's nothing I can do to make it up to you.
I want to stay with you,
but I have to get going.
There might still be people that need saving.
So we have to stay in this city.
That's our job, you see?
To save everyone who might be in trouble.
I'm leaving now, okay?
If you ever feel lonely, the old guy
with the mustache will play with you.
Wait!
Ibara, Miku told me to relay a message.
Oh yeah? An accusation, huh?
She said, "Thank you."
And "Good luck."
What's up with that?
Straight outta some kid's book report.
Ibara!
Wait up!
aitsu wa tada hito
She's just human
shiritagaru mon ja nai
She doesn't ask herself what she is
watashi wa tada hito
I'm just human
ningyou ja nai to
I'm not a doll
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
tooku made tooku made aruiteku darou
We shall walk our path to the very end
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki kono setsuna
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
hito toshite
but be the human
hito de are
that you are
tooku toukeiteki ni fusegareta michi wa
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
aruiteku darou
but we will endure
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no okusoko made
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
shihai dekinai kara
and nobody rules over it
kangaeta hou ga katachi da kujiketa hou ga genjitsu da
Only sadness is real, and philosophy a waste of time
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
What are we?
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni ake ga sasu kara
Dawn will break on our blood-stained lives,
tada arukidase
so fear not and walk forward
shiranu mama warau yori
You might have to trade your innocent smile
kurushimi no munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
for knowledge of the vanity of grief,
hito toshite
but be the human
hito de are
that you are
Survivors.
The escape.
Three stars.
The Zone.
A changed world.
A fake sun.
The warmest place.
Next time on Coppelion: "Hope."
Episode
Hope