Ibara!
Please wait for us, Ibara!
You walk way too fast.
Slowpokes, the both of ya.
Morons.
Oh, come on!
This is taking forever!
I can't walk anymore.
I'm absolutely drained.
Didn't ya see it?
Oh, the sign!
Woohoo!
We made it!
We're finally here!
I know!
Let's take a picture!
What? We don't really have the time for that.
Nah, we'll be fine!
Get over here. You too, Ibara! Hurry!
Hello, Vice-principal?
Where are you now?
We've just entered one of the 23 wards.
Can you describe your surroundings?
Fields, a school, a hospital,
a pond, a steel tower,
cumulonimbi, trees,
utility poles, a scarecrow...
Is there anyone nearby?
No, not a soul.
Continue toward the city center.
You won't be able to use your phones from here on.
Roger that.
Time to move, Aoi, Taeko.
But, Ibara...
From here on, it's—
Don't sweat it.
Just think of it as a school trip.
Now let's do some sightseein' in the old capital!
Episode 1:
Coppelion
Let's cross the river first.
It's down this road.
Are we gonna walk the whole way?
Through the entire city?
Forgot what they told us at school already?
They can't tell what the city's like from the sky.
Somebody's gotta investigate from the ground.
Yeah, but that doesn't mean we should be walking around
like drones in this kind of neighborhood.
We're not puppets, you know?
But we still have a job to do.
I know that!
Does anyone even live here?
Who knows?
Our job is to find that out.
Yes, Vice-principal?
We've just picked up a radio signal.
It's an SOS.
It's being broadcast from within
a five-kilometer radius of your position.
So there are people nearby?
In all likelihood.
Find an open area and set off a smoke flare.
Roger that.
What should we do once we find them?
Don't do anything.
All you girls need to do is find them.
That SOS sure came out of nowhere, didn't it?
There's been a huge surge of them this past month.
They must've had a good reason to stay behind in this kind of place.
Reporting in!
We'll be flying over our destination
in ten minutes, Commander Mishima!
First and foremost, I am an instructor at a
National Defense Academy technical school.
"Vice-principal" will do.
Get everyone in their gear.
Yes, sir!
Wow!
This river's huge!
The breeze feels nice.
Whoa!
The water's all sparkly and stuff!
Do you see that, Ibara?!
Hey! Let's take a small break here.
It's already past noon!
Sure, why not?
This is a big, open area.
The vice-principal's helicopter should be able to land here.
All right!
You brought that much food with you?
Oh my gosh, it's so good!
So, so good!
What is this, a picnic?
I-Ibara?
Chock-full of all the nutrients ya need!
Ain't that much simpler?
But that's... that's like...
Like what, Aoi?
Never mind!
Ah, these rice balls are delicious!
So are the sausages and crab cream croquettes!
They're all so good!
I'm so glad I was born human!
There it is.
Take us down by that red smoke.
Did you hear that?!
It sounded close by.
Under the bridge!
It's a person!
H-He sounds like he's in pain, Ibara.
But the vice-principal said—
Yes, he told us not to do anything.
The reading on the counter is above normal levels.
It's coming from...
the guy in the hazmat suit.
Help... me...
Please... Someone... help...
Taeko.
Hand me the first-aid kit.
What?!
But we're not supposed to do anything until the vice-principal arrives.
Well, I say...
To hell with the rules!
Impossible...
How can she survive without a mask?
I'm going to give you a shot of Aether using this specialized handgun. It's a cure-all.
Relax and breathe calmly.
Feeling better already, right?
An angel?
Vice-principal Mishima...
Bring him in.
Hurry!
Yes, sir! Bringing him in, stat!
Bringing him in, stat!
What do you think you're doing, Naruse?
Aether is only meant for
people with minor symptoms.
I've been quite clear that we only have a limited supply.
It will only provide
temporary relief for severe cases.
See? I told you—
Then you should make more of it!
I intend to treat every living person we find.
That's our job.
Who are these girls?
How can they be okay
without masks or hazmat suits?
They are known as...
Coppelion.
Genetically engineered children
born with a strong resistance to this environment.
What's wrong with you two?
Normal humans can't live in this environment.
Does that mean we're...
puppets, after all?
Ya moron!
What kind of puppet would enjoy eatin' a rice ball as much as you did?
Come on, let's move.
Wait up, Ibara!
Ah, that rice ball sure was something.
Those girls are the only ones able to freely walk down the roads of the old capital,
You were eating way too much, Aoi.
Was not!
the world's largest ghost town.
Rise and shine in the old capital.
Huh?
Heya.
Oh, good morning, Ibara.
Care for a rice ball?
I have salmon flakes, tarako, and chicken soboro too.
Ibara! Come outside!
What is it, Taeko?!
Look. Over there!
It's a dog.
I think it followed me.
Oh, you're right.
Do you think it's all right?
It's like us.
It prolly adapted to this environment.
Come to think of it, there are birds here too.
Thank goodness.
We're not the only ones here.
What?
Are you lumping us in with animals?
That's right.
Living creatures are all one big family.
Let's get going now.
The SOS signals are concentrated in this area.
But they're not respondin' to our calls.
They might not be able to move.
Then how do we find them?
Let's use the counter.
We can just set the sensitivity to max,
and any nearby creature will show up.
Whether they're animals... or humans.
So...
Are we going to walk the whole day again?!
I vote we grab a car!
Modern man's best friend!
All the cars around here are antiques.
Flip on the ignition switch, and kaboom!
Then let's have the vice-principal get us a shiny new car!
One with a shower and a fridge!
Hey! Look at this.
I am Colonel Mishima Onihei,
vice-principal of the Ground Self-Defense Force 3rd Division's technical school.
I've been assigned to take command of this project.
Oh my gosh!
Our vice-principal is on TV!
That's so cool!
He's like a celebrity now!
News
Planet
Vice-principal Mishima,
the people are most concerned
about the health of the members of the Self-Defense Force.
There's no need to worry.
This Barrier Suit was developed for that exact purpose.
Tests have proven that they are 99% effective.
Still, they don't provide complete protection.
I've heard enough.
It's got nothing to do with us.
Turn it off, Taeko.
Let's go.
Thank you for this rare video footage,
Vice-principal Mishima.
This concludes our live broadcast.
Not quite.
We will now take you to the epicenter.
I want the people to see it.
I wonder what the epicenter is like right now.
I've heard that it's so contaminated that people can't even go near it.
Do you think it's under control?
Oh, who cares...
Can we please stay in a hotel tonight?
What do you say, Ibara?!
Why do we have to sleep in some old shack after walking this far?!
You might wanna reconsider after seeing this, Aoi.
No way...
The hotel's leaning?!
These are all scars from the past...
From the catastrophe that struck this city.
The fog sure is thick today.
We probably won't be able to see the "coffin."
Ibuse, put us through to the TV station.
Don't blame me if something goes wrong.
How is the situation, Vice-principal Mishima?
News
Planet
For the majority of the day,
the epicenter is surrounded by thick fog.
It is actually a cluster of fine particles, known as "hot particles,"
that have been swept up by the sea breeze
to form something that resembles mist.
Are you saying that this area is still highly contaminated?
Yes.
No normal human could go anywhere near it.
I see.
You can't examine the site unless you're a robot or a puppet.
The fog...
It cleared up!
We've got fifty seconds!
We can't stay here any longer than that!
Citizens of Japan,
I ask that you momentarily suspend your current activity
to take a look at your television sets.
On that day, the entire world changed.
Why did it happen?
Why couldn't we prevent it from happening?
This is the epicenter of the tragedy
that destroyed 90% of the capital.
Citizens of Japan—no, people of the world...
It was Man's hand that opened this Pandora's box.
Yet we do not know how to close it.
Come on.
Our job is finding people.
Y-You're right!
Let's go!
Huh?
That tall tower...
Could it be?
It's some kind of plant.
H-Hold on a second!
Sentou Prison
This place is huge!
It's at least three times the size of the prison next to it!
Sentou Prison
Oh my god! It's ginormous!
It goes all the way down to there!
It's like a town of its own.
Whoa!
We got somethin'!
The numbers on the counter suddenly spiked!
I-Is it a person?!
Huh?
It's comin' from the direction we just came from.
Oh!
What the heck?
Is that the same dog from this morning?
He must have followed us.
Gimme a break.
That thing's gonna keep us from findin' other people.
I'll go talk to him and ask him to stay here.
It'll be all right.
I used to take care of the animals at school.
Okay.
We'll come back for ya if we find anyone.
Got your radio, right?
We'll be on channel two.
Okay!
Ibara, does Taeko love animals because of her...
Yeah.
It's written right into her DNA.
She was born with enhanced senses,
just like an animal.
The alarm's going off again.
D-Do you see anyone, Ibara?
Hey...
Shit. We're too late.
Stay back, Aoi.
Suicide?
He's been dead for at least a month.
I can't take it anymore!
I wanna go home!
This is scary!
Ibara! Something's in there!
Ibara!
I hit it with a tranquilizer. Is it out?!
Y-Y-Yeah... Probably.
Is this the dog from earlier?
No.
Take a look at these fangs.
That's a wolf.
What's a wolf doing in the city?!
Stray dogs probably became feral.
This whole place is like an
uninhabited forest, after all.
Wait a second. What about...
What about the dog with Taeko, then?!
She's unarmed!
Hey! Taeko! Answer me!
Can you hear me? Hey!
This is why...
This is why I didn't want to come here!
People don't belong here anymore!
Let's move.
We're gonna rescue Taeko!
aitsu wa tada hito
She's just human
shiritagaru mon ja nai
She doesn't ask herself what she is
watashi wa tada hito
I'm just human
ningyou ja nai to
I'm not a doll
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
tooku made tooku made aruiteku darou
We shall walk our path to the very end
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki kono setsuna
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
hito toshite
but be the human
hito de are
that you are
tooku toukeiteki ni fusegareta michi wa
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
aruiteku darou
but we will endure
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no okusoko made
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
shihai dekinai kara
and nobody rules over it
kangaeta hou ga katachi da kujiketa hou ga genjitsu da
Only sadness is real, and philosophy a waste of time
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
What are we?
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni ake ga sasu kara
Dawn will break on our blood-stained lives,
tada arukidase
so fear not and walk forward
shiranu mama warau yori
You might have to trade your innocent smile
kurushimi no munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
for knowledge of the vanity of grief,
hito toshite
but be the human
hito de are
that you are
A missing child.
A gentle gaze.
A mother.
A puppet without compassion.
A person to protect.
A promise.
Next time on Coppelion: "Future."
Episode
Future