Shoot me!
Where's Naruse?!
Naruse!
hey men koko de kike
Hey men, listen up,
jikken wa mou jissen darou
the crisis is real
hey men nare no hate ni
Hey men, look at the angel
sono hate ni tatsu tenshi
among the ruins of civilization
show time arehateta
On this ravaged stage
stage ni kyaku wa inai
you will find no kin
on time doro darake kizu darake kedo tenshi
This angel is smeared in mud, covered in wounds
kanzen na kotoba de
Don't be appeased
anshin nante shitenna
by pretty words
kyokou come on
They deceive
shinjimai ga shijiyou ga
If everyone is free
katte da to iu nara
to have faith or not,
yes or no?
will you have faith?
kirisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should draw our swords?
tsukaisuteru tsumori or dou nano?
Do you think we should cast them aside again?
tatetsukou yo all right
Let's rise up and fight
nukedashi no nakimushi wa nukedashiteshimae
Run and flee if you're a coward
tatakatte hanatte ima wo shoumei shitai kono mama
I want to continue to fight, rage and live in the present
dare no tame ni ikiru tame ni
I live for the good of others
jibun no tame dake ja nai darou
I don't live for myself alone
aru ga mama waga mama mama naranai
The lives of others will always occupy my mind
watashi wa tenshi
I'm an angel
Naruse! Can you hear me?!
Naruse Ibara!
Episode 7:
Haruto
Say something! C'mon!
She's unconscious!
What should we do?
Turn her face-up.
She's bleeding badly!
Slowly...
There's a piece of shrapnel lodged in her body!
She's not breathing.
She's in cardiac arrest!
What?!
Fukasaku Aoi!
Grab the AED kit from the back seat of the armored vehicle!
Hey!
Snap out of it, Fukasaku!
I-Ibara's going to die...
And it's all my fault. What am I gonna do?
Ibara's going to...
Fukasaku Aoi.
If we don't do something now, Naruse will die!
We all need to work together to save her!
I need you to get me the AED kit.
Can you do that?
Y-Yes, I can, Kurosawa!
Hey, kid, the bleeding ain't stopping!
Should I pull out the shrapnel?
Don't!
Keep pressing firmly around the wound!
Hey, the guy in the white coat is also down.
Good riddance!
If we don't revive her soon, it'll be too late!
Kurosawa!
Is this it?
That's the one!
N-Now what?
We apply an electrical jolt to her heart.
This man won't be able to withstand the shock.
You press on the wound!
What?!
I don't think even Coppelion are immune to—
Forget it!
If you can't help, then stand back!
Charged.
Get back.
The hell I will!
What's a tiny shock gonna—
Move, mister!
Hey! What the hell?!
This is my job!
I will save her!
That's the spirit.
Here goes!
D-Did it work?
Damn it!
For goodness' sake...
Our class president sure likes to give us trouble!
What's the point of risking your life to help a scumbag like him?
Human beings aren't worth saving!
Ibara!
Oh! She's come to!
She's bleeding too much!
We can't treat her here!
Then we'll take her back to the Planet!
But that guy's still alive.
He's just unconscious.
You guys go on ahead.
I'll tie him up and make sure he doesn't get away.
Okay. Let's head back to the Planet!
Are you awake, Miss Taeko?
Oh, Mr. No-sense.
Hang on, Ibara!
Please don't die!
Wh-What happened?!
Taeko! Ibara got hit!
You're Nomura Taeko of the Medical Unit, right?
How good are you at surgery?
They taught us the basics in school.
We'll operate immediately!
Prepare the instruments!
R-Right!
I knew we could count on you, Taeko!
She's lost a lot of blood.
She needs a blood transfusion.
A transfusion?!
She's a third-year student.
You understand what that means, right?
Let's begin the operation.
Surgery in Progress
Miss Aoi,
are you not feeling well?
You appear depressed and emotionally unstable.
Maybe it'd be better if I weren't around.
I mean, I've never been useful.
In fact, all I do is get in the way.
But what's the point of saying all this to a robot, right?
Taeko.
Where am I?
You're at the Planet, Ibara.
Thank goodness.
There don't appear to be any complications.
Complications?
We gave you a blood transfusion. A rather large one.
A blood transfusion?
No wonder I feel all warm and fuzzy inside.
Thanks, Taeko.
Your blood is very warm.
Ibara, have you forgotten?
The blood type of us Coppelion differs by each grade level.
Therefore, a third-year requires a third-year's blood.
Haruto's... blood?
What a day.
We are here today broadcasting live from the National Diet Building,
where the international
conference is about to begin.
The event will be held for the next three days.
Attention will be focused on whether or not Japan, the host nation,
will be able to show the world a path toward transitioning to next-generation energy.
You get TV here?
Yup. We have a satellite dish.
Hey!
My baby just kicked!
Really?
Want to feel it?
Can you hear its heartbeat?
Yes.
We really need to call for the rescue team soon.
They didn't train you in obstetrics and gynecology?
I thought you girls could do anything.
No one expected we'd find a pregnant woman.
Hey, Taeko!
Ibara! What do you think you're doing?!
Where's Aoi?
I can't find her anywhere.
Well, you see...
Hey! Open up, Aoi!
What're you doin' cooped up in there?!
It's time for breakfast!
Open up!
Aoi!
You sure you don't have another key, Miss Ibuki?
No one's used this storage room in ages.
What's her problem anyway?!
With Taeko and I out of commission from injuries,
it's her turn to pick up the slack!
She probably feels responsible for your injury.
Why's that?
Her getting captured was what caused all of this.
You should give her a pep talk, Ibara.
I'm sure that'll cheer her up.
Aoi, I really do feel your pain.
But ya know what, Aoi?
A healthy young person like yourself not doin' any work and lockin' yourself in a room like this
makes you a social recluse!
No, even worse, a good-for-nothin'!
Is that whatcha wanna be, Aoi?!
Huh?
Hello? Are you listenin', Aoi?!
Hey, Kurobe!
I brought the Coppelion boy.
What is this building?
A police station, of course.
I'm not gonna bring that bastard back with us to the Planet.
Damn white-coat bastard...
He hasn't been wearing an
oxygen tank this entire time.
He must have a serious death wish.
That geezer gives me the creeps.
Who are you?
Why are you collecting waste?
I know you didn't just go after the low-level waste in the water purification plant.
I'm told you went after the high-level waste in the boat-racing pool as well.
In both cases,
the canisters were labeled in English,
indicating they were brought in from overseas.
It's probably the work of the
back-end company "Yellow Cake."
I don't know of any "Yellow Cake."
We're not doing this for money.
Oh! He spoke!
Then what is it that you're after?
Shall I make it easier for you to talk?
Hey!
You didn't have to shoot him!
That was a neurotoxin.
Without this antidote, you'll be dead in five seconds.
Tell us what you're after.
Five.
Hey, hold on.
Four.
This guy doesn't care about dying at all.
Three.
Two.
One.
W-Wait! I'll tell you!
What the hell?
Did he just beg for his life?
If he was truly prepared to die,
he'd have killed himself a long time ago.
That would protect the 1st Division's secret.
But he didn't, because he has a reason to stay alive.
There's no stopping it anymore.
What? What're you talking about?
Our 1st Division has no leader.
Every last man is probably on his way to the sarcophagus to carry out his mission.
What did you just say?
We're collecting contaminated waste at the sarcophagus.
From there, we shall unleash its terror upon the entire world!
Naruse, come in.
Haruto?
What's wrong?
What?
Are you sure?!
Miss Ibuki?!
The baby's coming!
D-Did she just say the baby's coming?
Oh no...
Ibuki!
Are you having contractions again?!
I can't... stand up.
The time between contractions is getting shorter and shorter!
Call the rescue helicopter immediately!
Really, Mr. Australia,
you do everything in a big way!
Mr. Australia, it benefits both our countries if you make an exclusive agreement with Italy!
Non, non. France is a much better candidate.
What?!
She's about to go into labor?!
Yes, Vice-principal.
We need a medical specialist.
Please send a helicopter right away.
I really do wish I could help you,
but the Prime Minister seems to think this international conference is a national expo.
He's trying to display Japan's power
so that he can preserve the country's dignity.
Are you telling me you can't spare a single helicopter for that stupid reason?!
Mr. Gojirou, how is Miss Ibuki doing?
I'm guessing she can last two, maybe three days at most.
Is the helicopter coming? Ibara!
Vice-principal!
I'm telling you...
This bastard's completely nuts!
Let's say it's true.
Is the 1st Division even capable of such a thing?
Think of it like this.
The sarcophagus constructed around the accident site
is filled with deadly, contaminated materials.
It's like a bomb, so to speak.
Just having it there is dangerous enough.
But let's say someone sets off a bomb.
If the sarcophagus gets blown up,
this country is toast.
If that's what their objective is,
they must bear one serious grudge against the Japanese government.
Then take it out against the Prime Minister, not us!
C'mon, calm down, Kurobe!
That'll probably happen soon.
Naruse reported this matter to our vice-principal.
Vice-principal Mishima, over here.
Ougai!
I see.
You've ascertained what
the 1st Division is planning?
Ougai, we urgently need to send reinforcements to the site!
You must report this to the
Prime Minister immediately.
If I did that, the Prime Minister would be too flustered to lead the conference effectively.
What?
It might seem like a silly expo to you,
but if we fall further behind the rest of the world, our survival as a nation could be at risk.
Wait until the conference concludes.
Until then, I'll leave the fate of Japan
in the hands of those cute dolls of yours.
Foreman Kurobe has returned!
What?!
What do you mean, "They can't"?!
What's going on?
If you're gonna squabble, take it outside!
Foreman...
Just listen to this!
These Self-Defense Force people
are going to abandon my daughter!
They won't send a helicopter for another two days!
Some stupid conference is more important than the life of a citizen, they say!
Is Ibuki getting close to giving birth?
Yeah.
Just to be clear,
I don't know anything about being a midwife!
If we don't get her to a hospital,
there's no telling what will happen to my daughter or her child.
The hospital...
Didn't you say you were originally on your way to the hospital in the old downtown area?
Huh?
Yeah. That's where our headquarters are.
Did you already forget?!
We got attacked on the way there!
I haven't even said anything yet!
This time,
I'll make sure they don't attack!
Haruto, come in!
You've reached the police station.
We're headin' downtown.
Hold the fort while we're gone!
Are you nuts?
You almost died yesterday.
Thanks to your blood, I'm fine today.
By the way, Aoi's still not comin' out.
Look after her, will ya?
See you later!
Okay, then!
We're headin' east!
Our destination is the hospital in the old downtown area!
Do you want to be here until dark? Hurry!
Where do I put the weapons, Kurobe?
By the doors!
Make sure they're not inside the shelter trailer!
Walk slowly.
Okay... Thank you.
This is No-sense speaking.
May I inquire as to your destination?
The hospital!
Look after Aoi!
Understood.
I will nurse and feed Miss Aoi during her convalescence.
Okay! Everybody on board?
Then off we go!
This is quite a big shelter.
Do you know which route to take to the hospital?
Don't worry.
I've memorized all the roads this truck can take.
Azumagawa Avenue
Tonoda Highway
We'll start by heading north to get onto the highway.
Azumagawa Avenue
Tonoda Highway
That'll take us straight downtown.
Azumagawa Avenue
Tonoda Highway
Cleanup Crew, come in.
Do you copy, Cleanup Crew?
Haruto, it's me.
Our plan is to arrive at the hospital within the day.
Were you talking to someone just now?
I can't seem to reach the other
two members of the Cleanup Crew.
The way they keep disappearing all the time is a pain in my ass.
Come on, Haruto!
You all have to get along!
Right.
Thanks for the advice.
Anyway, keep your guard up on your way there.
The 1st Division will be sure to come after you.
What?
I thought the 1st Division was headed for the sarcophagus.
That's what's been bothering me.
Do you know why those guys need us Coppelion?
The sarcophagus...
Wait, you mean they need us because...
You're on the right track, Nomura Taeko.
The 1st Division needs a Coppelion to get inside the sarcophagus.
The vicinity of the sarcophagus has become a massive Zone.
A normal human would be killed instantly
even with the best hazmat suit in the world.
In other words, we are the only ones who can proceed any further.
I get it now!
Without us, they can't get any closer to the sarcophagus!
The ghosts want to capture you alive.
They have no intention of killing you,
so I don't think they'll be too rough on you, but still...
Hey, watch it!
It's a Zone!
It's expanded to this area!
The counter's rising!
What?
Hey, that's not right, Kurobe.
This isn't listed on the map.
Did another Zone appear?
That's absurd!
Anyway, I'm backing up.
Wait! Over there.
That drum...
The cover is open.
Is that what I think it is?
High-level waste?!
Who said they "won't be too rough"?!
Don't worry!
We'll just take a different route.
Something's not right.
Not right? What do you mean?
This stuff is extremely hazardous.
Who could've brought it here?
I've totally lost contact.
With your friends?
Friends...
Such a meaningless word.
Okay. Coming this far south
should let us avoid the Zone!
I'm turning left to get onto the highway.
You gotta be kidding!
Can't go through here either.
The entire highway's probably inaccessible.
Is there any other road the trailer can take?
That's what I'm trying to think of now!
The freeway!
You're right!
That should take us downtown!
I'll just turn back a bit and hop on the freeway!
This is Kurosawa!
Where are you now?!
If you read me, come in, Ozu Sisters!
All right, we're at the ramp to the freeway.
No Zone readings!
That'll show you ghosts!
Hey! There's someone here!
It can't be!
Ibara?
I-Is something wrong?
Hey, Sis.
We've got company.
She just says:
aitsu wa tada iu
"Don't worry about it"
shiritagaru mon ja nai
All I say is:
watashi wa tada iu
"I'm not a doll"
ningyou ja nai to
Our loneliness grows when we ponder this
kangaesugiru to kodoku ga kasoku suru
Our sense of self disappears when we do not
kangaenakattara koko ni wa inai
We shall walk our path to the very end
tooku made tooku made aruiteku no nara
There nobody rules over the depths of our hearts
mune no naka soko dake wa shihai dekinai kara
Our lives are made of endless moments until the worms eat us
hateru made kuchiru made hate naki you de setsuna
You might have to trade your innocent smile for knowledge of the world
shiranu mama warau yori shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Our odds may be slim on the path we walk,
tooku tooku toki ni fusegareta michi wa
but we will endure
aruiteku no nara
Our hearts are bottomless, a vast cosm,
mune no naka sono ichiban oku no oku no okusoko made wa
and nobody rules over it
shihai dekinai kara
It's easy to despair, simple to give up
nayamu hou ga kantan de kujikeru hou ga kanketsu de
What are we?
jibun ga nanimono de aru ka
Men will grow tired of their blood-stained lives,
sonna satsubatsu toshita mainichi ni iyake ga sasu kara
so fear not and walk forward
tada arukidase
You might have to trade your innocent smile
shiranu mama warau yori
for knowledge of grief and vanity,
kanashimi ya munashisa wo shirisugita to shitemo
but be the human
hito toshite
that you are
hito de are
Kanon and Shion.
Crop breeding.
Special abilities.
A serial killer.
The sarcophagus.
Human experiment.
Guilt.
Next time on Coppelion: "Sisters."
Episode
Sisters