Um...
Please...
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Come
develop
some
fun
games
with us.
We'll be
waiting in
classroom 3-4
in the B wing.
Hey, you okay?
Here.
Be careful, okay?
Later.
Thank—
Hey, Ken-chan!
What are you up to?
Nothing much.
Hey, hey!
What say we ditch first period?
Don't be stupid.
The Kazama Family!
It's all the rage!
What's with those guys?
They're a group of country delinquents who've been causing waves in Fujou Academy:
the Kazama Family!
First up, the fat one over there is "Little Foot" Yokoshima!
He wears a striped polo
even though he's overweight?
How confident is this guy?!
And that's "Long Mountain" Nagayama!
That's just his name in English!
And last but not least, the leader...
Uh...
Huh? Er...
Kazama Kenji!
Didn't you just call us the Kazama Family?!
Oh, shoot!
Run away!
Sorry, Ken-chan.
I guess the two of us stand out too much.
You really do!
Geez...
But man, we really gotta get our act together.
We call ourselves delinquents,
but we don't actually do anything bad.
Maybe we should just quit being rebels and join a club or something.
Yeah, everyone else seems to be having fun.
I've come too far to start living like a wimp now.
I want to conquer the world with my fists!
I finally managed to play an F note on this thing.
Really?
Remi!
Game Dev
Club
Domino
Shougi
Jessica
Space         Game
The Life of Game
Hum-de-dum... hmm?
Sorcery Village
A new experience!
A new beginning!
A new adventure!
The
Second
Coming!
The
Second
Coming!
Club Disbandment Notice
Name: Game Development Club
The Game Development Club has yet to recruit
the minimum required members for activities.
Moreover, it has continually failed to report or
record any achievements whatsoever.
Thus, we have concluded  that disbanding the club
is the most appropriate course of action.
However, the club shall be allowed to continue
its activities if, and only if, it is able to meet
either or both of the above requirements.
No potential recruits showed up today, either.
At this rate, we really will be disbanded.
Why are we in danger of being disbanded to begin with?
We're a culture club, but we haven't reported any creative accomplishments.
But haven't we been playing games every day?
I took this too lightly.
A Game Development Club won't be recognized
as a club unless it actually develops games, huh?
Oh dear.
Took you long enough to realize.
And above all, while we somehow managed to sweep it under the rug until now...
Game
Dev
Club
Urgently
Recruiting
...we don't have the minimum number of members.
And here I liked how relaxing and comfortable this place was.
When's our deadline for recruiting members?
Today.
So if we, the Kazama Family, want to take over
the world, we gotta make a name for ourselves.
We gotta show everyone we own this place, yeah?
You wanna start with the Golf Bag Gang, then?
The who?
That doesn't sound very exciting.
Besides, the culture clubs should have plenty of fun stuff lying around, right?
Like manga or games.
Yeah...
Why don't we have them lend all of that to the
Kazama Family, the soon-to-be rulers of this school?
For someone with such a baby face, you sure are one evil bastard.
Come on, come on!
Let's go!
A fire?!
Hey! You okay?
What d'you think you're doing?
N-Nothing. These flames are merely an illusion.
It's friggin' hot in here!
What kind of an excuse is that?!
Ken-chan.
Here's a fire extinguisher.
Thanks!
Outta the way, you two!
All right!
Begone!
Hooray!
It's gone!
What have I done?
Trying so hard is totally unlike me.
I'm amazed you dealt with that illusionary fire.
You just admitted it was a fire!
How did you end up with a fire in your clubroom?
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Fire... works?
Well done. Now take a nap.
Yokoshima!
Where did that come from?!
Nagayama!
What the hell are you guys doing?!
My element is lightning.
And mine's water.
The hell does that mean?
We can't let outsiders find out about this incident.
So we'll help you forget what happened, okay?
Say what?
You, too,
will lose your memories
to my fire-elemental abilities.
Fire-elemental?
The hell do you mean, "elemental"?
An elemental affinity exists
within each and every one of us.
That shit doesn't exist in real life!
What are you doing? Lemme go!
Water Lock!
Lightning Lock!
Like I said, that shit doesn't exist!
You know too much.
Are you gonna burn me to a crisp?!
Knock it off!
If you don't forget everything,
I won't like you anymore!
The hell was that?
Wha—?!
How could the ultimate flame attack, Burning Love, not have any effect?!
Burning Love
Pull yourself together.
Your injuries may not be that severe.
Crash
& Burn
She crashed and burned.
Crash
& Burn
Maybe she really is a fire elemental.
Crash
& Burn
Earth elemental.
Excuse me?
Earth Punch!
Earth?!
How the hell is your bare fist "earth"?
That was non-elemental, if anything!
Non-elemental, he says.
He catches on quick!
Yeah, not many people would say that on the spur of the moment.
Just before,
I was building a castle in the sandpit.
And you call yourself a high schooler?!
In other words, my hands are now covered in earth.
Go wash them already!
For now, I should make my...
Ken-chan!
Gencuggy Fried
Sudden Flashback
You can have some of my chicken!
Gencuggy Fried
You can count on me to make the final shot!
No, I can't leave those two behind.
I have to say, though, his memories sure aren't going without a fight.
Yeah.
Th-This time, let's combine all our elements into one simultaneous attack.
Huh?
All their elements?
Hey! Ken-chan!
Sorry, guys!
Hey, you!
What's this? You're abandoning
your friends to save your own skin?
I had no other choice!
Wait, why am I trying to justify myself to the enemy?!
Be a man and die.
Wow, she actually told him to die.
They're gonna kill me!
That was just a figure of speech.
But I bet it wasn't that far off the mark!
Nooo!
Okay.
I think I lost them.
What the hell is wrong with that club?
They're freaking insane.
Um...
It's the fire elemental!
Thank you very much.
For extinguishing the fire, I mean.
Oh...
We've learned our lesson.
Never again will we play with fireworks in the clubroom.
Be sure to play with fireworks safely in an appropriate location!
Well, duh!
Why were you setting off fireworks anyway?!
We wanted to come up with a cool illusion to attract new members.
That's what caused the fire?!
Stupid illusion!
Stop blaming the poor illusion!
Oh, and one more thing.
Thank you for this morning, too.
You kindly picked up my flyers for me.
Oh...
Are you the girl who was
at the front gates this morning?
You don't remember?
You were headhunting for that freaky club?
Freaky...?
Anyway, I won't tell anyone about the fire,
so stop following me around.
Later.
Actually, I'd like you to join my club.
Your club?
I'm the president of the Game Development Club,
Shibasaki Roka.
You're the president?
I will now proceed to recruit you.
I'm not interested in some Game Club.
It's not the Game Club.
It's the Game Development Club.
Just so you know,
your fire-elemental Burning Love attack won't work on me.
That element was a decoy.
My true element...
is darkness.
Huh? Darkness?
Huh?
What were we...
Where's Ken-chan?
The darkness!
Where? Where am I?!
What's going on?!
You have two options to choose from.
It's so dark and so scary!
Either you obey us and join the Game Dev Club,
It's pitch-black!
or else...
Hey, can any—
So, which will it be?
I'll join!
Please let me join your club!
We welcome you with open arms.
Let's take it from the top.
I'm Shibasaki Roka, the president.
Welcome to the club.
I'm Karasuyama Chitose,
a second-year.
Mizukami Sakura, a first-year.
Who the hell cares?! Get this off of me!
Are you even listening to us?
The hell are you doing?!
Wait, why are you rubbing your cheek up against my leg?
Ew, do you have a leg fetish?
I did nothing of the sort!
Get this thing off of me already!
What was that for?!
We figured you wouldn't
listen to us of your own accord.
Your methods are way too extreme!
Well, you heard our introductions, Mr. Leg Fetishist.
Wait!
Why are you trying to pin some weird-ass element on me?!
You've yet to introduce yourself to us,
but it doesn't really matter.
It doesn't?!
Just put your name down on this club registration form.
If they hand that thing in to a teacher, I'm screwed.
But I'm also screwed if I don't do what they say.
What now?
Now that's a surprise.
I thought you'd whine a bit first.
You've finally resigned yourself to your fate, huh?
Here.
I'm outta here for the day, then.
Sure, I guess.
It does look like you filled it out properly.
All right!
That gets me out of this clubroom.
Now all I need to do is beat them to the staff room,
steal the form from whoever takes it there, and then pretend it never existed!
Then I win!
Here you go, Miss.
Thanks. That should do it.
Hold it right there!
The hell? A teacher?
You're a goddamn chalk pusher?!
I'm the Game Dev Club's adviser, Oosawa Minami.
Pleased to meet you.
Déjà vu?!
Hey, don't run away!
Don't go too wild out there.
Shit! That was a total miscalculation!
How the hell was I supposed to know she was a chalk pusher?!
You're fast!
I fell behind earlier because you caught me off guard,
but things won't go so well for you this time.
I've been waiting for you
in a crouching start all this time!
Is she stupid?
Or wait, could she actually be a genius?
Let me introduce myself properly.
I'm Mizukami Sakura from Class 1-D.
My element is water!
Enough with the elements!
Give up and hand over that club registration form!
Oh.
What?
I forgot to bring water with me.
Huh?
I'll go get it, so wait for me!
So she can't do anything without water?
Are their elements that important?
Guess I should've known it wouldn't be that easy.
Um, if you hand over that form right now,
I, uh, don't mind putting in a good word for you with the others...
No thanks.
I'm not into that cutesy stuff.
Your words will not defeat me!
Holy shit, she survived!
Oh crap!
Not the darkness again.
Quit it with your odd fixations!
Indeed. The darkness is my domain.
I shall wring the very life from your body in this blackened realm!
Damn, I can't see a thing.
I have no time to waste!
That dirt freak's gonna get here soon!
Chitose will still be a while.
She went to the sandpit to replenish herself.
Are your elements really that important to you?!
But wait. That means...
You're my only opponent, eh?
Come to think of it, I can burst through
the mere cloth of this "domain" whenever I want!
Huh?
I went the wrong way...
Nice! Now just pull—
You're already at your limit?!
If this keeps up, we'll both end up falling.
Worst I'll get is a fractured leg, so let go alrea—
I won't!
You're the potential recruit
we've been looking for all this time.
I will not let you go!
But I'm gonna drag you down with me!
I don't care!
Seriously, this is no time to act cute!
I'm not acting!
This is the real me!
You...
Shoot. I can't hold on any longer...
After all the cool things you said?!
This is putting an incredible
amount of stress on my belly.
At this rate, I won't be able to have kids anymore.
Aww...
So much for my dream of a happy family with two sons and a daughter...
You're scaring me!
I'm sorry! Let me down!
Right this very instant!
Well done, Prez.
Took you long enough.
Man, I thought I was a goner.
Let's go, Roka.
Club Registration
Game
Dev
Club
Kazama Kenji
Club Registration
Game
Dev
Club
Kazama Kenji
Club Registration
Game
Dev
Club
Kazama Kenji
Club Registration
Game
Dev
Club
Kazama Kenji
I'm Kazama Kenji from Class 2-B.
Welcome to the Game Dev Club.
Thanks.
So I got kinda caught up in the flow and joined the club yesterday.
What's gonna happen to me now?
Yesterday?
What're you talking about?
They seriously did forget everything!
Anyway, check out my hairdo!
I don't even remember getting it!
That's super rad!
I know, right?
Now I just need a spiked bat,
and it'll be perfect!
This is for the best.
I can't let my buddies get mixed up in this.
Kenji!
You okay, Kenji?!
Are you all right?
Are you all right, Kenji?!
This is strange. I don't see any external injuries, but...
Does this mean...
something weird happened underneath his clothes?
Ataru!
I have no idea what this is about,
but keep that up and you're a dead man!
What are you here for, Vice President?
Don't address me like I'm some stranger.
Drop the "Vice President."
Call me Acchan.
The four of us have been friends
since we were in Fujou Elementary!
Yeah! Let's go!
Wait up!
And what do I see once we all
make it to the same high school?
Everyone but me turned delinquent!
You damn traitors!
Seriously, why are you here, Ataru?
Oh, right.
Kenji, I heard rumors that you joined the Game Development Club.
And what of it?
It's a dangerous club.
No. Perhaps I should say it's not the club itself,
but Karasuyama Chitose's authority that's dangerous.
What? That dirt freak has that much authority?
You didn't know?
She's the student council president here.
For real?
She's the president?!
Fujou Academy's fifteenth
student council president, Karasuyama Chitose.
With her forceful methods and bewitching charisma,
she has made not only the students submit to her, but also the teachers!
She is truly the queen of this academy!
Her power is such that
even the Five Devas of Fujou,
the Double Brothers,
and the Evil Orchestra of Fourteen are keeping a low profile.
What?
There were that many
delinquent groups besides us here?
You guys are but the tip of the iceberg,
you damn country bumpkins!
Really? We're that insignificant?
Karasuyama Chitose.
As the vice president,
she is my archenemy and eternal rival!
Hey, lemme in on this.
Me too.
And include me too, while you're at it!
Sh-Sh-Sh-She's here!
What are you eavesdropping on us for?!
That's just wrong, woman!
I just happened to hear your idiotic voices from up here.
You seriously think I'm gonna buy that?!
By the way,
this is the girls' changing room.
P-President, hurry up and shut the window!
Uh, well...
You damn voyeurs.
It's not what you think!
Please stop saying things like that, seriously!
Don't be polite to her, you idiot!
It makes it feel like we've lost!
Come to think of it, you're up on the second floor!
We couldn't peep in there even if we wanted to!
If you worked together,
you could easily get up here and peep!
If we worked together?
We could peep?
No! Too unbalanced!
Too heavy!
Just right!
You didn't include me!
You wanna peep that badly?
Ha! You got left out!
You're always so pathetic.
That's why you lost to me.
Oh yeah, you lost in the
student council elections, didn't you?
That's right. I lost in the presidential elections.
But I still wanted to contribute to my school, so I took up the post of vice president,
only for the president to walk all over me
whenever anything went wrong.
Or even when nothing went wrong!
She dug her heels right into me!
I...
I find that president...
irresistibly unforgivable!
Irresistible?
You okay, dude?!
Whatever. I don't care anymore.
Get lost, you guys.
If you don't, I'll make you leave.
With one of your earth-elemental attacks?!
To defeat you lot,
all I need is my own saliva.
Gross!
How the hell did she become president?!
In that case, bring it on!
I'll catch every last drop!
You're not supposed to catch it!
You were bitching about people changing earlier,
but you're the one who's changed the most!
This attack won't work against that pervert.
Let's see if there's something else I can use.
Stop!
Lemme go!
Lemme catch it!
In fact, lemme drink it!
Yeah!
Oh shit!
Can we go back to the earth-elemental attacks?!
Hey, what are you doing?
Hurry up and run!
I won't...
I won't run away!
If that thing hits you, you won't have a brain left to feel pleasure with!
That's not it!
If I run away now,
I'll just be returning to the days I spent in servitude!
So I'm going to throw away my past self,
right here and now!
And I'm going to save you, Kenji!
Ataru, you...
We've got your back, Acchan.
You guys...
All right! Bring it on, President!
Huh?
I will surpass you!
For a lowly vice president, you've got balls!
Take them to Hell with you!
Hey, Kenji!
What are you goofing off for?!
Did you need me for something?
You fool!
I can't do anything without you!
Help me so I can change!
Says the guy who picked
a fight without me just fine.
Go! You've got two minutes!
We can't hold out any longer than that!
Nagayama...
Make that one minute.
You cut my time!
Just one minute, huh?
But one whole minute...
Go!
...is more than enough!
I intended to save you,
but you wound up saving me instead.
It's no big deal.
Thanks to you, I managed to get a shot in on her.
You're pretty good.
I had my doubts when Roka brought you along,
but now I get it.
You've scored a few points in my eyes.
I win this round, though.
Nooo!
Suspension Notice
xx/xx/xxxx
The following students have been suspended:
Class 2-B Kazama Kenji
Class 2-F Kawahara Ataru
Kazama-san.
Oh, it's you.
The Game Dev Club meets
on Tuesdays through Fridays.
Say, why me?
Do you really not want to join?
Game Development Club
Currently Recruiting
Well, I did submit the club registration form.
Guess I gotta follow it through.
Yeah.
love to fight love to fight
Love to fight, love to fight
soy demo koi demo iin ja nai
Fresh soy, lover's joy, either one's all right
love to fight love to fight
Love to fight, love to fight
i'd love to fight
I'd love to fight
high tension de high na high touch
Give a hyped high-five with extra height
mainichi jet coaster
Every day's a rollercoaster ride
you will stun understand
Do you realize your touch electrifies
jibun wa joujou tungsten
Feeling good like high strung wires
i never know why
I never know why
anpan kutte ingaouhou na hankenteki ni chousenteki
Cram a sweet bun in your mouth;
cheat fate, cheat law, bring down the house
karamatte kamitsuite snipe spike suttenten
Get beat down, chew 'em up;
snipe 'em, spike 'em, go bankrupt
you never know why
You never know why
sou deshou
Isn't that right?
kousenteki na geek no shuudan
We're the meanest gang of geeks you ever saw
yabou zetsubou taikoubou nante
With ambition, derision, and fishin' rods... Yeah, as if!
gedou na made ni gekiteki na gesu
You've never met such hammy scumbags,
I bet it's just unbearable
game seisaku uchikomasu yo
Let's tackle game dev head on
wakatte nai tte nai sou ja nai
It's not like we don't know a thing, don't you know
kore mo hallelujah (fight fight fight fight)
So say hallelujah (Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight)
chimeishou de sunda koi wa ne
Even if your broken heart leaves you dying,
souzetsu na hima no tsubushiai yo
at least you killed time like a champion (Oh, yay!)
kizuite nai tte nai sou ja nai
We realize at least that much, thanks a bunch
sore mo hallelujah (fight fight fight fight)
That's one more hallelujah (Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!)
tatoe yuusha sama ga sekai wo sukuwanakutemo
Even if a gallant hero doesn't go and save the world,
arui wa maou sama ga sekai wo horobosazu to mo
Or if a dreadful demon king doesn't go and destroy the world,
atashi totemo
I'm feeling, more than ever...
fever (oh)
Fever (Oh!)
ever (oh)
Ever (Oh!)
never (oh)
Never (Oh!)
game over
Game over
all right
All right!
Illustration: Takeuchi Takashi
Coloring: Aotsuki Takao