Well?
Pardon?
I switched to wearing glasses.
Oh...
They look nice.
You think so?
They say that glasses make men look 30% more handsome.
So how much progress have you made?
But some girls don't want men to cover up their faces.
Kirishima-senpai.
Can you review the new school club budget?
Yep, looks okay.
I trust you know what you're doing.
Right.
That takes care of the club budget.
Next, we need to budget for student council expenses.
It seems Hiwako's changed quite a bit.
Don't you have work to do?
I liked it when she was snappy and cool,
but she's even better now that she's softened up a bit.
Oh, you're also cute, Mizuho.
Thank you very much.
So what happened to my proposal?
What?
For our uniforms.
Come on, now.
As I've said many times, we won't be changing our uniforms.
What?!
Hold on, people!
Are you okay with spending your
high school days in these dated uniforms?!
Girls' uniforms should be cuter!
Could we give it another year?
I'll be gone by then.
Personally, I'm a fan of sailor uniforms.
Then I became student council president in vain!
Why did he choose this school?
I need to get going.
You're leaving?
Yes. The meeting's over, after all.
Then let's go home together, Hiwako!
There's someone waiting for me.
Hiwako!
Bye.
Goodbye.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Don't be. Welcome back.
Thank you.
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Humans are Strange
Thank you very much.
Then we'll continue this tomorrow.
E-Excuse me, Mother...
What is it?
Well, Father's birthday is soon,
so I was wondering when he'd be home.
Oh, you're right.
He should be back from his overseas trip next week.
I see.
Then I'll excuse myself.
Next week!
I hope I can find a good present for him.
You have a new message
Makoto
Look what I made!
Orange0001.jpg
Orange0002.jpg
Orange0003.jpg
Orange0004.jpg
Is something wrong?
Huh?
Oh. Well, er...
You've been visiting your friends' places,
and you seem to be having fun at school,
but you look somewhat subdued today.
I was wondering if something had happened.
You always know everything.
There's something on my mind right now.
If you need someone to talk to, I'm always available.
Huh?
Oh, I'm sorry!
That was rude of me.
Not at all.
You don't need to apologize.
Besides, Yoshizumi-san...
Yes?
I feel bad about making you drive me around when you're my father's assistant.
There's no need for you to feel bad!
But the school is close enough for me to commute by bike.
Though I've never ridden a bicycle before.
Don't worry about it.
Your father has other assistants.
This is just part of my job.
Your job...
Er, I mean...
I'm sorry.
You have your own reasons for being here.
N-No...
Say, about your offer earlier...
Would you be willing to listen to what's on my mind?
Yes, absolutely.
My father's birthday is coming up,
but I don't know what to give him.
A birthday present for your father?
Perhaps...
You could go with something tried and true, like a tie.
He wears those every day.
A tie...
I'm not sure how to pick one out, though.
I don't know my father's tastes.
Then I can ask my colleagues if they know anything.
Thank you.
It must seem strange that
I don't know my father's tastes.
Your father's busy, so you don't get to see him much.
It's perfectly understandable.
Thank you for being so supportive.
Do you have any stories to tell me about my father?
You can even say bad things about him, if you want.
That's not...
Say, can I open the window?
Go ahead.
Let me know if you're going to study with your friends again.
Of course, we'll keep it a secret from your mother and father.
Our secret?
Yes.
A birthday present?
Yes, my father's birthday is coming up.
Oh, a present for your dad?
The last time I gave my dad a present was in grade school.
I usually ask my dad if there's anything he wants,
but he always says that anything will do.
That doesn't help at all.
No kidding.
Sorry, Funabashi-san.
We're not much help.
It's okay.
I'm thinking about giving him a tie.
A tie?
I asked Yoshizumi-san this morning,
and he mentioned that my father wears ties every day.
Makes sense.
Your driver's pretty sharp.
Yoshizumi-san isn't my driver.
He's my father's assis—
I know! Let's ask your driver to take us shopping!
As I was saying, he's not my driver.
Look at this.
There's a new shopping mall that opened last week.
A shopping mall?
Oh, I heard about that place.
It's supposed to be huge.
It's not exactly close,
but if we have someone to
drive us, it won't be a problem!
Don't make it sound so simple.
Tomorrow is Yoshizumi-san's day off.
We can take the train.
We'll have tons of stuff to carry afterward, though.
Going by car's way easier.
Right? You interested, Saeki?
Yep, you bet.
I'm coming for sure!
See, Funabashi?
There's three of us, so we should go by car.
We'll help you pick out a present, so ask him if he can drive us.
Fine, but if Yoshizumi-san is busy, we're taking the train, okay?
Okay! I'm sure he'll take us, though.
Funabashi Akihiko
Oh, a tie, huh?
As a politician, the most important thing is to present a clean image.
If you're looking for help,
I believe he has a lot of blue ties.
I see.
Oh, don't you need to go pick up his daughter?
Oh, that's right!
What? On Saturday?
Yes, we're looking to go shopping somewhere far away.
Oh, are you buying a present for your father?
Yes. I feel really bad about making you do this.
No, it's no problem at all.
I'm happy to be able to help.
Thank you very much, Yoshizumi-san!
Thanks for picking me up!
Silver  Fox
Check it out!
That's so cute!
Well? Does it look good?
I think it does.
That doesn't look too bad, Funabashi.
Yeah, bikinis are the way to go.
How about this one, Saeki?
It's a little flashy for me.
This is what you need!
Which one do I pick?
There's a lot to choose from.
Hey.
Isn't this one nice?
Huh?
U-Um, I'm not sure...
Whoa! 15,000 yen!
That's expensive.
I'll put it back.
Oh, Funabashi-san.
How about this one?
It's really cute,
and it only costs 2,800 yen!
Oh, that one's nice.
But...
Which one do you like, then?
Oh, your father's main assistant, Kida-san,
said that your father wears clean-cut ties for work.
Clean-cut?
And he wears a lot of blue ties.
In that case, how would these look?
What do you think?
Oh, they look nice.
Let's check the price.
8,000 yen?
That's within my budget.
Huh?
But which one do I choose?
I don't know which one will look better.
We have the perfect model here.
Have him try them on.
Wait, you mean me?
Um, is that okay?
Uh, yes...
Excuse me.
Well, it seems like a safe choice for a politician.
Yep, but what about the other one?
This one also looks nice.
It looks nice, but it seems a bit casual for work.
I think both work.
Yep, it comes down to whichever one you want to give him.
I agree.
Huh?
Your father buys his own ties to wear at work,
so you should decide on
the one you want to give him.
I'm sure that he wants a present
that his daughter chose for him.
You're right.
I understand. I'll go with this one.
Thank you for all your help today.
It's no biggie.
Let's grab something to drink.
Yep.
Yoshizumi-san, do you have
enough time for us to stick around a bit?
Absolutely. Take your time.
I'll be waiting in the car, so please call me when you're finished.
Why don't you join us?
As thanks for your help today.
Are you sure that's all right?
Look at all the fruits!
Delicious!
There seem to be a lot of women here...
Hey, there's something that's been bugging me.
Why did you choose our high school, Funabashi?
I've never heard of anyone coming to our school in a fancy car.
You're smart enough to get into
a school for the rich and famous.
My mother recommended
that I attend a local high school.
We should be grateful to your mom, then.
She helped us become friends.
Yes, you're right.
I'm very grateful.
This is definitely rare.
It's not easy to find girls as sorry as you are.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Now, now.
But I have to say that you've really changed.
Huh? What do you mean?
Remember how you used to snap at everyone?
You used to be really hard to approach.
Really?
Totally!
You seriously didn't realize it?
I have to agree that you didn't let people approach you.
That wasn't my intention.
But you've definitely opened up.
Is that so?
Right? Don't you agree, Mr. Driver?
Huh?
I told you that Yoshizumi-san is my driver, not my father's assistant—
I mean, he's my father's assistant, not my driver!
Well, either way, don't you agree?
Y-Yes...
She's running late.
I must admit that I was quite surprised the other day.
She was having so much fun with her friends.
She certainly feels like a different person now.
When I first met her, she was almost like a doll.
Allow me to introduce you to my daughter.
My name is Hiwako. It's a pleasure to meet you.
Hiwako, this is Yoshizumi-kun.
He's my youngest assistant,
who just joined us this year.
He'll be taking care of you.
Yoshizumi...
Huh? No "-san"?
I know that you're busy with work,
but can you take my daughter to and from school?
I'll also need a daily report from you.
Of course.
And now...
Yoshizumi-san...
She's become a beautiful girl.
What am I thinking?!
She's in high school!
Ten years younger than me!
My boss's daughter!
What is that guy doing?
I wonder why she's so late.
I'll call her.
Yes?
Huh?
Hello, Hiwako's driver.
Aren't you the student council president?
Kirishima Seishirou.
Kirishima-kun?
So, about Hiwako...
Do you have business with Hiwako-sama?
Oh, she's not here yet?
Hmm...
Pardon?
You can leave, then.
I'll take Hiwako home.
Huh?
Don't worry. I'll make sure she gets home safely.
Oh, is that Hiwako's phone number?
Huh?
Excellent. Give it to me.
She always refuses to give me
her number when I ask.
Wait!
What's the problem? Sharing is free!
No! No! No!
O-Oh, no...
All of my contacts were in here...
What's wrong with you?!
There's no way that I could give you her number!
What is your relationship with Hiwako-sama, anyway?!
Come on, you sound like her father.
Of course!
I've been asked by her parents to take care of her!
To protect her from bad boys, right?
It's not fair for her to be monitored all the time.
She's in high school now.
She should be allowed to spend more time with people her age.
Right? You should talk to her parents about it.
Yoshizumi-san!
Oh, Hiwako!
I'm sorry. My friend isn't feeling well!
What's wrong?!
Her stomach suddenly started to hurt.
Ow...
The school nurse isn't around!
Please take us to the hospital!
Huh?
Ow...
Are you okay, Kozue-chan?
U-Uh, Hiwako...
Oh, Kirishima-senpai.
Goodbye!
Let's go! Please!
Y-Yes!
Shinto Central Hospital
Sorry about scaring everyone.
It was just constipation.
I'm glad it wasn't anything serious.
Yes, that's a relief.
Someone from my family will come pick me up, so I'll be fine.
Thanks a lot.
Saeki-san, I can take you home.
That would be great.
Sorry about dragging you around like this.
Oh, it's fine.
It was an emergency.
I'm more worried about my cell phone.
Is something wrong?
Er, n-no!
Oh, it turned on!
Thank goodness!
Thank you very much.
Oh, do you wanna come up for a bit?
My dad is probably around.
Y-You can drop by, if you'd like.
You're welcome too, Yoshizumi-san.
Yes, we should visit while we're here.
Er, is it really okay?
Okay...
Don't worry. We rarely see any cars pass by.
I'm home!
Hold on a sec.
Dad!
Now that I think about it,
this is the first time I've met someone who lives in a shrine.
Yoshizumi-san, do you know how to pay your respects?
Not in detail, no.
I learned the right way just recently.
You go like this...
Since I'm here, I should pray for your father's success.
You don't have to do that.
You should pray for something you want.
Th-That's true.
I know what to do here.
I bow twice before clapping my hands.
That's right.
What's your problem, Gintarou?!
Well, I just thought it seemed appropriate.
Something I want...
Does Hiwako-sama find her current lifestyle restrictive?
I...
When you clap your hands together,
your right hand is supposed to be a little lower.
After you've made your wish, you move it back.
Did you know that?
I didn't know until they told me.
R-Right.
She's my boss's daughter.
I pray that...
I never fall in love with her!
Funabashi-san!
Sorry. Looks like my dad isn't around.
Really? We should get going, then.
Sorry about this.
I wonder where he went.
Why are you sitting in the corner?
Saeki-san, do you have any charms for driving safely?
Yep.
Here.
Please take this.
Th-Thank you very much.
Huh? Your face is red, Yoshizumi-san.
Are you okay?
I might have caught a cold.
What? Are you feeling all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
We need to get going.
I don't get it.
His wish was weird!
Does it really matter what he wished for?
Don't worry about it.
Why can't he fall in love?
This is nothing.
There's a whole world of weird out there.
Humans are strange!
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
This is Hiwako.
Normally, a charm is said
to be effective for one year.
Afterward, you're supposed to
return the charm to the shrine.
Next time: "I'm Sorry."
I'm Sorry
May fortune be with you.