Kamio Shrine
Are you really leaving?
Yes, Otomatsu-sama.
Tahara-sensei helped me find this place.
It's a trustworthy shrine.
I see...
It'll be lonely without you around.
There will be many a tear shed.
This is the only way.
There is nothing else...
I can do.
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Satoru and Haru
Huh?!
Wh-What did you just say?
Huh? I thought I mentioned this before.
We'll be welcoming a new member of our family next week.
Since when?!
This is news to me!
What's going on?!
Well, now you know.
That doesn't make it okay!
I can't believe you made such an important decision without talking to me.
I refuse to call her "Mom"!
Huh?
Wh-What's so funny?
You've got it all wrong.
Honestly, Makoto... It's not what you think.
Huh?
Someone from another shrine will be staying with us?
Yes, my former teacher asked me to do this.
I only wish there was someone interested in me that way.
From what I hear, our guest is a kendo expert who will also be transferring to your school.
Isn't your school a kendo powerhouse?
Kendo?
I think our school does well in tournaments, yeah...
That's why your school is a perfect match,
and our shrine can provide accommodation.
Oh...
Wait! That still doesn't make it okay!
Hmm? I don't see a problem.
We have plenty of spare rooms, you know.
Do you know their name?
Is it someone I've met before?
Kamio Satoru-kun.
A boy?!
Wait! You have a young girl living here!
I'm not sure I could even handle living with a girl I don't know,
let alone a boy!
You're overreacting.
And you didn't even get permission from Gin!
I'm sure he approves. He's a herald, after all.
Gintarou-sama is also a boy, come to think of it.
What? Other people can't see Gin!
Wait, that's not my point!
Honestly, you're too relaxed about this, Dad!
What?
Who's on duty?
Saeki?
Can you take these back?
Yes.
He's supposed to arrive today.
This sucks.
Let me give you a hand.
That's too much for one person to carry.
Sure.
Reference Room
Thanks for your help, Funabashi-san.
Don't worry about it. By the way...
I saw you sigh before. Is something wrong?
Um, just a little family issue.
Oh, dear.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing...
Saeki! Funabashi!
I was looking for you guys.
Ikegami-san...
We're getting a transfer student next week!
And guess what? It's a boy!
Yeah...
What? How come you already knew?
I only just found out from our teacher.
Uh...
Did you use your fortune telling again?
N-No, I didn't.
So is he hot? Handsome?
How tall is he? How's his hair?
Tell me everything!
Honestly...
Is that all you ever care about?
What's wrong with that?
It's what matters the most!
Now spill it, Saeki!
I'm hungry.
Gintarou!
Is that boy here yet?
I've never seen such a large fox spirit before.
You can see him?
Hey, there.
You brought another fox with you, huh?
The shrine is adequate, but it's a bit on the small side.
Haru.
Satoru!
Can't blame me...
Come down here for now.
Fine.
Do you live here?
Uh, yeah.
U-Um...
Excuse me. Where is your partner?
He's gone.
I see.
Was that you?
You're adorable!
Hey, girl!
Don't you know how to respect your betters?!
Satoru, this place is no good.
This girl has the Sight, and yet she talks down to heralds!
And she's standing right in the center of the path!
Didn't anyone teach her manners?
You're one noisy brat.
None of that stuff matters.
Yes, it does!
Haru!
But...
Hey, Makoto! You're home—
You must have had a long trip, Satoru-kun.
Yes.
My name is Kamio Satoru.
Thank you for your hospitality.
Oh, no need to be so formal.
I'm sorry that you're stuck with this small room.
Let me know if there's anything at all you need.
No need to concern yourself.
I don't plan on staying long.
Huh?
Please let me stay here for one week while I look for a place to live.
I can pay for food.
H-Hold on...
Your guardians already sent me money.
Plus, I was told that you would be staying here until you graduated.
I have the money my parents left me
and what little I've saved up.
If need be, I'll get a job.
But you'll need an adult's signature to rent a place,
not to mention all the other—
Makoto, talk to him.
Could you leave us for a minute, Dad?
We need to talk alone.
Huh?
C'mon, hurry up.
What's this about?
When did you two get so close?
Well, I wouldn't want to get in your way—
Just go!
The chief priest here can't see heralds.
Neither could ours.
Yep, Dad married into the family.
But he knows about Gin.
I see. So you were the one who inherited the Sight.
It's unusual for someone so young to have it.
You're just as young as she is.
Satoru, don't bother.
The Sight's wasted on her.
The fox here has no idea what he's doing.
Haru!
So why are you looking for another place to stay?
Is it because of your herald?
I have a request to make.
Please let Haru stay here.
Silver  Fox
Please.
I have the Sight, but I won't be taking over our shrine for various reasons.
However, Haru followed me when I left.
Fortunately, it appears that you don't have a partner at the moment.
I promise that I will convince Haru to go home eventually.
No way! I'm never going back!
I don't want to live in that shrine if you're not there!
I'm staying with you.
Could you please let Haru stay here?
Why? That fox already has a shrine to call home.
What will happen to that shrine if the priest with the Sight should leave?
W-Well...
I won't ask for an explanation,
but I don't like it.
A-Anyway, you should just live here, then.
You can be with Haru-chan that way.
You don't want your guardians to worry about you, right?
Gintarou!
You have no idea how bad it'll be
if I get stuck with that kid.
You didn't have to be so mean about it.
I'm sure they have their reasons.
I doubt it's anything important.
Honestly, you're so heartless.
You're both heralds!
Doesn't matter.
Jeez...
This is getting weird.
The Kamio Shrine priest's son and his wife died in an accident.
They had a young son together...
Satoru! Satoru!
Grandpa.
Come here and we can play together.
Uh-huh!
It must be hard for the chief priest.
Yes, he has to raise his grandson all by himself.
Father, it's too difficult for you to run a shrine this big by yourself!
You should retire and let us handle it.
Nonsense! Why are you bringing this up again?
That boy is my successor!
Father!
From now on, Satoru-kun will live with us.
What?
That sucks.
He has nowhere else to go.
Your grandpa passed away.
Clean up this mess, okay?
Satoru-kun!
Why are you still practicing?
Honestly, you're free to dedicate yourself to kendo,
but try not to make any trouble for us.
Satoru!
You're a real pain, you know that?
Satoru-kun! Don't do anything without our permission!
We are your guardians now!
I overslept!
Sorry, Satoru-kun.
This is my job.
It's okay.
Um, where's Dad?
He went out.
Oh...
Offering
Box
Where's Gin?
Looks like he made his escape.
Satoru-kun, you haven't done this side yet, right?
It's okay. I'll take care of it.
It's the least I can do.
But...
It's okay, really.
You know...
I bet you don't sweep this place properly.
Huh?
That would explain why there are so many leaves around.
And that big fox ran off.
Seriously, this shrine's a mess.
Just let it slide.
You're talking to a herald.
And it's true that I haven't been sweeping every day.
S-Sorry.
Haru.
Why won't you go home?
B-Because...
I'm worried about you.
I told you I'll be fine.
But...
Just go home.
No! I don't wanna go back there!
U-Um...
I'm staying with you!
Go back!
I'll be fine on my own!
Satoru...
Do you not want me around?
Am I bothering you?
You are.
Hold on!
You need me...
I need you!
Haru-chan?!
Hey! You shouldn't yell at a little kid!
Aren't you gonna go after Haru?!
Satoru-kun?!
A little kid?
Haru's over eighty years old.
That fox has been around longer than me
and knows more than I do.
Haru is the herald of our shrine.
That's why I have to do this.
Satoru-kun...
But don't you want to be...
with Haru?
Just drop it!
It's none of your business!
But...
Gintarou!
Man, looks like this is going to be messy after all.
Gin, what do we do?
That kid could disappear if you don't do something.
Well, it's not my problem.
Hey, you don't really hate Haru, do you?
Satoru-kun!
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
The gate serves as a barrier
between the sacred ground of
the gods and the human world.
Gates come in many different
forms and colors.
Next time: "Season of Warmth."
Season of Warmth
May fortune be with you.