Funabashi, you better not let go.
Okay, okay.
Good morning.
Good morning!
A-All right. Got it.
I'll see you around noon, then.
Sure. We'll be waiting for you.
Good morning, Gin.
Saeki?
What are you doing?
N-Nothing.
I'm digging this whole "early to bed and early to rise" thing!
Feels great!
Except you were the last one to wake up.
Good morning!
Oh, Etsuko-san.
Good morning.
I see you're working hard.
Oh, Sis? You're here already?
It's eight.
Why are you already changed, then?
Oh, I wanted to hit the ground running today.
You just want to show off because so many people are here.
Hey, Takami-kun.
I can't do this.
This is when I usually go to bed.
I'm about to keel over.
Why don't you take a nap?
No, I'm staying awake!
I won't let you win!
Not in front of these teenage girls.
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iou kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Summer Cleansing
Oh, you girls look nice.
How about I take you all out on a date?
Yes, you all look wonderful.
Oh, right. There's a boy here.
A friend of Satoru-kun's with blond hair.
Blond hair?
Isn't that Shohei-kun?
Huh?
He's already here?
I told him we weren't starting until noon.
He almost looks like a foreigner.
A foreigner?
Aha.
Will this really cleanse my soul?
Well, Japanese people have always enjoyed traditional events that grant them temporary peace of mind.
Who is this guy?
So, since my soul is already as pure as can be, what do I do?
You can leave.
Huh? It's not Shohei?
Oh, it's Kirishima-senpai?
Hiwako!
What? The student council president?
Hello.
Senpai, what are you doing here?
I came to enjoy this summer cleansing with you.
But the ceremony doesn't begin until three.
Oh, really?
It doesn't start for another five hours?
I guess I got carried away.
Funabashi, you should have told us he was coming.
It's not like I invited him.
Still, it worked out in the end since I get to see Hiwako dressed up as a shrine maiden,
I'm being welcomed by lots of other cute shrine maidens,
and there aren't any ghosts around.
Ghosts?
Oh, never mind. Just talking to myself.
Who is he?
Beats me.
So he's a friend of yours?
Please make yourself at home while you wait.
Sure thing!
Man, I'm beat!
You should be ashamed of yourself.
You're too hard on us!
Help yourself to some rice balls.
Okay.
Let's eat!
My grandmother was British, you see.
He's fitting right in.
Y-Yeah...
Oh, take your time eating lunch.
Okay.
Come to think of it, where's Takami-san?
Not sure where he went.
Makoto-oneechan!
Oh, Aki-chan, Sacchan!
This is Taiga-kun from our class.
He sits next to me.
He's in my group!
Hello.
Wow, cute boy!
Is he really a boy?
Hey, Taiga.
What are you doing hanging out with girls?
Hey, Yuuya!
You shut up!
Taiga, you sure you're not a girl yourself?
Taiga-kun is sweet, unlike you!
Shut up, ugly!
Hey, Yuuya!
Uh-oh, it's Grandma!
Crap!
Run!
We were like that once, you know.
Makocchi!
Thank goodness.
We finally made it!
Kozue-chan, Saki-chan.
You made it!
We got lost.
She went in totally the opposite direction.
There's still plenty of time left, so it's okay.
Look! Shrine maiden outfits!
Nice! You all look really cute.
Is that your dad?
Yep, that's him.
Oh? He looks like a nice guy.
It's a real priest!
It's no big deal.
This is my first time, so tell me what to do.
Sure.
Here. First, you need to write your name and age on this paper figure.
Then you breathe on it three times to transfer any impurities.
You can also rub it against any part of your body that doesn't feel right.
Oh, I know this.
My family does it every year.
Oh, they have car-shaped ones too.
Sample
Saeki Tarou, 39
Ichirou, 14
Anyway, we collect a small fee for each cleansing...
Oh, it's okay.
Thank you.
P-Prince?!
You scared me.
You just noticed he was here?
Sorry. I'll be right back.
Okay.
Hiwako-sama!
Yoshizumi-san, you made it.
Y-Yes...
Wait! This isn't good!
Hiwako, need any help?
We're fine.
Senpai, you weren't kidding about stopping by...
Wow, you're dressed all in white.
That's a good new look for you.
He forced me to come!
Come on. You should be happy that you get to skip practice.
Anyway, here you go.
I got all of the members to write one like you said.
I'm amazed they actually did it.
They were all glad to participate.
Did we have a choice?
And for the fee...
What fee?
No fee, huh...
Wait, hold on!
We want to do this by the book, you know?
Is 1,000 yen enough?
Kosugi, chip in.
Hey, I only brought enough for the bus ride home!
Is 50 yen enough?
I can probably contribute another 5,000 yen.
Seriously?
Wait, how are you so loaded?!
Sorry.
Well, they'll be grouped together.
It's the thought that counts.
I promise to physically return the favor!
In that case...
Hiwako, why don't you join me for dinner when you're finished?
No, thank you.
When you leave, please take him with you.
Oh, he's here too?
Um, are you Kinu-chan-senpai?
I wanted to thank you for the delicious tofu.
Oh, it's okay. It was nothing special.
Hey, Saeki!
Coming!
I need to get going.
Yep.
I'll be right back.
Dude, that girl's so cute!
Is she an angel?!
What?!
Huh, so the turnout's pretty good.
Not too bad, I guess.
Well, our shrine got way more visitors.
Is Satoru okay?
He looks like he's doing fine.
Come on. We have a job to do.
I know that!
You don't have to carry me there!
Uncle!
Grandma and Grandpa!
Thanks for coming!
Oh, what a lovely little shrine maiden.
Please make yourself comfortable.
You're late. We've been waiting for you.
Silver  Fox
And it's so good!
How's business?
Uncle Yoshitomo!
You look sharp!
Like a totally different person from before!
Where've you been?
Well...
Wait, does that mean it's almost time?
Dad, you're still not changed yet?!
It'll be fine! Take it easy or you'll trip!
Come on, Dad!
She really does look just like Yuu-chan now.
Saeki's mom?
Yeah, though Yuu-chan's hair was longer and black.
Are you married, Takami-san?
Nope. Sorry to say it, but I'm still looking for a wife.
I'd expect women to be all over you, though.
Are priests not very popular?
Nah, popularity wasn't the problem.
Then what was it?
People tend to put priests on a pedestal, so to speak.
We're popular, but they tend to keep their distance.
In truth, though, we're just the same as anyone else.
Oh...
I can see why people admire priests, and that admiration is important,
but that's as far as it should go, don't you think?
Now I know why you quit being a priest!
Some woman told you that you didn't look the part at all, right?
To be honest, you might've hit the nail on the head.
You hear that?
If you keep chasing after him, you'll get burned.
I'm not—
Yo!
Hey, Shohei!
You're late!
Takami-kun, stop fooling around and go get changed.
Okay, okay...
What were you teasing that girl for?
Oh, you were watching?
I wish I had a teenage girl chasing after me.
Honestly, you never grow up.
Popular!
You need to get married!
I was married once, but...
There are a lot of people today.
I'm getting nervous.
Honestly, pull yourself together.
There, you look okay.
Get going.
Dad!
You look cool!
Thank you, Makoto.
We will now perform the
Summer Cleansing ceremony.
Come on! Over here, guys!
Huh? We can join in?
Yes, we can do this together.
Once, in times long past, there lived a god and goddess in the heavens.
They gathered the countless gods
in a grand meeting.
After many a heated debate,
they reached a decision.
"Our grandchild will be sent to rule over Japan..."
Those who participate in the June Summer Cleansing
have a thousand years added to their life.
Those who participate in the June Summer Cleansing...
Oh, if you're underage, you only get to take a sip.
Hiwako, are you busy after this?
You take the thatch and keep
wrapping it around to form a ring,
and then you hang it on your door and pray for good health.
Hiwako! Hiwako!
We're leaving!
See you on Monday!
Bye-bye!
I'll be back later to pick you up.
Okay.
Funabashi-san, you don't look too good.
Are you tired?
I feel fine.
Saeki, is there anything after this?
There's the banquet.
Everyone shares the offerings that were made to the gods.
It's basically a feast.
Sounds great!
But first, we need to cast the paper figures into the river.
Wanna come?
That sounds fun! Let's go, Funabashi!
Sure!
What do I do?
Why don't you leave?
Feels so good!
Satoru-kun.
Huh? Saeki?
I like to watch from above.
Gin.
Yo.
Satoru!
How did it go for you?
What do you mean?
Well, aren't you always inside the shrine during festivals?
Are you talking to the gods?
Yeah, something like that.
Oh, I don't think I've ever asked.
What are the gods like?
Uka-no-Mitama, for instance.
Well. Gods, by nature,
never stay in one place,
so they leave as soon as the festival ends.
That's what we were taught.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter if the gods are around or not.
But your world has chosen to believe in them.
It's all about possibility.
They're there if you believe they are.
Shouldn't that be good enough?
But since you can see heralds,
you're more likely to believe in the gods.
Oh.
That's right.
But it's funny, you know.
Festivals have been happening for a long time,
bringing people together,
and you've been there to watch over us.
You'll continue to be there,
so we'll all continue to be brought together.
Those who participate in the June Summer Cleansing
have a thousand years added to their life.
If I really could live for a thousand years, I'd get to be with you forever.
Don't be crazy.
You'll be all withered up before then.
Well, I'll be with you 'til the end.
Jeez, don't treat me like a kid!
As far as I'm concerned,
even Tatsuo and Yoshitomo are kids.
Right...
It's my turn now.
Hey, Gintarou.
When I grow up, I'm gonna be Dad's bride.
That's nice.
Don't be jealous.
It's the only way.
You're a fox spirit, so I can't marry you.
Dad is the chief priest here,
so he'll always be around.
So I'll just settle for Dad instead.
Yeah, yeah. Whatever you want.
Then I get to be with you forever.
How could I forget?
Gin!
What is it?
I want to protect the place
that brings everyone together from generation to generation.
So, Gin!
Promise that you'll stay with me!
Wh-What's this about?
What? This is a pinky swear.
I already made a promise.
Jeez... Come on!
It won't work! Your hand's too big!
And which one's your pinky?
Stop complaining.
Come on, Gin.
Everybody's here for the summer cleansing.
You should go visit your friends.
What? I don't have any friends.
Huh? What are you are talking about?
Humans and gods get together a few times every year,
so heralds should do the same.
There's Saimaru-san, Utamaru-san, and the turtle.
There's also Fuu-chan and Fuku-chan.
Sounds like a pain.
Jeez. Kinjirou probably left because you were always like this!
R-Really?
Come on!
Fine, fine. I'll go!
Wait, why do I have to come?!
See you later.
There they go.
Yeah.
Saeki! Can you see them from here?
Yep.
Look how far they've gone!
Good thing the weather's nice.
Yep.
Summer's almost here.
Yeah.
My home is a small Inari shrine that's been around since the Edo period.
Our shrine is dedicated to the god of agriculture, Uka-no-Mitama.
Cream Bun
Tangerine
Jelly
Cream Bun
Tangerine
Jelly
Cream Bun
Tangerine
Jelly
Cream Bun
Tangerine
Jelly
Cream Bun
Tangerine
Jelly
Cream Bun
Tangerine
Jelly
If you happen to be in the area, please stop by Saeki Shrine.
You might run into my father, the relaxed priest,
and maybe even a small and energetic fox spirit
and a large, gruff, and very lazy fox spirit.
We'll all be here waiting for you.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky