I feel bad for the priest.
Makoto-chan's only four years old.
She still needs constant care and attention.
"Makoto," was it?
Can you see me?
That makes you the fifteenth.
That was how I first met Gintarou.
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
The Fifteenth Successor and Gintarou
My home is a small Inari shrine that's been around since the Edo period.
Our shrine is dedicated to the god of agriculture, Uka-no-Mitama.
Wait, what?
Man, what happened?
There's my father, who's the shrine priest, myself,
and Gintarou, the herald who serves as a messenger for the gods.
The three of us live together.
Hey, Makoto.
Can't you keep it down a bit when you wake up?
Oh, Gintarou! Good morning!
Oh, is Gintarou-sama on the roof?
Yup.
I'm not fortunate enough to see him, since I married into the family.
I hope that you will continue to put up with Makoto.
Gintarou is a herald, so normal people can't see him.
I can see him because I'm a true successor of this shrine.
Anyway, Makoto, don't you need to go to school?
Right! Can you take this, Dad?!
Bye!
Be careful now.
Heralds usually come in pairs,
but it sounds like his partner left a century ago,
so Gintarou is the only herald at our shrine.
Still, the most important thing is to have faith,
so our shrine isn't any worse off than the others.
Wait! I need to get on!
Here's a special charm for you.
This will help you get better in no time.
Yup.
Hey, it's Makoto-oneechan!
Good morning, Onee-chan!
Good morning, Sacchan, Aki-chan!
What happened to that cat?
She's hurt,
so we're gonna take care of her together until she gets better.
Her name's Mi-chan.
I hope she gets better soon.
Uh-huh!
Oh!
I need to be somewhere, so I'll talk to you later!
Bye-bye!
She's late again.
Shinto West Public High School
All rise.
Bow.
Saeki, see me in the faculty office.
Busted!
For real?
And the new term just started, too.
Saeki.
Oh, um...
I'm Yumi. Ikegami Yumi.
We need to talk.
What is it?
I hear that you can tell fortunes.
Gin!
Where are you?
Gin?
Fool.
Gintarou!
Why would I be down there?
I need you to look at a classmate of mine!
Do you understand what it means to be a herald?
I'll give you an orange.
Offering
Box
Don't mess around. Ordinary people can't see you.
She got in a fight with her boyfriend?
Well?
Eh, she'll probably be fine.
Really?
Yeah. Her boyfriend is sorry as well.
But as a few words of warning,
this girl has a real stubborn streak to her.
She needs to be humble when approaching him.
Really?! Awesome!
Great news, Yumi!
See? Aren't you glad you talked to her?
Um, try to be humble when you apologize.
See ya around, Saeki.
Thanks.
Be humble!
Try to be humble...
Man, you're the first oracle to abuse a herald like this.
Yuuko was far more composed and ladylike.
Please don't compare me to Mom.
Anyway, I'm never doing anything like this again.
Even for oranges.
Fine.
Gimme another one.
I'm out.
What?!
Really?
I wonder why he likes oranges so much.
Oh, Ikegami-san—
You fraud! You said everything would work out if I apologized!
I apologized just like you told me to!
I even said I was sorry!
No way...
The girl you just looked at said that my advice only made things worse!
You told her she'd be fine!
Huh? That's not my problem.
The future isn't set in stone.
How can you say that?
Everyone comes here asking for help because you're always right!
You're the one who's always asking me for help.
Besides, you didn't give her the entire message.
Well...
Man, some people make me laugh.
They never visit shrines,
but when they're in trouble,
they turn to the gods anyway?
Gimme a break.
What's wrong with that?!
That's what this shrine is for!
It's a place for people to come when they're in trouble!
It doesn't help when you can't tell fortunes the way Yuuko did.
Well!
You call yourself a herald, but you're just a stupid fox!
Yeah, that's right.
I'm just a mischievous old fox.
I fooled you all real good.
Serves you right.
What's that?
Stupid Gin!
I hate you!
Go away!
Oh, really now?
You need me more than I need you.
I don't care!
Just leave!
Silver  Fox
Offering                Box
Makoto-oneechan!
We can't find Mi-chan anywhere!
She just disappeared!
You mean the cat that was in the park the other day?
She almost got better from when she was hit by a car.
Please help us! You can find her, right?
You helped me find my mom's ring!
But that was because...
Onee-chan?
Don't worry.
I'll help you look for her.
Can you tell me where Mi-chan might be?
Uh-huh.
Wow, this is filthy.
This tiny shrine should be outside of Inari's jurisdiction.
There used to be Inari shrines all over the place, too.
The land has changed quite a bit.
Oh, it's the cat lady!
Sacchan! Aki-chan!
Onee-chan!
Did you find Mi-chan?!
No, I can't find her.
Ugh, Saeki?!
Ikegami-san?
Are you friends?
She took Mi-chan to the hospital.
What could I have done?
I'm not just going to leave an injured cat lying around.
Anyway, let's look for Mi-chan!
Uh-huh!
Don't just stand there, Saeki!
What's wrong, John?
What are you barking at?
Wh-What's this?
Actually, there's no need for me to avoid those.
Oh.
Matsuume Shrine
Right, they live in this area.
Matsuume
Shrine
You got in a fight with your oracle?
She's not an oracle yet.
A herald can't allow a human to abuse him.
We heralds only exist because of the gods we serve.
The same can be said of shrines.
A shrine without a herald
will quickly crumble as the gods' presence fades away.
You should return to your own shrine.
Thanks for having me.
By the way, what happened to your partner?
Heralds are meant to be paired.
He's gone.
He's been gone for a long time.
This is all I could find.
She's still hurt, so she can't have gotten far.
This is Mi-chan's!
Sacchan and I drew this to help her get better!
Makoto-oneechan, use your fortune telling to find Mi-chan!
Please, Onee-chan!
That's...
Forget it.
Her fortunes are totally off the mark.
But she's been right before!
I'll check with the animal shelters.
What do we do?
Mi-chan...
We'll find her soon.
Stupid Gin!
I hate you!
Go away!
Yes, that's what I said!
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
She's a little overweight, and her legs are wounded.
Can you hold on a little longer?
Onee-chan?!
Saeki?!
Hmph, I'm supposed to be the boss here.
It doesn't matter if Makoto's upset.
Gintarou!
Gin!
Where are you, Gintarou?!
Please show yourself!
Gin!
Come on, Gin!
What's wrong?
Have you seen Gintarou, Dad?
What?
Well, I can't see him...
Is he gone?
What do I do, Dad?
I can't find Mi-chan without Gin's help!
Just calm down and start from the beginning.
Oh, she wants me to tell fortunes for her again?
Don't worry. He'll be back soon.
I wish
for a year
of business success
and health for me
and my family.
Yoshida
I wish
for a year
of business success
and health for me
and my family.
Yoshida
He probably went out for a walk.
I got in an argument with Gintarou yesterday and said some terrible things.
I said that I hated him, and I told him to leave.
It was my fault that the advice I gave was wrong.
I told Gintarou that he was just a stupid fox!
I wanted to apologize,
but now Gintarou's gone!
I've made Gin do all kinds of silly things for selfish reasons.
But now that there are people out there who truly need Gin,
I can't even ask him for his help.
Maybe I'm just crazy,
and Gin never existed at all.
Now, now.
If you say that,
Gintarou-sama really will leave.
Makoto, have you ever thought about why you're the only one who can see Gintarou-sama?
No...
I don't believe it's wrong of you to ask Gintarou-sama to help you tell fortunes.
I believe it's your role to serve as an intermediary
between Gintarou-sama's world and the human world.
An intermediary?
You have the ability to see Gintarou the herald
and to relay his words.
I want you to always keep that in mind.
Or something like that.
Dad, I'm gonna go look for Gin!
I'll apologize for what I said yesterday!
And then... And then...
There are kids who need Gin's help!
I'm the only one who can find him!
Don't stay out too late!
Oh, Dad!
Can you have a bunch of oranges ready?!
Of course.
Gintarou-sama does love oranges.
Gin...
I'm sorry, Gin.
I've been with you since I was little, so I should know better.
No, I've been with you for such a long time
that I forgot you were a messenger from the gods.
I have to find you and tell you that I'm sorry!
Gin!
Where are you, Gin?!
Gin?!
Man, where does she think I went?
That girl just doesn't use her head.
Hey! Quit ruining my fields!
You damn fox!
Don't you show yourself around here again!
What's the matter?
All I can offer you is an orange.
But please help yourself.
Damn, come on now!
Gin...
Gintarou?
Fool!
Man, why would I seriously be down there?
Gin...
Gintarou...
I found you!
I finally found you!
Stupid!
I was worried, stupid Gintarou!
Wait, that's not what I wanted to say.
Um...
I'm sorry about what I said yesterday.
Oh, right.
What do I do, Gin?!
The cat's gone! Mi-chan's missing!
Guess I'll have to step in.
Seeing as how you can't do anything without me.
I'm expecting all the oranges I can eat for this.
Sacchan and Aki-chan were thrilled.
What's surprising, though,
is the fact that Ikegami-san's boyfriend found Mi-chan first.
Her bandages came off before she was healed,
and he couldn't just ignore her.
It looks like Ikegami-san was able to make up with her boyfriend after all.
So, um...
Thank you, Gin.
What's so funny?
In all the centuries I've spent serving the god Inari,
the oracles have always feared me, revered me, and worshipped me.
I've learned my lesson now.
But to be honest...
I like it better this way.
Gimme.
Hmm?
Don't play dumb.
I want my oranges.
Oranges.
Say, I've been wondering.
Why do you like oranges?
I'm never gonna tell you.
Why not?
Why not?!
I refuse to tell you.
You don't have to be so mean!
Oh, really?
Ow! What's that for?!
If you happen to be in the area, please stop by Saeki Shrine.
You might run into my father, the relaxed priest,
or a gruff, lazy fox spirit.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
An Inari shrine is a shrine for worshipping the god of foxes.
What kind of Inari shrines are near where you live?
Learning to Compromise
Next time: "Learning to Compromise."
May fortune be with you.