Man, where did that cat go?
She didn't even touch her food.
Hey, Ugly!
Ugly!
I'm leaving!
I've had enough of this place!
Calm down, man!
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Shrines and Temples
Jeez...
Is this gonna be a dry monsoon?
There are a lot of trees around.
This is a temple, Haru.
A temple?
Man, this is all because you said you wanted to meet the lion-dogs.
What a pain.
I'm very sorry, Gintarou-sama.
It's okay.
We can show him around town this way.
If you're not happy, go back to sleep.
I would if I could.
What's taking you so long?
Just come over!
Yeah, I get it.
Just hurry up.
That voice sounds familiar.
Sheesh.
Oh, it's Mako-chan.
Shouhei-kun, why are you here?
Amabuki Temple
This is my home.
Really?
Amabuki Temple
Wow, what a big temple!
It's old as dirt, though.
Amabuki Temple
Was that Yumi-chan?
Bingo.
She wants to come see Ugly.
Sounds like you two
are doing well.
What about you, Mako-chan?
Is that your boyfriend?
N-No!
He's a family friend from another shrine.
Why are you blushing?!
I'm not!
Huh?
N-Nothing!
R-Right...
Other people can't see Haru-chan and Gintarou,
so it looks like the two of us arrived alone.
The name's Amamoto. Hi.
I'm Kamio.
He goes to a different school, but he's Yumi-chan's...
Oh...
Oh.
What was that pause for?
Huh?
It was nothing.
You look like you have something you wanna say.
Huh?
Saeki!
Yumi-chan!
Why are you and Kamio here?
Are you on a date?
No way!
I'm just showing Satoru-kun around town.
Anyway, let's go in and see how Mi-chan's doing.
Come on, this way.
Amabuki Temple
A temple, huh?
What's wrong, Gintarou?
Nothing.
Hello.
Well, well.
Glad you could come.
Here's a little gift.
Oh, thanks as always.
Shou-chan, is Yumi-chan here?
Yumi-chan!
Hey, I haven't met these two before.
These are my friends, Saeki and Kamio-kun!
Thank you for coming.
I'm Shouhei's mother.
I'm his older sister, Fujino.
I'm Kikuri.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Saeki.
Hello.
L-Look, Fuji-nee!
That boy's totally cute!
Uh-huh!
When'd you make friends
with this guy, Shou-chan?
He's a real man!
Uh-huh!
He's adorable!
Geez, what a pain.
Oh, Serika-oneechan.
Hmm? We have guests?
Serika-san, I finished washing the car.
I need you to come shopping with me, then.
I actually have yard work to do—
You can do it later!
I cannot.
It is part of my training.
I love it!
He's so hot!
I'm gonna make him mine!
Sorry...
I wish we had this much fun at my home.
It's just me and my dad.
I would never want to live here.
I think it's time to shave that head of yours.
Ugh, Dad!
Let's get going.
You wanna see Ugly, right?
Shouhei-kun must have a rough time at home.
Mi-chan.
What are you doing here, Mi-chan?
Come out.
Yumi-chan!
They can see your underwear!
This time, I'm really leaving!
I can't take any more of this!
I've had enough!
Come on, not again.
Calm down, Mi-chan.
You okay?
Seriously, what's wrong with your place?
Well, actually...
We've been getting visitors.
Huh?
Like this!
What?
I'm going home!
You mean ghosts?
Well, this is a temple, so it's not that weird.
You never told me about this!
It's not that unusual.
Yes, it is.
It's not.
Quit lying!
I'm not!
You are!
Now, now...
Sheesh.
I think it's time we left.
I feel the same way.
It's not like anyone's actually seen a ghost.
I've gotten used to it.
So what do you mean?
We've had stuff fall down during meditation,
and candles have gone out
when there wasn't any wind.
And the yard sometimes gets
messed up right after we clean it.
That's about it.
My old man said that this was
"just another part of Buddhist training."
It's possible that Ugly can see them.
This isn't funny!
Maybe you need to show
more respect for the dead!
That has nothing to do with it!
Why else would there be ghosts?!
Ghosts...
It's not my fault!
Right. Unlike shrines, people are laid to rest at temples.
Gintarou-sama, did you sense that?
Yes, I felt something.
Huh? There's a shrine over there.
How come? Isn't this a temple?
Oh, it's always been there.
We maintain the whole grounds,
but it's not that unusual to find a shrine in a temple.
Are you interested, Mako-chan?
You're a true shrine girl.
The gods and Buddhas used to be lumped together.
It's not that strange.
Back when the religions were mixed together?
What was that?
There it is again.
You can look around if you want.
Huh?
What do you mean?
What's wrong, Mi-chan?
Wait up, Mi-chan!
Yumi-chan?
Mi-chan, there's nothing to be scared of!
Gintarou, could that little shrine have...
The size of a shrine doesn't matter.
It looks like they're here...
and they like to play pranks.
Heralds!
Satoru, let's go look!
Good grief.
They see heralds every day.
It's starting to happen more and more often.
How did this fall over?
See that, Fuu-chan?
You bet, Fuku-chan!
What fun!
Silver  Fox
Check out the dumb looks on
those humans' faces, Fuku-chan!
They sure look dumb, Fuu-chan!
But something's not right.
Humans aren't supposed to be able to see us.
And look at that little weirdo.
Oh, there's also a big one.
Hey!
Get down here!
Who're you calling a little weirdo?!
What's going on?
F-Fuu-chan...
Fuku-chan...
I'm scared!
Hey, Gin. You're frightening them.
I haven't done a thing.
Haru.
But they were making fun of me!
Good grief.
Aren't you heralds?
Have you never spoken to a human before?
Are you a herald too, old-timer?
Old-timer...
You look totally different from us.
I'm a fox.
Oh, a fox!
We're monkeys!
Yep!
I can tell!
I know, Fuu-chan!
This is what Grandpa was talking about!
He said there were other types of heralds out there!
That's right! This is great!
It's our first time seeing one!
Yay!
Everything clear now?
They're responsible for that ghost business.
It doesn't look like there are any other humans around with the Sight.
Satisfied now?
Let's go home.
Huh? We can't go now!
We need to talk to them
and tell them to stop their pranks.
We're outsiders.
I think it's best if we don't interfere.
But...
You can stay behind by yourself, then!
Human! Human!
Can you see me?
Can you really see me?
Really?
Yup.
Are you leaving now?
So cute!
Yay!
Honestly...
Cute this, cute that.
Human women have no self-control.
No fair!
Fuu-chan gets all the fun!
Hey, am I cute? Am I?
S-Sure.
Yay!
Hey! Get your dirty mitts off Satoru!
What's this ribbon?
You don't deserve it!
My ribbon!
H-Haru, stay calm.
I'm mad now!
Gintarou, catch them!
We need to teach them a lesson!
Too much effort.
Get to it!
Now, now...
You're their elder, Haru-chan.
Funny face!
Hey, can you cut it—
Fox!
Scary face!
Ow!
If you're mad, follow us up here!
Kiss my butt!
Like you could!
Hey!
Nothing good ever happens when I leave the shrine.
What do we do, Gin?
Hold it right there!
There's no difference between human brats and herald brats.
Okay, Makoto.
Let's get this over with so we can go home.
You're fast, old-timer!
Amazing!
Get 'em, Gintarou!
Round 'em up and
show 'em who's boss!
That goes for you too.
Now cut it out!
Gin!
Keep your voice down, stupid!
S-Sorry...
Mi-chan, where are you?
Oh?
What's this?
Did I interrupt something?
It's not what you think!
Sorry!
Yumi-chan!
Gotcha!
We made her cry!
What is with today?
Man, I wanna go home.
Sorry, the altar fell over.
Didn't mean to scare everyone.
Oh, Shouhei.
I can't find Mi-chan anywhere.
Maybe she ran into the graveyard?
Let's look over there.
Grr!
Gintarou, hurry up and catch them!
I've done enough.
You need to calm down.
Fuu-chan, let's do it!
Ta-da!
What do you think you're doing?!
Ouch!
It was just the wind!
Oh, so you can control the wind.
Must come in handy for those pranks of yours.
Did they do that?
Hey, it's harder to play pranks
when humans are watching us.
They're a real pain.
Hey!
Heralds aren't supposed to play pranks!
Huh? Why not?
It's so much fun!
Everyone forgets about the sad things!
Everyone's happy!
Hey, are you gonna try to catch us?
That means the old-timer's it!
I don't have time to waste on you!
Hey! Wait up!
No way!
Stop running around!
Shut up, the lot of you!
I hate brats.
Stop! This isn't fair!
Let's play tag!
Haru!
Try and catch us!
Satoru!
I've had enough! Let's go home!
Are you okay, Haru-chan?
Stupid girl always has to meddle.
No more!
Honestly, it's like you're still in grade school.
Say, Satoru-kun...
Why do you think those heralds are playing pranks?
Because they think it's fun!
Why else would they do it?
But...
Their pranks are causing fights
and scaring people who think they're ghosts
when they're really heralds.
Haru-chan, would you want people to think you were a ghost?
No...
This place is a temple, there's no one with the Sight,
and they're still kids.
Maybe they've grown too far apart from humans.
Let's go talk to the chief priest.
He might know something.
Yeah.
We maintain this shrine right now,
but it was here when the temple was originally built,
and our temple is actually using the shrine grounds.
Really?
I already taught you that!
Long ago, there were many monkeys living around here.
That may be why the heralds for this shrine are monkey spirits.
When Shinto and Buddhism were separated, the temple was larger,
and the shrine was uninhabited, so it was left like this.
Well, I suppose that the temple grew so large
because it benefited from being near the shrine.
Monkeys are the symbol of victory.
Sacred monkeys are the key to victory.
So we're as grateful to have them as gods as we are to the Buddhas.
I'll go see if Mi-chan is in the graveyard.
We'll look over there, then.
There used to be lots of monkeys around.
Maybe they're lonely.
They may be trying to drive the humans away.
They used to live happily with their friends,
but once the temple was constructed, the monkeys had to leave.
I-It didn't look like they were trying to drive anyone away.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Heralds know their own history,
so this can happen when you have young heralds without humans who can see them.
There were humans I truly hated, too.
Why don't you ask them?
Let us go!
Gin.
We keep running away, but he still finds us!
Why?! Why?!
That's a secret.
What? Drive away the humans?
We don't wanna do that!
Then why are you playing pranks?!
Because the humans who come here all look so unhappy.
They're always crying and grieving.
It's too much for us to bear.
So we thought we could cheer them up by scaring them a little.
Wasn't it fun?
No!
Plus, that's what Grandpa said.
Grandpa?
The herald who used to be here.
But he's gone now...
Fuu, Fuku.
You don't need to be sad if the other monkeys stop coming.
They've merely been replaced by humans.
Many things will happen as more humans come,
but all you have to do is smile.
After all, we monkeys bring victory.
If you don't smile, nobody will win.
That's why we want to have fun!
Plus, there's a temple and a graveyard around.
We're going to live a long time,
so we have to watch over this place for the humans, the other monkeys, and Grandpa.
That's our job.
Well, I guess we might have taken the pranks a bit too far.
We're sorry.
But you were trying to cheer everyone up, right?
Yeah!
Humans know how to pick themselves back up.
Yep, so you don't need to play pranks anymore.
What? That's no fun!
We like scaring humans!
It's what we live for!
We can't stop!
H-Hey!
What? Monkey heralds?
You're a big fan of the occult, huh?
But I like the idea that the gods were playing pranks.
It bodes well for our temple.
I don't see anything wrong with having a monkey spirit or two around.
We already have plenty of monkeys as it is.
Is she talking about us?
We should be grateful that the gods have
joined the Buddha in blessing this temple.
Bye-bye!
I'm worried about them.
We should probably check on them every once in a while.
It'll be fine.
They didn't mean any harm.
Shouhei-kun's family didn't seem to mind, either.
That's good.
You're a fool.
They don't believe that heralds exist.
That's not important.
It's our job to serve as a bridge between heralds and humans.
Still, I thought it was interesting.
Fuu-chan and Fuku-chan didn't seem to differentiate between the temple and the shrine.
The Japanese gods are wonderful.
Yeah, the Japanese gods are about as irresponsible as it gets.
You should say that they're big-hearted.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
Heralds serve as
messengers of the gods.
There are foxes, monkeys, rabbits, turtles, crows,
and lots of other kinds.
Next time: "Humans Are Strange."
Humans Are Strange
May fortune be with you.