Men!
Clean hit. Point awarded.
Did you see that?
That was so cool!
Bow.
But you know...
What? Saeki-san and Kamio-kun?
Yep, they live together!
Why...
Why is this happening?
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
How Do I Look?
How come everyone knows?
We asked him where he lived.
And he told us...
The Saeki shrine.
That's your home, right?
U-Um...
He's a family friend who's staying with us.
He transferred to this school because he practices kendo.
Oh, that makes sense.
Our school does well every year,
and Kamio-kun's already a starter on our team.
He's like a modern-day dashing swordsman.
I know, right?
Give me a break.
The transfer student next door certainly seems to be popular.
Is he as handsome as Ikegami-san was hoping?
Are you interested in him, Funabashi-san?
No, not especially.
But I heard that his grades are good as well.
Sounds like he can do everything.
Saeki!
Yumi-chan.
This is awkward.
How do I bring up Yumi-chan's proposal?
Thank you for the meal.
Oh, you don't need to do that.
You washed the dishes last night, after all.
It's Makoto's turn.
O-Okay.
Satoru-kun, I can do it.
Excuse me.
Satoru-kun, you should take a bath.
You must be tired after practice.
I'll go last.
Please let me know when you're done.
Come on, Dad.
You'll make him uncomfortable if you keep bugging him.
But he always goes straight to his room when he comes home.
He's pulling an Amaterasu-sama on us.
You know how she hid in the Ama-no-Iwato?
He'll get used to living here eventually.
But he's acting the same way at school, right?
The girls were making a fuss because
he's good at kendo and a good student.
Oh, Dad. So, tomorrow...
It's a smaller shrine, but I like how much quieter it is.
Yeah.
Tatsuo is a nice guy.
Makoto talks too much.
Yeah.
Satoru, you just keep saying "Yeah."
Are you listening to me?
I am.
Man, you're all over him.
It's mortifying.
Quiet!
Ugly! Fatty!
Hey, Haru!
Wait, what are you doing?
It's your turn, Gintarou-sama.
Don't bother. I don't like
people doing that kind of stuff.
That won't do.
You represent this shrine.
It's okay, really.
I can't accept that.
It's okay!
You kicked Satoru!
F-Forgive me for offending you.
Apologize!
Apologize to Satoru!
Hey, what are you doing, Gin?
Makoto doesn't mind when I'm rough with her...
That hurts! Stop it!
But I don't know how to deal with this kid.
You don't have to apologize every time.
It's not worth the time.
You should probably put that effort toward getting to know other humans instead.
I-I've been trying my best.
Satoru-kun!
Look, there's the noisy girl.
Get some practice.
Sorry about making you help out.
Are you missing practice?
It's not a big deal.
I helped out at home, too.
Shrine work is more important than kendo.
So, Satoru-kun, do you have any plans after this?
Why?
Hey! What are you up to?!
N-Nothing!
Hey, walk on the left!
Did you forget what they taught us?
They said that, huh?
They're already here?
Yo!
Saeki, we're here!
Wow, you're both wearing kimonos!
We were performing a
purification this morning.
Oh, really?
This should be fun.
More noisy girls around.
Um, I don't believe you've met them before, Satoru-kun.
These are my classmates.
Ikegami Yumi.
Funabashi Hiwako.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I'm Kamio.
Um, we're throwing a welcome party for you today.
So you really are living at Saeki's place.
What's with that stupid girl?!
Hey, let go of me!
I'm gonna curse her!
You can't curse anyone.
You see how annoyed he looks?
This is a good opportunity for him
to get used to being around humans.
You probably realize that he can't go on like this.
He may be able to see us,
but he lives in the human world, not ours.
Hmph! What do you know?
Satoru got used to putting up walls
because of the people he was living with.
He knows what he has to do,
but it's hard to change.
Ah, that's nice.
I'll always be there for him.
But I know it's not good for him.
So I'll restrain myself today!
I'm not doing this because you told me to!
Yeah, yeah.
I thought you'd be taller.
You're the same height as me?
Yu-Yumi-chan!
I mean, he's shorter than Funabashi.
That bitch!
I thought you said you'd restrain yourself.
Oh. Welcome, girls.
You're wearing a kimono too!
I have a ground-breaking ceremony to attend.
U-Um, thank you for having us over.
Please accept this small token of our appreciation.
Oh? Why, thank you.
Well, I'll be back as soon as I can.
Okay. Bye!
Funabashi-san?
I always found it odd that you
weren't interested in any guys at school.
So that's why.
You don't like immature boys, huh?
I-It's not like that!
I knew something was up.
You were so eager to come along, after all.
You like dads?
Stop it! You're being rude!
Satoru-kun?
I'm grateful for the welcome party,
but I don't enjoy loud celebrations.
Sorry for going ahead with this without asking you first.
But everybody's here, and Dad's all excited.
Let me know when everything's ready.
Man, he's no fun at all.
I didn't get the chance to tell him yesterday.
What?! You didn't tell him?
Isn't this your fault, Ikegami-san?
Huh? What'd I do?
Whatever. Let's go shopping.
My dad left a list.
Lots of snacks!
Well then, let's welcome Satoru-kun!
Cheers!
You're such a good cook, Mr. Saeki.
I couldn't have done it without you all.
And then you have...
I-I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
It's a little burnt, but it still tastes good.
Anyway, you kids should live it up!
How's the food, Satoru-kun?
I-It's good.
So you listen to Mr. Saeki.
When's your birthday, Satoru-kun?
Yes, we'll want to celebrate.
Anyway, you were all wearing kimonos today.
They sure looked nice.
I've only worn yukatas before.
Would you like to try one on tomorrow?
Oh? Can I?
That's a good idea.
Do you think I'll look weird?
What should I do?
Kamio!
Let's party together!
Won't you join us for a bit?
Thank you.
But I've had enough fun for one night.
You girls can enjoy yourselves.
Oh, okay. Thanks for putting up with us today.
We can't force him into anything.
All right, shall we go upstairs?
Oh, Satoru!
Welcome back!
Did you have fun?
Yeah.
Are you studying?
Yeah. There's a test coming up.
Hey, stop it!
That hurts!
That hurts, Ikegami-san.
They're so noisy.
Well, unlike someone else I know.
Yeah.
What do you mean?
What's that supposed to mean, Ikegami-san?!
They're so loud!
How can they keep giggling on and on?!
If you're curious, you can go look.
You'll only get bored here.
You're free to do what you want, after all.
I'm staying here.
I never get bored with you around.
They wanted to throw you a welcome party, right?
Yeah.
Doesn't that make you happy, Satoru?
It made me happy when Seigo was nice to me.
Hey, Grandpa Matsu. Why did you tell Satoru to take it easy?
He looks like he's having fun when he's with us.
You see, Satoru has been forced
to put up walls so he can stay here.
That just shows that this isn't where he belongs.
It's tiring and lonely for him.
But he has us.
That's true, but we are heralds, while Satoru is human.
I've spent a long time watching humans,
and if I've learned anything, it's that they belong with other humans.
But when you put up walls, you can't see other people,
and they can't see you.
So he needs to bring down
those walls and take it easy.
He may be able to see us, but he lives in the human world, not ours.
I'm not sure...
I wasn't able to tell them
my birthday when they asked.
The only days I remember are the days my parents and grandfather died.
Haru.
How do I look right now?
Silver  Fox
You look the same as always.
Really...
Satoru, if you're happy, you should show it.
It's not that hard.
You just have to look the way you do when you're with me.
Then everyone will like you more.
I'm such an idiot.
I'm making Haru worry about me again.
This is getting boring.
We should go to bed.
It's only 11 o'clock.
Anyway, what's Kamio doing?
He's probably studying.
Seriously?
People like that need their own space.
But when someone resists, it just makes me want to mess with them more.
That's why cats are fun.
Oh, I know what you mean.
Stop it, Makoto!
Oh, well.
Ikegami-san, where are you going?
You need to ask?
Satoru?
Sorry, Haru.
I understand.
They threw the party for my sake.
I'm happy that they made the effort.
I'll try to express myself better from now on.
Really? You don't have to do anything you don't want to.
Yes, I know.
Why are they so loud?
Excuse us!
Wh-What are you doing?
I want to know more about you.
Let's chat a bit.
Sorry, Haru-chan.
Ikegami-san, this is...
Wow, you really are studying.
What's this problem?
What?! He's already up to these?!
That reminds me.
So, when's your birthday?
S-September 23rd.
Hey!
Stop that girl!
Th-This might be a good chance for Satoru-kun to get to know them.
It's just making things worse!
What's your blood type?
I'm guessing it's B.
A.
And you're the same height as me, right?
Cut it out!
Give that back!
Why do you want to know more about me?
You're a transfer student.
People want to know these things.
See?! Now stop her!
I can't do anything about this.
Forget it. Have it your way.
I've never seen kendo gear close up before.
U-Um...
Could you show me your notes?
That's a nice shot of you getting cozy.
What?! You shouldn't take pictures without consent!
It doesn't hurt anyone.
Anyway, we should get going.
Yeah! Leave!
Oh, so this is what kendo gear looks like.
What's going on?
Don't change the subject!
Why did this happen?
No, I'm sure they're doing this for my sake.
I was a little happy when they came.
Happy?
Really?
Are they really doing this to help me?
I keep telling them that I don't want them to bother me.
And I'm supposed to just put up with it?
Be quiet!
Ow! What was that for?!
I'm the one asking questions here!
What are you girls trying to do?!
Quit taking notes!
Quit taking pictures!
Quit touching my stuff!
S-Satoru...
I said that I don't like too much noise!
Don't you realize that you're bothering me?!
P-Plus...
Plus...
I can still grow taller!
S-Sorry.
Er, uh...
I didn't realize you were sensitive about your height.
I'm sorry.
That's right, Ikegami-san.
You kept bringing up that sore subject.
I said that I'm sorry.
Huh? Why are you laughing?
Sorry.
I don't think that's the reason Satoru-kun is mad, though.
But it's our fault, right?
Wait, it's because...
I feel really stupid.
Sorry.
We weren't trying to bother you.
We just want to become friends.
That's right. You should have seen how we started with Funabashi.
Ikegami-san!
So we should take this opportunity to talk.
The welcome party doesn't end
until the day's over!
Is that okay?
I guess I can't stop you.
I suppose I can humor you today.
Really?
Yay!
Let's move the table to the middle of the room.
Sorry, Haru-chan.
Huh?
How'd it go?
It was absolutely horrible.
Those girls are crazy!
So you couldn't fall asleep after being left alone, little kid?
No way!
But I've never seen Satoru act like that.
It's gonna keep happening.
I don't care if he belongs with the humans instead of with us.
But you look pretty lonely,
so I guess I can keep you company.
I appreciate it.
You all look happy.
Good morning!
We only just went to sleep, you know.
I have bags under my eyes. It's embarrassing.
How do I look, Mr. Saeki?
You would all make wonderful shrine maidens.
Otomatsu-sama is his name.
Huh?
The name of Haru's partner.
He's an old fox spirit who gave me some advice before I left.
He told me to take it easy.
Take it easy...
You girls kind of forced me to relax last night.
I'd like to meet Otomatsu-sama.
I'm sure you'll get the chance.
Should I buy a charm?
Should I get one for good grades?
We have midterms coming up.
You're that desperate?
You're not supposed to buy charms for yourself.
They're more effective when they're given as presents.
Didn't you know that?
Oh, really?
I feel like you're talking down to us.
Take these.
Academic
As thanks for the party.
Fortune
I'll pay for them.
Thanks!
Charms are more effective if you care
about the person you're giving them to.
Oh, does that mean you care about us?
I'm glad to hear that!
Hello!
Makoto-oneechan!
Aki-chan! Sacchan!
Yo.
Oh, it's the lady who likes cats!
How's Mi-chan doing?
She's doing great!
Oh? I don't know the other lady.
And there's a guy I don't know.
He's a new family member.
Be nice to him.
Hi there.
We live nearby.
N-Nice to meet you.
Oh, there are lots of cute shrine maidens here today.
Welcome, Granny.
Good morning!
Okay, let's pay our respects!
Let's! Let's!
We're here to thank the fox spirit.
Our recital went well.
This shrine is completely different from mine.
Shrines are all the same.
Perhaps.
I'm sure that our shrine was the same.
It's just that I never noticed.
That's not a big deal.
Most people never notice.
Kamio! Let's take a picture!
Excuse me.
What were you talking to Gin about?
Nothing important.
I was just saying that this shrine is a nice place.
I'm looking forward to staying here.
I'm glad to be here.
Yep, glad to have you!
It's so cute.
Isn't it?
You look great!
How do I look right now?
You look like you're having fun.
It looks like he's left the Ama-no-Iwato.
Oh? What do you mean?
Mr. Saeki!
You should get in the picture!
You too, Granny!
What? Can I?
Oh my...
Yeah, another day of peace and quiet.
Okay, say cheese!
Cheese!
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
Yumi here!
Do you know the difference
between a shrine and a temple?
You see...
Actually, I don't know either!
Shrines and Temples
Next time: "Shrines and Temples."
May fortune be with you.