Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Season of Warmth
Come on, hurry up!
Gintarou, did Haru-chan come back?
Nope.
See? What do we do now?
Let go of my arm.
I'm not going anywhere.
Oh, sorry.
Hey, you know that heralds will disappear if they're away from their shrine for too long, right?
I told you that kid would be trouble.
Heralds shouldn't get so emotionally attached.
I'm sorry.
I had a feeling this might happen.
Haru is a relatively young herald.
There's another herald at our shrine.
Haru should not have left him behind.
That kid isn't the only one who left someone behind.
W-Well...
Don't you get tired of being so uptight?
You need to learn to take it easy.
This girl's an heir to a shrine, yet look at her.
Huh? Me?
Heralds have their own minds.
They do what they want.
If they get sick of it all, they'll leave.
That's happened before, hasn't it?
So if the kid wants out, let 'em go.
Don't make this my responsibility.
Hey there!
Persimmon
What?
Another fox spirit?
And that's the only surprise?
You can really see them?
No wonder you kids hit it off so quick.
I see how it is.
I'm the only one who can't see them, huh?
I feel so alone.
Sorry about this.
I'm thrilled about the new family member,
so why do the two of you
look like someone died?
Oh, is that what Gintarou-sama said?
Yeah.
Gin doesn't seem to like Haru-chan.
He doesn't want the responsibility.
Huh?
Our doors are open.
No, I believe that I'm the one Gintarou-sama is upset with.
In any case, I'll be sending Haru back.
I apologize for the trouble I've caused.
Can you stop doing that?!
We need to worry about finding Haru-chan before we talk about sending anyone back!
Now, now, Makoto.
Sit down.
Your father and I went to the same college.
I never got to meet him, but we had the same teacher.
Tahara-sensei...
Yes, I believe he was friends with your grandfather.
That's right.
He's been helping me out.
I recall that your family's shrine has been around for about 1,200 years, right?
Your aunt and uncle are running it right now, if I'm not mistaken.
Ah.
If you can see Haru-sama, you must be the successor.
When did you inherit the Sight?
I was four.
I was... five.
Satoru,
this is an Inari shrine, which means there are fox spirits around.
Where?
You'll meet them soon.
Don't worry.
I'll keep you safe.
Father...
It's only been two years since my brother's accident.
He was pushing himself too hard.
Satoru-kun, there's nothing to worry about.
We'll take care of everything.
He has the same eyes as that brother I could never stand!
Don't say that.
Honestly, why did Father have to leave a will?
We're the ones managing the shrine.
Clearly, one of our children should inherit it!
Hey, Sayaka. You're too loud.
Satoru-kun.
Y-Yes?
I decided to take you in because it was a request from my teacher.
However, you seem a little too responsible for someone the same age as Makoto.
It's rather unfortunate.
Yes, it's unfortunate.
If you'd like, you're free to consider this shrine your new home.
Or something like that.
Sorry, I can be a bit meddlesome at times.
Now, don't you need to go look for Haru-sama?
But Gin said to leave Haru-chan alone.
He doesn't want the responsibility.
Aren't you always saying how Gintarou likes to be contrary?
That certainly sounds like something he would say.
Does he mean that they should figure it out themselves?
Yes. I'm guessing that Gintarou-sama's point
is that it's down to whether Satoru-kun wants to be with Haru-sama or not—simple as that.
Fortunately, our shrine is also an Inari shrine,
so the two of you can stay here together if you want.
It hurts to be separated when all you want is to be together.
W-Wait, Satoru-kun?!
I'm leaving.
Where are you going?
Satoru, I'm coming with you!
You can't.
I wanna be with you!
You are the fox spirit here.
You must remain in my place.
I'm not going to succeed the shrine.
I'll live on my own.
Satoru...
I'm sorry, Haru!
Hold on. You won't find Haru-chan by running around on your own.
This is all my fault!
I'll find Haru by myself!
Let's ask Gin, then.
Gintarou can divine where people and objects are.
Satoru-kun!
Just leave them alone, you nosy idiot.
What?!
Like I said, heralds have their own issues.
Humans are no different, right?
I guess...
Then let them be.
Besides, you should probably be here when that kid comes back,
since I'm staying out of this business.
Huh?
W-Wait, Gin!
Come on!
Jeez!
Silver  Fox
Haru-sama!
Oh, you're outside.
Have a look.
My grandson just left the hospital today.
He's so small!
Though it hasn't been that long since you were his size.
Please, have mercy on me.
So this is your grandson.
We've named him Satoru.
He will be the 77th successor.
Satoru...
Look, Tougo! Satoru can see me!
No, he can't see you yet.
He's looking right at me!
So you're Satoru.
Satoru...
They still aren't back.
Should I go look for them?
You didn't find Haru-chan?
I thought I could live on my own now,
but I can't do anything after all.
Then ask Gin for help.
I'm already imposing on you and Tatsuo-san.
I can't ask Gintarou-sama for more help.
It's all because I'm just a child.
How stupid are you?!
It doesn't matter if you're a child or not!
What matters is that you're human!
Nobody can live on their own!
What's wrong with asking the gods for help?!
Gin!
Look for Haru-chan!
Stop pretending to be asleep!
You know, you're not asking the gods for help. You're asking me.
Please!
Hey, you need to learn some self-restraint.
Please help.
I knew deep down that I couldn't do anything on my own.
I was running away from that fact.
If we have to be separated, I thought separating sooner would be less painful for Haru—
or rather, I thought it would be less painful for me.
Haru's always been there for me,
even when I came here.
That really made me glad.
If possible, I want to spend more time with Haru!
I see you've opened up quite a bit.
Damn. Guess I can't refuse, then.
I've never searched for a herald before,
so I don't know if this will work.
It's a goner.
Make sure you clean yourself off.
Foxes can carry disease.
I'll give it a proper burial.
But it's not your fox, is it?
I live in an Inari shrine.
Kamio Shrine
Oh, you must be that fox.
It appears that you've become a herald.
A herald?
Oh, dear. It appears that Seigo brought you here.
My partner passed away last month.
And before I know it, a new one arrives.
Funny how things work out.
What's he doing?
He's making a grave for you.
It's a cherry blossom tree.
Come spring, it'll be in full bloom.
What's spring?
A season of warmth.
Warmth...
My name is Otomatsu.
What's yours?
I understand.
That boy will inherit this shrine.
He can't see us right now,
but he will some day.
When the time comes,
you should name yourself Haru, for "spring."
Haru...
Tougo, don't go.
Otomatsu-sama.
Haru-sama.
Once I'm gone,
please take care of the shrine...
Please take care of Satoru.
Satoru.
I'm Haru.
Haru?
Could you just make up your mind?
It's not that simple.
Satoru, don't be sad.
I'm here for you.
Am I going to disappear?
I guess it doesn't matter if I can't be with Satoru.
Tougo, I'm sorry I couldn't keep my promise.
Haru!
Haru.
Sa—
Satoru, I'm sorry I've been bothering you.
So I'll just...
You're not...
You're not bothering... me.
Haru...
I'm... sorry.
Satoru!
I'm sorry I said all those things!
We did the right thing.
Oh? Shouldn't you be all,
"Aww, isn't it beautiful?"
at this point?
Since when do I do that?
And I'm not sure.
I mean...
Heralds shouldn't get so emotionally attached.
They can't be together forever, after all.
Why worry about the future?
You're the ones who do as you please and live in the moment.
Gin...
They still have some growing up to do, as do you.
Wait a few years and they'll find an answer.
Right.
Then it's okay for now.
For now...
Man, I was getting a little worried.
This is wonderful news.
Then let's celebrate our new family!
It's a pleasure...
Glad to have you...
So, Haru-chan?
Where's Haru-chan?
Over here?
Or over there?
Oh, I shouldn't say Haru-chan.
Haru-sama would be more appropriate.
Well, you'd use Haru-chan if you could see.
What's that mean?!
Sorry, I should stop calling you Haru-chan.
How about Haru-kun?
I'm a girl!
What?!
I don't believe this!
I'm sorry!
This is outrageous!
I haven't seen Haru having this much fun before.
What about you?
We won't leave you alone, Otomatsu-sama.
I'll talk to Haru.
Oh, don't worry about me.
Haru is still young.
She should go out and see the world.
I'm old now.
I'll stay and see what happens to this shrine.
And the people who can't see me.
Satoru, you are very similar to Seigo.
My great-grandfather?
That's probably why Haru thinks of you as...
Well, it's not important.
Take it easy, Satoru.
Satoru, this girl's a lost cause!
What?
My name is Makoto!
Take it easy...
Hey, girl!
Don't stare at Satoru!
What? What?
Man, it's so noisy...
You both have school tomorrow.
Thank you for everything.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
Heralds are messengers from the gods...
Hey, girl!
You know nothing about heralds!
S-Sorry, Haru-chan!
How Do I Look?
Next time: How Do I Look?
May fortune be with you.