Hey, Kinjirou. You serious about this?
Yeah. Don't try to stop me.
Well, I wasn't planning to.
Where will you go?
No idea. I haven't thought that far ahead.
I am powerless to help the people who come here with their wishes and concerns.
And after decades and centuries of watching time pass by,
I've grown tired.
You need to take it easy.
Let those humans say whatever they want.
They don't believe in the gods,
and they can't see us.
You're wrong.
It's easier for them to be honest when speaking to someone they can't see.
Hmph. I guess you've grown attached to the humans after watching them for so long,
but you really shouldn't waste your time.
That's not how you truly feel, Gintarou.
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
The Place Where the Gods Are
I've been thinking.
About what?
What are you doing here?
Got a problem with that?
Now, now...
Oh, hey, Funabashi-san.
Did you get in trouble for staying at my place?
No, nothing happened.
I haven't talked to my mother since then, though.
It's nothing you need to worry about.
It wasn't your fault, and I feel much better now.
Yeah! You show her!
Anyway, back to what I was saying.
What's this?
It's a map of modern Shinto City.
And this is a map of Shinto City in the Edo period.
So?
You can see that there are castles, shrines, and temples that have survived.
Including Saeki's home.
Uh huh. Our shrine's been around since the beginning of the Edo period.
When I visited your home, it made me think:
We all go to the same school and spend most of our time together right now,
but we'll eventually graduate and go our separate ways.
And yet, there are some things in our lives
that haven't changed in hundreds and thousands of years.
Isn't that fascinating?
That's an interesting way of looking at it.
Huh? Really?
Our shrine started off as a small altar surrounded by farms.
Every year, they would use the glowing lights lit by fox spirits
to divine how the upcoming year's harvest would fare.
That was how it all began.
In the Edo period, to improve harvests,
a feudal lord built the shrine that's there today.
Inari is the god of agriculture, after all.
That's a fascinating story.
That's right...
Our shrine's watched over a lot of people over the years.
And I'm sure it will for many more.
But it's not like the castles and shrines themselves can remember anyone.
Now, now...
Ishii, when did those three get so friendly with each other?
The rumors about Funabashi and the student council president were just that, too.
We totally embarrassed ourselves.
Funabashi-san's interest gets piqued by some strange things.
Gin! Gintarou!
Look! A turtle!
It's pretty heavy.
I found it at the bottom of the stairs.
It wasn't moving, so I brought it with me.
Say, is Dad around?
Hey, Makoto...
Oh, Makoto! Welcome home!
Look, Dad!
I found a turtle on the way home.
Did it get lost?
A turtle?
Where is it?
What do you mean, "where?"
It's right here.
That's a herald, you fool.
What?!
Honestly...
Can't you tell a herald apart from a normal turtle?
That's just sad.
Well, this is only the second herald I've ever met!
Hey, wake up.
Oh, there he goes.
Wow, there are all kinds of heralds.
Of course.
Lion-dogs are the most common, though,
since they're considered sacred animals.
This is the first time I've ever spoken to a human.
You didn't come from another shrine?
P-Pardon me...
Could I trouble you for some water?
Oh, sure!
That hits the spot!
So why were you lying on the road?
You see...
I lived in the small shrine by the lake beyond the mountains.
But as time passed, our shrine was forgotten and began to fall apart.
Then they tore up the lake and shrine to build new roads.
I had no choice but to set off on a journey to find a new home.
It was a long and grueling trip, and I just couldn't go on.
The lake he's talking about is just over in the next town.
Well, he is a turtle.
Now that I have nowhere to go,
perhaps I should curse the humans who did this to me!
Well, that thought had crossed my mind,
but I'm not that powerful, so I gave up.
Plus, it would require effort.
Yeah, a wise decision.
Besides, the shrine was built for protection from droughts and floods,
but now they say that the lake's a drowning hazard for children
Well, at least he'll recover sacred energy while on the shrine grounds.
and that the new road will make life easier for everybody.
Sacred energy?
If a herald leaves his shrine for an extended period of time,
his power drains away.
Oh...
Why'd they even build the shrine in the first place, then?
Well, we'll have to ask him to leave soon.
Why?!
This is an Inari shrine.
Goodness, when did humans turn into such ungrateful monsters?
He's a herald for a different god.
He won't be able to make a full recovery here.
And dogs kept barking at me...
Are you listening to me?
Oh, a turtle herald?
That's amazing.
Is he over there?
E-Er, who might this be?
Oh, this is my dad.
He's the chief priest here.
I appreciate the hospitalit—
A turtle, huh?
I used to see a lot of turtles
around when I was a kid.
You'd find them on roads near rivers.
Whenever a car hit one, the shell would explode like fireworks.
D-Dad!
Anyway, are there any shrines nearby with turtle heralds?
I believe that turtles can be found at branches of the Matsunoo Grand Shrine in Kyoto, right?
If you go past the station,
I believe you'll find Shoubai Grand Shrine, which has a Matsunoo altar in the back.
Oh, that's the place with the lion-dogs.
You know where it is, Gin?
I've been in the area before.
Is it okay if we take you to a small altar instead of a full shrine?
I believe they have a lake there.
Okay! Let's get going!
It'll have to wait until tomorrow.
The pain...
Um, are you okay, Mr. Turtle?
Is this better?
Yes, it feels wonderful.
Seriously, this is one high-maintenance turtle.
O-Oh, I've been wondering...
Where might your partner be?
His name is Kinjirou, right?
You said he left a long time ago?
I-Is that so?
Gin, aren't you lonely without Kinjirou around?
Not really.
Feels like it was just yesterday that he left.
But I guess it has been a pretty long time.
I completely forgot.
I understand what you mean.
When you've lived for this long, your memory starts to go.
I can't even remember what the weather was like yesterday.
Um, I don't think that's quite the same.
Hey, Makoto!
The bath's ready for you!
Okay!
Well, good night, Mr. Turtle.
Good night.
Silver  Fox
Let's go, Gin.
Why do I have to come with you?
He's pretty heavy.
Come on. You can think of it as a date.
S-Sorry about this.
Then get off.
Okay, let's go!
Man, dates are a pain.
The castle's still around?
Any fond memories?
No.
I'm starting to understand what Funabashi-san meant, though.
Some things in our lives have been watching over us for hundreds or thousands of years.
How stupid.
It's not like a castle remembers anything.
That's what Yumi-chan said.
Come on, kitty. Over here.
Hey, aren't we supposed to be catching a movie?!
Hey! You scared it away!
You got plenty of petting time before we left my place.
Isn't that ugly cat good enough for you?
You better not be giving Mi-chan a hard time.
Why would I do that?!
Listen to this!
The other day, she came into my room and peed on my guitar!
So what?
You hardly use it anyway, just like everything else you pick up!
I'm sure you'll like the shrine.
Say what?!
I hope the lake is clean.
We'll come visit you once you've settled in.
Saeki!
Yumi-chan?
Where are you headed?
I need to stop by Shoubai Grand Shrine.
Oh, there's a flea market there right now!
I'll come with you!
Huh?
But...
What about your boyfriend, Shouhei-kun?
Don't worry about him.
I'm sure you don't wanna go alone!
Wow! It's so big!
Wait, haven't you been here before?
Only when I was little.
Right, you live at a shrine.
There are a lot of priests around.
Wow, what a hottie!
Can he see you, Gin?
If he's a true successor, he can.
Anyway, let's get this over with.
Right...
Yumi-chan, I have some business to take care of, so you can browse through the flea market.
What's this? Something's up.
Are you hiding something from me?
I-I'm not hiding anything!
Mind your manners.
These creatures are over a thousand years old.
R-Right.
There we go.
Um, Gin?
What's got you so worried?
You told me to mind my manners.
Hey! Are you geezers around?
Hello?
Who's there?
Keep it down.
Lion-dogs!
Good grief. Guess you're home.
Oh, you're back again.
Yo.
Did you get in another fight with your priest?
I'm here for a different reason today.
Has it been three days since we last spoke, Righty?
It's been seven days, Lefty.
Really? Seven days?
Oof.
No sleeping!
Oh my...
Oh, you're a priest?
This young lass is a priest?
Um, I'm not a priest just yet...
It can't be easy, possessing the Sight at such a young age.
Plus, you're stuck with this fool of a fox.
Who are you calling a fool?
E-Excuse me...
Oh?
I-I have a request to make.
Could you please help us?
Could you please let this turtle stay at the altar here?
I said no sleeping!
We don't see a problem with that.
He can make himself at home.
There's plenty of room.
Thank you very much!
Isn't that great, Mr. Turtle?
Ow... I can't breathe...
Is this okay?
Of course!
The altar is nearby and there's a lake.
It doesn't get any better than this.
And you're the ones who made it all possible.
I'm glad to hear that.
I've recovered enough energy to talk a little faster now.
Doesn't seem any faster to me.
Ah...
Well, I'll go look for Yumi-chan.
Sure.
Young lass! Young lass!
Righty and Lefty!
The turtle is thrilled about his new home.
Thank you very much!
That's good to hear,
but could you stop calling us Righty and Lefty?
Those are just nicknames we use for each other.
Huh?
My actual name is Saimaru.
I'm Utamaru.
Saimaru-san and Utamaru-san.
Those are cool names!
You sound like old-style comedians.
Are you twins?
No, I'm slightly older.
In most cases, we're born without names.
So I'm the one who named him.
See the silly look on his face?
Yep! It's cute!
You think he's cute?
That's not very respectful.
I'm starting to see why you and that fox had a spat.
Huh?
Er.
I-I'm sorry!
Oh, don't worry about it.
It's been a long time since we've
had the chance to talk to a human.
Thank you, young lass.
O-Oh...
I should thank you for welcoming the turtle.
Er, wait...
The turtle spirit...
No need to thank us.
I've had no one but my partner
to talk to all this time,
so it'll be more fun with a new resident.
When we were young, there were more humans who could see us,
but there aren't so many these days.
It's very rare to see a young one like you.
What about the chief priest here?
The chief priest is a true successor,
but his predecessor is still alive, so he can't see us.
The previous chief priest has grown old and gone into retirement.
He's very weak now.
I never wanted to see him in that state.
Oh...
It may be hard for a young person like you to understand,
but when you live as long as we do, time passes in the blink of an eye.
The lifespan of a human is very brief in our eyes.
We meet a priest we like, and then he dies before we even know it.
We've experienced many farewells over the centuries.
And as time goes on,
we can no longer remember the faces of the priests we were close to.
It's rather sad.
That fox may not want to admit it,
but he's enjoying his time with you.
Gin, aren't you lonely without Kinjirou around?
Not really.
Feels like it was just yesterday that he left.
But I guess it has been a pretty long time.
I completely forgot.
Hey!
That's enough outta you guys.
Oops!
Seriously, don't get carried away just because you have a young girl to talk to.
My apologies.
Foxes have sharp ears.
Let's go, Makoto.
'Kay.
Goodbye, Makoto-chan.
Come visit us again.
Sure! I'll be back!
Bye!
Fool.
Don't believe what those lion-dogs said.
That hurts.
I'm going to die before you do.
Yeah, that goes without saying.
But stuff like that doesn't bother you,
so you'll forget about me in no time!
I couldn't forget about a stupid girl like you,
even if I wanted to.
There you are!
Shoubai                             Grand Shrine
Jeez, where did you go?
Sorry.
Anyway, I found a place with these cute cat accessories!
More cat stuff?
Shut up!
This way!
Gin.
Let's go! Our date's not over yet!
Hold on!
This way!
Yeah, dates sure are a pain.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
When you see a pair of
lion-dogs at a shrine,
they typically have different faces.
Take a closer look next time.
Satoru and Haru
Next time: "Satoru and Haru."
May fortune be with you.