Who the hell are you?!
They call me Murakami Zanzou, the Executioner.
I shall send you to Hell.
Hosokawa-sama!
Kill him!
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iou kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Makoto's Future
Ah, Okawa Shigeto is so cool!
Did you enjoy it, Gin?
Yeah. The same thing happens every episode.
Dad.
Hmm?
Gin says the same thing happens every episode.
But that's the best thing about it.
I know.
I borrowed the movie, so we can watch it.
Gintarou-sama should enjoy this.
Huh?!
Don't you need to prepare for the cleansing ceremony, Dad?
I've finished everything that I can do today.
No! You have to go pick up the thatch tomorrow!
Go to bed!
You've grown harsh.
When you were little, you used to say,
"I'm gonna be your bride when I grow up!"
When did I say that?
This can't be...
Hey, don't make Tatsuo cry.
It'll be annoying.
S-Sorry, Dad.
Well, Zanzou's over, so I should get going.
Gin, you said that it's the same thing every time, but you still enjoy it.
Still, a bride, huh...
I'm okay with any job that lets me work with animals.
I'm going to college.
I'm thinking about becoming a chef or nutritionist.
I need to worry about what I'm doing after high school first.
I was talking with my classmates the other day,
and I was surprised
that they'd all put thought into it.
Is there anything you want to do?
Huh?
I got to choose what to do with my life.
Your mother had a lot of things she still wanted to do,
but she had no choice but to take over this shrine.
She said that she wanted you to be able to choose.
So I think you should do what you want,
and if you fall in love, you can get married.
I'll support you, no matter what you decide.
Oh, Gin. You were here?
Hey, turn the lights off.
You were awake anyway.
What? You're creeping me out.
Hey, Gin...
I wanted to become a shrine maiden like Mom used to be.
But I can barely remember what she was like.
So I think I just wanted to know what my mom was like.
Oh, you want to talk about your future.
Humans spend a lot of time on that topic these days.
If you want to know about Yuuko, ask Tatsuo.
Dad has a biased view.
I was talking to him earlier.
He told me to do what I want to do.
That's great, then.
Say, did Mom want to become a shrine maiden?
Did she want to become one?
It was more like it was the only choice she had.
She had health problems
and couldn't spend much time outside.
Does that mean she never got to realize her dreams?
I wouldn't say that.
She married Tatsuo despite objections from everyone around her.
Wait, what?
People didn't want Mom and Dad to get married?
Pretty much.
I wanted to become a shrine maiden because that was what Mom was.
I wanted to know what Mom used to do.
I still think shrine maidens are special and important servants of the gods.
But it's not the same now.
I didn't want to be a shrine maiden.
I just wanted...
to be like Mom.
I'm getting sick of thinking about this.
I wish you could divine my future for me.
Hey, don't act like a spoiled brat.
You're so mean.
Well, I wouldn't be able to do it, anyway.
Really?
For some reason, I can't see
the futures of those with the Sight.
Well, I don't care to find out when someone I know is going to die, so it doesn't matter.
It's not very fun when you
know everything beforehand.
Oh.
That reminds me.
Did I really say that I wanted to be Dad's bride?
Yeah.
That's cute.
I probably told you the same thing.
Don't think so.
Really?
Still, I just don't know what to do.
Well, it's your future.
Spend it however you want.
Come on, Gin!
Stop talking and go to bed.
Don't you have a busy day tomorrow?
Jeez! Stupid Gintarou!
Turn off the lights.
The number you have dialed
is not available at the moment.
Man, he's not answering his phone!
I haven't heard anything since he said he was running late!
Where'd he go?!
Keep it down. And relax.
But it's already noon!
He said he'd be back by ten!
Gin, can you divine where Dad is?
Too much effort.
What?!
More importantly,
we need to finish cleaning up before your dad returns.
Look. There are still some weeds left.
You're not gonna accomplish anything by throwing a fit.
He'll be back soon enough.
Stop bothering Gintarou-sama.
S-Sorry.
There's one day left and you still haven't finished the wreath?
Well, we usually take it slow.
"Usually"...
Satoru, are you okay?
Saeki! Kamio!
Yumi-chan! Funabashi-san!
Don't you have school?
We ditched.
Fifth period is study hall,
and sixth period is music.
Funabashi-san ditched too?
She's turning into quite the bad girl!
She came here for a naughty reason too.
Um, I...
Right, everybody's talking because
both of you are absent from school!
What?!
Just kidding!
They're so loud.
So what's this?
Oh, this is...
Makoto-chan!
We're almost finished. Where's the chief priest?
I'm so sorry!
My dad isn't answering his phone!
Jeez, where'd he go?!
Now, calm down.
What's going on?
My dad went with his friend from another shrine to pick up thatch, but they're not back yet!
Is the thatch for the wreath?
Yes!
Wreath?
We wrap the thatch
around this ring to make a wreath.
We can't do tomorrow's ceremony without it!
Oh, this ring?
Anyway, please take a break.
I'll get you something to drink.
Oh, thanks.
Do we have enough tea?
Saeki! The boss guy wants to talk to you!
Oh, okay!
Funabashi-san, could you wait a moment?
Sure.
Man, that sucked.
The highway was jammed because of an accident.
Oh, sorry. I thought you were the girl who lives here.
Hello.
Hello...
Hey, Tatsuo!
There's a really pretty girl in your kitchen!
How'd you get someone like that in here?
What?
Oh.
She's Makoto's friend.
Oh, really?
Welcome, Funabashi-san.
Thank you for having us.
Mako-chan!
Oh, Uncle Yoshitomo!
What? Who's that hunk?!
Jeez, stupid! You're late!
Sorry! It's been ages, though!
Everyone, please have something to drink.
You've filled out a bit since I last saw you.
What? That's a priest?!
I thought you weren't interested in older men.
Handsome ones are an exception!
Don't worry.
I'll take responsibility by making you my bride.
Good for you, Makoto.
No way!
Hey, you shouldn't be laughing!
Mako-chan's like a daughter to me.
I'm always worrying about her
ending up with some bad apple.
Looks like I'm too late.
Oh, this is Satoru-kun.
Oh, you're the boy from the Kamio shrine.
Yes.
Right, I hear that you also...
Jeez! Why didn't you answer your phone, Dad?!
Huh?
Oh, it's out of power.
Jeez!
Anyway, Saeki, how about some introductions?
Oh, right. This is my dad's friend.
Oh, I'm Takami Yoshitomo.
Uh, Funabashi-san?
Sorry about what happened earlier.
I was thinking that Tatsuo
had found himself a young lover.
Don't be silly.
I'm Ikegami Yumi!
So, are you really a priest?
Oh, I'm actually retired,
but I help out when needed.
Usually whenever there's a ceremony.
We appreciate the help.
His lover...
Stop it!
He's my friend's father!
I'm sorry, Saeki-san!
So what do you do when you're not a priest?
I own a bar.
Gintarou
People like the idea of a bar run by a former priest.
We even offer purifications.
Gintarou
That sounds interesting!
There are more strangers around.
Something seems wrong about that.
It's just for show.
Festivals tend to do that.
But it's still quieter than our old shrine.
Well, festivals are important, so we should support them.
But is that guy really a priest?
You mean Yoshitomo?
You know him?
He comes every year.
Etsuko should be here soon, too.
Etsuko?
Oh, there she is.
Silver  Fox
Honestly...
Hey! If you park the van there,
nobody else can get in!
Oh?
Everyone's here.
Oh. Sorry, Sis.
I'll unload the thatch now.
That's his...
...sister?
Oh, Takami-kun's here too.
Yep, it's me again.
You're not up to any rogue priest antics, are you?
Like performing purifications at your bar?
Th-That's crazy talk.
Tatsuo, I brought some sake.
We have a good batch this year.
Really?
Mom and Dad said they'll be here tomorrow.
Oh, I'm sure they must be busy.
Thank your husband for me.
Oh, are you Satoru-kun?
It's nice to meet you.
Oh, Aunt Etsuko. Let me introduce you.
These are my friends.
Have we met before?
Huh?
Hiwako-sama!
What's wrong, Yoshizumi-san?
You left your cell phone in the car.
Oh, no!
Oh?
Huh?
Aren't you Funabashi-sensei's assistant?
Mrs. Toyokura?
H-Hello!
Allow me to thank you for your continued support.
What brings you here today?
Oh, I'm here as an escort for the young lady.
The young lady...
What?!
She's Funabashi-sensei's daughter?!
Toyokura? What?
Huh? What's going on?
Oh, my dad's last name used to be Toyokura.
Toyokura?
As in Toyokura Brewery?
Yep.
What?!
Toyokura Brewery
Toyokura
Toyokura Brewery is a local icon!
Toyokura Brewery
Toyokura
Even I've heard of it!
Toyokura Brewery
Toyokura
Man, this is a shock.
You're from a rich family too...
No, no. We're not rich at all.
Please, we're not rich or anything.
And business has been poor lately.
Wait...
The priest is Toyokura-sama's son?
That's right.
That boy was supposed to inherit the business,
but he fell in love with the shrine maiden here
and became a priest instead.
I'm not a boy anymore.
Wow, sounds like a romance novel!
Awesome!
Anyway, do you have enough for the offering?
I think we need some more dried foods.
And something that's more in season for summer.
Okay.
U-Uh, is there anything I can do to help?
Oh, I appreciate the offer,
but don't you have work?
It's okay. My boss is in Tokyo right now.
Hey, assistant.
You should take off that expensive suit.
Yes.
I'll lend you some work clothes.
Okay, we'll let the men do their stuff while we go shopping.
Yay!
Is this really going to work out?
I'm gonna take a nap.
Mako-chan, is there anything else you're after?
I'll buy you anything you want!
Oh, I need some underwear!
Underwear?!
It's finished!
Good work.
Satoru-kun was a huge help.
Thanks, Satoru-kun.
I-It's not a big deal.
So what do we do for dinner?
The priests aren't allowed to eat meat right now.
Oh, that doesn't apply to me.
Quiet, you.
Thank you, Yoshizumi-san.
It was nothing.
Please stay for dinner.
Oh, I need to get going.
I need to bring the car back to the house.
Really? That's too bad.
Please join us tomorrow, then.
Yes.
Is this the first time you've seen a wreath?
Oh, yes.
I believe that the summer cleansing
is when you pass through the wreath
to cleanse impurities from the past six months
and protect yourself from summer illnesses.
Ah, you're quite knowledgeable.
Oh, I'm sorry. I did some research.
I didn't know anything before.
I wouldn't expect young people to know.
The people who come here tomorrow will be looping around both sides in a figure eight.
"Those who participate in the June summer cleaning
have a thousand years added to their life."
They're supposed to say that
as they pass through the wreath.
What does that do?
It means that if you go through the cleansing, you'll live to be a thousand years old.
That's a little too much!
We're not supposed to live as long as the gods!
Well, it's not meant to be taken literally.
A thousand-year...
lifespan...
Yep, that's right.
We're asking the gods to share their life.
That might be it.
Whoa, what are you writing?
This is the prayer that'll be used for the cleansing tomorrow.
You work too hard, man.
It's the same prayer every year.
Why not just use a computer?
That would be easier,
but a priest's prayer is made on behalf of many people.
I want to write the prayer by hand so the gods hear it.
You lose!
What?!
Well, I need to get going.
Are you staying here tonight?
We start early tomorrow morning.
Oh, Satoru-kun's using your old room, so you'll have to sleep here.
What?
I'll sleep with the teenage girls, then!
Absolutely not!
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yep. Thanks, Sis.
The bath's ready, sir.
Thank you, Satoru-kun.
Right, Dad. Go take your bath.
There are a lot of people waiting.
So, how about I wash your back for you?
You're scaring me.
Your father and Takami-san seem pretty close.
Yep, they've been friends ever since they were kids.
Oh, when will your father perform the Misogi purification ritual?
Tomorrow morning?
Right now.
He does it every time he takes a bath.
Huh?
I thought it only counted if you were under a waterfall or in the ocean!
Of course not.
Oh, so you can perform the Misogi in the bath.
We had a special room for it at my shrine.
Your shrine's bigger than ours.
Gin!
Sorry about all the noise today.
I've gotten used to it. Why apologize now?
Festivals are important for us too.
Gin, I'm sorry about yesterday.
What's this?
Did you already solve your problem?
No. I'll be busy tomorrow, so there's no point in worrying about it.
And panicking won't help me find an answer.
Well, wish us luck tomorrow.
I'll do that.
Oh yeah, tell Yoshitomo to act
more like a priest while he's at it.
I'll let him know.
What did Gintarou-sama say?
He was as aloof as always, really.
And he said that you need to act more like a priest.
That's no good.
Oh, right. We have another fox spirit now.
She's called Haru-chan.
Hey, Uncle Yoshitomo,
why did you stop being a priest?
Why did I stop?
I wasn't really cut out for it.
That's not true.
I'm getting old.
You're getting old?
It's time to go to bed.
It's been a while since the last time I talked to the old Inari-no-Okami.
I guess I won't be able to sleep tomorrow.
Tomorrow is June 30th,
the summer cleansing ceremony.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
Those who participate in the June summer cleaning
have a thousand years added to their life.
May fortune always be with you.
Next time, the final episode: "Summer Cleansing."
Summer Cleansing