My home is a small Inari shrine
that's been around since the Edo period.
Our shrine is dedicated to the
god of agriculture, Uka-no-Mitama.
See you around.
Have a good day!
Good morning, Makoto-chan.
Good morning!
Makoto-oneechan!
We wanna make a wish to
the fox before going to school!
Yeah, we wanna wish that our recital goes well!
It's a small shrine, so it's just my dad,
who's the shrine priest, me,
and...
Hey.
Gintarou, the fox spirit who serves as the herald for this shrine.
You're going to be late for school.
What do I do?!
I'm gonna miss the bus again!
Huh? You haven't left yet, Makoto?!
Dad, tag!
Oh, are those oranges?
They are. The fox spirit who lives here loves them.
I'm off!
Does she have to make such a scene every morning?
Gintarou is a herald, so normal people can't see him.
The bus is here!
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
Learning to Compromise
I'm starving.
Come on, it's only first period.
Like, seriously?
Hey, Makocchi...
Saeki, thanks for your help.
Oh, Ikegami-san. I should be thanking you.
You can call me Yumi.
O-Okay.
Don't expect me to ever trust your fortunes, though!
You made up with Shohei?
Yeah, all because Saeki used her
fortune telling to help find a cat.
Makocchi, when did you become friends with Ikegami-san?
Um... It just kind of happened.
So Saeki was spot-on!
I should ask her to tell my fortune!
No, no, no.
I wouldn't if I were you.
It was probably just a fluke.
How's Mi-chan doing?
She's doing great!
Excuse me. That's enough chitchat.
We're supposed to be forming teams so that we can start playing.
Six people to a team.
Come on, we're on our own today.
Don't be such a spoilsport, Funabashi.
I might as well say this now.
Uncooperative people like you are a nuisance to everyone.
What?
What brought this on?
I dunno why you're trying to pick a fight here.
I'm not trying to pick a fight.
I'm sure a model student like you would think that we're useless.
This doesn't look good.
Yeah...
Well, you keep on trying to boss
people around, Miss Vice President.
What a pain.
Let's go.
Wait, Ikegami!
Honestly, she's a lost cause.
Saeki-san.
Um, yes?
I believe you live at a shrine?
Y-Yes.
You should choose your friends wisely.
Huh?
Never mind.
It's no business of mine who you choose to associate with.
However,
I hope that you'll stop distracting the
other students with your fortune telling.
Even though I'm sure you
enjoy the attention you receive.
What?
What?!
Funabashi
I'm home, Mother.
Welcome home, Hiwako-san.
Is something the matter?
Um, where is Father?
His trip overseas has been extended, so he won't be back this week.
I see.
Now hurry.
I will.
So that's what happened.
Are you listening to me, Gintarou?
Yeah.
Jeez.
As I was saying, Gintarou,
Funabashi-san comes from
a family steeped in tea ceremony.
Her father is a member of the Diet,
and she's the vice president of the student council.
She's smart and pretty,
but she can be difficult.
Are you listening?
Y-Yeah.
I mean, compared to Funabashi-san, I may look like a total failure,
but that doesn't mean she has to be so harsh on me or Yumi-chan.
Well, I shouldn't let it get to me.
I just have to get my act together so
Funabashi-san stops saying those things.
Okay! I gotta work harder!
Hypocrite.
What?!
Aren't you mad about what that girl said?
Cut the goody two-shoes act, and vent away.
I'm not...
Seriously, humans care too much about what other people think.
You're always complaining to me when you're home.
Huh?
That other girl sounds more reasonable to me.
You're wrong.
I'm not that bad.
Besides, if everyone just did whatever they wanted, it'd be a huge mess!
Not my problem if humans want to make a huge mess.
I'm home!
Welcome home, Dad.
It's a real scorcher out there, isn't it?
In that respect, Tatsuo is really something.
There haven't been many priests like him.
What? Is Dad that special?
Yeah. I never quite know what he's thinking.
Huh?
Oh, what's going on?
What'd Gintarou-sama say?
It sounds like my father's trip has been extended.
Indeed.
It'll be a few more days before he returns.
Good morning!
Yo, Saeki!
Oh, Yumi-chan. Good morning.
Have a good day, Hiwako-sama.
Yeah, she's living the good life, all right.
No wonder she's such a snob.
Sure, we were kinda fooling around,
but that doesn't mean she should just unload on us.
Now, now... Can't we all get along?
Are you crazy?
I want nothing to do with her.
Though I might change my mind if she apologizes.
Ah, Yumi-chan!
U-Um... Good morning, Funabashi-san.
Good morning.
Say, Funabashi-san...
I don't suppose you'd be willing to
apologize to Yumi-chan... would you?
Why should I? Did I say something wrong?
But—
Yes, I may have put her in an uncomfortable position,
but that's unavoidable
in a group environment like this one.
We're in high school now.
We can't just live as we please.
Huh?
The bell's about to ring.
Totally hilarious!
That comedian's really funny.
I saw that segment!
I was laughing my head off!
He'll be ancient history in a year, though.
No way!
Hey, Funabashi.
Sir.
Class 6 is the only one
that hasn't turned in their reports.
I asked you to collect those, right?
Huh?
You're usually on top of things.
Bring them to the office right away.
Right.
Huh?
Serves her right.
Ishii-san, you said you would drop off the reports for me.
What? When'd I say that?
Don't blame other people for your screwups.
Stop playing dumb.
You agreed to take them.
What? No way.
Geography Report
Funabashi.
We'll drop these off for you.
You look busy.
Thanks. I appreciate it.
Stop fooling around and hand the reports over!
No idea what you're talking about. Why don't you look for them?
Um, I saw—
Saeki-san, you should stay out of this.
But...
Those girls are friends with Ikegami-san.
Yeah, they're scary.
It's out of our hands.
Silver  Fox
Makoto, you're late today.
Hey now. You were about to walk into the statue.
What's wrong?
Why the long face?
Say, Gin...
Am I a hypocrite?
I would like Yumi-chan, Funabashi-san,
and everyone else to just get along.
But deep down, I don't really care what they do,
as long as I'm not involved.
Sorry about making you listen
to me complain again, Gintarou.
Just let it all out, stupid.
You usually tend to speak your mind,
but since you can see me,
you never get to actually vent.
Just let it all out and you'll feel better.
That's what a shrine is for.
But you don't like listening to me complain.
You see...
I'll just pretend that I never heard a word.
Student                Council
Kirishima-senpai, here is the
budget plan for the student council.
You move fast.
Anyway, let's go out somewhere after we're finished.
I'll be leaving now.
She's so shy.
Saeki!
Oh, Yumi-chan.
Good thing I caught you.
Can I stay at your place tonight?
Huh? At my place?
I got in a fight with my parents.
I asked around, but I haven't had any luck so far.
Oh, sure, I guess...
Super! I'll go grab my bag!
Wait, Yumi-chan.
I need to go to the restroom.
Okay.
Girls'    Restroom
Well, I guess this works out.
I'll have time to talk to her
about Funabashi-san tonight.
Oh, it's Saeki.
Why weren't you keeping watch?
Well...
Funabashi-san.
Saeki-san, we're busy right now.
Could you go somewhere else?
Why are you taking the lead?
Don't you understand the position you're in?
Your business is with me, not with Saeki-san.
I'm willing to listen to what you have to say,
but this isn't the place—
I can't stand that attitude of yours!
What does Kirishima-senpai see in this girl?!
Huh? What does the
student council president have to do with it?
Um, could you stop this?
None of your business.
U-Um...
Shut up, Saeki!
What's going on?
Th-They're scary.
What are you doing?
Yumi-chan.
I-Ikegami...
What's this? Are you teaching Funabashi a lesson?
Why's Saeki here?
Oh, remember how mad you were at Saeki?
So we figured we'd—
Saeki just happened to walk in.
What?
I'm the one who doesn't like Funabashi.
What does that have to do with all of you?
W-Well...
Could you stay out of my problems?
Besides, the teachers are coming.
Everyone outside can hear you.
Crap!
Huh? I thought you were
friends with them, Yumi-chan.
What?
We talk and stuff, but we're not really friends.
Huh?
What is it?
Nothing!
Yumi-chan is the type of person who's easy to misunderstand.
So why—
Should I thank you?
I don't really care,
since you still tick me off.
I don't intend to apologize.
Do you understand that you're
making trouble for other people?
I don't see a problem!
You may be smart, but I wouldn't want to be you!
Yumi-chan!
Doesn't she piss you off?
She's so judgmental.
Judgmental?
You're the one who's being judgmental!
I'm a good student?
My parents are elite?
I'm usually on top of things?!
"My daughter should be able to do everything"?!
I've had enough!
I am what I am!
Don't try to make me something I'm not!
O-Oh no!
S-Sorry, that just slipped out.
Man, what was that about?
It really threw me off.
You usually play it cool and show no emotion,
but you're really just like the rest of us.
Don't bottle it all up inside.
I bet you were just jealous of me, right?
I'm not jealous!
Oh, did I hit a nerve?
Now, now...
Say, Funabashi-san,
Yumi-chan's staying at my place tonight.
Would you like to join us?
Hey, Saeki!
At your place?
I live at a shrine, but it's nothing special.
Still, I was thinking it'd be a new experience.
Is that okay, Yumi-chan?
I guess so.
S-Sorry, Yumi-chan.
I'm sorry.
Why are you crying?
I'm sorry!
Gintarou, I'm such a fool.
Welcome ba—
Yoshizumi, take this message to my mother:
"I won't be coming home tonight."
Let's go, then.
Did you see the look on his face?!
Was that the right thing to say?
I've always wanted to say that.
That's our shrine.
Welcome back, Makoto-chan.
I'm back, Granny!
I made lots of pickled vegetables, so I brought some over.
Thank you for being so good to us!
Hey there.
You're not supposed to use the middle of the stairs.
Huh? Why not?
The middle of the shrine path is reserved for the gods.
So you're not supposed to walk there.
Oh, I never knew about that custom.
I think I've heard it before.
That's right.
Though sometimes I forget and walk in the middle.
It's so quiet.
My house is quiet too, but in a different way.
For some reason, this place is very calming.
Yep.
Welcome home, Makoto.
Oh? Are these your friends?
Wait, Dad! Why are you dressed like that?!
Good afternoon.
Hi there.
Thank you for having us.
Um, we were just told
that the middle of the path is reserved for the gods...
That's right.
Once you pass under that gate, you're on sacred ground.
When visiting a shrine,
you're supposed to walk on the left side
in order to leave room for the gods.
Though at the same time,
it also makes sure that people don't run into each other.
It's a way of teaching the lesson
that people should learn to compromise.
Learn to compromise...
But our herald always says
that people should just run into each other.
Herald?
A herald is a messenger of the gods.
Ours is a fox spirit.
Don't worry too much about it.
Oh, Dad?
Can they stay here tonight?
Sure, that's fine.
Thanks, Mr. Saeki!
Thank you for your hospitality.
No need for that.
We're glad to have you.
Go ahead and make yourselves at home.
Okay!
Are you going to take over
this shrine one day, Saeki-san?
I'm not sure yet.
Are you going to take over your family's tea ceremony school?
I don't know.
To be honest, I'm not sure what I want to do.
Shrines are magical places.
They bring all kinds of people together.
Together?
Uh-huh.
This shrine has brought three
different people together today.
I don't want to lose that magic.
You know, I want to become a vet,
but fat chance of that with my grades,
so I'm looking at my other options.
Huh? You're giving up?
They say you should find something you wanna do,
but there's no guarantee that
you'll actually achieve that dream.
I can help you study.
For real?
You're not so bad after all.
Oh? You thought I was a bad person?
You're the type to hold grudges, huh?
I wouldn't say that.
Well, I would!
That's not true.
Oh, does that look on your face
mean that everything's resolved?
Uh-huh.
Don't you wish you were born to a family
where you could do whatever you wanted?
But I can see you.
What more could I ask for?
I took a quick peek.
It looks like the three of you
will be together for a long time.
Not that you would care about
how compatible you are with girls.
Gintarou.
What is it?
Thanks.
I love you.
Did you say something?
Nope.
Bah, she got me.
After ringing the bell, you bow twice,
clap twice,
and then bow one more time.
Hey, I can actually see our fox spirit.
Whoa, this girl's got a few screws loose.
I believe you.
What?! What's wrong with you?
I mean, I could totally see one living here.
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
The center of the path at
a shrine is reserved for the gods.
When visiting a shrine,
you should avoid walking
down the middle of the path.
Next time: "The Place Where the Gods Are."
The Place Where the Gods Are
May fortune be with you.