Offering                  Box
Good morning, Gintarou-sama, Haru-sama.
Yes, good morning to you too.
Just a minute.
Here you go.
Good morning.
Good morning. You're here early.
I have an easier time
getting out of bed when it's warmer.
It's already June.
Ah, are those summer oranges?
Yes.
Why don't you leave them inside?
The offerings inside are for the gods.
Our fox spirit likes his offerings out here.
Oh?
It sounds like you heard that
from the herald himself.
When I was little,
my great-grandfather used to say
that there was a fox spirit dancing
on the roof of the Inari shrine nearby.
You also have a fox spirit here?
We do.
Yes, of course.
Silver
Fox
watashi no umareta kono basho kono heya de
I met you here where I was born,
deatta yo
in this room
furuboketa ranpu wa ima mo yasashii hikari wo
My old lamp sheds a soft light
terashitekureru
even now
zutto mukashi kara tsumugaretekita
You made me realize
jikan wo kizukasetekureta
how much wonderful time we spent together
mune ni tomosou kokoro no naka no ranpu
Let's light a lamp in our hearts as well
ima kakureteta kizuna terashi
The bonds we suppressed will be cast into light
watashi ni sotto sasayakikakeru yo
for all the world to see
boku wa itsumo koko da yo
This is the place where I belong
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
Here,
take my hand,
sashinobeta te hora
tsunaidara kimi ni
iu kotoba wa
and after that,
kimi wo shinjiteiru kara
don't ever let it go again,
kono te wo hanasanaideite
because I believe in you
I'm Sorry
Satoru-kun, I can take it from here.
You're gonna be late for practice.
Okay.
Satoru, it's going to rain today.
Really?
Just a drizzle, though.
You probably won't need an umbrella.
I'll take one to be safe.
No way.
The forecast said it would be sunny today.
Heh. Forecast, you say?
I guess I should take an umbrella, too.
You can get rained on.
Haru-chan's so cold to me.
Anyway...
Why do they always give
tangerines as offerings?
That's so weird!
Hey!
These are hard to find
this time of year, you stupid brat!
What kind of fox eats tangerines?
Gin, don't get so worked up over tangerines.
Come on, Haru.
You shouldn't waste food.
Not my fault...
In that case...
What do you like?
W-Well, I like fried tofu!
You're just eating
whatever they put in front of you.
I bet you've never even
tried anything else before.
That's not true!
Now, now.
Oh, I've heard that foxes like blue cheese.
They said so in a special on TV.
Would you like to try some?
Cheese?
That was a special on foxes in the wild.
Don't feed Haru anything strange.
Have fun, Satoru!
This one's pretty big.
Oh, that's a summer tangerine.
Dad never learns.
I don't mind it when Tatsuo does it.
What? You're really soft on Dad.
You always complain when I give you stuff.
Tatsuo is allowed to get away with it.
Makoto! You need to get
ready to go, or you'll be late!
Okay!
Dad, Haru-chan likes regular old fried tofu.
Oh, really?
Regular, huh.
You should have said something sooner.
I'm off!
Take care.
It's coming up "rain" every time.
That's a pretty poor excuse for a flame.
Why do you have to be so annoying?
I can make bigger ones, you know.
A bigger flame will bring different things.
What can you do, then?
First of all, you're not holding your hand right.
Want me to teach you?
I don't need your help!
I don't wanna tell fortunes
just to suck up to humans.
Besides, all you've got going for you
is that giant body and tail.
Quit acting so high and mighty.
You should pick on someone your own size.
Seriously.
For such a big guy,
you've sure got a tiny little heart.
Yeah, that's right.
I guess I'm the bad guy here.
So sorry about that.
Hey! Come down!
Go to sleep already.
I'm not tired!
You're running away
because you can't beat me!
Gintarou-sama, Haru-sama.
I'll be heading out for a bit.
Please watch over the shrine for us.
Tatsuo...
It's so quiet.
That cloud looks like Grandpa Matsu!
That one looks like Satoru!
That big one is Gintarou.
But seriously,
I don't get how he can
sleep so much every day.
I'm—
Wait!
Hurry up!
Wait for me!
More noisy humans.
It's ringing!
I want to sit next to Taiga-kun.
I want to be in the same group as Taiga-kun.
Sacchan, what did you wish for?
It's a secret.
Why?!
Kids these days...
Come on! Tell me!
You go first!
It's embarrassing!
What do you mean?
Jeez! Keep it down!
Oh, we need to wash our hands.
Yep, that's right!
It's too late!
Hey, Aki! Sachina!
What are you doing here?
We're gonna tell on you!
Yuuya!
And the noisy brats just keep coming.
We aren't doing anything wrong.
We live nearby.
But you're supposed to go straight home!
You're the one who's
always following us around!
You probably like Sacchan!
What?
They call people like you "stalkers."
What?! That's not true!
Uh, Yuu-chan?
Is that true?
It's not!
Is too!
Why you...
Shut up, stupid Aki!
Stop it!
Shut up, ugly!
Hey!
Stop it!
That's cold!
Th-These kids make me so mad!
Now I'm really mad!
Yeah! Make them pay!
Stupid Yuuya!
Yeah! Way to go!
That's the spirit!
One more time!
Don't let that boy beat you!
You're gonna get it!
You started it!
Make them pay in spades! Keep it up!
Yeah, like that!
There!
Take that!
Darn it!
Don't let those boys win!
Wait a second....
How can he sleep through all of this?
Hey! Stop it!
Get 'em, Yuu-chan!
Don't let 'em beat you!
Do it!
Get down from there!
Take this!
Dual wield!
Ow...
Uh-oh...
Not my fault!
Wait up!
A-Aki-chan...
What do we do?
We're sorry!
What?!
Hold it right there!
Wait...
Silver  Fox
John! Why are you barking again?!
There's nothing there!
That scared me!
Huh?
Where am I?
I'm lost...
And I'm supposed to be a herald.
Satoru's gonna be worried
when he gets home.
I probably won't be able to divine the location of the shrine, either.
Satoru...
I just noticed that this is an Inari shrine.
Should I spend the night here?
Stupid.
What are you doing?
O-Oh, it's just Gintarou.
That's not very nice.
I came down here to get you.
Weren't you sleeping?!
You think anyone could
sleep through that racket?
And you were the noisiest one of all.
Man, don't go wandering off if you don't know the way back home.
I never asked you to come look for me!
Come on, now.
I didn't even have to look for you.
The shrine's right over there.
You must be blind.
Then leave me alone!
I wish I could, but I can't.
If I don't do something,
it'll only get worse later on.
Why didn't you do something?!
H-Haru ran away again?
Come on. Let's go.
What are you two doing here?
Hey.
Oh? That must have been awful.
I'm gonna make them pay!
Well, they're just kids, you know.
Oh, good thing it didn't rain.
I ran back in a hurry.
That's weird.
Hey, it's them!
What's going on, Dad?
Oh. Welcome home, Makoto.
Makoto-oneechan...
We're sorry!
We're the ones who broke the dippers.
And we messed up the fox statue, too.
Sorry. We did something bad.
And then we ran away...
We won't do it again.
So...
Please don't curse us!
What?
Th-That's what Grandma said.
You've angered the gods!
If you fool around at the shrine, the fox spirits will eat you!
Right?
It's okay.
The fox spirits won't eat you.
Really?
Yes.
You shouldn't have broken the dippers,
but the important part
is that you understood what you did wrong, and apologized.
I'm sure the fox spirits will forgive you.
Besides, the fox spirits will be lonely if you don't come to visit.
So please drop by when you have time.
I'm so relieved.
Uh-huh.
Tatsuo really is too soft.
Now, now.
Uh, here.
We used our allowance to buy these.
Grandma told us that
the fox spirit here likes them.
They didn't have any tangerines, so we bought oranges.
Thank you!
I'm sure the fox spirit will be happy.
Forget it.
They apologized, so I'll forgive them.
Too bad I hate tangerines!
Rain?
Oh? But it's so sunny.
It's a fox wedding.
Hey, why are sun showers called fox weddings?
Well...
I've heard that foxes have their weddings
when it rains while the sun is out...
Or that foxes are responsible for making it rain,
but I don't know the real reason.
It's a good question.
That's weird.
Yeah, it's just an old superstition.
Humans shouldn't blame foxes for everything.
Let's play in the rain before we go home!
Come on!
Yeah!
Make sure you don't catch cold.
Uh-huh!
Bye-bye, Makoto-oneechan!
A fox wedding, huh?
Oh, Haru-chan, why don't you marry Gin?
You're a girl, after all.
Why?!
I don't like anything about Gintarou!
And I want nothing to do with this noisy brat.
Oh, welcome back!
Welcome back.
Oh, Satoru!
I'm home, Haru.
You're back early!
Yeah, practice took less time than usual.
Satoru, you're wet! Why?
Didn't you take an umbrella?
Oh, it was a short run.
And it was a fox wedding,
so I didn't mind getting wet.
Since it's like the rain was a present from you.
Jeez... You'll catch cold, you know...
At least everything worked out.
Here are your oranges, Gin.
Oranges?
They're similar to tangerines.
Oh, the rain's stopped.
Hey, what are you holding, Dad?
Oh, this?
It's a present for Haru-sama.
You said that she likes fried tofu,
and I was thinking it might
be better with some udon.
I'm a big fan.
Oh... should I have brought
some hot water after all?
Come on, Dad!
Are you okay?
Haru, stop being so stubborn.
You like cream buns, right?
Satoru! Don't tell them!
What? Cream buns?
Yeah, someone made an offering of them once.
Oh?
Hey, and you were making fun of me?
I like cream buns, too.
They're really good.
You're just as weird as I am.
Take that!
Ow!
Turn orange, Gintarou!
I told you to stop wasting the tangerines!
Shut up!
A rainbow.
It's lovely.
The sky is the one thing that never changes.
Oh, what were you saying about cream buns?
Haru likes them.
Really?
I think it's very cute of you, Haru-chan.
Shut up!
tooku kikoeteru hito no koe furikaeri
I hear a voice far away, turn around,
hokusoemu
and chuckle
ichi kara hyaku ni naru setsuna sono isshun ga
A hundred short moments follow the other
eien da ne
to be my eternity
kodoku sae shihai shitai to omotta kedo
I wanted to have control over everything,
including my loneliness,
gishin anki kanawanai ya
but the paranoia ruined my life
te wo nobasou
Let's hold out our hands
sekai no hajimari wa itsuwari no monogatari
All stories of the world's beginning are wrong
tsuki ga sotto waratteru yo
Saying that the moon seems to laugh
nayuta no mirai he to tsunagu message
It's the message that connects me to countless futures
boku wo sora he michibiitekureru story
It's the story that guides me towards the sky
Preview
Silver  Fox
Yo, this is Gintarou.
You want to know
more about shrines?
Go look it up yourself.
Next ti—
Next time:
It Really Doesn't Matter
"It Really Doesn't Matter."
May fortune be with Satoru.
Hey!