Ready for invasion!
shinryaku junbi OK
Right: all clear!
migi yoshi
Left: all clear!
hidari yoshi
Let's go invade and give it our all!
zenryoku shinryaku let's go
INVADE!!
Squid Girl
Today is still at the height of summer
kyou mo ichinichi natsu ga
kaimaku harikitteiku yo
yo! yo!
Go for the vanguard!
ichibannori mezashi
Advance on the road to invasion!
susumeyo shinryaku road
do! do!
The sun shines everywhere, a carnival circling the globe
taiyou giragira nishi he higashi he guuru guru carnival
good! good!
Summer stretches out
araburu nami koete
beyond the wild waves
manatsu no saizensen
My glittering sweat
and the pounding of my heart
hikaru ase mo hazumu mune mo
are the rhythm of excitement
doki doki rhythm
Once you're honest with yourself,
sunao ni naretara
you'll be able to more, longer, better, I'm sure
kitto motto zutto gutto dekiru
Let's squid now with all we have, and dance!
zenryoku mood de ika dancin'
Run, run, run! It's invasion time!
run run run let's shinryaku time it "ika"
She's in squidly hyper mode!
hyper mode de gessoo
Run, run, run! It's invasion time!
run run run let's shinryaku time sir "ika"
Let's go squidly straight!
massugu gessoo
Line squidly up!
narande gessoo
Spin around!
guruguru mawatte
Goof off!
uneune ugoite
Flail around!
wakiwaki tonde
Go squidly now!
ika susume gessoo
Go! Go invade!
go go shinryaku
Go! Go invade, Squid Girl!
go go shinryaku ika musume
Squiddy squiddy...
Squiddy squiddy squiddy squid!
They've got a pool
in their garden!
I'm so squidding envious.
What're you saying?
We've got this huge pool called
.the "sea" right outside our door.
They're not the same at all.
Conquering a small pool like that
.is a much easier problem to tentackle.
You're one puny invader.
So I wanna have a pool
in my garden too!
Your garden?
Well, whatever.
I'll ask Sis if we've got one
.lying around somewhere.
Is that an inkflatable pool?
Sure, we've got an
.inflatable pool.
We do?
Yep.
Here.
This isn't it!
I was talking about a big, round
plastic pool filled with water
that I can have all
to my squidly self!
There's a valve, isn't there?
You need to blow air
.into it to make it bigger.
Blow air?
Yeah! Blow air into it
.until it's big and round.
Then you can fill it with water.
What?
Make it bigger.
Do it yourself!
You squidding me?
.That's way too much effort.
You want it, you work for it!
Isn't that obvious?
Is there enough air in it yet?
Nope, not at all.
You've got a ways to go.
This inkvasion is taking
...a lot longer than I thought...
Huh?
What're you two
doing in the garden?
Sanae?
She said she wanted to
.play in an inflatable pool.
I've been blowing air into it for ages,
but it just won't get any squidding bigger.
That means that pool contains
none other than Squiddie's breath!
Her respiration! Her air!
She gave it life!
It contains her very essence!
Would you like
some help, Squiddie?
That'd be great!
I know my lungs
.won't let you down.
I think it's about
.two-squirds full already.
Just leave it to me.
Whoa, she's really getting into it.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
You sucked all the air out?!
Huh? Ah, whoops. Tee-hee.
What's going on in your lungs?
I worked so hard...
Eiko! Squid Girl!
Ah, you're here too, Sanae?
I found the pump!
Where the squid were you?!
Leave it to me!
Just wait, my little Squiddie!
Wow, she's fast!
Done!
Time to jump right in!
This feels squidding great!
Lemme in too!
Not in those clothes, you're not!
Then I'll change into my swimsuit!
I put my swimsuit on, Squiddie!
Huh? Squiddie?
That's weird.
She was there just a minute ago.
She said I could get in
if I wore a swimsuit!
She didn't say you could.
I wanted to have a
.water fight with her,
have an underwater
.staring contest,
tickle her from head to toe,
and do all kinds of
lovey-dovey lewdness!
Didn't she just run away?
But she really was here
.until just now.
An inkflatable pool is
.for one squid only.
It must be enjoyed in
complete privacy!
I can feel the breeze of
freedom in my tentacles!
And what a squidly stunning sight!
Inkdeed, there's no
better place for a pool!
Then I'll change
into my swimsuit!
That was lucky.
Don't waste the water!
That's right. It's not safe here.
If Sanae comes back,
she'll inkvade upon my territory!
Oh, but up there should do!
Squiddie?
Where are you?
All I can see now is the sun,
the sky, and the clouds!
The sun's all mine!
With this, I can call my
inkvasion a squidly success!
I guess I can allow a few
birds to fly my skies.
She might've gone
.down to Lemon.
You think so?
Did she already
give up on the pool?
She sure is fickle.
That's how she rolls.
But I even put on my bikini!
I wanna play with her!
Then how about
hitting the beach?
Sure!
Sanae's tentacles
.can't reach me here.
This is my very own territory.
Paradise itself!
Huh?
It started raining
.all of a sudden.
Um...
Huh? Squiddie?
What is she doing?
Lemon
Pasta •
Beer
.Octopus
Dumplings
House by the Sea
Curry rice
Ramen
Yakisoba
'Scuse me! A beer here!
Some dumplings too!
Right away!
This is Lemon, House by the Sea.
For a lifeguard like me,
entrusted with the safety of so many,
it's like an oasis for the soul.
You always have
shrimp pilaf, don't you?
Yeah!
I just can't get enough
of Chizuru's cooking!
Thanks for the meal!
It was as delicious as always, Chizuru!
I'm glad you liked it.
An oasis.
Or so it was supposed to be.
Yes, supposed to be...
Huh? Goro!
There you are!
That is,
until my mother showed up.
Squidn't your mom stop by?
Why're you here, Mom?
Sorry, did I need
your permission to visit?
Eiko, Chizuru,
long time no see!
Takeru, you too!
Hello, Auntie!
Long time no see!
You're looking great, as always!
Sure am!
But it doesn't feel like that long
.since I last saw you, Chizuru.
Really?
You see, in Goro's room ther—
What are you doing here?!
Did you come just to embarrass me?
Then take a hike!
Sorry, did I need your
permission to stay here?
I'm not going anywhere
.until I've had something to eat.
Damn, she pisses me off!
What a pain.
Mom, what're you
sitting there for?!
Is it that unusual for a mother
to sit with her son?
That's not the problem!
It's embarrassing!
Embarrassing? How so?
Come on, people don't just come to these places
...with their mothers after a certain age...
Oh, please! Maybe someone'll
even mistake us for a couple!
Isozaki! Save me, Isozaki!
Huh? What's wrong, Goro?
Ah, your mom's here?
If you don't like it, there's not
.much you can do but leave.
I'm worried about what she'll
.get up to when I'm not looking.
Oh, right. I'll have fried rice,
dumplings, and oily soba!
And a pork cutlet curry
.for good measure.
Gotcha. Won't be a minute.
Eiko, Chizuru!
I'm back from shopping.
Oh my, how cute!
I know! You're one
of them "cosplayers"!
It's not cosplay!
I'm the mighty
.inkvader from the sea,
Squid Girl!
Saints alive!
Now she understands what a
squidly tentaculous threat I am!
I love how you young'uns these days
are all ready to take on the world!
This woman really rubs
.my tentacles the wrong way.
Much obliged for the meal.
I'm on a diet, so I'd
.better leave it at that.
It was delicious, Chizuru!
Thank you very much!
You're such a great cook!
No wonder Goro's
head over heels for you!
M-Mom... Can I have a word?
What?
Why would you say that
straight to her face?!
It's so awkward!
I'm just helping you along because
you've been too scared to make a move!
I don't need your assistance!
You've had your lunch,
so go home already!
What's wrong with you?
For one thing, can you really
afford to slack off like this?
You keep the beach safe so everyone else
.can play without a care in the world.
Isn't that your job as a lifeguard?
Great, now she
.plays the serious card.
Well then, since you're here,
why not enjoy the water yourself?
What's this? You know
.I'm a terrible swimmer.
Then why the swimsuit?!
Don't worry, Auntie.
I couldn't swim either,
but Goro taught me how to.
Really now?
What?
Would you even save someone
like me if I was drowning?
Huh?
I mean, I'm sure you'd save one of those young,
cute girls without a moment's hesitation,
Are you okay?
Hang in there!
but would you still give CPR and stuff
to a middle-aged woman like me?
Of course! It's my job!
But could you stop saying things
people are gonna misunderstand?
Arashiyama saved me once too.
I was out surfing, and then I got dunked
.by a huge wave and started to sink.
If not for him, I might not
.have been here to tell the tale.
He even saved Squid Girl once.
She went swimming
.without warming up first,
and her tentacles cramped up.
I was just in bad shape that day!
Oh, so you actually
can do your job?
Of course!
I wasn't so sure after seeing how
.lousy you were with women,
but I guess I was
.worried over nothing.
You really are here just to
embarrass me, aren't you?!
Let's go, Isozaki!
I've had enough of this.
Right...
Look how shy he is.
You drove him to the very brink.
I'm squidly inkpressed.
I just teased him a little!
He's still such a kid.
But you talk in a
.rather interesting way.
With all your "squid" and
."ink" and "tentacle".
Is that what's hip these days?
I'm not talking like this
to be squidding hip!
Geez. Lemon was my sole refuge.
Give me a break.
Goro!
What is it now?
I'm heading back home.
Yeah, whatever.
Watch your tone, young man.
I know!
I'm busy!
Geez.
Goro! Don't just peep
on the girls all day!
I'm not peeping on anyone!
I'm just kidding.
I know you're doing a good job.
But I wanted to see it for myself so I could
.tell everyone what a wonderful son I had.
There were a few other times I stopped by
.without you realizing, you know.
I'm not here to
.embarrass or tease you.
I really am proud of you.
Mom...
I never knew you felt that way...
So you can squidding bet
I'll come back!
Please don't.
Mornings really do feel great.
Yeah!
What the squid are you doing?
Don't dump your trash
in the ocean!
It's not trash!
I was sending a
message in a bottle!
Message in a bottle?
You know, when you write a message,
put it in a bottle, and throw it out to sea?
You throw it out? So you are
just dumping trash in the ocean!
That's not it, Squid-sis.
The bottle will eventually reach another beach
somewhere around the world, right?
The point is you hope someone
reads your message in a bottle!
So with this message, you can extend your tentacles
past Japan and reach the entire world?
It'll take some time, though.
As an inkvader,
I cannot lag behind!
Is that a message ink a bottle?
First, we need a bottle.
What are you doing, Squid Girl?
I like this shape!
Could you ink this for me?
Drink it yourself!
Then let me have it.
Isozaki?
Whoa! He's chugging
the whole thing!
Burp
Learn some self-control!
Now we need a message.
I'll write one too!
Ah, so you're putting a
message in the bottle?
"Please respond."
Aizawa Takeru.
pRe
ParE
"Prepare for inkvasion!"
!
That should do it.
If that ends up in the wrong country,
you're gonna cause a diplomatic incident.
There!
I can't squidly wait to get a reply
from whoever gets them!
Yeah, me neither!
My bottle from yesterday
has squidturned!
I don't see mine anywhere, though.
It must be because of the waves.
Go further!
Why the squid is it coming back?
It's up to the sea where it goes.
Maybe it doesn't like
.the message I wrote.
It's the sea, not a spam filter...
I'll ink another!
What are you writing this time?
Mind your own squidness!
This time...
It got thrown back!
The sea just won't accept it.
I ink it hates me...
Weren't you supposed to be
the messenger of the sea?
So you want this bottle to reach
a current that'll carry it away?
Just leave it to me,
..Cindy Campbell, and...
...the three finest minds of MIT!
We've got it covered!
The Three Stooges!
This state-of-the-art rocket launcher
features our most advanced technology!
The Flying Thunder!
It uses liquid-hydrogen–
fueled propulsion!
Our precise calculations allow it to
maintain the perfect angle and trajectory!
That sounds squidding awesome!
Okay, nerds, how about you launch it?
Starting countdown!
Ten!
Nine!
Eight!
This is the launch trigger.
Seven!
Six!
Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
One!
Fire!
You trying to kill us?!
I guess we used a bit too much fuel.
That was more than just a bit!
Don't worry. Let's try again.
This will take it to the current!
Squids away!
Oh no!
Oh my God!
It couldn't carry
the bottle's weight!
Could you guys stop
screwing around already?!
Scientists never lie!
Yeah, we're really
trying our hardest!
This is weird.
Where could the problem lie?
It's in your thick skulls!
This time, it'll be just fine.
I sure hope so.
This time, it'll launch
for squidly sure!
How far did you send that thing?!
We tried to launch it
.as far as possible.
Looks like it left the stratosphere!
So much for that!
This time...
By the way...
Why don't you just
throw it with your tentacles?
You're right!
I ink that one did it.
But seriously, how could you
forget about your tentacles?
Looks like it managed
.to drift away.
Squid-sis!
Are you okay?
What's this squidding
trench doing here?!
It wasn't here yesterday.
More importantly,
where's my reply?
How could anyone
reply so soon?
F-R-I-E-N-D.
Gimme
a
squidding
big
shrimp!
When I act strong, I can't be honest
tsuyogari de sunao ni narenai
I want to make up with you, but it never works
nakanaori shitai kedo
We just say whatever comes to mind
iitai koto wo iiatteru you de
and forget to say the really important things
daiji na koto wa ienai yo
This feels a little embarrassing
nandaka hazukashii you na
No, I just want you to understand me
chigau wakattehoshii you na
Neither my head nor my heart
atama to kimochi ga
are listening to you
iu koto kikanakute
I want to say "Thank you,"
arigatou tte iitakute
and although we quarrel sometimes
demo toki ni senaka awase de
because we're so close,
chikasugite kenka mo suru
I know you feel the same way
demo kimi mo onaji kimochi da to
I know that
itai hodo
so well that it hurts,
wakatteiru yo
but tomorrow,
ashita ni wa
we will laugh again
waratteru