Inari, konkon!
Change into Mom!
Hey, Inari!
Huh?
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
nanige naku tsuita tameiki wa
I sighed involuntarily
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
takai takai sora no mukou ni
and that little bit of sadness
habataite kietetta
flew with the birds to vanish in the distance
guuzen no misu mo waratte shake hands
We committed our share of faux-pas, then shook hands
sonna fuu ni otona ni wa narenakatta keredo
That didn't really turn us into adults,
ima wa sukoshi wakaru yo
but now I understand
akogareta dareka no kage wo nazoru dake ja
that just imitating those you admire
kimi ni todokanai tte
is not enough to reach you
nee itsuka tsutaeru yo
One day I'll tell you of my feelings
dakishimeta negaigoto kimi ni mitsukaranai you ni
I didn't want you to know of my wishes,
watashi no koe ni tokasu yo
so I lowered my voice
kamisama ni sasayaita
and whispered to the gods
mainichi ni koi shiteru kono kirameki tayasanaide
Every day I feel the love inside my heart and hope I won't faint
somatta hoo wo naderu kaze
The wind turns my cheeks red
itsu made mo tonari de waratteite
Please keep smiling next to me
Wh-What now?!
Mom, where's Inari?
Oh, right! He didn't see me before I transformed!
M-Maybe the bathroom?
Hmm, okay.
What a shock!
Scarlet,
Festival Eve,
Romance
Scarlet,
Festival Eve,
Romance
Oh, Touka. The bath's ready.
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
But
she's
here
...
What is it, Touka?
Dad, Mom...
Inari... may have been endowed with divine power.
There you go again!
Isn't it about time you grew out of that stuff?
Okay, so that didn't come out right.
But this isn't some kind of manga, so it can't be true.
Can it?
Inari! Bath's free!
C-Coming!
Touka sure is keepin' a super-close eye on me.
Better go to sleep.
I'll join you!
Staare
Wh-What's all this?!
Please let me be the one person you tell the truth to,
Uka!
Oh, what to do?
Lady Uka!
Ah, Inari!
Today's the last day of the semester, ri—
I see. So Touka wouldn't leave you alone.
Funny how we both have clingy older brothers
givin' us a hard time.
Lady Uka, when we were at the Celestial Plains the other day,
Great Amaterasu and I were discussing how we might retrieve your power from Miss Inari.
But even she didn't have the slightest clue.
If I give you your power back,
my brother will leave me alone.
But then I won't be able to see you, Kon, or the others anymore.
Say, Inari...
Tomorrow's the eve of the festival.
Oh, right! I'll be there for sure.
With Tanbabashi, perhaps?
N-No, of course not!
He comes every year with his family. You'll definitely see him there.
I will?
I'll tell Touka nothing's going on so that you can live a normal life again.
That's what I want for you, after all.
Lady Uka...
Okay!
It's going to loosen up a bit as you move,
so I'll tie it a little tighter to begin with.
Now, hold this.
All set!
You don't think this color's a little childish?
I told you, it's fine. It looks good on you.
Enjoying yourself, Lady Uka?
I can't wait!
Hey, Mom!
Do I look weird with this hairpin?
I think it might be too gaudy.
Oh, nice! Here, let me help you with that.
Really? It's not too much?
It's super cute!
Ow, ow, ow!
Inari! Time to go!
Oh, right.
New sandals?
You've grown out of last year's.
Thanks, Mom!
Do they chafe at all?
You might want to wear some thin socks.
Nope, I'm good. See you!
Sumizome!
Wow! That yukata's the cutest!
So is yours!
And I love that sash!
It's so you!
You really think so?
I picked it up on sale last summer, and...
Huh?
That hairpin...
Doesn't it look just like Anze's?
Like on the cover of the manga I lent you,
Midnight Thrills volume twelve!
Oh, right! That was such a cute picture!
Do I really look like her?
Yeah, totally! Have you read it?
Uh-huh!
Just remembering that one scene,
where Anze is under attack by the demon envoy,
...to
kill
you!
Bring
it!
Is
that
all?
Ba-dump
and Manabe comes to save her...
I know! She's so scared of men, but then something like love stirs within her...
Couldn't you just cry?!
Miss Inari? Miss Inari!
Oh, yeah. Keiko and Maru said they'd be waitin' out front.
Then let's get going!
Yeah!
It's pretty crowded. Let's go 'round that way.
Sure!
So, whose team are you on, Sumizome?
Hmm... I guess I'm rooting for Manabe.
I thought so!
What's wrong?
I get the feeling we're being followed.
By who?
I don't know. It just feels like someone's behind—
Hey, you two! Get down!
Splendid!
You okay, Inari?
And... Oh, Sumizome.
What was that all about?
Miss Inari, that's, uh... Master Toshi.
Huh?
Master Toshi, are you still alive?
What an unparalleled pleasure,
being punted by a girl...
I'll hand him over to the police.
Keiko, you take over from here.
You all right?
Oh, uh, thank y—
Huh?
Well, as long as you're okay.
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Hey, Inari, why'd you bring her along?
Why not? The more the merrier!
Um, Manabe—
I mean, Sanjo, what's your favorite festival food?
Skewers, maybe? The pork belly ones.
Oh, so you like skewers, huh, Manabe—I mean, Sanjo?
You sure are slippin' up a lot tonight, Sumizome.
No way... right?
Shooting Gallery
Hey, a shootin' gallery!
I'm in!
You sure are into all this guy stuff.
Is something the matter, Fushimi?
Nope! Nothing at all.
Let's hope Tanbabashi comes.
Yeah... Huh?
I knew it! I knew you were into him!
Yeah...
But how could you tell?
While I was reading that manga you lent me,
I noticed that Anze's face when she's talking with Manabe
looks just like yours when you're talking with Tanbabashi.
Whoa, a little shoujo manga's
a dangerous thing!
No wonder they call it Romance 101!
Yeowch!
Hey! Whaddaya think you're doin'?!
Kids, don't try this at home!
Hmm?
Huh? What's so...
M-My hair! Does it look weird?
And my face! Well, there's no fixin' that...
You're fine.
In fact, Fushimi, you're adorable!
See ya!
Now all we can do is pray.
Which one are you gunnin' for?
That watch.
The batteries in mine just went kaput.
That one's so cute!
Here goes!
Congratulations. You've won yourself a bunny!
Hey, good for you!
What good's a bunny?
Actually, uh—
Eh, whatever.
Inari'll probably like it.
Huh? Fushimi!
Oh, hi! Fancy meetin' you here!
Are you here on your own?
Y-Yep!
Well, somethin' like that, anyway...
Kouji, I'm taking Shirou to the Bon dance, okay?
Then I'll come, too.
No, no. You stay with Fushimi.
Got it?
Uh-huh.
Mother dear!
Well, then... Shall we?
O-Okay!
You wanna get something to eat?
Huh? Well, uh...
Takoyaki... A hot dog?
No. I don't wanna get my mouth too messy.
Sh-Shaved ice!
Shaved ice it is, then.
You know, Fushimi, you look
real cute in that yukata.
Cute
C-Cute?!
This is it. I'm gonna die today, aren't I?
Ah, there's the shaved ice stand.
Pardon me.
Whew, that startled—Huh?
Tanbabashi?
Tanbabashi!
This sucks...
Just when we were finally alone together...
Ta—
Thank goodness!
Don't worry!
Wow...
My heart's beatin' so fast,
it feels like it's about to burst.
What about him?
The sucked-in stomach, the awkward sandals—
everything I've endured for the sake of fashion
has been to make his heart race, too.
I guess it'd be just plain selfish to want anything more right now.
I can feel Inari's joy.
It's like nothing I've ever experienced before.
This yearning for someone from the bottom of one's heart...
Tonight we celebrate!
You've had too much to drink, Lady Uka.
And what's wrong with that, huh?
To tell the truth, I'm a little envious.
I see now.
Inari was right. He is just like my brother.
You rang?
Who's a snookums?
Huh?
What is it?
I just heard this familiar-soundin' scream...
Seriously? I didn't hear a thing.
Must've been your imagination.
Yep! Just my imagination!
Officer!
Oh, Uka! You've finally let me touch you again!
How'd he get in here?
Didn't I set up that barrier?
Oh, Uka!
You've finally chosen to dispel that barrier and embrace me!
I-It couldn't be...
Never fear. It only hurts the first time.
Could I be... running out of divine power?!
You've been manhandling Inari just like this, haven't you?!
Don't lump me together with him!
Wh-What...
What's this feeling in the air?
Maybe... we look like a couple too.
You all right, Fushimi?
Uh-huh. Sorry... Ow!
Sandals rubbin' you sore, huh?
Oh, I'll be fine.
I'm tougher than I look! So, uh...
Huh?!
I'll give you a lift.
Can't have you makin' it worse.
You're a girl, after all.
The shrine...
The festival...
I'm glad there's all this red around.
Hold on tight, now!
I'm blushin' like crazy,
but this way Tanbabashi won't notice.
What do you wanna do next?
Hit up another food stall, maybe?
Or we could buy some drinks and take a breather.
It's just like back then.
Say, Tanbabashi.
Have you gotten a bit taller?
Huh?
It just seems like you have, compared to last year.
Your shoulders are wider, too.
Yeah, I've been havin' growin' pains lately.
I ache all over.
Didn't think you'd notice, since you see me every day. You've got a sharp eye!
Oh, totally!
I mean, I have been watchin' you all this time!
Huh?
I-I mean, uh, that is...
I-I've taken up people watchin' as a hobby!
People watching?
Yep! I'm so clueless and clumsy that I figured I could improve myself by watchin' people!
Phew, dodged that bullet.
But I know I can't put off tellin' him forever.
Eh, it's all right.
This fire's barely kindled,
and I'm happy enough with things the way they are right now.
Uka!
I'm totally into bondage, just so you know!
H-Hey, are you sure about this?
Hush! And don't make eye contact!
Hey. Hey, listen!
Did... You didn't give any, you know...
You didn't give any divine power to Inari... did you?
You bastard! Get your filthy hands off my Uka!
Can't you tell she doesn't like that, you pervert?!
Uka, you poor thing!
Look who's talking!
L-Lady Uka!
Well? Answer me!
I-It's nothing, really.
I wanted to make friends with a human—with Inari—
so I made it so she could see us gods. That's all.
And I should believe that, right?
You're not lyin' to me, right?
Sorry for all the meddlin'.
Forgive me, Touka.
Wh-What are you apologizing for?
You need not worry yourself on account of that rabble!
Touka is my friend!
It's only natural to feel guilty
about lying to a friend!
Do humans even deserve to
become friendly with the gods?
We gods must treat all humans even-handedly.
Th-That much I know! I—
Then I'm sure you're also aware that even as humans confide in the gods,
their brief lifespans flash past us
in the blink of an eye.
Honestly, I don't think it's such a good idea
for you to get so close to—
It's fine!
I've chosen the proper path. I'm sure of it!
I just...
I just want to catch a glimpse of their happiness,
even if only for a moment.
And then...
If I'd never met Lady Uka,
none of this would ever have happened.
Now it's my turn to help her find happiness, too.
watashi wa naze koko ni ite
Why am I here
aisuru sube mo shiranaide
if I don't know how to love
sukuwareru toki wo yume mite ikiteita
I lived my life dreaming of salvation
unmei no kodou ni makasete yanagi no michi wo nukete
I rode my bicycle home past endless willows
jitensha de kaetta
and left my life to the vagaries of fate
chiisana dekigoto ni
The waves of life
yosete wa kaesu mainichi ni
break on the little things around me
anata ga soba ni ite
Please be with me
watashi ni hikari wo ataetekureta kara
You gave me the light
you saved me
You saved me
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
See you next time !