Inari...
You shut Uka up in the Ama-no-Iwato?
Yes.
She's grown much too close to humans.
She must remember who she's meant to be.
The more Inari uses that divine power, the more Uka loses herself.
You wouldn't want that to happen, would you?
Sis...
She needs some time by herself to do some soul-searching...
in the Ama-no-Iwato, which only we can open.
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
nanige naku tsuita tameiki wa
I sighed involuntarily
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
takai takai sora no mukou ni
and that little bit of sadness
habataite kietetta
flew with the birds to vanish in the distance
guuzen no misu mo waratte shake hands
We committed our share of faux-pas, then shook hands
sonna fuu ni otona ni wa narenakatta keredo
That didn't really turn us into adults,
ima wa sukoshi wakaru yo
but now I understand
akogareta dareka no kage wo nazoru dake ja
that just imitating those you admire
kimi ni todokanai tte
is not enough to reach you
nee itsuka tsutaeru yo
One day I'll tell you of my feelings
dakishimeta negaigoto kimi ni mitsukaranai you ni
I didn't want you to know of my wishes,
watashi no koe ni tokasu yo
so I lowered my voice
kamisama ni sasayaita
and whispered to the gods
mainichi ni koi shiteru kono kirameki tayasanaide
Every day I feel the love inside my heart and hope I won't faint
somatta hoo wo naderu kaze
The wind turns my cheeks red
itsu made mo tonari de waratteite
Please keep smiling next to me
Huh? Lady Uka's not back yet?
But it's November!
Well, it's never really exactly one month...
We can only assume she must still be in Izumo.
Huh.
I wonder when she's coming back.
So anyway, the last boss is crazy hard.
You should give it a shot one of these days.
Sure! Let me borrow it sometime.
There you are, Kouji!
Okay, see you later!
Sure.
Bye!
You two sure are friendly these days!
Huh? Wait... Don't tell me...
You're into Fushimi?
K-Keep it to yourself, okay?
Fox,
Twilight,
Milky Way
Fox,
Twilight,
Milky Way
U-Um...
I'm sorry. I wanted to apologize.
When I wrote you that letter, I... I didn't know.
Letter? What letter?
M-My confession of love?
I asked Fushimi of all people to give it to you. I'm sorry.
A letter?
I never got any letter.
What's up, Minami?
The letter...
Fushimi never...
What's wrong with me? How can I be so distracted at such a crucial time?
You can tell me everything.
I...
I don't want to fade away.
No!
Getting my divine power back from Inari would solve everything,
but not being able to see Inari anymore would be even worse!
Touka?
What?
Do you have a minute?
Lady Uka still hasn't returned.
When will she be back?
How should I know? Quit buggin' me!
Don't talk to me like that!
Excuse me for interrupting your studies!
Where is she, and what's she up to?
What a drag.
We gotta pick up litter now? Seriously?
I'm looking forward to it.
A real, live angel!
But it looks like rain.
If it rains, can we go home?
Always looking for a way out, huh?
Uh, Fushimi?
Here.
A charm?
Expel Evil, Invite Fortune
Yasaka
Shrine
Charm
You gave me one ages ago, not to mention a souvenir from the beach,
but I still haven't given you anything in return.
If you don't need it,
you can just throw it away.
Thanks, Tanbabashi! I love it!
S-Sure.
Where are you cleanin' up?
Just over the bridge. Not far from here.
Are all the guys workin' up past Yotsutsuji?
Yeah. Just gettin' up to the
Ganriki shrine is exhausting!
I can believe it!
We're still better off than Miyamaki. He's way up on the shrine summit.
Inari...
I'm so glad it worked out!
Don't exaggerate.
When you have social anxiety,
being put into a random group is a matter of life and death!
You gotta try to do something about that anxiety of yours, Maru.
Well, what would a normie know about it, anyway?
You'll be fine!
The geeks in all those romantic comedies all end up pretty normal by the end.
Well, here's our assigned area.
So those two are together, huh?
Go get 'em!
C-Could we please have...
some... garbage bags...
It's been a whole year and she doesn't know her classmates' names, but look at Maru go!
Hey! Why are you ignorin' her?
Are you out of bags?
Did I do somethin' to deserve the silent treatment?
If it's somethin' I did, just tell me!
What's the big idea, ignorin' us both like that?
I feel so blah.
The sooner we finish,
the sooner we can go home.
Let's do this!
You're a hard worker, huh?
You think?
Everyone else is just doin' the bare minimum.
Wh-What is it?
You got some dirt in your hair.
It's not comin' out.
Your hair's so pretty. Why don't you put it up?
P-Pretty?!
Anyone got a hair tie?
Hey!
Ow!
I'm talkin' here!
S-Sanjou! Calm down!
What're you whisperin' about, huh? It's creepy!
Don't think I'm afraid to hit a girl!
It's okay. I promise I won't get mad.
Tell me what's wrong.
Huh?
We're sorry. We didn't want to ignore you.
It's Kangetsu, in Class E.
Who's that?
The girl who's always with Momoyama.
Kangetsu's the one who told us to ignore you.
Why?
Kangetsu? Where is she?
Inari!
There's no use broodin' about it.
Maru doesn't deserve to be caught up in this with me.
Kangetsu!
Why are you ignorin' us? Why be so mean?
If it's my fault, I apologize, but leave my friends—
Who's the mean one here, huh?
Minami trusted you with that letter,
but instead of giving it to Tanbabashi, you threw it away!
That letter...
To Tanbabashi
Could you... give it to Tanbabashi for me?
C'mon, help a girl out! For love!
You pretended to be on her side,
then you tossed the letter and
cozied up to Tanbabashi yourself!
How could you?
You're despicable!
The letter... got caught up in a gust of wind...
Don't even!
Same difference.
I didn't give it to him, so I might as well have thrown it away.
I've always liked you.
I changed into Momoyama and told him in person instead of by letter.
I thought it was taken care of,
but I left her hanging.
See? You hurt my friend first!
But I didn't mean to...
I didn't... but now the people who care about Momoyama are angry.
All because I used my divine power without thinkin'.
Inari?
She probably only became friends with Sumizome to get closer to Tanbabashi.
Wow, sucking up to popular girls just to use them? How low can you get?
But Sumizome's been pretending to hang with the basketball team, hasn't she?
Yeah! They're birds of a feather, all right!
But—
You are way wrong!
You don't know the first thing about Inari or Sumizome!
You watch your mouth!
Get your hands off me!
I don't wanna catch your nerd germs!
Maru!
What...
Miss Inari!
Inari!
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari...
What's goin' on?
Kouji!
What is all this?
Huh?
I think... These girls... I...
I hate them.
Inari!
Everybody hit the ground and don't move!
Miss Inari!
You mustn't! Inari!
Inari...
Inari!
Did she just...
Lady Uka!
Inari. Inari...
Lady Uka...
I've done it again!
I... I...
It's all right. I'll protect you.
Lady Uka...
Let's climb down now,
while we have the chance!
Hey!
We're doing roll call! Hurry up!
We'll talk later. Go, quickly.
Thank you!
Come on. Let's head back down.
It's under control.
Thank goodness, Inari.
It's calmed down.
Good thing, too.
Inari! Maru!
You're all right!
Momoyama, could you explain?
What's going on, Kyouko?
Is it true you've been telling
people to ignore Fushimi?
B-But she did such a rotten thing to you, and... I got angry.
I never told you to do any such thing!
What?! But you were so depressed!
W-Well...
Did she do anythin' to you?
No, that's not it.
I'm so sorry!
I... I...
The mean part of me that didn't want to hand over that letter
took control of that divine power.
You poured your heart into that letter,
and I threw it away.
Please... Please forgive me!
Fushimi...
By any chance... do you like Tanbabashi?
Uh-huh. I'm so sorry.
But you told him how I feel, right?
When he heard about the letter, he said he was still flattered.
So I think I can forgive you.
Momoyama...
I mean, I don't think most people could tell someone they like
that another person has feelings for them.
All I did was use the power of the gods
to change into someone else
and say what I could never say myself.
I don't deserve your forgiveness.
Hey, aren't you forgettin' something?
Say you're sorry!
We're sorry.
I...
Inari!
Touka?
Come with me.
What was with that earthquake?
Tell me that wasn't your divine power!
Oh, right! Lady Uka!
What about her?!
The divine power surged out of me,
but Lady Uka rescued me...
Miss Inari!
Miya!
Please hurry! It's Lady Uka!
Wait, what? You're sneaking out, and we have to cover for you?
I think we can manage.
Right?
Yep.
Thank you!
Lady Uka is fading away?
What do you mean?
Well, uh...
It's your fault.
Her divine power grows fainter
every time you use that power.
No... That can't be true.
Well, it is.
If Inari keeps on using that divine power, then...
my divinity—my very godliness itself—will move into her.
And if that happens...
You changed into her at Izumo, didn't you?
She was in a real bad way.
When I confronted her, that's what she told me.
No...
Then what was that?
It's all right. I'll protect you.
Miya?
It's true.
Great Amaterasu has said the same about using such power in that way.
Touka, why would she tell you something so important but not tell me?!
Because she didn't want to not be able to see you anymore.
Because she didn't want you to worry.
It's not that she didn't tell you.
It's that she couldn't.
No...
If that's true...
If I had known, I...
Touka! I need money!
What?
I'm going to Izumo! I have to see her!
Uh, Miss Inari?
Lady Uka isn't actually in Izumo.
She's at the Celestial Plains.
The Celestial Plains?
How can I...
No way, no how! I'm exhausted!
What good are you?
Lady Uka... Lady Uka...
Lady Uka!
Kon?!
Kon, what's wrong?
What... What's going on?
When I look back, I realize
that I spent my days of joy in fear of losing them
Miss Inari! This way!
Let's go, Miss Inari!
Long ago, I resolved
to one day be free,
Honestly...
Humans can't handle godly powers.
and to that end
I mustered all my determination
I know you knew that much, Uka!
Why do you hold mortal ties in such high regard?
Back then I kept hidden
Do you really think Inari can
respond to those feelings of yours?
much of my weakness
Great Amaterasu!
Where's Uka?
Has something happened to her?
from those around me
Miss Inari!
I'm... okay...
But I hesitated, got hurt,
Let's go!
and lost so much of what I treasured
Lady Uka...
Lady Uka!
Inari...
I didn't know.
I was all alone
This is all because I gave you my divine power.
You've been the one protectin' me all this time.
But I met you,
I just wanted you to be a normal girl.
Lady Uka, I... I...
But I also wanted to stay friends with you, so I...
and you taught me the joy of living
Now I'll protect you!
I'm sorry, Inari.
Lady Uka, you can have your divine power back.
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
See you next time !