30 days till the Cultural Festival!
Festival
Committee:
Sumizome + Koudo
Class Play:
"The Fairytale Prince"
by Hashimoto
King...  Demon Lord... Princess...  Prince...     Roles:
Please... Please...
Role Draw
Class Play:
"The Fairytale Prince"
by Hashimoto
King...  Demon Lord... Princess...  Prince...   Roles:
Let me get the role of Tanbabashi's lover!
Princess:                                          Prince: .....
Fushimi                                       Tanbabashi
Inari                                             Kouji
What a shocking development!
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
nanige naku tsuita tameiki wa
I sighed involuntarily
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
takai takai sora no mukou ni
and that little bit of sadness
habataite kietetta
flew with the birds to vanish in the distance
guuzen no misu mo waratte shake hands
We committed our share of faux-pas, then shook hands
sonna fuu ni otona ni wa narenakatta keredo
That didn't really turn us into adults,
ima wa sukoshi wakaru yo
but now I understand
akogareta dareka no kage wo nazoru dake ja
that just imitating those you admire
kimi ni todokanai tte
is not enough to reach you
nee itsuka tsutaeru yo
One day I'll tell you of my feelings
dakishimeta negaigoto kimi ni mitsukaranai you ni
I didn't want you to know of my wishes,
watashi no koe ni tokasu yo
so I lowered my voice
kamisama ni sasayaita
and whispered to the gods
mainichi ni koi shiteru kono kirameki tayasanaide
Every day I feel the love inside my heart and hope I won't faint
somatta hoo wo naderu kaze
The wind turns my cheeks red
itsu made mo tonari de waratteite
Please keep smiling next to me
Akio
What seems to be the matter?
You look unwell.
I have just the thing to make you better.
Doctor's orders.
Lady Uka!
A medicine called... love.
Maiden,
Aflutter,
Madder Red
Maiden,
Aflutter,
Madder Red
Good for you, Inari!
To think you'd get the part of Tanbabashi's love interest in the cultural festival play!
You must be over the moon!
I'm a little nervous, though.
Like I'm just waitin' for the other shoe to drop.
Inari...
I mean, October's comin' up.
Won't you be goin' to Izumo
with all the other gods?
Never fear.
No matter what happens, I'll look out for you.
Lady Uka...
Pardon me, Lady Uka.
Miya!
Oh, good day, Miss Inari.
Come in! What brings you here out of the blue?
Lady Uka,
To Uka
I carry a missive from your mother,
Kamu-Oichi-Hime.
To Uka
From Mother?
Uka!
You'll attend the dates I arrange for you
next month, or I'll burn up every last scrap
of the oh-so-precious junk you left behind!
Uka's Room
Got it?!
Oh, Miya, whatever shall I do?
Well, if you have a particular god in mind...
You know I don't!
Then is there someone you simply enjoy
being with, even if there's no love involved?
You know I—
Impossible...
Lady Uka?
Er, Lady Uka?
If there's something bothering you,
you can tell me, okay?
I'll help you! We're friends, you and I!
Thank you, Inari.
It'll be okay.
Sure, I'm a little nervous,
but if Lady Uka says it's
gonna be fine, then it will be.
Right now, I'm gonna enjoy my lucky break!
What?! A kissing scene?!
I thought it might make a bigger impact if we put one in.
Okay? You won't actually kiss.
B-B-But—
Uh, er, I—
You're okay with this, right, Kouji?!
Yeah.
S-So casual!
This part, right?
Yep, that's it.
Fushimi?
Yes?!
Looks like we've got our work cut out for us, huh?
I'll be counting on you.
Sure!
Fujinokusa
Middle
School
Cultural
Festival
Fujinokusa
spirit
comes
alive!
Don't miss this year's festival!
A kissing scene, huh?
Hmm? Why the ugly expression?
Master Ootoshi...
What are you doing?
I was bored, so I thought I'd come hang out in your world.
Plenty of pure girls here, after all.
Girls?!
What is with you?
Kouji! Get a load of this!
For someone so head-over-heels for Lady Uka, you sure flirt a lot!
Unhand my face, you wretch!
Shut up! I'll stretch you silly!
Turns out that hottie is Fushimi's boyfriend!
That's rich! I don't even need to stretch yours!
Streeeetch! Streee—
You're going through with the arranged dating, Lady Uka?
No, I haven't really made up my mind ye—
Uh... Hey.
You haven't been by lately. Everything okay?
Oh, has it been that long? I've just been so busy...
What the hell was that?
It's like I'm straight up askin' her over!
Cut that out, dummy!
Um, Touka?
I, uh...
I might have to go on some arranged dates.
Next month is October.
All of Japan's gods meet up at Izumo, and I am no exception.
My mother sees it as her chance to try to set me up with someone.
I... I see.
Do you have a special someone, Touka?
I-I'm not telling you that!
Then what's your type?
Why are you askin' me?
Well, embarrassingly enough, you're the only man I can talk to about such things.
Mountain
Pilgrimage
Route
Main Shrine,
770 m
Gods may declare their "passionate love" for me,
but all they see is my status.
Are human men the same way?
If someone falls for you, consider it a compliment.
Nobody likes a cynic.
I'm telling you, they only love me for my status!
Did they tell you that?
Or are you just afraid it's true?
Women are so damn self-conscious!
Why are men so quick to paint
all women with the same brush?
It's downright rude!
Because you women treat our feelings with nothin' but contempt!
Like you could understand a woman's feelings! No wonder you can't get a girlfriend!
A-A woman's feelings, you say?
The only womanly part of you is your boobs!
Should I squeeze 'em?!
No!
This is ridiculous.
Go on and have your little
arranged dates or whatever.
Maybe they'll teach a game nerd like you a thing or two about bein' a woman.
Fine! I will!
I'll go on tons of dates!
You do that!
We're through!
And not a moment too soon!
Goodbye!
You're the one who saved me, aren't you?
Won't you tell me your name, princess?
Yes. My name is...
Aaaand screwed it up again.
Always in the same spot, too.
Feeling the pressure, Miss Inari?
What with the kissing scene—
It's not like we're really gonna kiss, okay?!
And yet, you certainly have been in a good mood all day.
That's not it at all!
I'm happy for you.
It's all thanks to that divine power.
M-Miss Inari?
What do you mean, "divine power"?
Well, uh... when drawing your role in the play,
you subconsciously used your divine power to pull the "lover" card.
D-Did I say something I shouldn't have?
So I cheated.
I cheated! I...
Whoa!
C'mon, Fushimi, that's "Yes, handsome gentleman. My name is..." Right?
S-Sorry! Let's see, um...
Fushimi?
About the kissing scene...
We don't have to do it if you don't want to, you know.
Huh?
We still have time to change the script.
Why now, all of a sudden?
U-Uh, Tanbabashi...
I don't—
Tanbabashi!
Gimme a hand. I can't reach!
Sure thing!
I'll go with you when you tell Hashimo, okay?
Why?
What's goin' on?
Why would he just up and say such a thing?
13 days
till the
Cultural
Festival!
13 days
till the
Cultural
Festival!
Because I cheated, that's why.
Fushimi!
How many times are you gonna mess this up? You haven't gotten the line right once!
I-I'm sorry! Just one more time?
Time's up.
Let's continue in the classroom!
Okay!
I'm the worst.
I cheated to get the part, and now I'm holdin' everyone back.
Oh, sorry, Inari.
Didn't see ya there.
Keiko...
Keiko!
Hurry up, or we'll miss out on the sewin' machines again!
Coming!
Hang in there, Inari.
Okay!
Miss Inari...
U-Um...
You're Fushimi, right? From Class A?
Attagirl!
Y-Yeah, that's me...
You're in Class E, right?
I'm Momoyama!
Um... here.
What's... what's this?
To Tanbabashi
Could you... give it to Tanbabashi for me?
She's liked Tanbabashi since first year.
I always knew.
You and Tanbabashi seem pretty friendly these days, so...
Lots of other girls like Tanbabashi.
C'mon, help a girl out! For love!
That much I knew.
Leave it to me!
Have I been shovin' them aside all this time with my divine powers?
I'm so sorry, but I...
I'm droppin' out of the play.
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
I'm so sorry, but I...
I'm droppin' out of the play.
You're quitting?!
This late in the game?
How come? Is there a reason?
W-Well, I... I can't seem to learn my lines, for one thing...
I'm just not sure of myself.
That's no reason to quit, though.
Um... if you need someone...
Are you sure? Can you learn the lines if you start now?
I think so. I'm pretty good at memorizing stuff.
The costume probably won't have to be altered, either.
I'm sorry.
Okay, take it from this scene.
Let's see... Here? Okay.
What?
The hell's she thinkin'?!
Dunno. Maybe she couldn't do the kissing scene with her boyfriend around?
Boy—
Boyfriend? Whose boyfriend?!
Y'know, Fushimi's boyfriend. Real hunky type.
Where'd you hear that?!
We saw her getting all friendly
with this hot guy. Right?
Y-Yeah.
I would expect other boys to jump to conclusions like that, but not you, Tanbabashi.
Wh-Why single me out?
Look, we're her friends, and if we know one thing, it's that Inari does not have a boyfriend!
That's the bell! I've got to get to the committee meeting!
So that's what Sumizome looks like when she's mad.
G-Gap moe...
Fushimi doesn't have a boyfriend, then?
Phew.
Huh? Wait... "Phew"?
I gotta get this to him.
Momoyama poured her heart into it, after all.
Even though I don't really want to.
To Tanbabashi
Hey! Whoa!
Kon, was that... Did I just...
Y-Yes. That was likely another
manifestation of divine power.
But why? Why do I do all this awful stuff?
And with Lady Uka's special power, no less!
Why? Why?
M-Miss Inari!
I'm such a cheat.
I hate myself like this!
Lady Uka?
Something just...
Could it be?
Inari...
Inari, konkon!
Change into Momoyama!
Miss Inari! What do you think you're doing?!
I'm going to confess to Tanbabashi.
But you can't!
Using your divine power that way won't end well for anyone!
I know that!
I know... but...
Miss Inari...
I... I...
I don't know what to do!
Tanbabashi? But why—
Uh, sorry to spring this on you, but...
Have you seen a girl around here?
About yay tall?
He actually came to look for me?
Selfish old me?
What—
I like you.
I've always liked you, ever since first year.
Funny how easy it comes out
when you look like someone else.
But the truth is...
I wanted to tell him as myself.
I like you, Tanbabashi.
I love you.
Huh? Er, uh...
I'm sorry!
B-But I'm flattered, I really am. Thank you.
I-It's all right...
H-Hey, can I ask you somethin'?
What, uh... What's love feel like?
W-Well...
I'm so sorry!
I just... don't really know.
Um, it's... H-How do I put this simply...
Let's see...
It's when they're all you think about.
All you dream about.
You try hard to impress them,
but you mess up and get depressed,
and you're too shy to look them in the eye.
And when you peek at them from afar, you see their not-so-hot side, too.
Still, you can't help wantin'
to get to know them better.
I know! Maybe being in love is like an obsession!
But, uh, maybe that's too simple an explanation.
No...
I think it's spot on.
Miss Inari, it's about time...
Oh, uh, I'd better be going.
An obsession, huh?
I'm droppin' out of the play.
Why would she say that?
What is she thinking?
Why is she crying?
I want to know more.
I mean, I have been watchin' you all this time!
More about you, the one who's been watchin' me.
Oh, wow. I guess that means...
I love Fushimi.
I knew it wouldn't work out.
I wasn't putting much effort into
making him love me back, for one.
When a girl like that tells you she loves you,
of course you'd turn her down.
I'll have to try harder myself next time.
Right!
It feels like it's been so long.
I'm really sorry. I was flat out preparin' for the cultural festival.
Don't be. I'm just glad you were having fun.
Have you finally grown accustomed to your role as Tanbabashi's lover?
Oh, that...
I, uh, I dropped out of the play.
What?! But why?
You seemed so thrilled about it before.
Well, bein' a stagehand is pretty excitin', too!
Hard work, though.
Inari?
So, uh... You haven't been playing games with my brother much, huh?
N-No, that's right.
Touka's been rather busy himself, it seems.
Oh, okay...
Any good games come out lately?
Maybe we could go head-to-head on something!
The real reason Miss Inari quit the play is that she'd accidentally used her divine power to get the part.
It really started to bother her, and so...
So it was because of my divine power?
Fujinokusa Festival
Tarot
Readings
Our next program is a play
by our second-years in Class A.
The princess is mine!
Not so fast!
dizzy
Stagehand! Here! Now!
Coming!
dizzy
Won't you tell me your name, princess?
Yes, handsome gentleman.
Fushimi! We need help with this backdrop!
dizzy
O-On it!
Won't you accompany me, Your Highness?
You'll need this next, prince!
Thank you.
I might have to go on some arranged dates.
Your hands
are sooo big,
Touka!
What am I doin'?!
Riiip
Dammit.
I'm goin' to the shrine!
What? Arranged dates?
Yes. I'm about to leave for Izumo.
I suppose it's convenient,
what with all those gods in town.
But you were so set against it!
When are you comin' back?
Even if I get married, I can always see you,
so long as that divine power remains within you.
We can still be friends.
Touka!
Divine power? Inside Inari?
You said you didn't do anythin' to her.
You lied to me!
No! I—
Lady Uka, it's time!
T-Time to leave this world behind!
Wait—
watashi wa naze koko ni ite
Why am I here
aisuru sube mo shiranaide
if I don't know how to love
sukuwareru toki wo yume mite ikiteita
I lived my life dreaming of salvation
unmei no kodou ni makasete yanagi no michi wo nukete
I rode my bicycle home past endless willows
jitensha de kaetta
and left my life to the vagaries of fate
chiisana dekigoto ni
The waves of life
yosete wa kaesu mainichi ni
break on the little things around me
anata ga soba ni ite
Please be with me
watashi ni hikari wo ataetekureta kara
You gave me the light
you saved me
You saved me
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
See you next time !