You said you didn't do anythin' to her.
You lied to me!
No! I—
Lady Uka, it's time!
T-Time to leave this world behind!
Wait—
That was three days ago.
Touka hasn't said a word since.
More to the point,
why does Lady Uka have to
do all this datin' stuff now?
Hey.
Hey!
Wh-What?
The cultural festival's over,
so I know you have time to spare.
You're comin' with me today.
I have a test to study for.
Come on. You never study until the last minute anyway.
You're just gonna spend all day
muckin' around, so come with me.
Er... Where to?
Izumo.
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
nanige naku tsuita tameiki wa
I sighed involuntarily
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
takai takai sora no mukou ni
and that little bit of sadness
habataite kietetta
flew with the birds to vanish in the distance
guuzen no misu mo waratte shake hands
We committed our share of faux-pas, then shook hands
sonna fuu ni otona ni wa narenakatta keredo
That didn't really turn us into adults,
ima wa sukoshi wakaru yo
but now I understand
akogareta dareka no kage wo nazoru dake ja
that just imitating those you admire
kimi ni todokanai tte
is not enough to reach you
nee itsuka tsutaeru yo
One day I'll tell you of my feelings
dakishimeta negaigoto kimi ni mitsukaranai you ni
I didn't want you to know of my wishes,
watashi no koe ni tokasu yo
so I lowered my voice
kamisama ni sasayaita
and whispered to the gods
mainichi ni koi shiteru kono kirameki tayasanaide
Every day I feel the love inside my heart and hope I won't faint
somatta hoo wo naderu kaze
The wind turns my cheeks red
itsu made mo tonari de waratteite
Please keep smiling next to me
Go get ready for your dates!
Dressing up the outside...
won't change what's inside!
See?
This is exactly why you're doomed to stay a virgin forever!
A vir...
Jeez! Keep your voice down, would y—
Touka?!
Izumo,
Arranged Dates,
Kerfuffle
Izumo,
Arranged Dates,
Kerfuffle
Lady Uka!
Inari?!
What are you doing here?
I was wonderin' the same thing. Why'd you come here for these dates all of a sudden?
I'm so sorry, Touka! Here, let me fix it!
Uka, one does not use one's divine power on a mortal's nosebleed!
But it was my fault!
Look here.
Plenty of gods are after Uka for her status,
but why would a human like you with no use for such things be attracted to her?
I never said I was!
I-I just came by to talk to her!
Women Over Men
Are you still stalking your sister?
Honestly.
If you have so much time on your hands,
you can show these two around until dinner.
Wh-Why should I be saddled with these humans, Mother?
M-Mother! Why not let me—
You have dates to attend! Now, let's be off!
My sole duty is to protect my darling Uka!
They're all yours!
Inari!
Oh, Uka!
What if one of her dates forces himself on her?
I'm absolutely sick with worry!
If only she'd force herself on me!
Why the rush to get her married off, anyway?
Uka's a first-class deity.
Countless gods would love to marry someone of that standing.
That much I know.
But she was dead set against it.
It's our mother!
She's forcing Uka into it because of her rivalry with Kushinada-Hime!
Rivalry?
She's trying to one-up Kushinada-Hime
by marrying Uka off to a high-ranked god.
What?!
So that's what Lady Uka's caught up in.
I'm gonna put a stop to it.
How can she marry her daughter off out of petty rivalry? That's insane!
I won't allow it!
The gods might, but I sure won't!
It's party-wreckin' time!
Right, Touka?
Whatever.
But Touka...
First class gods, arranged dating... What do I care?
I just want to hear more about this divine power inside you,
straight from the horse's mouth.
Oh, really?
You're not here to catch Uka's eye
by crashing her dates?
Jeez! Lay off already!
I don't care about her stupid dates!
I'll go on tons of dates!
T-Touka, where are you—
Okuni Shrine
I know she's been takin' good care of Inari.
But why didn't she tell me about that power?
Didn't she trust me?
Is that why she lied to me?
Is it because I'm human?
First-Class Uka-no-
Mitama-no-Kami
Official Dating Venue
Er...
Please accept this gift.
Thanks.
Fragrant Dumplings
With Stinkbug Extract!
Pee-yew!
Couldn't you turn up the charm just a notch, Uka?
But... the stench!
You just want this over with so you can hang out with Inari.
It's written all over your face.
Th-That's not true at all!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I just
want this over
with so I can
hang out with
.Inari!!
I'm sure you realize this,
but you mustn't get too close
to any particular human.
I know.
We are gods. Inari and her brother are humans.
Nothing more, nothing less.
Such beautiful eyes... Such a graceful manner...
To think Lady Uka could be married off to that bug...
It stinks!
That smelly stinker better not
get any closer to my Uka!
Phew!
I never actually thought about it before,
but what kind of man would
Lady Uka want to marry?
This is where I gallantly step in to sweep her off the feet, eh?
Master Toshi!
There you are!
Spend more time with your family, or I won't hear the end of it!
B-But I was gearing up to be Uka's Prince Charming!
Leave your sister alone already!
Date In Progress
What? I gotta do this myself?
Kon! What do I do?
What do I do?!
I'm just an apprentice familiar!
I can't defy Lady Kamu-Oichi-Hime!
I've got to do something, or Lady Uka...
May I bring in some flowers, Mother?
Come back quickly, now.
Okay, here's my chance!
Inari, konkon!
Change into Lady Uka!
But that's impossible!
You can only transform into other humans!
Not again...
My divine power is leaving me... again...
I did it!
But how?!
If Lady Uka won't put a stop to this herself, I will!
Inari...
Touka...
I have returned!
My, that was fast.
Mother?
You know, maybe we should call this whole dating thing—
She's very much been looking forward to this meeting!
What now?
Uh, Lady Uka, what kind of marriage did you have in mind?
Here we go!
Not marrying a bug would be lovely!
Just what do you think you're doing?
But... But I just...
Don't tell me you're doing this on purpose.
It's just...
To hell with arranged dates!
There! She's—
N-No! I-It's not what you're thinking!
Oh? How so?
W-W-Well...
A sister-obsessed son,
a daughter well past her prime...
The once-glorious first class,
reduced to an inglorious disgrace.
No, it's just, um...
And now Kushinada-Hime
will laugh at me... again!
I'm sorry!
Get back here!
You'd never have done this if you hadn't been consorting with those humans!
The rest of you!
Find Fushimi Inari and Touka
and apprehend them!
Forgive me, Touka!
Damn. I'm completely lost.
Nothing but trouble wherever I go.
This just isn't my year, huh?
There he is! Fushimi Touka!
Get him!
Whoa! What the hell is this?!
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
I haven't run... this much... all year.
Having fun?
Not really.
Miss Inari!
Where are you?
Was she over there?
No... Where'd you go, Miss Inari?
Miss Inari!
Now what?
You can't keep running forever!
Somethin' wrong, little lady?
Thank you. I'm feeling a little better now.
Oh, okay.
Well, I must be going.
H-Hey, uh, why don't you rest a little longer?
It's all right. I seem to be just fine.
Does this exhaustion of yours
have anythin' to do with Inari?
That's amazing, Touka.
Nothing gets past you.
What is it?
You already know that I gave Inari a portion of my power.
Yeah. That's what I came to see you about.
Inari must have used that power to try to transform into me.
And... she did. Which is why I grew so weak.
If Inari keeps on using that divine power, then...
my divinity—my very godliness itself—will move into her.
And if that happens...
Inari will become a god?
Sounds...
like the stuff I write.
This is serious!
I just want Inari to be a normal girl.
This is all because I gave her that power!
Hey!
Worry about yourself for once!
If Inari becomes a god,
what'll happen to you?
It's all right.
I'll be fine. No need to worry—
Don't lie.
You can tell me everything.
Or can't you, because I'm a human?
I can't be trusted, huh?
That's... That's not it...
Um... I can't breathe.
D-Don't take this the wrong way!
You were worried about Inari
and gettin' all trembly with guilt!
Thank you, Touka.
I'm so happy.
I...
I don't want to fade away.
No!
Fade away?
Getting my divine power back
from Inari would solve everything,
but not being able to see Inari anymore would be even worse!
I'm sorry.
I was bluffing about the arranged dates.
I never wanted to attend them.
Not any of them, ever!
I know.
Inari was all fired up about puttin' a stop to
the datin' thing, so you should be okay there.
She was?
She really likes you, you know.
Let her help you out for a change.
I guess so.
But I don't want her to worry.
I can't let Inari know about my fading away.
Not yet.
I'm so sorry. Everything's getting jumbled together.
The divine power, the arranged dates...
Truth be told, I'm not sure what I should do next.
Even though I'm a god.
Th-Then maybe we should, uh,
all think it through together.
Isn't that what Inari'd say?
I mean, like... we're... f...
F...?
Friends... right?
Right!
Lady Uka's father?!
Yes!
Master Susanoo-no-Mikoto!
Lady Uka's father, and Great Amaterasu Oomikami's younger brother.
Great Amaterasu's...
Ah, you're that top-secret girl who got some of my Uka's power. Inari, yeah?
U-Um... Please forgive me for taking your precious daughter's power.
What're you apologizin' for?
If Uka wanted to give it to ya, where's the harm?
I-I want to call off Lady Uka's arranged dates!
Can't you do somethin' about it as her father?
That I cannot.
If you wanna stop it, do somethin' about it yourself.
Convince me it's in my interest to help, and I'll do it.
But I can't do it on my own.
Worryin' about those gods?
Paralyzed with fear of what
they might do if they caught ya?
What do you want to happen?
I...
I want to help Lady Uka, but how can I?
Am I really powerless?
On my own, without her power to draw upon...
Can I do nothing at all?
There she is!
Miss Inari!
We've got you now.
You've ruined my Uka's marriage interviews.
How do you plan on making it up to us?!
I'm just a human, with no special powers.
I can't give Lady Uka anything.
But...
Hey now, what's all the fuss?
Susanoo, you too?
But... I bet...
Is a first-class marriage
really so important?
Is showing up Kushinada-Hime
What are you—
Are they more important
than Lady Uka's feelings?!
Arranged dates... Marriage...
If you don't even understand those,
how could you ever manage
to appreciate Lady Uka?
I-It's humans like you that have made Uka far too humanlike!
Hear, hear!
Those first-class powers are wasted on you!
You said it!
Give Uka's power back!
Hand over that divine power!
Humans shouldn't play at being gods!
You've got a lot of nerve!
None of you can do anything without marryin' into power!
You'd leave all the hard work to her
without liftin' a finger yourselves,
just to improve your status...
You do not get to hurt my beloved friend!
But...
Such colossal courage from such a tiny human.
Don't ya think we should hear her out?
I-I don't mind...
But...
Right?
Oh, you know I can't resist you,
my darling Susanoo!
If that's what you want,
my sweet little brother!
Thank goodness!
That was truly moving, Miss Inari!
Inari?
Lady Uka!
Can we really stop having those arranged dates?
Anything for my dear Susanoo!
You've really cheered up
since last I saw ya, Uka.
H-Have I?
On the other hand...
Toshi's as hopeless as ever.
Called off! Called off!
All you gods can suck it!
Inari! Hurry up, or you'll miss the bus.
Comin'!
Then I'll see you next month, Lady Uka.
Thank you, Inari.
I love you so much.
Ever since we became friends,
my life has been filled with joy.
Mine too.
You two sure have gotten close.
Yes.
You already know how to get that divine power back, don't you?
Is that true, Lady Uka?
Tell us!
You should know by now that you can't hide anything from me.
I order you to confess everything!
When Inari...
I hate myself like this!
When Inari wanted desperately to return that divine power,
I could feel it coming back to me.
That means...
B-But that makes it so much harder!
I mean, Miss Inari...
Great Amaterasu? Why are we at the Celestial Plains?
The Ama-no-Iwato? Why here?
Now listen. You stay in here for a while.
I shall let you out when the time comes.
But...
If the time comes.
Uka has grown too close to humans.
Amaterasu
Do you mean to pull those two apart?
I'm not pulling them apart.
This is simply a cooling-off period.
If not for this, that girl would...
Hey, Inari...
Actually, let's talk when we get back.
The seasons are changing.
Our class trip's coming up,
and then there's Christmas...
This divine power'll let me spend lots of time with Lady Uka.
I can't wait! Hope she comes back soon.
Inari...
watashi wa naze koko ni ite
Why am I here
aisuru sube mo shiranaide
if I don't know how to love
sukuwareru toki wo yume mite ikiteita
I lived my life dreaming of salvation
unmei no kodou ni makasete yanagi no michi wo nukete
I rode my bicycle home past endless willows
jitensha de kaetta
and left my life to the vagaries of fate
chiisana dekigoto ni
The waves of life
yosete wa kaesu mainichi ni
break on the little things around me
anata ga soba ni ite
Please be with me
watashi ni hikari wo ataetekureta kara
You gave me the light
you saved me
You saved me
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
See you next time !