I just don't know how to interact with people.
I want to be friends with Marutamachi,
but I can't even talk with her.
I've kept my distance,
built walls around myself...
I don't know what to do.
And what's more,
all Sanjou talks about... is you.
I've been so envious of you lately.
I'm an awful person.
Huh? Envious?
But I was the one who was envious of her.
I want to be Sumizome!
But that's no good!
Isn't there any way I can help her?
I...
If there's anything I can do...
Anything!
I wish I were you, Fushimi!
What... is this?
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
nanige naku tsuita tameiki wa
I sighed involuntarily
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
takai takai sora no mukou ni
and that little bit of sadness
habataite kietetta
flew with the birds to vanish in the distance
guuzen no misu mo waratte shake hands
We committed our share of faux-pas, then shook hands
sonna fuu ni otona ni wa narenakatta keredo
That didn't really turn us into adults,
ima wa sukoshi wakaru yo
but now I understand
akogareta dareka no kage wo nazoru dake ja
that just imitating those you admire
kimi ni todokanai tte
is not enough to reach you
nee itsuka tsutaeru yo
One day I'll tell you of my feelings
dakishimeta negaigoto kimi ni mitsukaranai you ni
I didn't want you to know of my wishes,
watashi no koe ni tokasu yo
so I lowered my voice
kamisama ni sasayaita
and whispered to the gods
mainichi ni koi shiteru kono kirameki tayasanaide
Every day I feel the love inside my heart and hope I won't faint
somatta hoo wo naderu kaze
The wind turns my cheeks red
itsu made mo tonari de waratteite
Please keep smiling next to me
Touka,
Lady Uka,
A Woman in Love
Touka,
Lady Uka,
A Woman in Love
Wh-What is this?!
Such divine power!
Miss Inari... No!
You don't mean to grant her wish, do you?!
Lady Uka!
Lady Uka?
You mustn't!
Miss Inari, you have to stop! Please!
I know! But I can't stop it!
It's just... happening!
I wish I were you, Fushimi!
Miss Inari!
What do I do?
Stay calm, Miss Inari!
Just... keep it together!
Should I change Sumizome into me?
No! That won't solve anything!
But... What can I do for her?
Me too.
I mean, I wanted to be you.
Boys like you, you do well in school...
You have everything I don't.
I thought I'd be so happy if I were you.
It's not like that!
I'm nothing like—
You're just like me.
Just like you?
Yep. We're the same.
So whenever you have
something on your mind,
come talk to me. Just like this.
Are you sure?
I might not be able to turn you into me,
but I want to do everything I can to help you out.
We're friends, after all!
Thank you.
I hope I can come to you, too, if something's botherin' me.
And I think you should just
go ahead and talk to Maru.
The divine power!
Lady Uka?
Er...
I'm okay.
It's settled down now.
Miss Inari...
How did you manage to
dispel that divine power?
It just went away on its own.
It was when I realized that Sumizome wasn't askin' the gods for a favor,
but just openin' up to me.
How very mysterious indeed!
Fushimi?
I'm going to try talking to Marutamachi.
Good luck!
There you are!
Yoohoo!
You were so late comin' back
we thought something'd happened!
Sorry, Maru.
Geez!
Oh, right!
Our fight...
Maru, you blockhead!
This is all your fault!
I gotta apologize!
I'm sorry!
Sumizome? But why?
I think it's my fault everyone's
been so on edge today.
And after you were kind enough
to invite me, too...
No way! We were all keyed up because I kept bashin' you!
No, it's my fault!
It's all my fault! All of it!
It is not, Inari!
It is so!
Is not!
Uh—
Is so!
Inari, it's my fault!
Guess I'm the odd one out.
Maru, it's my fault!
Um... Um...
How about a drink?
Oh, uh... Thanks.
Maru!
Marutamachi!
I-I'm so sorry! It was carbonated?
How...
Oh, I'm so sorry!
Super Bubbly
Not sure how you missed the "carbonated" part.
I'm so sorry! I'm so, so sorry!
It's okay. I was just about to take a bath anyway.
Why? Why'd it have to be carbonated?
I never noticed from far away,
but she's a totally normal girl.
All of these are carbonated!
Hey, uh... Sumizome?
Isn't "Marutamachi" kind of a mouthful?
Maru!
Huh? Not really...
Take a hint!
No, what I mean is, uh...
Y-You can call me "Maru"... if you want.
I-I'm fine either way, but if it's easier for you...
And it might be easier, so, uh, you know...
I might not be able to actually be Fushimi...
Now, Inari has her issues,
but she can make friends with anyone.
...but I can try my hardest to be like Fushimi.
"Maru" works for me...
You know, just, like, "Maru"...
M...
Maru!
Oh, Sanjou! Is everything all right?
I heard you were so tired that you went back ahead of us.
Say what?
Uh, er, M-Maru! You're all sticky!
Let's all hurry back and take that bath!
We can all get in together!
Seriously?
Huh?
There's no way we'd fit!
Don't be like that! We can do it!
Ah, youth! Music to my ears!
Isn't it, though?
Oh, before I forget...
Make way!
Hello?
Hi, Touka! Have you eaten dinner yet?
I'm just about to.
What time are you coming home tomorrow?
Eight o'clock at the latest,
so it'd be great if you could
have dinner ready for us.
Yeah, sure th—
Touka?
Uh... Dinner, right? Got it.
What are you, a guardian spirit?
C-Call me a guardian deity, at least!
Fortunes
So you didn't go to the beach?
Yeah, right. I'm an indoors guy.
Fortunes
Why are you followin' me?
Y-You said I could come by to play games!
I said I'd think about it.
No one ever said—
Are you gettin' sick again?
I-I'm fine.
I'm sure I'll feel better
if you play with me. Probably.
No can do.
It's too late today.
Come again tomorrow.
Through the front door.
Inari'll be home tomorrow night, so it oughta work out nicely.
P-Promise?
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
What the hell—
I've come to play!
You said I could come visit today, right?
Do you have any idea what time it is?
Where's your common sense?!
I understand.
I'll come back later.
Hang on.
No point turnin' you away at the door.
Come on in.
Summer vacation's almost over.
What's with the sighin', Maru?
I gotta do my homework at
mach speed when I get back.
Why do vacations have to be over so fast?
I'm lookin' forward to school, myself.
Say what?
Because you get to see Tanbabashi?
No, no, no! I'm looking forward to the Wisteria Festival, that's all!
But all those plays and stuff are such a pain!
And the class displays are borin' beyond belief.
Last year, Maru, Keiko and I
went around to see all of them.
Boring!
You and Keiko should just go with the flow.
You were such huge downers last year!
But it is boring!
U-Um, if you don't mind...
Can I tag along this year?
Of course you can! Right, Maru?
It's a promise, okay?
Sure! It's a promise.
Beaten again!
How the heck did you get so strong?
How many sundaes do you owe us now?
Keiko, Inari, Chika, Akemi...
The next one's for me, okay?
This time I'll win for sure!
All right! Here goes!
Bring it!
I...
I think I might like Sanjou.
There, I said it.
The secret I couldn't tell anybody.
I think... it might be love.
Is that weird?
It's not wei—
I think it's fantastic!
I-It is?
I'm totally into that!
You have my support for sure!
Thanks!
Most of what you draw is gay
"bara" or "yuri" stuff, right, Maru?
Don't expose me like that
here in the great outdoors!
Bara? Yuri?
Another defeat!
Yep!
How can I be as close to her
as you are, Fushimi?
Keiko and I grew up together.
When you spend that much time with someone, it's natural to become friends.
So just try to be with her a lot.
Hey! The meat's ready!
Mackerel
This is adorable!
Souvenir Keychains
Why don't we all buy one?
Yeah! To remember our trip to the beach!
Right, Keiko?
Sure, why not?
Top Seller
Let's see... I'll have this one!
How about you get this one, Maru?
Sure!
You wanted this one, right, Sumizome?
Here's yours, Keiko.
Different colors...
We have the same kind, eh?
Uh-huh...
Hey, Inari, are you sure that's everything?
Huh?
Nothing for Tanbabashi?
I-I'll think about that later!
Say, Kon...
What would be a good souvenir for Lady Uka?
I'm sure she'd love anything if it came from you!
You think so?
I do!
I'll have to tell her all about my trip. She'd like that.
Oops! I got both mushrooms! Sorry!
Hey! You tryin' to kill me off
so you can go on without me?!
I really am sorry!
Dammit! This sucks!
Stop that! There are gods
living in there too, you know!
Who cares? If you wanna play,
play by yourself.
Easy for you to say...
Sheesh.
"If I don't rescue Irina from
the sinister Deo's clutches,
I will be wracked with such
....indescribable pain that my senses—"
Hey!
Quit snoopin' around!
My apologies. May I go through your photos?
Hang on!
Here.
I wouldn't have said anything, you know.
Hmph!
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Elementary School
First-Grade Ceremony
What's so great about
someone else's photos, anyway?
Touka...
You never did visit the shrine much, did you?
What'd you expect?
I didn't want another scare.
I had no idea you were just some gamer.
The same goes for me.
Even though I'm a god, and you've been so close
all this time, I still don't know a thing about you.
But I'd like to learn, Touka.
You probably don't remember...
Rats! Where am I? How do I get home?!
...that time you got lost on Mount Inari.
I didn't want to scare you,
so I took on a human form.
Where the heck am I?
Stupid Inari shrine.
It's okay. Don't be afraid.
Come, let's go back together.
D-Don't tell anyone I was crying, okay?
We walked together, hand in hand.
It's only been ten years,
but look how much you've grown.
Wh-What's the big idea?
I was just thinking how big your hands are.
M-Men's hands usually are.
Amazing. Time passes so quickly for humans.
We're home!
Welcome back.
Ah, I smell curry!
Thanks, Touka.
I'm beat!
Hey, Inari?
Oh, hi, Touka.
You have a guest.
I do?
Did I fall asleep again...?
Touka, she's a god! How could you?!
Idiot! You weren't here to hang out with her,
so I've been playin' babysitter
since the crack of dawn! Geez!
Sake!
My favorite! Thank you!
Glad you like it!
I figured all gods have a taste for sake, right?
That's quite the assumption to make.
Lady Uka...
You've had too much to drink...
We had a lot of fun at the beach.
So much happened!
A lot, huh?
Yeah, tons!
Sumizome said she couldn't be friends with Maru, and then—
I don't need to tell her about that divine power showin' up, right?
Nothin' really came of it, after all...
What is it, Inari?
U-Uh... Then a drink exploded in Maru's face, and they made up...
Oh, wow, what am I saying?
I don't want her to worry, after all.
watashi wa naze koko ni ite
Why am I here
aisuru sube mo shiranaide
if I don't know how to love
sukuwareru toki wo yume mite ikiteita
I lived my life dreaming of salvation
unmei no kodou ni makasete yanagi no michi wo nukete
I rode my bicycle home past endless willows
jitensha de kaetta
and left my life to the vagaries of fate
chiisana dekigoto ni
The waves of life
yosete wa kaesu mainichi ni
break on the little things around me
anata ga soba ni ite
Please be with me
watashi ni hikari wo ataetekureta kara
You gave me the light
you saved me
You saved me
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
See you next time !