Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
nanige naku tsuita tameiki wa
I sighed involuntarily
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
takai takai sora no mukou ni
and that little bit of sadness
habataite kietetta
flew with the birds to vanish in the distance
guuzen no misu mo waratte shake hands
We committed our share of faux-pas, then shook hands
sonna fuu ni otona ni wa narenakatta keredo
That didn't really turn us into adults,
ima wa sukoshi wakaru yo
but now I understand
akogareta dareka no kage wo nazoru dake ja
that just imitating those you admire
kimi ni todokanai ne
is not enough to reach you
nee itsuka tsutaeru yo
One day I'll tell you of my feelings
dakishimeta negaigoto kimi ni mitsukaranai you ni
I didn't want you to know of my wishes,
watashi no koe ni tokasu
so I lowered my voice
kamisama ni sasayaita
and whispered to the gods
mainichi ni koi shiteru kono ki mo ne tayasanaide
Every day I feel the love inside my heart and hope I won't faint
somatta hoo wo naderu kaze
The wind turns my cheeks red
itsu made mo tonari de waratteite
Please keep smiling next to me
Inari!
A shrine! An Inari shrine!
You can't just run off like that!
Why didn't you wake me up?!
You're the worst brother ever!
Better hurry!
All right, that's it!
Shortcut time!
Good morning!
Was that a cat? Or a dog?
A-A dog!
The poor thing!
Hang on... I'll be... right—
At least it's not too deep.
Oh well. Bein' a little late won't kill me.
Good thing fools don't catch colds!
Inari,
First Love,
First Change
Inari,
First Love,
First Change
Kyoto Fujinokusa
Middle School
You can come up with a better excuse than that, Fushimi.
But it's the truth!
All right, split into teams, and let's get started.
You're something else.
Yeah, pull the other one.
There really was a dog!
It hurt its leg, so I bound it
with my handkerchief.
You okay?
And it answered me!
Uh, Maru?
Moe!
Nice!
So cool!
There go the sparkles again.
I don't get it. What's so great about Tanbabashi, anyway?
He's always so cheerful,
and he works hard at practice even when no one's there to see him.
I know he does!
May Tanbabashi play well in his next game.
What am I, his girlfriend?!
I better get this to him before
the game in two days.
I-I wonder when I'll have my chance?
Maybe he'll think I'm too serious or just plain awkward, givin' him a charm in this day and age.
Maybe I need to increase his affection level
in some flag event first...
Buck up and go get rejected already.
Jeez! Some friend you are!
Sumizome just sparkles, doesn't she?
Onto our next match!
Inari! Heads up!
Wow. Did you hear that?
Sorry!
Moe!
Hey, Tanbabashi!
Here. Show Fushimi the ropes.
Oh, sir!
Good job!
S-Sorry to pull you away from the game.
No big deal. We've been playing plenty of practice games lately.
You got a big game in
two days, right? Good luck!
Um...
Could you teach me how to dribble?
Starting from square one, eh?
Why couldn't I say it?
Okay, watch me. I'll go first.
That was my big chance!
Fushimi?
Okay, now you try.
Sure.
Ow...
Sorry, Tanbabashi—
Kouji's lettin' it all hang out!
Fushimi's done it again!
Uh... Tanbabashi...
Tanbabashi!
Why...
Why do I have to be so dumb?
I...
I hate that!
And...
I hate myself!
C'mon, Inari.
Cheer up already, will ya?
Lunch break's almost over.
No way. I'm stayin' here for the rest of the day.
Why do I always screw up at the worst possible time?
More like any possible time, if you ask me.
You've always been quick to give up, y'know?
Enough with the cryin'! Jeez!
You don't have to go that far!
Inari?
What a weird name!
Like the shrine!
It's a real lucky name, y'know.
It's like the gods are lookin' out for ya.
The gods?
Yeah...
All right.
I think I'm okay now.
There, there. Good girl.
Oh, Tan—
Wow, he looks pretty ticked off.
I guess I'd better...
apologize and...
m-make—
make things right.
I gotta do this.
Um...
Huh?
I read your letter.
Sumizome Akemi
Tanbabashi Kouji
What...
Sorry it took so long for me to get back to you.
Oh, uh, no rush.
Uh, so... What do you say?
Sorry, but could I have a little more time to think about it?
Y-Yeah, sure.
Is this...
You've got a basketball game in two days, right?
Ah, yeah.
Are they...
Okay, well...
Good luck!
Thanks.
Inari?
Tanbabashi's ideal girl is someone who's super-cute and charming.
Someone totally unlike me.
Someone... like Sumizome.
Oh, gods!
Huh?
What?
Where... are you takin' me?
So bright—
Good day, Inari.
We are Uka-no-Mitama-no-Kami,
the resident deity of this Inari shrine.
We are the god you humans call "Inari."
A-A god?!
And the puppy from this morning!
That little fox is our familiar.
We heard that you rescued her today.
You have our gratitude.
Not at all.
And as thanks, we would like to grant one of your wishes.
Thanks? From a god? I'm not worthy!
Not even the spiritually attuned can see these pups.
And yet, you were able to.
All because you have loved this shrine since you were but a child.
You are a special person indeed, in our eyes.
Special...
We heard your soul cry out in anguish today.
That is why we'd like to help you, Inari.
Come, tell us your wish.
I-I...
If I'm such a special person...
I want to be special to him, too.
I want to be Sumizome!
Huh?
Better head back.
What?!
N-No way!
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
Inari,
Konkon,
Koi Iroha
That's right. Inari still hasn't come home.
Thank you.
Not this again.
Where could she have gone?
Sanjou, wha—
You! This is all your fault!
Huh?
Inari!
She tried to apologize a million times, and you ignored her! Idiot!
B-But I—
Calm down, Keiko.
Hey, Tanbabashi, why don't you lend us a hand?
Inari's gone missing!
What?
Sure am hungry.
H-How much money do I have on me?
I-I'm one of the have-nots!
Hungry?
We're buyin'.
Nice uniform. Fujinokusa Middle School, right?
We're from Peach High.
Th-They're hittin' on me?!
I-I'm not particularly hungry, no.
Whaddaya say? Let's go grab a bite.
N-No, thank you!
What, again?
T-Tanbabashi...
Sumizome! Are you looking for Fushimi, too?
Huh?
What's wrong?
Well, uh...
I'm so hungry... I could die.
H-Hey, hold on!
She's missing?!
Y-Yeah.
Hope I've got enough for her tempura bowl.
What if I'm stuck like this forever?
It's all my fault.
Huh?
I kinda blew up at her, and I've been avoiding her ever since.
I wasn't angry, exactly.
But for a girl... to see... that...
I'm too embarrassed to even look her in the eye.
No...
I swear, if anything's happened to her...
It's not your fault.
I'm right here.
I want to be Sumizome!
I thought if I were Sumizome,
I could tell him.
I honestly believed I'd be able to.
Good luck!
And Lady Uka went and granted my wish.
And yet...
I still can't say what I want to say.
I can't say the one thing
I most want to. Not like this.
Tanbabashi, as soon as I turn back—
Huh?
I, uh, I'll pay you back as soon as I can!
Wait, er...
Hey, if you find Fushimi, let me know!
I haven't changed after all. Not one bit.
I'm still causin' everyone trouble.
She sure doesn't look happy for someone who got her wish granted.
You dummy! What are we gonna tell Lady Uka?
Isn't this what Miss Inari wanted?
I know, but... Hey, we better keep it down!
Gotcha!
So, in other words...
I'm terribly sorry, but I think I need my wish un-granted.
Wow, what a disaster.
Chin up!
Lady Uka's the kindly sort,
so she'll understand for sure!
Yeah...
What counts isn't what's on the outside.
Right now, I want to know what you're thinking.
Lady Uka!
I want to experience the inner you.
Come, now. Lay yourself bare for me!
Yikes! Change back! Hurry!
I see.
It appears we have made a royal mess of things.
No, not at all!
I mean, it was my wish.
I'm so sorry!
No, it is we who should apologize to you.
Forgive us, Inari.
We cannot return you to your original form.
A god granting multiple wishes for a single human
would violate the rules of the Celestial Plains.
With so many humans bringing their wishes to shrines every day,
we cannot grant another of yours in such a short period of time.
Yes, of course.
Miss Inari?
I may look different, but I'm still the same.
And I still can't do anything.
Then let us try this.
Eat up, Inari.
Huh? But...
There's nothing to fear.
It's good!
Now you can change back.
We have placed a portion
of our power within you:
the power to become
anything in all of creation.
You may change your shape at will.
You mean I can transform? Seriously?
Seriously.
However, as a human, you can transform only into other real, live humans.
Then that means... That means...
I gotta think of some magic words!
That's right! You do!
Something cool!
How about "Trans-cadabra"?!
What? Can't I do something
more magical-girl-like?
Like saying your name in reverse
and twirling over a colorful background?
Yeah, like that!
Okay, here goes!
For real!
Inari, konkon!
Change back!
I'm back!
Come, Kon.
This is Kon. Take her as your familiar.
No other human should be able to see her.
Thank you very much for
rescuing me this morning.
I-It's you!
Now palm-sized for your convenience.
Looking forward to working with you!
Same here!
Kon can tell you more about our rules.
Sure!
Oh, uh... Can I still come to visit?
Yes, of course. Any time at all.
You are a dear friend of ours, after all.
Inari!
What the heck have you been doin'?!
Er, um...
Sumizome—I mean, I'm so sorry!
Glad that's settled, anyway.
Could you quit stretchin' out my face like that?
Don't worry. It's not gonna get any floppier than it is already.
I just hope Lady Uka will be okay.
Oh, okay... Wait, that's mean!
It may be just a tiny little part of her divine self...
But should she really have given that power away without consulting Great Amaterasu first?
Inari!
Touka...
I knew you'd be here!
Run on home, now.
Mom and Dad'll be worried sick!
I-I'm really sorry.
Guess we'd better tell Tanbabashi, too.
I'll give him a proper apology at school tomorrow.
Tanbabashi? It's Sanjou.
We found Inari.
Take your seats!
Now, let's see. Tanbabashi's the only one absent.
Is he sick?
But what about the big game tomorrow?
watashi wa naze koko ni ite
Why am I here
aisuru sube mo shiranaide
if I don't know how to love
sukuwareru toki wo yume mite ikiteita
I lived my life dreaming of salvation
unmei no kodou ni makasete yanagi no michi wo nukete
I rode my bicycle home past endless willows
jitensha de kaetta
and left my life to the vagaries of fate
chiisana dekigoto ni
The waves of life
yosete wa kaesu mainichi ni
break on the little things around me
anata ga soba ni ite
Please be with me
watashi ni hikari wo ataetekureta kara
You gave me the light
you saved me
You saved me
Inari, Konkon, Koi Iroha
See you next time !