You...
You did this?
You killed them all?!
I didn't kill them.
Liar!
I'm not lying.
People killing one another is now a thing of the past.
All I did was get them to stop moving.
Killing them is the job of a gravekeeper.
I was seven when my mother died.
Without her, I was all alone,
but then the villagers told me...
Ai, starting today, you're a gravekeeper.
Lady Alfa was a splendid gravekeeper.
We need a gravekeeper.
As the last of her bloodline,
only you can take her place, Ai.
Me?
That's right, Ai.
Become a gravekeeper?
That day, I became this village's gravekeeper.
Since my mother passed away, none of the villagers have died.
But each day, I've been digging grave after grave.
After all, I'm a gravekeeper!
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
The Valley of Death I
God created the world on a Monday.
On Tuesday, He drew the line between Order and Chaos.
On Wednesday, He arranged each and every number.
On Thursday, He permitted the ebb and flow of Time.
That's it for today, everyone.
Until tomorrow!
On Friday, God explored every nook and cranny of the world.
On Saturday, He rested.
And on Sunday, God...
forsook the world.
"Heaven and Hell are too crowded."
"It won't be long before this world is, too."
"Ah, I have failed."
When God abandoned the world, leaving behind only those words,
people stopped dying.
Even as their hearts stopped beating,
even as their flesh rotted,
the dead kept moving.
It is said that in order to save those very people,
God sent to this world one final miracle:
the gravekeepers.
It's time, Ai.
Grant Lady Alfa a peaceful slumber.
You're the only one who can do it.
Okay.
Only burials by gravekeepers
can grant a peaceful slumber for the restless dead.
Perfect!
I am clearly an excellent and dignified gravekeeper!
Heeey!
Ai!
Mr. Yuuto...
Come on, Ai! Stay dignified!
Hey, everyone, Ai's back!
I greet you all as gravekeeper.
May your lives continue—
You're late.
Are you hungry?
We brought cookies.
I baked some muffins!
Uh, everyone...
The lemonade's ice-cold!
Hello?
Hey! What do you all think you're doing?
How many times must I tell you to stop feeding the gravekeeper?!
Well... you see...
Well, Ai?
I dried do zdop dem!
Good grief.
Let's head home, Ai.
Anna's waiting for us.
Ogay. Fanks.
Well, ebryone,
take care!
See you tomorrow, Ai.
Thanks for always giving it your best!
Anna!
Ai!
I'm home!
Now, now, Ai!
Welcome home.
Anna, you stink.
Ai!
It's just perfume.
I don't see why you wear that stuff.
I like your natural scent.
Well, I'm sure you'll understand
the ways of us adults when you become one.
That's what you all say.
After my mother died, Yohki and Anna took me in.
My real father is out there somewhere.
His name's Humpnie Humbert.
My mother told me he'd come see me someday.
This is so painful sometimes.
She's only twelve years old.
She's just a child,
and we're putting the weight
of the world on her shoulders.
Anna.
I truly am happy we took her in.
Having a child in this day and age
is like a dream come true.
But...
I wonder if she's happy.
I wonder why sometimes...
Yohki and Anna look at me with really sad faces.
Why would that be?
It sometimes feels like they're keeping something from me.
I'm finished!
Forty-seven in all.
I went and dug enough graves
for everyone in the village.
What will there be to do starting tomorrow?
Guess I could always go and help everyone out.
What?
Where is everyone?
I wonder what could've happened.
Whoa.
Huh?
Excuse me.
Do you live here?
Are you by yourself?
Can you talk, or are you dumb?
I-I can talk!
Good for you.
So, who are you?
I'm Ai, the gravekeeper.
Oh?
Wh-What is it?
You?
You're the gravekeeper here?
Is there a problem with that?
No, not really.
Guess I might as well.
There's something I must ask a gravekeeper about.
May I?
Uh...
Sure.
Query:
I would like information on one called or one who calls herself "Hana."
I'm not asking whether she's dead or alive.
Well... I'm not sure.
Supplemental query:
I would like information on a woman
who matches the following description.
Um...?
Between thirty and forty years of age.
Brown hair. Black eyes.
Distinct facial features.
Approximately my height. Flat-chested.
Again, whether she's dead or alive is irrelevant.
Um, well...
I think Anna's around that age,
but she's not flat-chested.
And Yohki's a guy.
Hmm...
Not here either, huh?
H-Hold—
Hold on a second!
What is it?
I'm a busy man, you know.
Um...
Well, uh...
Y-You're very handsome!
Thanks.
Later.
Um...
Anything else?
Yes.
Uh...
Are you...
Oh, right!
Who are you?
Me?
Well, all right.
I...
I am the Man-Eating Toy, Humpnie Humbert.
Oh!
You have the same name as my father!
What?
It all makes sense!
So you're Humpnie Humbert!
Now hold it right there.
Who the hell would have that kind of name?!
But that's my father's name.
Huh?
You have parents?
So, what?
Your dad's name is Humpnie Humbert?
Yes.
My mother told me
that he'd surely come see me someday.
Father? Father, is that you?!
Are you serious?
Do I look like I could be your dad?
I must admit it is a little strange.
Exactly.
In my mind, my father's always been
this tough guy around forty years old.
Huh?
And it'd be strange if he didn't show up
letting out some fierce battle cry.
There are much stranger things about this situation.
But those are just minor issues!
Nope, you've definitely got big issues.
You're still my father!
And why's that?
Just intuition!
We were fated to meet!
You have no intention of holding a conversation with me, do you?
Of course I do,
Father.
Hey, you're a gravekeeper, right?
Yup.
In that case, I have a job request for you.
What is it?
There's only one thing it could be.
Huh?
Everyone...
Everyone!
Yohki. Anna.
This can't be.
This can't be happening!
If it isn't Ai!
Mr. Yuuto...?
You okay, Ai?
Mister...
There's...
a big wound on your head.
Oh, this? This is nothing.
It doesn't even hurt.
Oh, right!
There's big trouble!
Er, what was it again?
Anyway, we're in trouble!
W-We've gotta run away!
What's the matter, Ai?
I'm sorry.
Why are you staring at me like that?
Stop it!
What's the matter with you?
You're staring at me like I'm some kind of monster!
I'm still the same!
No, you're not!
Ai, stay down.
It's that punk again.
Hey, you! Undead monster!
You've got three seconds before I unload thirty rounds of lead in that direction.
Two seconds!
One!
A splendid display of character.
My bad.
I should've finished him off earlier.
Not to worry. I blew the rest of their heads clean off.
You...
You did this?
You killed them all?!
I didn't kill them.
What have you...
Why?
How could you?
You're not my father!
My father would never do something like this!
You cannot be my father!
Haven't I been saying that from the beginning?
Come with me.
Bury them.
How long do you plan on following me around?
What?
More importantly, what do you plan on doing from now on?
Well, I'm a gravekeeper.
You're no gravekeeper.
At first, I thought maybe
that asshole of a God could've indeed
made a weirdo like you a gravekeeper,
but I was wrong.
But my mother was—
Let's start with that.
Gravekeepers don't have parents.
What?
They tend to show up out of nowhere, like flies.
They couldn't possibly have parents.
But everyone in the village—
Called you a gravekeeper?
That's pretty flimsy proof.
Didn't you consider that
they could've been lying to you?
But that...
No, it can't be!
My mother was Alfa, the gravekeeper,
and my father's name is Humpnie Humbert—
Listen.
"Humpnie Humbert" is just a fairy tale.
It's the name of a toy
that keeps moving even without a spring.
I only borrowed the name from that fairy tale.
I bet your mother did the same thing.
Th-That's a lie!
I wonder what the villagers here were trying to do.
They convinced a little kid like you that she was a gravekeeper
and that her father was out there.
What?
What are you saying?
What's going on?!
The truth is shrouded in darkness.
Actually,
I guess it'd be buried in a grave.
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
This is all your fault.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
What you did to everyone...
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
So you wanna kill me?
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
If you really were a gravekeeper,
you would bear no malice or ill will.
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
you couldn't attack a living person.
What?
You're no gravekeeper.
You're just a human.
Life on the planet
life on the planet
Even so,
I'm a gravekeeper!
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
Look behind you.
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Now that's what you call a gravekeeper.
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
Cruelty. Avarice.
But that's so embarrassing!
"Murderer."
It's been six long years
since you killed her!
I'm talking about the night
that "God" disappeared.
Th-This has got nothing to do with me!
...while you're still pure.
I'm a gravekeeper.
The Valley of Death II
I can't forget that!