Who cares about this Princess of Mai High crap?
I'm skipping the after-party.
I wanna get this stupid outfit off right now.
Oh, you're right. It's open.
But...
Festival Eve
Dressing Rooms
Do you think we can actually get up on the roof?
Festival Eve
Dressing Rooms
Don't worry. I know the passcode for the door.
How do you know that?
Because I go up on the roof all the time.
Typical gamer.
I don't see how that's relevant.
Looks like things are going well for those two.
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
Wow, this is a nice spot.
No one's around, and it's cold.
And the campfire looks like a little speck.
Are you making fun of me?
Oh, Katsuragi!
I can see the Akanemaru!
Okay, maybe not.
Say something.
This feels weird.
You're not acting like your usual self.
How so?
You're throwing me off.
It's just as weird for me.
I never thought I'd be talking to you this way.
Back in the day, if someone told me I'd be walking around with a geek like you,
I would've laughed.
But today,
I feel like I want to be with you forever.
W-Well, "forever" might be a bit of an overstatement...
U-Um...
Katsuragi...
Ka—
Ch-Chihiro!
Chihiro, c-can I?
Yeah.
Katsuragi, be gentle...
This is...
my first time.
Huh?
This is...
your first kiss?
Yeah.
Is that bad?
No, it isn't.
There's no way she'd lie at a time like this.
She's telling the truth.
Chihiro doesn't remember the conquest.
There is no goddess...
inside Chihiro.
Girls'
Dressing
Room
Girls'
Dressing
Room
Ayumi.
Don't cry, Ayumi.
I'm not crying.
I can confirm she's not hosting a goddess before the ending.
This is my last chance.
I can still turn back.
What's wrong?
I can end Chihiro's conquest
then switch over to Ayumi's route.
I just have to say, "You seem to be confused."
"I brought you here to ask how I can get closer to Ayumi."
That will result in the target and accomplice switching places.
A Copernican revolution.
There will be some—
no, a lot of trouble,
but I can handle it.
Chihiro.
Huh? Eh?
Wh-What?
Wait...
Is that the right thing to say?
Thinking back, Chihiro always acted before I could do anything myself.
I only appeared to be going down her route.
It was nothing like a conquest.
So how do I explain what's happening right now?
Katsuragi?
Chihiro...
Do you really love me?
Why would you ask that?
Yes, I do.
Why?
Since when?
Since when did you feel that way?
Since when...?
I-It's hard to say,
but I guess sometime during spring.
What?
I'd understand that if you still remembered the conquest,
but I didn't even interact
with you during spring!
What do you mean, "conquest"?
I-I mean...
You were always making fun of me,
and you asked out a bunch of different guys!
Ah! That's not important!
But...
You...
You were the one
I was always thinking about!
Tomorrow is the Mai High Festival!
Let's have the time of our lives!
I-It's impossible to fall in love with someone that way.
There was no conquest, no interaction.
What would make you fall in love with me?
You don't need a reason to fall in love.
I just realized at some point that I loved you!
Katsuragi...
Do you love me?
Of course not.
Huh?
Katsuragi?
This is stupid. I'm leaving.
You actually thought I'd fall in love with a real girl?
What?
Then why did you go on a date with me today?
This doesn't count as a date.
I was just pulling one over on a real girl.
Stupid.
You're lying.
You must be lying.
You've always made fun of me,
so I thought I'd pay you back.
But I've had enough.
Stay away from me.
Ka—
Katsuragi.
Why did you say that?
Ayumi! Why are you here?
I thought you went out with Chihiro because you knew how she felt.
How could you say those terrible things?
I r-realized that...
I've been lying to myself.
But now I know
who I truly care about.
It's...
You're a total jerk!
A total jerk...
Yes...
I am.
Ayumi, why did you go to the roof?
This is your own fault.
Why mope over a man you've already given up on?
Humans are so inefficient.
Katsuragi.
Diana?
Why are you here?
Is your search going well?
It is.
No problems at all.
There's only one goddess left,
and then it'll be over.
No.
There are two left.
P-Please bring out my wings, too.
I have something to tell you.
It appears that
I've fallen in love with you!
Huh?
Ah, so...
I realize that falling in love with Tenri's fiancé is inexcusable.
I believe my wings have not returned
because my guilt is curtailing the power of Tenri's love.
There's no time to waste.
Please love Tenri.
Before I fall deeper in love with you!
Tenri!
I did all this for—
Stay away, you animal!
Keima! Why are you here?
Would you calm down?
Now, Tenri...
Tell him how you feel!
Or my wings will never return!
I-It isn't that simple...
This is all your fault!
You're so withdrawn that I'm always the one who has to talk to him.
I had no prior experience talking to men.
So after spending all this time together,
it's only natural that I'd fall in love, even with a lowlife like him!
What kind of logic is that?
You're not normal, Tenri.
Huh?
You live next door to someone you've loved for ten years.
You must want to talk to him, to spend more time with him!
Not that I have those urges.
You should tell him how you truly feel, Tenri!
What do you want to do, Tenri?
Huh?
I'm sick of these cryptic conversations!
There's a proper sequence that should be followed,
but you all just keep adding more useless noise!
Seriously, what...
What... are you doing?
Keima...
Did something happen?
Nothing happened.
Just leave.
Tenri?
Keima...
Did you say something?
It's a fake ear.
Yeah, I can see that.
Why are you performing magic tricks?
You looked like you were feeling down,
so I wanted to make you smile.
I don't feel down.
I'm perfectly normal.
I can also do escape tricks.
That's big.
You really like magic, huh?
Please lock the box.
Why me?
I...
do love you, Keima.
But the Keima I love is the one who's always playing games.
I want you to go back to your normal self.
To the Keima who's always smiling.
You don't have to worry about me.
I'll find a way to bring Diana's wings back.
How?
I'm not sure.
No one ever does what I want them to.
But you have my thanks.
Um, you don't have to force yourself to smile.
Yeah.
But I have to keep going, or this will never end.
Is there any more to your magic show?
Might as well see what else you can do.
Then I'll use this wonderful wand of magic—
Is this the one where flowers pop out of the wand?
W-Well, I already did my best trick...
Mai
High
Festival
Mai High Festival, Day 1
3 Hours Before the Festival
Light   Music     Club
Elsie?
Exalted Brother!
Our band's having a dress rehearsal.
Are you here to listen to us?
Er, wait...
No one else is here yet.
Dress rehearsal?
Gawd, and here I'm like, flat-out being a celeb...
I've gotta book it to another rehearsal right after this,
and I totes have no time to reschedule.
Talk like a normal person.
The concert is tomorrow.
Should I attempt to conquer Ayumi now?
Exalted Brother, did you know
that the Mai High Festival has been around for a long time?
Nikaidou mentioned something about it.
Hasn't it been around since the school was founded?
Wrong!
The festival's been around even longer than our school.
Oh? It's that old?
I never really noticed, but our school emblem is...
School emblem?
A goddess...
What's wrong, Exalted Brother?
Why did we come to the theater?
This is the oldest building around.
Ten years ago, we found a swarm of loose souls underneath.
The goddesses... Maijima...
I get the feeling that everything is connected.
Huh?
What's wrong?
The hole's gone.
When I came here with Tenri during summer break, there was a hole.
Elsie.
Huh?
Let's change location.
What? Right now?
It won't take long.
Ten minutes.
Maijima Seaside Park, Artificial Beach
The exit's gone, too...
That hole couldn't have closed up naturally.
Someone must have sealed it off.
Elsie.
Let's go over there.
You mean that rock?
Yeah. Use your raiment to make us invisible.
Huh?
Why do we need to be invisible?
Just in case.
That's a big rock.
It's known as Point Rock.
People usually stay away.
Let's check the other side.
I don't see anything.
No. Look down there.
The waves don't look right.
Let's check below.
Underwater?
Yes. Hurry up.
My clothes will get wet!
Huh?
We went through the rock...
Just like ten years ago.
There's an opening under the water.
Still, getting in was too easy.
Did I guess wrong?
E-Exalted Brother, this...
Elsie. Time to run.
Exalted Brother!
Don't stop! Get us out of here as fast as you can!
Hurry up!
O-Okay!
Why did you remove the barrier?
Better than them hitting it and being found out.
If they're captured, we'll be at a disadvantage,
though it doesn't look like anyone found out.
The ones inside wouldn't have noticed what I did.
My barrier-penetration skills are flawless.
I'll check to make sure they weren't bugged.
You worry too much.
That's what it means to be a homeroom teacher.
No tracers or anything on me, right?
Nope.
But I can't believe there was a place like that inside the rock.
What was that place?
It certainly looked ominous.
The egg-like things lying around looked familiar.
Those were mature loose souls!
And those black figures belonged to Vintage!
Vintage is raising loose souls
so they can revive the Weiss!
Raising loose souls? Without hosts?
Um... Um...
Elsie, do you know why our
school emblem is a hexagon?
Huh?
The goddess on our school emblem...
The swarm of loose souls...
The underground passage that was sealed...
The operation being run beneath the rock...
Something huge is about to happen here.
In other words...
It has nothing to do with me.
Man, I wasted all that time on an empty route.
What?
Aren't you going to do anything with that information?
If those loose souls are released, terrible things will happen!
Then I guess it'll all be over.
I'm just going to proceed with the conquest, no matter what.
It's almost ten o'clock!
The festival will soon open to the public!
The Mai High Festival's about to begin!
Whenever we see each other
fukakute atsui itoshisa
my burning love only grows stronger
au tabi ni tsumoru no
like white feathers gathering on the ground
shiroi hane no you ni
We passed each other so many times
nandomo surechigatteita
where the roads of love and hate meet
suki kirai daisuki sukuranburu-kousaten
In the morning and during the day
asa mo hiru mo
At night and when I dream
yoru mo yume no
I always want to be with you
naka demo zutto soba ni itai
I want to protect you
anata wo mamoritai no
This is the first time I've felt like this
konna kimochi hajimete no kanjou
Even if you make the whole world your enemy,
sekai wo teki ni shitemo
I will be your only ally
watashi dake wa mikata de itai kara
I trust you
shinjiteru
Labyrinth
I've played games in which the last boss appears as the first enemy,
but I never expected that Ayumi would host the last goddess.
And Vintage is getting aggressive.
Time to go on the offensive, Elsie!
Sorry!
All requests must go through my agency and manager.