Finally.
The last goddess.
Ayumi's parameters are such a mess that they're impossible to analyze.
I need to skip the logic and jump straight to the confession.
Apologize to Chihiro!
I never want to see your face again!
Run all you want.
I'll still catch you!
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
No way!
Yes way!
Labyrinth
Sorry I'm late!
Our charismatic waitress has arrived!
Over here!
Master, everyone's here.
Okay.
Then it's time to open shop.
Why'd a stick-in-the-mud like you
suddenly decide to lend a hand?
My family runs a café, you know.
I can't just stand by and let you serve bad coffee.
Whoa! This coffee's really good!
It's like I've been drinking muddy water up until now!
Gold Blend! Excella!
With the dweeb as barista and Ayumi as waitress,
we've got one heck of a dream team!
Welcome!
This is the 2-B Café!
I said I never wanted to see your face again.
The more I see you, the more I hate you.
At least that means you won't forget I exist.
Huh?
What's that supposed to mean?
It's like he's trying to sweet-talk me...
Two cafés au lait.
W-We need cafés au lait.
Don't give her time to think!
I must confess my love first!
Ayumi...
Hey, what are you trying to do?
You working hard, Ayumi?
Check this out!
It's like a real café.
Ch-Chihiro!
Ayumi...
You look good.
Go get 'em.
Chihiro!
The cafés au lait are done.
Katsuragi...
Don't talk to me anymore.
Damn.
Gauging the effect Chihiro's having on Ayumi is too hard.
Welcome!
Hey, where are the cups?
It's pretty early to be running out of cups.
They should have been more prepared.
I need you to say something, or I can't advance!
Advance what?
I told you not to talk to me, you jerk!
Is this the right approach?
I can't tell.
J-Just stop it, stupid.
Ayu—
Yo.
Chihiro...
Your shift's over, right?
Lemme have your apron and headband.
Right...
What were you talking to Katsuragi about?
I didn't think you two were so close.
I-It's not what you think—
I was...
rejected by Katsuragi.
And this time, I thought I was pretty serious.
But I guess I wasn't really.
So you don't need to stick up for me with Katsuragi anymore.
You're a good friend,
so I'm sure you were putting in a good word for me here and there.
That's all I wanted to say.
Chihiro!
We've got another customer!
Could you take her order?
Sure thing.
Ayumi...
Thank you.
Yeah, get as many soldiers as you can.
Welcome! What would you like?
Coffee with heaps of sugar.
Gotcha.
One coffee!
Nothing important.
I just feel like a little goddess-hunting.
It's no good.
Regardless of the route I take,
I'll still run into Chihiro eventually.
How can I remove her from the route?
Humans are such an enigma to me.
Mer...
Why are you so hesitant?
You already know what to do.
All that's left is for you to decide whether you want to go through with it.
I just tagged her.
This is your target.
Once your preparations are complete,
I'll begin the hunt.
Hey, young lady!
How about some takoyaki?
I'll take one.
Where did Ayumi go?
There she is!
Chihiro!
Join forces with me.
Huh?!
No matter what route I use to conquer Ayumi, you will be an obstacle—
one that can't easily be removed.
So I'll have you help me instead.
It's the only way to end this quickly.
So let's work together—
What are you babbling about, you cockroach?
How can you act like nothing happened?!
Have you forgotten what you said to me?
Of course not.
But there's no time for that right now.
Let's set aside our differences
and form an alliance.
You scumbag!
If the goddesses escaped with the loose souls
and they're both in this world,
the goddesses may be hiding among those loose souls.
I guess it's not out of the question.
Our preparations are complete, Lune-sama.
We will begin now.
Go for it.
Where did Ayumi go?
Oh, hey!
Chihiro...
I've been looking for you.
I wanted to talk about the band member introductions for tomorrow.
I can't.
I just can't...
be in a band with you anymore.
Ayumi?
Damn! She beat me to her!
What do you mean?
I just can't forgive myself.
I was never rooting for you...
Why is she saying that?
It'll just make it harder to advance!
I'm terrible.
While you were hurting,
all I could think of was Katsura—
Finally found you.
You wanted to talk to me, Chihiro?
Huh? What are you—
Hey, wait!
Could you please leave without saying anything?
If you hear what Ayumi's about to say, the conquest will take longer!
What's your problem?!
Sorry, Ayumi.
What were you saying?
Uh...
Wh-Where was I?
I can't let this conversation continue.
Listen to me!
I need to talk to you both.
The alarm?
Who is it? Who set it off?
What is this?
Stop it!
Vintage...
Damn! They found us out?
Lune-sama, I have secured the two, plus one other.
Gira?
Ah. I just captured one myself.
It took a bit of effort, though.
It sounds like everything's gone smoothly with the other targets.
We'll gather the goddesses and kill them.
Tell me.
What are you all up to?
Ayumi! Chihiro!
Say something!
Damn, I was so close!
Take them away.
Who are you?
Return from whence you came,
servants of evil!
I see you've awoken.
You?
Was I taken off the Loose Souls Team?
You were to be dismissed and punished.
Otherwise, Vintage would have killed you.
Where are we?
The surface of Old Hell.
Once we reach the boundary, you can escape.
You're smuggling me out?
As though I were a criminal.
Well, you were dismissed from the Loose Souls Team for treason,
so you actually are a criminal.
I didn't do anything wrong!
Yeah, I...
I just did what I thought to be right.
But now everything's gone wrong...
Haqua.
Long ago, there was a battle between good and evil
that rendered Hell uninhabitable.
When New Hell was created afterward,
nothing had really changed beneath the surface.
All kinds of scheming still takes place behind the scenes,
while the righteous are framed and driven out.
We must put an end to this.
There's no miasma up here.
Haqua, in the past, the Scythe of Testament
was only entrusted to demons from noble families.
However, you were able to outperform your peers,
earning the scythe through individual distinction.
It was the first time such a thing
had ever happened in our school's long history.
Haqua du Lot Herminium,
you are no longer a member of the Loose Souls Team.
You exist outside the law.
However, only you can save New Hell.
I have a special mission for you.
Go to Earth, rescue and protect the goddesses,
and put an end to Vintage's plot!
The future of New Hell
is in your hands.
Haqua!
Are you with the Loose Souls Team?
No. I am the one...
who will defend the honor of all New Hell's inhabitants!
Chihiro! Ayumi!
Run!
Is this the magic of Old Hell?
How can you fly
without a raiment?!
These are simple movement spells that anyone can use.
It just takes twenty of them at once!
Which is impossible for demons like you that rely on the power of others!
It's okay.
I didn't kill them.
Sorry for taking so long to get back.
It's okay. You saved us, after all.
K-Katsuragi?
Is it safe over there?
Think fast.
Great! You've put together an excellent show!
Huh?
Your Special Effects Film Society will be the talk of the Mai High Festival!
I'm in the middle of Ayumi's conquest.
Play along.
We have to cover up what happened.
You never change.
What did you think of our Film Society's superhero show?
Film Society?
That was an act?
Sorry to have dragged you into it.
Katsuragi said there was this girl he wanted to surprise.
Wait! This was your idea?
What the hell was all this about?
Uh, well...
You're always doing stupid things!
It's all yours now.
You've gotten good at this.
No kidding!
So, are these guys all Film Society members?
They're people who want to conquer the world.
This plot seems a little shallow.
You might want to rethink it a bit.
Katsuragi, Vintage has attacked the goddesses.
The special effects were great, though.
How much do they know?
They hacked into my raiment's tag
and learned that we were investigating your former conquests.
Someone in Vintage was smart enough to realize that goddesses might be hiding
alongside loose souls.
No luck.
I can't reach Yui, Tsukiyo, or Shiori.
Did all the goddesses come under attack?
It could be even worse.
If they don't know which girls are hosting the goddesses,
they'll target every possible candidate.
Which means they may have attacked every girl you've conquered.
We've got them all.
So which are goddesses?
Well, checking them one by one would be too much effort.
Might as well just kill them all.
Our first priority is to get somewhere safe.
Vintage is everywhere!
What are they talking about?
I'm going home.
Huh? Didn't you have something to tell me?
I'll call you later.
Bye.
Ayumi?
I'll bring her back!
Wait.
For my conquest to succeed, it's better to let Ayumi leave.
What?!
Isn't it a bit late for conquests?
Can you guard Ayumi without her seeing you?
Then who'll protect you?!
I'll keep an eye...
on that Ayumi girl.
Nora!
I'm not siding with you guys.
I just don't like the idea of Vintage running loose on my turf.
Feel free to refuse my offer,
but are you in any position to be choosy?
Fine. This gives us more options.
We'll let Nora look after Ayumi.
That leaves...
Chihiro.
Let me go!
You're coming home with me.
What's wrong with you?
Elsie is waiting!
Huh?
How did I end up...
back at Katsuragi's house?!
He told me to wait here, but...
Is Ellie in her room?
So Kanon was taken too...
They've taken every goddess except Ayumi's?
They didn't get all of us.
Diana, you're okay?
I was never attacked.
I saw some suspicious figures leaving your room with a large container.
It seemed quite odd.
But I thought reaching out to my sisters might be dangerous,
so I laid low.
That confirms our suspicions.
Vintage has determined the goddesses
to be inside Katsuragi's conquests, and has taken them all.
Officially, Nora captured Tenri's loose soul, so they excluded her.
Wait, what about Elsie?
Elsie, you okay?
Soufflé?
Okay, let's have soufflé for dinner, Nii-sama...
She's fine.
Katsuragi, before I came back, I did some research.
Vintage seeks to revive Old Hell.
The problem is where they intend to do it.
They plan to use the rock by the Maijima beach as a gate
to bring the Weiss to this world!
If we don't stop them, Earth will be in big trouble.
What are they talking about?
Earth and Hell are separated by a gap in space-time.
Beyond that rock
lies the final battlefield of Almage-Machina...
East Greda Fortress.
That is where the goddesses placed the seal.
Vintage intends to create an opening
and summon the Weiss that remain in Hell.
They will abandon that barren world
and revive Old Hell on Earth!
When will they put their plan into action?
I'm not entirely certain,
but I suspect tomorrow.
Please give me a chance.
I will stop Vintage, on my honor as a goddess.
No!
It's not just Vintage.
That place is filled with Level 4 loose souls!
It's too dangerous!
Those things?
I'll go.
Haqua-san?
This is Hell's war!
So—
No!
If war breaks out, none of us
will be able to contain it.
Therefore, we must not
let this become a war!
Then what do we—
We can still stop them!
There must be a route.
I will conquer Ayumi.
You intend to release Mercurius?
They were trying to kidnap us.
If they suspected we'd interfere, they'd have attacked us as they did Kanon.
There's a reason they didn't try to kill us.
We still have a chance.
No change in plan.
We'll continue to follow the route
that brings the goddesses together.
Ow!
Chihiro?
What are you people going to do with Ayumi?
Call from
Ayumi
Hello?
Huh? Katsuragi?
Why are you answering Chihiro's phone?
I'm on my way over...
to confess my love!
Huh?
Diana, wait in the house.
Haqua, you come with me.
And, Chihiro...
Hold on!
Let me go!
Just come with me!
What are you trying to do?
There's no time to hesitate.
I must go straight for the ending!
aoi sora wo
Together we looked
isshou ni nagameteta
at the blue sky
kyou wa sukoshi
Today, it doesn't quite feel
funiki chigau ne
like it did that day
sunao ni ienai keredo
I can't quite put it into words,
kimi no koto sugoi to omotteru
but I think you're a really great person
hakanai hodo utsukushiki sekai
The vast beauty of this world is so short-lived,
unmei ga tomadou yoru ni mo with you
but I am with you when our destiny falters in the dark of night
dare yori ichiban chikaku ni itai
I want to be the one closest to you
asu wo terasu kisetsu no naka de
as we bathe in the dawn of another day
The goddesses have been captured.
Vintage is swarming around us.
But there's no need for panic or fear.
It's conquest time!
Ayumi, prepare to be conquered like never before by the great Katsuragi Keima!
You sound like a villain.