What have you done?!
You'll find out soon enough.
Damn you!
There's no way things'll just
go back to how they were!
Stop!
Stop it!
Let go of me, Dee!
This little piece of shit needs to—
See for yourself.
Get it now?
This is a false world,
a closed space.
Whatever gets damaged beyond repair
will be reset to its default values...
including humans.
Quit fucking around!
Forgive me.
Stop!
Stop it, Alice!
Hey, Alice!
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Class 3-4  I
Is this the place?
There's no one here—alive or dead.
It's desolate.
Even as I am right now, that much is clear to me.
Alice, where's Class 3-4—
Never mind that.
Just follow my lead, and do exactly as I do.
What are we doing?
Just keep up.
This is...
Class 3-4.
But at the same time, it's not.
What is that thing?
It's some incomprehensible barrier.
That's all I know.
And Class 3-4 is imprisoned on the other side.
Can't we get in through that hole?
Nope.
This is the only entrance.
Is that so?
You don't seem surprised.
Well, I've seen all kinds of things lately.
Attagirl.
Is it dangerous?
Not at all.
I see.
However, those not originally from Class 3-4
can never get back outside once they enter.
Unless they resolve everything, that is.
You just had to wait till the last minute to mention that part, didn't you?
You can always refuse.
Huh?
It's my dream to save the world.
It's true that I'm starting to get a little confused about how to go about it,
but there's a world on the other side of this door, isn't there?
The world you want to save, I mean.
Yeah.
Then I'll go.
I'll help you save your world.
That so?
What about you guys?
If Ai's going,
we're going. Right?
Right.
What?
Nothing.
You two sure are close.
You guys need to learn
to respect your elders!
Anyway, looks like we've come to an agreement.
Let's go.
Welcome to our home.
It's winter here?
This feels like a completely different town.
Yeah.
Hey, look! It's Alice!
When did you get back?
Just now.
Looks like you brought
some more new people, too.
Looks like it.
Come and hang out with us for a bit.
Nah, I was just about to take them home.
See you all later, then.
Y-Yeah.
We're almost there.
You finally made it.
U-Um...
Dee, why—
Why am I here, you ask?
'Cause I'm a member of Class 3-4 too. That's why.
Wow, it's true!
Tanya and everyone were totally right.
You're sooo soft, Ai!
Well? How come you've got a body now?
So are you, Dee.
Huh?
I don't really know why.
I just do.
Make do with this bread and stew for dinner tonight, okay?
And let me know if you need more winter clothes.
Thanks, Dee, for doing all this.
Well, you never take things like these into consideration.
I know that better than anyone.
So it's up to me to take care of all of it.
Yeah, yeah.
One "yeah" is enough!
Oh, come on.
Anyway, I'll get going.
Ai, see you at school tomorrow!
School?
Please tell me...
How come Dee isn't a ghost here?
And why is it winter?
The calendar says it's fourteen years ago,
and so does the newspaper.
What is this place?
I don't wanna tell you just yet.
What? How can you be like that now that we're already here?
Sorry.
It's just that I don't wanna give you any preconceptions.
What it makes you and Ai and Scar think, and how you all feel about it...
I wanna know that first.
Only then will we truly begin.
I did it.
All right!
Take that.
Alice!
Huh?
Where'd you go?
W-Wait, Dee!
Dee?
Dee!
Dee, where are you?
Alice...
What... What's going on?
Alice!
Dee...
I'm Ai Astin.
Nice to meet you all.
Where are you from?
Wait, how old are you?
You're so tiny and cute!
Do you have any siblings?
Your hair's so soft!
Um, well...
Did you skip grades
or something?
You're staying with Alice, right?
Wow, the school uniform looks great on you!
Totally. Especially with the huge ribbon and fancy color!
You really think it's okay to go outside?
I mean, she's a baby.
They don't exist anymore.
Still, we'll be living in this town for a while.
We can't keep her locked up in the house forever.
Yeah, you're right.
It's so peaceful here.
I don't sense any dead in this town.
Not too long ago,
that probably would've thrown me into a panic.
But now, I feel very calm.
And it's all thanks to this little girl, Ai, and you.
I see.
Ai!
Hey, which club are you gonna join?
Huh? Oh, um...
I hadn't thought of that.
In that case, you should join the club I'm in.
Huh?
Um...
The club you're in?
The Cooking Club.
Cooking Club?
As in, cooking food!
Like cookies and biscuits, and muffins and cake!
That sounds wonderful!
I know, right?
So let's go to the clubroom.
Huh? Oh...
I think I've gotta pass today.
How come?
I only just moved here, so I should sort things out at home first.
I see.
Yeah, I guess you should...
But you've got to come once you've settled in, 'kay?
Okay.
But I...
You also need to help Alice, right?
Huh?
Alice might say otherwise,
but this place is really nice.
I'm sure you'll come to love it too, Ai,
and that you'll wanna stay here forever.
So what do you think?
Hmm... How should I put this?
This place isn't normal.
I think it's a world that was born from someone's wish.
Am I wrong?
Not bad, Ai Astin.
You're dead-on.
This is a world that came to be
because Class 3-4 strongly wished for it.
It's a complete and utter fabrication,
one that is isolated and fictitious.
A world created fourteen years ago, huh?
Fourteen years ago on July 28th, to be more precise.
Since that day, this place has been
in a temporal loop of approximately one year.
Every July 28th in this world,
all the people here get reset.
So they're forever reliving this one year?
Yeah.
Again, to be more precise,
the loop lasts a little under a year.
That's why the seasons are
out of sync with the outside world.
The calendar and the newspaper,
and the scenery that lacks detail...
I see. Now I get it.
If I were to liken it to something else,
it'd be a human cage.
Class 3-4 are the prisoners of the cage,
the cause of its creation, and the cage itself.
Why they wished for this cage, no one knows.
They don't remember.
To make matters worse,
aside from Dee and me,
no one's even aware of the temporal loop.
Even though they were the ones who wished for it?
They probably also wished to forget all about it.
That's a big problem.
After undergoing two loops,
I luckily realized the truth.
Back then, the only people in this world were the students of Class 3-4.
I looked everywhere for a way out of this cage.
After plenty of trial and error,
Dee and I finally found a way out.
And Dee's been like that ever since?
Yeah. She loses her physical form in the outside world.
I don't know why.
Since we broke free, I've been trying to free Class 3-4 from this cage.
I even tried shaking up this world
by bringing loads of people and other things inside.
I figured out a lot, though.
The dead cannot pass through that black wall, and neither can people with special powers.
That's why this place only has living people.
Just how many have you brought here?
35,695 people in total.
When you bring in someone or something that wasn't here originally,
this world gets a little unstable.
But before long, it gets fixed,
and once that happens, a new loop including the outsiders begins.
It's been an endless cycle of that.
Instead of changing things from the outside,
is it not possible to directly affect the students of Class 3-4?
I've tried.
It was pointless.
You're actually much older than you look, aren't you, Alice?
Yeah.
You've stayed fifteen years old for fourteen whole years.
Well, I'm sixteen now.
You celebrated my birthday, remember?
Yup.
The others are just like me.
Isn't that weird?
I want to turn seventeen!
There's one more thing I need to tell you.
I have an enemy in this world.
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
An enemy?
Who is it?
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
Dee.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
Somebody take off the curtains.
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
Happy birthday, Ai!
I think wishes shouldn't be granted.
Be destroyed.
If you're not careful, you might get swept away.
Silence!
I've got his blood on my hands.
That's enough!
Class 3-4  II
I get it already.