Now that's what you call a gravekeeper.
Hey.
My, my.
I'm pleased to make your acquaintance.
Um...
You're... really pretty!
Your words are too kind.
My name is Scar.
"Scar"?
I'm Ai.
Now wait a sec.
That's just a nickname that means she's "scarred."
It's not actually her name.
Hey, Scar,
what were you called before this?
"Murderer."
Keep going, if you don't mind.
"Grim Reaper."
"Monster."
"Scar."
"Maria."
"Stubborn bitch."
"Grim Reaper."
"Scar."
That's enough.
And what was your very first name?
I didn't have one.
And that's all right with you?
Of course.
See?
This is a real gravekeeper.
A paragon of virtue
that's completely devoid of emotion.
Now, I have to ask.
You still think you're a gravekeeper?
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
The Valley of Death II
By the way, Scar,
I've got something to ask you.
A query.
Ask anything you'd like.
I would like information on one called or one who calls herself "Hana."
I'm not asking whether she's dead or alive.
I know of eight people
called by that name.
Supplemental query:
who among those eight
is between thirty and forty years of age,
has brown hair, black eyes,
and distinct facial features,
is approximately my height,
and is flat-chested?
I know of zero people matching that description.
Another dead end.
I've got another request for you.
Forty-seven people over there are in the ground.
Please give them a proper burial.
But I buried them already!
Only a real gravekeeper can kill people.
Only when a gravekeeper
shovels dirt onto their bodies
do the dead truly die.
Me blowing their heads off
and you burying them afterward
only gets them to stop moving.
B-But I did shovel dirt onto them...
Haven't you been listening?
To what "dead" are you referring?
What?
I do not sense any dead over there.
I do sense people who were
given a proper burial, though.
That doesn't...
No way.
That means...
Did you hear that?
I am a real gravekeeper!
She's a...
She is indeed a gravekeeper.
Sorry to have kept you.
That's quite all right.
It is also our duty to assist the living
and to ensure that they lead happy lives.
Well?
What do you plan on doing from now on?
I'm a gravekeeper—
So?
S-So I'll grant peace to the dead
and assist the living with their lives.
That's not what I'm asking.
Where will you sleep tomorrow?
What will you do the day after?
What about next week?
Or next year?
How will you lead your life?
I'll go someplace where people need a gravekeeper—
Wha—
What do you think you're doing?!
Forget it.
Forget this village,
and forget about being a gravekeeper.
If you don't, you're not gonna make it in the outside world.
This world is a cruel place.
Just you try setting foot
out there with that mentality.
You'll get beaten to death
before you know what hit you.
I...
Just forget it all.
No.
I can't.
I can't forget.
I can't forget!
You little...
I can never forget!
I'm a gravekeeper.
I can't forget that!
I see.
All right, then.
If that's the case...
how about you just die
as a gravekeeper, right here and now?
Cruelty.
Avarice.
Slaughter.
Depravity.
Loss.
Frustration.
Corruption and injustice.
They'll find you wherever you go.
And as long as you live,
you will be defiled by them.
It's quite unlikely that you'll be
yourself up until the moment you die.
The radiance you possess right now
will inevitably be polluted.
And in the vilest ways imaginable, no less.
So...
die now, while you're still pure.
Please tell me you're just kidding.
No.
I don't want to...
I don't want to die!
Sorry.
That's just not a good enough
reason to let you live.
You should learn...
the path you've chosen isn't one where you can stay alive by saying "I don't want to die."
The only words that can keep you alive are
"I want to live."
What just...
Damn it! My clothes!
D-Doesn't it hurt?
Of course it hurts, dumbass!
My left pulmonary vein's shredded.
And the bullet went clean through—
A-A-Are...
You okay?!
What?
Wh-Wh-What's going on?!
Wait there.
He's not dead!
Yuri "The Koutou Tiger" Dmitriyevich!
Hunter.
My friend!
Humpnie Humbert.
The immortal man.
My sworn enemy!
Good morning, living ones.
Immortal?
Long time no see, Yuri.
How long's it been? Five, ten years?
Six years!
It's been six long years
since you killed my wife!
I didn't kill her.
By then, she'd already been dead for a year.
Ai, this is Yuri,
my best friend.
This guy hid his already dead wife from the gravekeepers,
and the two of them lived with their daughter deep in the mountains.
So what?
The three of us...
I loathe the dead.
Just as dirt returns to dirt,
ashes to ashes, and dust to dust,
the dead ought to return to the ground quietly.
The three of us were happy!
But I simply couldn't accept that happiness of yours.
I'd like to apologize for that.
Sorry.
I don't need an apology.
I challenge you to a duel!
Isn't that strange?
I mean, don't you realize
what will happen to you if you fight me?
You just proved that I'm immortal.
In other words, you must've
come here to die at my hand.
That's ridiculous.
I came here to exact revenge!
Hey, Yuri.
How's your daughter?
She turns fifteen this year, doesn't she?
Haven't you been living happily enough
with her for the last six years?
So why bring up revenge now?
Did she die?
Shut up.
I see.
So she really did die.
Did you bury this one properly?
You bastard!
Answer the question.
I held a proper funeral for her.
That's fine, then.
So?
After losing all purpose in life,
you came to get yourself killed by me?
That sound about right?
Don't be stupid.
It's revenge I—
Revenge.
Revenge, you say?
I'll admit it's got a nice ring to it.
But your motives are suspect.
What?
You just don't wanna live anymore.
But you're too bitter to kill yourself,
so you're hoping to die
while pursuing something.
You're wrong!
Like, say, while attempting to avenge your wife,
maybe?
Shut up!
If you don't shut up, I'll kill this girl!
Wai—
Th-This has got nothing to do with me!
What's with you, Yuri?
Pretending to be crazy, now?
Have it your way.
At your insistence, I'll send you off.
But I'm not gonna be nice about it.
There'll be no meaning in your death.
If you're fine with that,
meet me at dawn in the center of the village,
and I'll accept your challenge.
Pay attention, Ai.
You must not live a life of ignorance.
Consider this a warning.
I'm...
You again?
What about the duel?
Isn't that obvious?
I'm running away.
I'm not gonna bother
fighting Yuri to the death.
I see...
Well, have you decided
to give up on being a gravekeeper?
That is none of your business.
I'm...
I'm leaving...
in search of people who need me.
Yuri is an exceptional hunter,
so we'd better hurry
if we don't want him to catch up.
I already told you that
what I do is none of your—
Some gravekeeper you are.
Please stop saying that.
Come here.
What?
I'll give you a piggyback ride.
Huh?
Otherwise, Yuri's gonna catch up to us.
B-But...
That's...
But that's so embarrassing!
What?
I mean it.
Someone could see us!
You always have the most bizarre reactions.
Just hurry up and get on.
Alley-oop.
A-Aren't I heavy?
Yeah, you are.
But it's not a big deal.
Ready to go?
What?
Whaaat?!
That was a terrible excuse of a piggyback ride.
Hm? That's strange.
When I was a kid, I always
loved it when my father did that.
I'd prefer it if you didn't
compare me to yourself.
First he tries to kill me,
and then he helps me out.
If he didn't want Yuri to catch up to him,
he could've just left me behind.
Huh?
Um...
I'm fine.
Huh?
I'm just some immortal monster.
Don't mind me.
You shouldn't do that.
What?
You shouldn't call yourself a monster.
Humans and monsters.
The living and the dead.
Not everything's so black and white, you know.
Um, well...
I'm not sure what I'm trying to say.
Ai, how old are you?
I'm twelve years old.
That makes sense.
What's that supposed to mean?
I should've realized it before
that gravekeeper spelled it out for me.
What?
When people stopped dying fifteen years ago,
they also stopped being born.
So there's no way a human could be your age.
Which means I'm a gravekeeper.
Nah, it might be hard to believe,
but you're probably a hybrid
between a gravekeeper and a human.
What?
A normal gravekeeper
would never give birth to a child.
Your mother must've been
a pretty messed-up gravekeeper.
My mother was not messed up!
Being messed up isn't necessarily a bad thing.
Especially in a world like this.
Um...
And how old are you?
The same age as Yuri.
Thirty-two?
Thirty-three?
Well, somewhere around there.
You said you two were best friends, right?
Yeah, since when we were kids.
In school, we were inseparable.
Do you know what a school is?
Of course I do.
I see. Well, let me explain anyway.
Schools are facilities where kids are segregated by age
and isolated from the rest of society
so that they don't impede its functioning.
Well, I don't know about any school like that.
That day...
No. That night...
Huh?
I'm talking about the night
that "God" disappeared.
Do you know of it?
How rude. Of course I do.
"Heaven and Hell are too crowded."
"It won't be long before this world is, too."
"Ah, I have failed."
Right?
Words that have been
echoed around the world.
But they're words that
were spoken after the fact.
After?
When that day actually came,
no one even realized it.
In fact, there weren't any noticeable changes at all.
Wanna hear my personal theory?
"God" is probably an idiot.
I can see that you're
not the most God-fearing of men.
Just hear me out.
I think He simply lost interest in everything.
This world had the laws of
physics and nature to govern it,
and sufficient sources of energy.
The world was well constructed
and had no contradictions,
but in the same vein, it was also pretty boring.
And that's why He felt inclined to
finally give mankind what it wanted.
I don't know why people stopped being born,
but people stopped dying
because it was mankind's
greatest wish to keep on living.
And He granted that wish.
Then after a while,
people started wanting to die instead.
That's when He sent the gravekeepers.
Although He may be a bit misguided,
He probably believes He is
giving mankind what it wants.
That's my theory.
I've seen so many miracles in my travels.
Like your immortality?
Aren't you a sharp one.
I'm what used to be called "albino."
I was so weak to sunlight
that I couldn't even attend school regularly.
But right around that time, my body stabilized.
So, at the age of seventeen, I made a wish:
"May these days last forever."
Ever since the events of that fated day...
aside from me, society had no choice
but to accept the restless dead
despite not knowing what to do with them.
Because of the Half-Dead Fever, right?
A brand-new epidemic:
The Half-Dead Fever.
It claimed two hundred million lives across the globe...
two hundred million dead, roaming the world.
Was yesterday your
first time seeing a dead person?
Then, you should learn...
if someone dies of natural causes,
their appearance and personality remain
relatively unchanged from when they were alive.
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
But eventually, they undergo gradual changes.
To their minds as well as their bodies.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
Their survival instincts intensify despite them being dead...
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
until they care only for themselves.
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
And once you've reached that point,
there's no turning back.
Even the most virtuous saint
would turn into nothing but a wild beast.
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Now imagine living with one of those.
Those who cling to the dead
only bring disaster upon themselves.
So that's why you killed Yuri's wife.
Life on the planet
life on the planet
Why?
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
Why did you kill all the villagers?
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Please tell me.
You don't need me to tell you.
Someday, you'll find the answer to that yourself.
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
Along with the secret
that was sealed in that village.
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
Secret?
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
It's a place in the skies,
where the dead go.
Just you try imagining it!
I've come to bury you.
Are you scared?
He was kidnapped.
What a pleasant surprise, Ai.
...you'd rather be a monster?
Finally up, Humpnie Humbert?
There'd be no one around. No one.
The Valley of Death III
He's not a monster!