I've got it!
It's gotta be a food and drinks stall!
Nah, a play's a way better idea!
Maybe, like, muffins and tea.
Oh, wow!
Nah, we should definitely do a musical.
I'll play the lead.
You? Please.
Alice Color.
Huh?
My name.
Oh! Nice to meet you.
I'm Ai Astin.
So, what's up?
You want me to save you too?
What?
You trying to pick a fight?
I'm more likely to do the saving than to need it, you know.
That's right!
I'm gonna save the world!
That's the spirit.
We finally meet, Ai Astin.
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Goran Academy I
Hey, Ai.
Do you wanna go to school?
School?!
Hm...
Elementary schools don't exist anymore.
Soon, middle schools won't either.
And in three years' time, neither will high schools.
Once that happens, you'll never get the chance again.
To tell you the truth,
I asked a friend of mine to talk to some of his connections about it.
Ai!
I believe that was one of Goran Academy's cars.
No way!
You gotta be kidding me.
Goran Academy?!
Ai Astin,
you have been accepted into this academy.
Huh?
"Yes," not "Huh"!
Ah, yes.
Get rid of that "Ah," too!
Yes!
That's more like it.
I am Manita Hausent.
I am a lecturer here at Goran Academy
and also the dorm supervisor.
Ai Astin,
be sure to devote yourself to your studies from today onward.
A-A concentration camp?!
N-No way...
Well, maybe calling it that is going a bit too far.
To be more precise, this is a mandatory education camp for minors.
But it is true that we're forced to attend.
I'm sure that's some kinda misunderstanding.
This is clearly a normal school.
I mean, a car came to pick me up.
Then a slightly strict teacher came to congratulate me on my enrollment.
I even got a uniform.
I'd been wearing pants all this time, so the skirt felt nice and new to me.
Then they showed me the dorms.
After that, I got the chance to introduce myself to all of you in Class Q.
I attended classes that, in my opinion, seemed perfectly normal.
And I even had a conversation with a guy from our class, albeit a puzzling one.
And finally, I was put on cleaning duty after school.
I think this is the very picture of normal school life.
Uh...
Having no common sense is a scary thing!
Huh? But my late father said...
Well, let me explain anyway.
Schools are facilities where kids are segregated by age
and isolated from the rest of society
so that they don't impede its functioning.
That's what he said.
He was just being figurative.
I mean, for starters, didn't you think it was strange how you were suddenly brought here?
What?
Well...
Yuri was just talking about how I should go to school,
so I figured this was the place.
Yuri?
He was traveling with me.
So you were sold out, huh?
Huh?
That guy sold you out.
That's impossible!
Sure, Yuri may be all brawn and no brains,
but he'd never do something like that.
Wow, you sure put a lot of faith in that guy.
Um, well...
If it's like you said and this isn't actually a school,
then there must've been some kind of mix-up.
Yuri and the others are probably worried about me.
I'd better leave immediately.
You can't.
What?
Once you're enrolled here, you cannot leave.
What? You're kidding, right?
Unfortunately, no.
No matter how much you might wish to go back, you won't be able to.
But I've got to fulfill my dream of saving the world!
Huh?
And I can't very well save the world if I'm stuck here.
What are you all slacking off for?
Hurry up and go bathe!
Perfect timing!
It seems my coming here was some kind of mistake.
Yes, Ms. Manita!
We'll go take our baths right away!
Get undressed quickly.
Huh?
Hurry up!
Um... I...
We have to follow a strict schedule.
Wh-What are you all doing?!
Well, basically...
Ai, you're...
Your hair's so shiny and silky.
And your cheeks are so soft!
Ai, you're so tiny and cute!
A village of the dead?
I was raised there.
So you see...
this is my first time seeing so many living people in one place.
By the way, I myself am half human, half gravekeeper.
I've never heard of that before.
That must be the reason you were brought here.
Reason?
Wait. You don't even know why we're all brought here?
Goran Academy is an isolation facility for kids with special abilities.
Special abilities?
I'm Volrath.
My strength is unrivaled!
I'm Mimi, the eldest.
I'm Meme, the second oldest.
We're not twins,
but triplets!
I'm Momo, the youngest!
Huh?
Our younger sister Momo died.
She was buried by a gravekeeper.
But she still lives on inside us.
In other words, we have
multiple personalities!
Whoa...
And I'm Run.
I can breathe underwater.
Y-You've been underwater this whole time?
Yep.
Wow!
All of us have had near-death experiences.
And when we did, we each made a powerful wish
and ended up with our abilities.
You each made a powerful wish?
That's right.
What about you, Tanya?
What's your ability?
The Inner Eye.
"Inner Eye"?
Well, I'm blind.
Rather than sight, I have this ability...
I "hear" my surroundings instead of seeing them.
What do you mean?
It's difficult to explain,
but I can sense form and even color through sound.
Green has its own sound,
and so do hexagons,
and even smoke.
Um, so do I have my own sound too?
Your sound is very pleasant.
It's like a "moonbow"—a rainbow made by moonlight.
Do you know what that is?
Uh...
Unlike a normal rainbow, it's not showy or extravagant,
nor does it make everyone stop and gaze at it.
It's a rainbow that shines in the dark of night,
unbeknownst to anyone—
an existence that's just a little bit sad.
That's what you sound like.
Like a rainbow of the night...
Wh-What's that?
A hole?
That's definitely a hole.
Well, yeah... but that's not what I meant!
That's Alice, isn't it?
Well, aren't you a tricky one, Alice!
First, you give off this mysterious aura,
and then you break into the bath like a pervert!
No, wait! This is just a misunderstanding!
It is!
Really, it is!
H-Hardy!
You already have me! How could you even think of peeping?!
Uh, well...
This is...
I can't believe this!
Not you too, Geegee!
You're usually so diligent and cute!
You're too young to be doing this, Gee!
Like we keep saying,
you've got the wrong idea!
Also, I'm twenty-two!
I only look like this 'cause I was asleep for so long!
Either way, all of you are gonna pay for this!
You guys are the worst.
This is unbelievable!
Time to atone for your sins!
You should be punished!
Wait!
Escape?
Yeah, that's right.
We're gonna escape from this detention facility.
We managed to secure a path all the way here from under the dorm.
Um...
Have you all been digging a long time?
Yeah.
Oh, I see.
Because you've got my darling, Hardy, with you!
Yes, that's right, my dear Volrath.
Um, I don't get it.
Well, Hardy's ability is to consume inorganic material for his own sustenance.
We dig, and Hardy eats.
Th-That's amazing.
We tried to use an explosion to connect this place to the tunnel we've been digging,
but things went wrong.
This underground aqueduct leads to the outside.
So if we can just destroy this, we'll all be free.
But, Alice,
you only arrived here last week.
Why'd you transfer in the first place, if you didn't wanna be here?
I didn't come here because I wanted to.
Why does this school keep doing that kinda stuff?!
Because ever since people stopped dying, children have stopped being born too.
That means the student pool is only decreasing.
Rumor has it that for each student, the school receives a large government stipend every month.
That's why they're apparently trying
to get all the students they can.
As things stand, we probably won't be able to leave this school even when we become adults.
What? That can't be!
"Can't be," my ass.
That's exactly why we're trying to break outta here, you know.
You say that,
but you guys were pretty careless, huh?
Only because my little ghost here played a prank on us.
Ghost?
Hey, Dee! Come out!
I know you're there!
Sorry!
I told you to use too many explosives!
Damn it, Dee.
I just figured it'd be better to tell the girls about the escape plan sooner rather than later...
Ai especially.
Huh?
Wh-Who's she?!
Did she just go through that wall?!
And is she floating?!
But she's not a student here, is she?!
Hey, nice to meet you, students of Goran Academy.
Oh, nice to meet you too.
I'm Dee Ensy Stratmitos.
A witch?!
Oh, please don't call me that.
Or at the very least, call me
by my full title: "Western Witch."
I-I'm sorry.
A witch?
Come on. Like I said,
don't lump me in with those minions.
Regardless of the time or place,
I show up randomly without so much as a physical form.
Then I whisper in the ears of those whose paths I cross, and offer them advice.
Advice?
That's right. Advice ranging from the most trivial to the most significant of things.
Sometimes, I tell kids where their lost toys are,
while other times, I lead nations to victory by providing information about their enemy's battle formation.
There are times when I make sure people hear my voice loud and clear.
And then there are times when I lower it to a whisper and pull people's strings behind the scenes!
In a way, you're granting their wishes, aren't you?
So, over time, you came to be known as the "Western Witch."
Thanks for the footnote.
But you know,
the name of mine I like best is one from long ago: "Whisper."
Whisper?
In any case, why are you here?
Because I'm haunting Alice,
and...
because Ai Astin's here.
M-Me?
You didn't notice, huh?
I whispered in your ear.
What?
I told you to go check out the clock tower during recess.
Oh, I was just curious as to
what the tower was like inside.
Really!
It wasn't because of a voice or anything. I decided to go there myself!
You're so straightforward, Ai.
I like that.
You know, for a while now—
as in, since back when you were in Ortus—
I've been keeping an eye on you
to tell Alice what you've been up to.
What?!
Um, well...
Alice, what's the meaning of this?
I can't tell you just yet.
Huh?
Like he said, we can't tell you right now.
But you know what, Ai?
You, Alice, and I...
The three of us were destined to come together.
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
...that's what dreams are all about, don't you think?
It's time. Let's go.
You're too much for me!
Buzzer Beater.
Do you think you have what it takes
to convince her?
We're eloping, just the two of us!
I don't know about this dream of mine anymore.
Goran Academy II