Got a bad cold?
Not to worry!
New
Kanonval
The brand-new formula that'll attack your cold head-on!
New
Kanonval
New Kanonval X!
That's a wrap!
Thank you very much.
This afternoon, you have
an interview and a rehearsal.
Cute as always, I see.
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
In the evening, you have your usual radio show and another rehearsal.
We have a letter here from one Wakakita Miki.
It's all or nothing with you, isn't it?
Being Kanon all the time is exhausting.
I hope my Exalted Brother is doing okay...
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
Did I... pass out?
I can't move an inch.
It's already noon?
My whole body feels so cold.
Am I sick?
And this just had to happen when Haqua was gone.
Come to think of it, I wasn't feeling well yesterday either.
And spending the night in the library must have made it worse.
Damn, maybe I shouldn't have come back home
after drawing out Shiori's goddess.
But there's no point in regretting my decision now!
I have to get to school.
Within either Chihiro or Ayumi resides the final goddess, Mercurius.
I found him, Nora.
Looks like he's sleeping.
You...
Hey. It's been a while.
That boy is likely the key to all this.
Keep an eye on him, Ryou.
Roger. Just leave it all to your brilliant buddy over here.
Hey, Nora's stupid buddy.
My name's Ryou, you know. Asama Ryou.
What are you doing he—
Whatever.
Could you grab that cell phone for me?
I only take orders from Nora.
Cell. Phone. Now.
Sheesh, fine.
So, what're you doing? What're you doing?
Starting the event.
Ayumi
Event?
I'm triggering the "sick visit" event.
Call From Ellie
Hey, Ellie.
Not coming to school today?
What about band practice?
Hello...
Is this Ayumi?
Huh?
Wait!
Eh? What?!
Katsuragi?
Why are you using Ellie's phone?
Elsie asked me to call you.
Something came up, so she won't be at school today.
Something came up?
Everyone but me is away,
attending a memorial service.
So, Elsie won't be...
You don't sound too good.
A-Are you okay?
Oh, sorry.
My head kinda hurts... Did you say something?
N-Never mind!
Later!
That should do it.
I hope it's enough to get her to visit.
You get a call?
Man, I'm starving!
Where are you going?
I forgot to get a drink. I'm gonna go buy one.
Please visit me, Ayumi.
Hey.
Potato
Chips
What's a "sick visit" event?
The sick visit is as classic an event as there is.
You can track your progress
by seeing if a girl visits or not.
And this is the perfect chance to advance,
because I really am sick!
Potato
Chips
I'll need your help.
Huh?
Call From Chihiro
Chihiro?
Hello, Ellie?
Why aren't you at school today?
I was thinking of dropping off that music I mentioned, if that's okay...
Sounds like Chihiro hasn't found out yet.
But how come you're not at school? Are you sick?
I can't have them both visit at the same time.
Want me to bring you some sweets?
Elsie isn't home right now.
Katsuragi? What are you doing there?
The rest of the family went
to a memorial service today.
No point visiting someone who isn't here, stupid.
That should keep her away for now.
I'll try getting her to stop by later tonight, though.
He didn't have to call me stupid.
Light Music Club
Hey, wanna stop somewhere on the way home?
Yui, how about grabbing some taiyaki?
Sorry, I gotta go straight home.
How about you, Ayumi?
U-Um...
I have to go straight home too.
Huh?
You guys are no fun!
Sorry.
Why do I have to stand watch outside?
I should just go home.
Ow!
Hey! Is anyone there?
Damn, of course not.
Excuse me... Is anyone home?
Damn, I didn't think getting water would be so hard.
K-Katsuragi!
Are you okay?
Huh? Ayumi?
I wasn't worried about you or anything.
But you were coughing so hard,
I had to make sure you weren't dying.
Like I said before, I don't wanna talk to you anymore!
Where are you going?
My room.
Hey...
Are you really home alone?
I told you, my family won't be back for a while.
Oh, fine then.
If you're that sick, I can't just ditch you.
Up we go.
You're burning up.
I didn't expect your room to be so messy.
This is actually Elsie's room.
Why me?
Arrangement by: Ryou
You should keep your room a bit tidier.
It'd be embarrassing for visitors to see this mess, right?
No one ever visits me.
You're lying. People visit you.
That's why I was a little happy that you came to check on me.
Only a little? That's kinda mean.
She left?
You said that you wanted water, right?
I'll get you some.
Here. Is this okay?
Can you sit up on your own?
Yeah, it's okay.
Okay. Don't spill it.
Th-That's a cute cup.
Makes sense, since there's a café downstairs—
Make sure you hold it tightly.
Sorry.
I didn't expect it to go this well.
Is this the power of the sick visit event?
Then I'll take this as far as I can!
Y-You have to stay in bed.
You want to get better soon, don't you?
Now, make sure you keep yourself warm.
Hey...
What is it?
Could you... stay a little longer?
I-I guess I can.
Good! I feel like crap, but I can take it from here with my eyes closed.
Time to max Ayumi's affection level!
The doorbell rang.
I don't feel like answering it.
Pretend no one's home.
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Ch-Chihiro?!
Wh-Why is Chihiro here?
I took specific steps to ensure she wouldn't come!
If she sees me with Ayumi...
I'm screwed!
Hey, Nora's stupid buddy! Do something!
No answer...
I just had something I wanted to drop off.
Is anyone home?
If a girl shows up, let me know!
If you need anything, you should tell the other buddy.
He's waiting for you upstairs.
Buddy?
That moron! What is he doing?!
If I've completed a mission once,
I can repeat it without having to be told!
That's what makes me special.
Upstairs?
Are those Ellie's?
She's so messy.
I don't have time to send Ayumi home.
That would only lower her affection level.
I have to do something.
H-Hey!
Don't make a sound!
Katsuragi?
Wh-Why are you here?
I told you that Elsie isn't home, Chihiro.
Chihiro?
Ellie asked me for some sheet music.
Could you give her this?
Wait...
You don't look so good, you know.
Hey...
Would you go downstairs and get me some medicine?
Huh? You really are sick?
Are you okay?
I have a cold.
That's rotten luck, getting sick when everyone's out of the house...
Hold on.
Wh-Why did I have to hide?
Because I'm not comfortable with other people seeing us together.
It'll be worse if she sees us on the bed together!
Then you'll have to hide until Chihiro leaves.
Our honor is at stake here.
Our honor? This is all your fault!
Katsuragi?
Is this the medicine you wanted?
It's just over-the-counter stuff...
I-It'll be fine.
K-Katsuragi, this is really awkward... U-Um...
Could you keep your voice down? My head's killing me.
Hey, shouldn't you see a doctor?
It all happened so fast that I didn't get the chance to.
You have a serious fever!
What are they doing? I can't hear a thing.
Want me to open it for you?
You're nicer than I expected.
Than you expected?
Isn't this what anyone would do for someone who's sick?
What are you talking about?
A-Are you okay?
I appreciate your concern...
Concern... Well, I just...
I'm impressed this is going so well.
Despite my poor condition and a critical accident,
I'm still raising their affection levels.
I can pull this off! The double sick visit event!
Katsuragi, you seem awfully bulky.
I-I was shivering, so I added an extra blanket.
A blanket?
Shivering? Are you cold?
Then I'll turn on the heat.
When you have a cold, it's important to keep yourself warm.
Thank you...
Hot! Hot! Hot!
You don't want to get dehydrated, so I'll get you some water.
O-Okay.
Man, why do I have to do this?
It's too hot!
Did you pour water on yourself?
I-I sweat a lot!
Got a problem with that?
You liar.
You said no one was coming to visit you.
Chihiro's here to see Elsie.
Shut up!
You called me a blanket!
You can go—
I'm coming in.
Huh? Katsuragi?
Yes?
Your legs are sticking out.
Shouldn't you be wearing sweatpants or something?
It's my choice!
S-So hot...
How did she not notice that they weren't my legs?
Maybe that'd just be too absurd?
Katsuragi,
do you remember that song from the other day?
When was that?
In the music shop, remember?
Yeah...
I've f-finished the next part,
so I wanted you to hear it...
But if you're not feeling well, it can wait.
Huh?
Didn't she come to see Elsie?
She did come to see you!
What's wrong? Are you okay, Katsuragi?
M-My stomach's hurting a little...
Anyway, let me hear your song.
Huh? You don't have to if you're feeling sick.
Go ahead.
This cold is nothing.
Your song is more important.
D-Don't expect anything special.
This wasn't part of my plan,
but the completion of that song is a crucial event.
I'll have to put Chihiro first,
even if I lose points with Ayumi!
Okay...
The song is basically finished,
but I don't have any lyrics yet.
A-All right, here I go.
Okay.
What do you think?
I usually only listen to game soundtracks,
but I really like your song.
Are you going to play it at the Mai High Festival?
It won't be done in time.
The festival's in three days.
Anyway, I'm gonna head off.
Take care.
Hey...
Th-Thank you for listening to my song, even though you're sick.
Looks like I survived.
And I made good progress with Chihiro.
Now, for...
Ayumi?
Ayumi! Are you okay?
My shirt's see-through!
Argh! Don't look, you jerk!
You slimeball! I hope that cold kills you!
Why are you always so angry?
What's that supposed to mean?!
You're the one who made me angry!
I wasn't lying. I really didn't know she was coming.
Then there's nothing going on between you and Chihiro?
The truth is that I...
Katsuragi?
I forgot to tell you something.
I'm...
in love with you.
S-So... T-Tomorrow...
Sorry.
Did you say something?
I nodded off for a moment,
so I didn't catch what you said.
Chihiro?
N-Never mind!
Katsuragi?
Were you listening, Ayumi?
What did Chihiro say?
Huh?
You didn't hear it?
I-I should get going.
Wh-What's wrong?
It's from you hitting me under the blankets...
Wh-What? You're blaming me?
I can't let Ayumi leave now.
Don't give her time to think.
Still, I can't believe Chihiro...
That confession caught me completely by surprise.
I can't handle this on my own!
If only Haqua were here.
Well?
Is she still upstairs?
I told her I had to use the restroom.
I misjudged Chihiro's affection level.
And those two are close friends, which just complicates things.
At this point, my only option is to choose one and go all-in.
Hey, which of those girls do you prefer?
I'd go with, uh...
Hmm, which would it be?
Exactly. Which do I conquer first?
Chihiro
Chihiro!
Calling Chihiro
I'm...
in love with you.
I'm sorry. I actually heard you.
I heard your confession.
Hello?
I heard...
Chihiro, answer the phone!
Chihiro, are you in love with Katsuragi?
Huh?
What do you mean, you heard?!
What did you hear?
Oh...
I heard some rumors...
What the heck?
Never mind.
Where are you right now, Ayumi?
O-Oh, I'm... Um...
Actually...
I kind of confessed my feelings...
To Katsuragi?
I just lost it for a moment.
I was mostly talking to myself.
He wasn't listening anyway.
I don't know what came over me.
Maybe I've asked so many guys out that I'll go for anyone now!
That isn't true.
You've found true love.
I'm rooting for you!
Ayumi?
Hello?
A-Ayumi?
Are you feeling better?
Yeah, much better.
Good.
Then I'm going home.
My cold's getting worse again...
Don't worry.
I'll ask Chihiro to come and take care of you.
What? It isn't working?
Ayumi, are you mad?
Why would I be mad?
Be nice to Chihiro.
Bye.
Ayumi isn't angry anymore?
And she keeps bringing up Chihiro.
I don't get it,
but I have a really bad feeling about this.
What...
...should I do now?
Well, it is what it is.
Was Ayumi...
at Katsuragi's house?
Goddess Mix
Chihiro and Ayumi.
They're classmates, bandmates, and best friends.
So I must exercise the utmost care when conquering them.
This is such a pain!
If the last goddess were in someone like Haqua, this would be much easier.
Huh? Where did she go, anyway?