You want me to go back home?
Yes.
We don't know how strong Vintage is.
If we're all in one place, we risk being crippled by a single attack.
Have Tsukiyo go about her life normally,
but be careful not to reveal yourself, Vulcanus.
On your left wrist is a bracelet made from Haqua's raiment.
If anything happens, tear it off.
I'll know something is wrong right away.
What are you going to do?
Search for the remaining goddesses.
I apologize for burdening you with everything.
By the way, Katsuragi...
You're not going to tell me that the other girls hosting my sisters
are all girlfriends of yours, are you?
Can't say.
I haven't found the other goddesses yet.
It boggles the mind.
Why is Tsukiyo attracted to this dirty,
disgusting unknown quantity of a man?
Everyone's a hater, huh?
Tsukiyo loves you.
Understood?
U-Unhand me!
Tsukiyo.
Be careful.
You be careful too, Keima.
Yeah.
Three more to go.
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
At least the goddess search isn't as urgent now.
Punch and Date
Why not?
Well...
Now that the curse on Kanon's been lifted, you can slow down...
No.
There's at least one conquest
I need to complete right away.
Yo, Katsuragi-kun.
Isn't it a lovely day?
Yui...
Shall we go out together?
Right now...
I should...
You shouldn't come to my house.
I don't like people who are too pushy.
Hey! What was that for?
Quiet.
The conquest has already begun.
Right now,
I need to conquer Yui.
Why?
Yui isn't herself right now.
She may have switched with her goddess.
You mean...
Indeed.
It's similar to how Diana and Tenri switch places.
Originally, Yui was
a rich, obedient girl who did everything her parents said.
But she's changed drastically since then.
It's entirely possible.
If the goddess in Yui is currently in control...
Vintage could find her!
Correct.
We should move fast.
However,
isn't Yui your one weakness?
You've got that right.
She came to my house of her own volition.
She behaves like a player character.
Conquering her right away won't be easy.
You're the one who said you had to.
We need a major event.
One that Yui won't be expecting.
Goddess Search, Day 5
Sucks that we have gym in the morning.
So, Yui...
I see you're still on the girls' team for gym.
I already told you I never became a boy!
But you wear a boy's P.E. uniform, don't you?
I'm a girl—
It really doesn't make a difference.
That's harsh...
Oh, what time should we practice today?
Let's see...
The Mai High Festival's coming up.
Huh? Yui?
Hey! Excuse me!
Wait!
Ow...
K-Katsuragi-kun?!
Wh-What are you doing?
U-Uh, this is...
I-I've been feeling strange lately.
My heart feels confused...
I know this can't be right...
You're so cute!
Now we match perfectly.
Wh-What are you talking about?
This is wrong!
I felt my heart skip a beat.
You're really cute, so you should make this your permanent look.
You certainly got her attention fast.
Yui is a highly skilled player.
If I try to assume the player's role as well, we'll never get anywhere.
Where did you go, Yui?
Nowhere.
Why are you grinning?
My goal is to reach the ending as soon as possible.
What? No reason.
If I play the heroine,
allowing Yui to conquer me, I'll arrive at the same goal.
I have collected data on tens of thousands of heroines.
I will use that data as Yui conquers me.
I shall become the Conquered God!
Will this really work?
N-Nii-sama?
Yep.
I think he went somewhere...
Oh.
Where'd he go?
Katsuragi-kun!
You're so cute...
U-Um...
I have a question for you.
Faculty
It's kinda awkward for me to use the students' restroom, so I come here instead.
Can you stand outside in case someone comes?
Sure...
I don't know how boys go...
Say, Katsuragi-kun...
What kind of underwear are you wearing?
Men's underwear...
Katsuragi-kun, in the past...
did something happen between us?
Maybe. I don't know.
O-Oh...
Anyway, Yui...
Hmm?
Would you go on a date with me today after school?
I want to get to know you better...
Huh?!
W-Wait...
Lemme think it over!
Yesterday, she was the one asking me out,
but when I asked her today, she ran.
Something has changed.
Huh? What do you mean?
That was the real Yui, not the goddess.
When I first ran into her again, she introduced herself to me.
She didn't remember the conquest, but her feelings for me still existed.
I will give those unconscious feelings a purpose.
During the conquest, Yui and I switched bodies.
I'm going to try to invoke her memory of the time she spent in my body.
That may, in turn, awaken her memory of the conquest.
Will that really work?
She's already shown a response.
I'm guessing the goddess in her is awakening right now.
Yui, you're not bad as a player character.
However, I am a master in this field.
We will settle this during our date after school!
Prepare yourself, Yui!
Faculty
Katsuragi-kun seemed different today.
Was it because he was dressed like a girl?
He's still the same person on the inside.
My head...
I feel dizzy...
What?!
Who are you?
Where am I?
I come from Heaven.
I am the goddess of war who judges the wicked.
My name is Mars.
I must really be exhausted...
Is this the human world?
Why have I been awakened?
Has the seal been broken?
I don't need this! I've got enough on my mind with this date!
Date?
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
I'm meeting Katsuragi-kun at DezeniSea at 5 PM!
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
From: Keima-kun
Title: To Yui
Yui,
DezeniSea
Main Entrance
5 (PM)
"Dezeni"...
What's that?
Okay... Let's do this.
Listen to me!
I have a bad feeling about this.
You should carry a weapon on you.
You're a strange one.
This world is too relaxed!
And why is a man like you in love with another man?
Like I keep saying, I'm a girl!
That's news to me.
That should do it.
How can you stand to act like that?
We're battling for control of the relationship.
I must stay one step ahead of her to—
Katsuragi-kun!
Sorry I'm late!
A tuxedo...
You look wonderful, Katsuragi-kun.
You're much cuter this way.
Crap! She's taken the initiative!
I brought clothes with me.
Could you put them on?
Welcome to StarJetter.
How many are...
Tickets for two.
Hey, what's with this dress?
You're so cute!
Are they in the parade?
My lady, if you will...
She's pretending to be a butler?
I have to applaud her initiative.
However, Yui's love for me won't grow if I let things stand the way they are.
I have to make her fall more deeply for me.
It's time to awaken the devilish girl inside me!
A bento?!
You made it yourself?
Yeah, I'm a pretty good cook...
I'm so happy!
Yui's a rich girl.
Food that's merely "good" won't leave an impression.
So make everything suck!
Come on, go crazy for my clumsy self.
I tried my best...
H-How is it?
My mom and dad are so busy
that I never get to eat home-cooked meals.
I'm so happy I could cry.
Say, would you cook for me again?
I'll think about it...
I'll go buy something to drink!
Honestly...
You always fall apart when you're on the defensive.
It's not my fault!
I'm not used to being conquered.
What happened to all that confidence?
I'm so happy.
Katsuragi-kun is opening up to me...
Was that your beloved?
She's a lovely girl.
Again?
I'll listen to what you have to say later.
Could you leave me alone for now?
Besides, Katsuragi-kun is a boy!
What?!
When were male and female clothing reversed on Earth?
It is a mystery.
However, I've taken a liking to you.
You have beautiful eyes
and a determined spirit.
I am the goddess of war.
I shall support you in your battle for love.
Wh-What?
Hey, are you alone?
Wanna have some fun with us?
You're a real cutie.
They're trying to pick me up?
What a banal effort.
You should rethink your approach.
At least try falling from the sky as an entrance.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Are you turning us down?
Excuse me!
You're scaring my beloved.
Eh?
What? Are you her boyfriend?
I am not.
Then butt out.
We're not scaring her.
I'm a girl!
Move!
Ryo-kun!
Uh, er...
Th-Thank you.
I was so scared...
Sorry.
I shouldn't have left you on your own.
I-It's no big deal...
Why does this keep happening?
I feel like something's right on the tip of my tongue...
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
Demons have taken over the castle!
Someone help us!
Restore the peace!
Welcome.
Everyone!
Wow, they've got costumes for us to wear!
This place is great!
I must say, you are a very handsome boy.
You again?
It looks like you're doing well with that girl.
Katsuragi-kun is a boy!
I'm a girl!
However, I've never seen such a facility used to spread love.
Even Heaven couldn't top this.
Haven't you ever been in love?
Ah, unfortunately, I've never had the chance.
I always spent all my time on the battlefield.
Battlefield?
Well, that's ancient history now.
Anyway, I wish you luck.
You must strike a fatal blow to her heart.
You're one violent ghost.
A princess!
You look so cute!
Quiet!
This place is pretty dark...
Are you scared?
Huh? No way.
Intruders!
That gave me a start...
So you are scared.
I can't help it.
It wasn't so long ago that I was a sheltered girl!
Amon-sama!
Congratulations!
You may now advance to the top floor!
Oh, that was easier than I thought it'd be.
Right, Katsuragi-kun?
Huh?
Katsuragi-kun? Where are you?
Katsuragi-kun!
Huh?
What's with this attraction?
Yui! Be careful!
This spell is magic from Hell!
Hell?
I didn't expect to find a goddess here.
What are you talking about?
Where are the others?
Tell me everything you know.
If you do, I'll release this girl.
What do you think you're doing to Katsuragi-kun?!
Stop!
Humans must not be harmed!
It's too late.
Very soon, they will all suffer.
What's going on?
I thought we sealed away the evil forces!
Before long, the world will be shrouded in darkness...
as Old Hell is revived!
Stop!
Get away from Katsuragi-kun!
A mere human dares to touch me?!
This is a world of peace in which humans are devoted to love.
I think it's splendid.
Do not interfere!
I, Mars, shall not allow you
to disrupt my friend's date!
You...
Y-You'll pay for this!
You're really gonna pay for this!
If Yui's goddess is already starting to manifest,
we must provide support.
We can appeal to both souls by creating a scenario that mimics one of Hell's plots.
It's still not right to set up a fake crisis like that.
At least it's fake.
That's much better than a real crisis.
Still...
I was hoping you would run away.
I hate the idea of being saved by a heroine!
You shouldn't say that.
Girls are supposed to protect weak boys.
I really did...
find my prince.
New Maijima Station
I'm so happy!
Hold on...
The Weiss are loose?
We must defeat them!
Cut it out!
We don't know who's watching!
This is vexing.
How long must I wait?
Take this bracelet.
If you tear it apart, it'll send me a distress call.
Mars, you goddesses aren't as strong as you once were.
Please exercise discretion.
Got it.
We'll behave.
But in return,
can I call you "Keima-kun"?
See you at school, Keima-kun!
Why didn't you tell her about Kanon?
You mentioned the other goddesses and Vintage.
Those two are so headstrong
that they make a fearsome pair.
We can't have them launching an attack alone.
Today's attack was staged,
but we don't know when we'll encounter a real threa—
Katsuragi!
I'd been pickling it for a year, but it's still alive!
What?
Nii-sama!
My radio show was canceled,
so I came home to make dinner.
It's pretty obvious who made what.
Huh? Really?
Still, you've already found three goddesses.
That's my Nii-sama!
I guess it's because you weren't around.
Don't say that!
Nii-sama, eat some of my cooking!
I refuse.
Nii-sama!
It's my first visit home in so long!
You should be nicer!
It's only been five days.
Jeez...
Oh, Haqua! Let's take a bath together afterward!
Huh?
Whenever we see each other
fukakute atsui itoshisa
my burning love only grows stronger
au tabi ni tsumoru no
like white feathers gathering on the ground
shiroi hane no you ni
We passed each other so many times
nandomo surechigatteita
where the roads of love and hate meet
suki kirai daisuki sukuranburu-kousaten
In the morning and during the day
asa mo hiru mo
At night and when I dream
yoru mo yume no
I always want to be with you
naka demo zutto soba ni itai
I want to protect you
anata wo mamoritai no
This is the first time I've felt like this
konna kimochi hajimete no kanjou
Even if you make the whole world your enemy,
sekai wo teki ni shitemo
I will be your only ally
watashi dake wa mikata de itai kara
I trust you
shinjiteru
My Story
Shiomiya Shiori likes books.
I've been trying to open her heart by encouraging her to write,
but nothing's going as planned.
I-I'm sorry...
I have everything worked out in my head.
That usually means you haven't written anything down!