Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Goran Academy II
All right.
The very first Great Escape Conference is now in session!
Don't you think it's a little late to be having a conference?
I mean, we're pretty much done already.
Yeah, all we have left to do is destroy that iron grill.
B-But you know—
Nobody's even listening to you.
Huh?
Well, if there's any reason to hold this conference,
it's to decide who wants to go with us
and who doesn't.
We're all going, obviously!
Right, Volrath?
Yeah, I'm getting outta here.
I mean, I go where Hardy goes!
Uh...
R-Run!
I want to escape too.
I want to go to Espia, the underwater city.
An underwater city?
I didn't know a place like that even existed.
See? Like I said, everyone—
I'm... staying here.
Tanya.
We can't really give you an answer right now either.
Why not?
Didn't you all say you were
brought here against your will?
And you looked so down when you told me
we could never leave this place.
Yes, that's true.
But I have nowhere else to go.
Huh?
What about home?
I have one...
but I can't go back to it.
Going back would only cause problems for my parents.
It's a tiny village.
For a long time now, the villagers have had peace of mind
believing that everyone who lives there...
is the same.
So there's no room for me there—not with this body.
It's pretty much the same with us.
We come from a family of nobles
where honor and prestige come before all else.
Us going home...
Papa and Mama would hate it, wouldn't they?
What?
Is that all?
Well, I mean...
Tanya, Mimi, Meme,
you all want to live with your parents, don't you?
That's your, well... your dream, right?
In that case, you should do
all you can to fulfill that dream.
And if your old home won't do, find someplace else that will.
Um...
And if you can't find that someplace,
then just build it yourself!
I mean, that's what dreams are all about, don't you think?
Tanya?
That's too much.
It'll be all right!
If you plan things thoroughly—
That's not what I mean!
You're...
too much for me!
Tanya?!
The battlefield is a unique environment
where respect, too, takes on a unique meaning.
The different ways you show respect
for your superiors, your subordinates,
your comrades, your enemies,
and the environment.
That respect forms a tight web—
the distinct atmosphere of battle...
She said I was too much.
Yep, she did.
Well, how should I say this?
That must've been hard. For Tanya, I mean.
Huh?
What you said was completely right, Ai,
but there are a lot of people who can't chase after their dreams like that.
Regardless, we're cutting through that grill and getting outta here.
If you want Tanya and the others to come along,
you'd better get them onboard before we finish.
What do you think?
She has even less common sense than I expected.
Can't hold it against her, though.
It's only been about half a month since she left her village up in the mountains.
She's senseless and unbalanced,
but that's exactly why she'll be useful, don't you think?
I sure hope so.
Um...
I'd like to talk to you about what I said earlier.
You mean about our dreams?
Yeah.
Ai,
I think you can dream because
you have somewhere you belong.
You mentioned a "Yuri," remember?
You said he traveled with you,
and that he worries about you.
Yes. There's also Scar and Celica.
Ai, if you leave this place, those people will welcome you with open arms.
But with me, it's different.
I was born blind.
It's not like I knew what I was missing, so it didn't really bother me.
But...
I feel so sorry for her.
Yeah, the poor thing.
...when I found out how my parents felt, it saddened me,
and I wanted to be able to see.
That wish was granted,
and I attained the ability to "hear" things—
the Inner Eye.
My parents were overjoyed,
but the other villagers didn't feel the same.
So I came here without telling my parents about it.
I bet you couldn't understand.
I don't.
The people of my village are all gone.
My mother was a bit of an unusual gravekeeper.
She tried to create a Heaven-like place
where the dead could live enjoyable lives.
But she passed away when I was five.
I grew up believing that all the villagers were alive.
But one day,
my father showed up.
The villagers as well as my father...
As a gravekeeper, I gave them all a burial.
But now, I've got Yuri and Scar by my side.
So that's why... you'll be fine too,
I'm sure.
You're so strong.
Forgive me, Ai.
You're just too dazzling for me.
And that's that.
Let's get out of here now.
How dreamy!
We're eloping, just the two of us!
Not quite.
Well, it's not like we can leave just yet.
But we're gonna try to escape tonight, right?
Yeah.
When Manita and the others fall asleep
and security is at its weakest.
At 3:00 a.m.
We're coming with you.
Mimi! Meme!
Momo says she's in, too.
Now it's just Tanya.
Can we...
Can we put it off for just one day?
But she's being so stubborn.
Do you think you have what it takes
to convince her?
I'm not sure.
I don't see why we can't.
It's just one more day.
It'd be nice if we had everyone in Class Q onboard.
Okay.
We escape tomorrow, then.
Tanya?
Tanya, give me another chance to talk to you.
Tanya...
3 a.m. tomorrow, okay?
Hey, we're short by over ten plates.
Seriously?
Hey, there's a spelling mistake on this sign.
Crap, you're right!
Who the hell wrote this thing?!
Oh no! I forgot to get a receipt!
Class Rep, can't anything be done about this?
Pay for it yourself.
Oh, that's right.
Somebody take off the curtains.
Did I wake you?
Nah.
What is it?
Come to confess your love to me after all?
Wh-What the heck?
I don't know about this dream of mine anymore.
To save the world.
That's my dream.
Until half a month ago,
that tiny village was my entire world.
The moment I set foot outside of it,
I felt like saving the whole world,
but then, someone in Ortus told me
I wouldn't be of any help.
And right now, I can't even help Tanya.
I just don't know what's what anymore.
Is it possible to save the world?
I see.
Well, we're trying to save it too.
What?
Really?
You two want the same thing I do?
Sorry to say, but not quite.
Alice wants to save the world by destroying it.
"Destroying"?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
For starters, you understand that in a manner of speaking, there are two worlds, right?
Two worlds?
Guess I've gotta go through this step-by-step.
I suppose I could call the first world the "objective" world.
It's the world that exists even without an observer.
The objective world? An observer?
Let's say mankind goes extinct.
The universe will still exist, right?
It'll continue to function with
the other animals and lifeforms.
Well, yeah...
That's world number one—
a world that stands on its own.
On the other hand,
world number two is what the observer perceives.
Wh-What do you mean by "observer"?
You can interpret it as people.
People like you and me.
No matter what we do, we can't see the objective world.
The world that people see through their eyes
is but an interpretation of the real thing.
In other words, our view is subjective.
Um, so basically,
you're saying that each of us sees a different world?
Yes, exactly.
From what I've seen,
most people consider what they perceive—
a small fraction of the universe—
to be the entire world.
For Tanya, that'd be her parents.
Probably.
And for me, the world is but a tiny community.
And the world can be saved by destroying that community.
H-How?
How can it be saved through destruction?
Well, the time to tell you that will come soon enough.
My mother's world was destroyed,
and her dream, broken.
What about my dream?
Without leaving me an answer,
Time just keeps flowing,
silently
but surely,
and never, ever stopping.
It's time.
Let's go.
Tanya never showed up, huh?
Nothing we can do about it.
It's her decision to make.
Ai?
I'm sorry.
I'm staying!
Well, I'm not really staying.
I'll definitely escape later—with Tanya!
That's hopeless, though.
I don't care if it is.
I'm not gonna leave Tanya behind—
You'd stay back for my sake?
I can't stand for that.
So instead...
take me with you.
Tanya!
Ai, a moonbow gives courage to travelers who would otherwise be alone.
Yeah!
Thank you.
Freedom's at the other end of this ladder.
That's right.
All right, let's go.
Okay.
You lot don't have what it takes to survive in the outside world, and you know it.
Come on, now. Give me an about-face.
This is your last chance.
Better take it while I'm still smiling.
So she says.
So they say.
I see.
Such bad children!
Time for sleep.
Buzzer Beater.
So your ability is perfect aim, is it?
Hey!
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
Ai!
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Yuri, where's Scar?
She abandoned her child.
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
...as long as it will .
actually save the world.
This is where
gravekeepers are born.
Scar!
Please stop!
The only words that can keep you alive are
"I want to live."
I'd hate it if I never saw her again.
The Birthplace of Gravekeepers