Light.
Let there be light...
Let there be excitement!
New game... start!
Farewell to this world!
To the crappy game known as "reality"!
And now,
I've returned...
to the world of dating sims!
My name is Katsuragi Keima.
Seventeen years old, born on June 6th.
I love the girls in games.
In contrast, real girls are unreasonable, snobbish, irrational,
and completely beyond hope!
But one day,
I signed a contract with Elsie,
a demon from Hell,
forcing me to conquer real girls instead.
I help them fall in love
in order to chase the loose souls from the emptiness in their hearts.
Loose soul in custody!
If I fail, the collar around my neck will activate.
A rather harsh rule, if I say so myself.
But I have cleared many kinds of dating sims, and I am known far and wide as the "God of Conquest."
God of Conquest
There is no girl I cannot conquer!
Trap
That's a cross-dresser...
These puny hurdles are nothing to me!
I understand you well...
I know how you feel deep inside.
Because...
I have experienced being a girl!
I'm so sorry!
Are you injured?!
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
This was during my conquest of Goidou Yui,
the daughter of a rich, famous family.
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Please get off me
before you apologize.
Goidou
Yui
Class:
Height
Weight
Apparently, the loose soul has caused Yui and me...
to switch bodies!                                    to switch bodies!
Eh?!
Well, this happens all the time in games.
This is the body of a girl...
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Score one for the real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Note the
obsessive
determination
to conquer
a girls'
dating sim.
Eyes show
new respect
for the
real world.
Master Keima, do not worry.
If we never regain our true bodies,
I shall still protect you,
even if it costs me my life!
Thank you.
Huh?
You've already captured fourteen loose souls?
Yup!
All thanks to my Divine Brother!
Ugh, how infuriating.
He's a total creep.
Huh? But my brother's so cool...
every now and then.
Long time no see, Haqua!
Ah, thank you for having me.
Wow, that smells wonderful.
Make yourself at home.
Will do!
I guess appearance doesn't matter for a buddy...
Speaking of which...
I've never met your buddy.
What're they like?
U-Uh...
Tai Chi Lesson 1
This is hard.
Well...
She's pretty normal.
"When I kiss you, I feel like I'm kissing a girl."
Conquest complete.
Underclassman, ghost, ramen cook, shogi player, older woman...
After racking up real-world conquests,
real girls are no problem!
However,
I did have trouble understanding a real-life mad scientist:
Kurakawa Akari.
I hope nothing like that ever happens again.
Everything went wrong, and then she disappeared without a trace.
Crap!
Is something fried?
This observatory is for Luna and me alone,
so you should keep out.
I am only interested in beauty.
Whatever.
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou Tsukiyo wanted everything to be beautiful, like her dolls.
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
Kujou
Tsukiyo
Class
Astronomy club member
obsessed with beauty.
Luna
Ouch
And the loose soul inside her
shrank her down to the size of a doll.
Tsukiyo!
Stay back...
This world contains so much beauty!
Keima!
We can search for that beauty together!
I won't let you go to the moon!
Keima!
Tsukiyo...
Once the conquest is complete and the loose soul exorcised,
the girls forget everything that transpired.
I'm the only one who remembers what happened between us.
Divine Brother!
It's about time we got started!
Save,
save...
Save.
Save!
Continue.
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
Together, we can run forever!
That was Nakagawa Kanon!
Bang!
You have three radio shows tonight.
Okay.
Followed by some additional recording at Aokawa Studios.
And the song you just did for—
Ms. Okada?
Yes?
Can I do some studying, please?
I have a test tomorrow.
Oh, I forgot all about it...
Things are getting busier by the day.
I hope I'll have time for finals.
But enough griping!
Focus! Focus!
Kanon.
Kanon!
Come on, Kanon!
Wake up!
You're supposed to be studying right now!
She's back.
No sleeping on the job!
Apollo...
You put so much love into your singing today.
I can feel my power returning!
Your power?
Who are you?
Didn't I explain this a month ago?
I'm a goddess from Heaven!
What do you mean by "goddess"?
And what are you doing here?
That, I do not know.
One moment, I was sealing the Weiss,
and next thing I knew, I was here.
What I do know is that...
This and that and something else happened, and now I'm here!
There's your answer.
You don't know anything!
Well, it doesn't really matter.
I am a descendant of Apollo, god of the arts.
My divine blessing is just perfect for you!
Am I so tired
that I'm starting to see things?
We're off!
Take care!
Wait for me, Exalted Brother!
U-Um...
G-Good morning, Keima.
Oh, Tenri!
Good morning.
Good morning, Elsie.
Did you need something, Tenri?
Ah, well...
Diana wants to talk to you.
That's nice.
See you later.
Diana!
Why must you always be so cold?
You were just reunited with Tenri after ten long years,
and you even shared a kiss.
I was simply putting on an act to get rid of Nora.
You know that.
Anyway, when did that thing appear?
It's a halo!
This ring is the symbol of the goddesses.
Tenri's love helped restore it.
The goddesses?
Yes.
I come from Heaven.
Your people would refer to us
as gods.
Aren't you surprised?
Well, there's a demon standing right next to us.
And if there are demons,
there are bound to be gods.
I'm glad you're so quick to understand.
However, the moment you said you weren't a loose soul,
you stopped being my problem.
You're still saying that?
So, what do you want?
I want you to marry Tenri.
Huh?
Loose souls feed on negative energy,
while goddesses require the power of love to grow.
To fuel my power, I require more love.
If you marry Tenri, she will be happy,
and my power will return.
That is why...
you must marry her.
Don't be absurd!
Why must you be so difficult?
You should pay more attention to Tenri.
Ayukawa
Residence
Katsuragi
She even moved in next door to you,
but you spend all your time on other girls.
Ayukawa
Residence
Katsuragi
but you spend all your time on other girls.
You can start by walking to school together every morning.
We go to different schools!
Whoa, it's Kanon!
She comes to school for tests!
Good morning.
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
Ms. Okada...
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
From: Manager Okada
To: Kanon
Good luck!
You sure are popular!
You're like a walking spectacle!
Good luck!
Okay! Let's begin the test!
Kids...
This is your day of reckoning!
Katsuragi!
Put away your game!
First demons, now goddesses...
Katsuragi, are you listening?
Why does this stuff keep happening to me?
Hey!
Put it away right now!
Katsuragi!
Huh? Kanon isn't here.
Didn't she come to school today?
Her popularity hasn't faded one bit.
No kidding.
Apollo, is it okay if I talk to someone about you?
No way!
Huh?
Blabbing about me to humans won't get you anywhere.
Then, do you have a plan?
Um... Um...
To be honest, I'm not the sharpest tool in the shed.
That doesn't help.
I'm a holy maiden.
Thinking isn't my forte.
B-But...
If Diana was here,
she'd think of something for sure.
Diana?
My younger sister.
She's super smart!
Where is she?
No idea.
That doesn't help either!
We're not getting anywhere by ourselves!
We need someone we can rely on.
Wh-What?
You just want an excuse to talk to Katsuragi Keima, don't you?
I can see the love blossoming inside you.
You only spent a week with Katsuragi, right?
It's really kinda sweet
that you're still pining after him.
It's not like I'm in love with him or anything.
It's just that...
after Apollo appeared,
I started remembering all kinds of things.
But when I asked Keima, he said...
You've got the wrong person.
I don't remember anything of the sort.
Good morning!
I guess there's no point in talking to him.
No. I'll pass.
He rejected me, didn't he?
There's nothing between us anymore.
I was lost in darkness,
and could not see.
But then I found...
Hey.
Oh, you're Diana now?
You ambushed me at school?
Only because you're so set on avoiding me.
I told you to walk to school with Tenri.
Excuse me...
Why are you walking around with an umbrella?
People will notice the ring above my head otherwise.
What happens if someone touches it?
P-Please stop.
Diana.
Why are you here in our world?
A while back,
you mentioned that you sealed the loose souls long ago.
Does your presence here relate to the trouble we've been having?
Perhaps it does.
To be honest, I myself don't know.
What do you mean?
Before everything began, there were three worlds—
Heaven, Earth, and Hell—
all linked by the flow of souls.
The humans, bearers of souls, lived on Earth.
After death, their souls went to Hell, where they were purified.
Heaven restored those souls to humans.
The souls flowed through the realms in a grand cycle.
However, the ancient demons of the old Hell
began to manipulate humans into evildoing
in order to fatten their souls and increase their energy yield.
Then, they concocted a frightening scheme.
They planned to lay waste to Heaven,
turning Earth into a graveyard of stranded souls,
so as to rule all three worlds.
And I'm guessing the modern demons were the ones who opposed them.
They were not alone.
The ones who banished the ancient demons known as Weiss
were gods from Heaven:
we, the Jupiter Sisters.
Sisters?
The ancient demons had Heaven in their sights.
As we were goddesses of great power,
we sacrificed ourselves to seal away the ancient demons and eliminate the threat.
But apparently, the seal has been broken,
bringing gods and ancient demons to Earth.
Yes.
When I awakened, I was already here.
Now then,
you mentioned that you have sisters?
It's possible that they've also arrived on Earth.
If that is the case, I want to find them.
Katsuragi.
Hmm?
Could you help me look for my sisters?
I'd be relying on you to lead the effort.
Do it yourself!
When I woke up...
Hey!
...there was a loose soul attached to my body.
I assume it was put there as camouflage
to hide me from the escaping souls.
If the other goddesses are on Earth,
they will likely be in a similar state.
In other words, you'll find one where you found the other.
Therefore, we can conclude that there may be goddesses
within the girls you've liberated from loose souls.
I need you to check each of them again.
Since when is that my problem?
I've already got my hands full chasing loose souls!
I can't just run off with no leads!
I do have a lead!
Which would be?
The other girls who host goddesses retain their memories of you,
just as Tenri does!
What did you say?
Once a loose soul is exorcised,
the host's memories of the event are erased.
But if one of us goddesses is within them,
our own memories will fill the gaps in theirs.
In other words, they will remember everything.
If one of the girls you've conquered is host to a goddess,
she will remember you.
She'll remember me?
I'm counting on you.
H-Hey! Wait!
Tenri?
I-I'm late!
Looks like she's causing you trouble, too.
It's Keima! But...
who's that girl?
Kanon!
Good luck on your test!
Kanon...
What is it, Apollo?
Someone's watching us.
Everyone's always watching us.
That's not what I mean!
Hey—
It wasn't just a regular onlooker!
It felt more...
different!
Different?
They're watching us right now!
Don't scare me like that.
Who could be watching us?
Diana's causing trouble again.
Who is Apollo, anyway?
The goddesses are inside my prior conquests?
Then, could there be one inside Chihiro or Ayumi?
That's right. There's one more of them in this class.
What should I do?
Kanon.
Maybe she...
remembers?
Excuse me, have we met before?
Forget it!
This is Diana's problem, not mine!
Who was that?!
Ms. Okada, please pick up!
Ah, Ms. Okada!
The number you have dialed is currently unavailable.
It's probably just fatigue.
I'm exhausted,
and it's making me see things.
Like the broken glass.
I'm sure I just imagined it.
Keima...
Kanon?
Oh no!
Wh-What are you doing?
I didn't forget you, Keima.
I remember everything.
You're the only one I can turn to.
Wait! Come with me!
Eh?
Kanon!
She and the dweeb know each other?
Are you saying you remember how we met?
Yes.
You remember Seaside Hall and the roof?
I remember!
Our kiss...
Do you remember our kiss?
Yes.
So you didn't forget either.
Hey!
We're having a test here!
I... I...
I love you, Keima!
I've...
I've wanted to say it for so long!
I love you, Keima!
Kanon's in love with the dweeb?
Hey, you two!
No way!
They ran away!
What are you talking about?
K-Keima, someone's after me!
Who?!
Humans oughta stay out of this.
A ring!
Oh, now I'm in control!
I can feel my power starting to return,
thanks to you.
But that's enough.
Can't be getting innocent bystanders involved, you know?
Kanon!
Exalted Brother!
What happened to Kanon?
There's a goddess...
There's a goddess inside Kanon!
Having said that,
I still can't fly.
So I'd better find somewhere to hide!
An agent of Hell?
So you're the one who's been following me!
Jupiter Sisters...
Damn it!
Why are you after me?
We goddesses saved Hell!
As long as you goddesses are around,
we cannot revive the glorious Hell of yore.
Revive Hell?
Who are you—
Lune.
Lune of Vintage.
Scramble Formation
Divine Brother!
Someone stabbed Kanon!
It's all my fault.
I should've realized something was wrong sooner.
So that this never happens again,
I will go conquest crazy!
Wh-What should I do?
Become an idol!
You must become an idol!
Huh?