Ortus's dark side?
Who are you?
The one who made that fox mask.
What? You made this?
D-Don't take it off! You'll give yourself away!
As I was saying, the living should just stay in the inns
and get out of this city as soon as possible.
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Ortus II
Oh, hey! It's Kiriko!
Ai? Is that you?
Yup, it is me!
H-Hey!
What do you think you're doing out here?!
I was just checking out a bunch of stuff around town.
Oh, and I talked to this mysterious lion, too!
What?
Let's just get you back to the inn.
Okay...
You're such a weirdo.
Hey! Where did that come from?
How rude.
A real, live weirdo.
Not only did you want to enter this ghost town,
but you're actually enjoying yourself too.
What can I say? This place is fun.
Any normal living person
would be more scornful of the dead.
Well, I was raised by the dead.
Wh-Where was this?
My village is gone already.
You see, Kiriko,
I'm a gravekeeper.
What? That's—
To be precise, I'm half human, half gravekeeper,
and I'm actually only twelve years old.
H-Hang on.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Why are you telling me all this?
Because I liked your smile.
Huh?
Princess...
The dead here are really different from everyone in my village.
Different?
Hmm... how should I put it?
They seem... lively?
Or more like, they look like they're having fun?
Well, a lot of effort went into it.
We had to create laws and a proper government,
and to figure out how to stop
everyone's bodies from rotting.
Wow...
Maybe things would've ended up different...
if my village had managed to do all that too, I mean.
Um, Kiriko?
This is the land of the dead,
so how come you're the only one alive?
Why is that?
I'm dead.
Huh?
Ai!
I was so worried!
Well, I'm back.
Sorry, sorry!
I did what I could about the van, but when I came back...
You were gone.
And Scar was bedridden, too.
Man, do you have any idea how worried I was?
Do you?
You don't, do you?!
Are you still not feeling good?
I would've hurried back if I'd known.
No.
Didn't I tell you already
that you were making things worse?
You didn't have to repeat it.
They're not even listening!
If you'd like, tomorrow I can summon a doctor I know for her.
But...
Don't worry.
They don't discriminate between
gravekeepers, the dead, or the living.
And on top of that, they'll keep your secrets safe.
A long time ago, there lived five humans.
In terms of age, gender, and upbringing, they were all different,
but they nevertheless lived together as great friends.
They were looking forward to a day when two of them would get married and have a child together.
But that day never came.
Because God abandoned the world, right?
Since they wanted a child above all else,
they went seeking help from a witch.
A witch?
The witch told them,
"If you people were actually wishing for a child,
then God would've granted that wish already."
God would've granted that wish...
Yeah.
But then, the witch said,
"I, too, can grant your wish."
"However, I can only do so in a very twisted way."
Using various body parts from each of
those five people, the witch assembled a new human.
And thus, a sixth was created.
That is who I am.
So then, Pox and Rex from yesterday are...
They're two of the five.
The others are called Diva, Oreus, and Veruera.
Together, we six are called "Lap Star"—
The Pentagram Lacking Parts.
"Lap Star"...
So yeah, maybe because I was
put together using living parts,
I stand before you, dead yet seemingly alive.
Um, but doesn't that mean
you were born as a living person?
No.
I was made thirteen years ago.
At the time, I looked to be around fourteen years old.
If I was living, I should be in my late twenties now, right?
Yeah.
In the past thirteen years,
I've only aged a couple of years at most.
Okay.
Outta the way, Kiriko.
Coming!
Hey, Ai!
Thanks a lot for yesterday.
The doctor Kiriko mentioned was you, Pox?
Actually, that doesn't seem quite right...
Wait... This isn't the same combination from yesterday!
Hey! You're Ai, right?
So cute!
Your skin's silky smooth!
And you're so squishy!
Pwease wemme go!
Come on, Diva.
You gotta introduce yourself first.
Oh! I'm so sorry, Ai.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Diva, the Royal Doctor of Ortus.
Oh, nice to meet you.
Well then,
now that I'm here, I'll smash those pesky diseases to bits!
Right...
This is who we'd like you to examine.
Hi!
Thank you for coming to see me.
Even as the Royal Doctor, I've never had a gravekeeper for a patient before.
Um, aren't you a doctor of the dead, Diva?
No worries!
I'm on the side of good health!
And when it comes to health,
gravekeepers, the living, and the dead all stand equal.
Huh?
Do health and illness even apply to the dead, though?
Of course they do!
You know how the dead start losing body parts
or gradually get really self-centered, right?
Yeah.
Well, my job is to prevent all that, by using neurosurgery, pharmacology, and psychology.
I see!
Ortus is so amazing.
Hey, Diva.
Get on with examining her already.
Oh yeah, you're right!
All right, everyone! Give us the room for a bit.
I'm not quite convinced,
but there's only one diagnosis I can think of right now.
False pregnancy.
Huh?
What's that?
It's a condition in which the body displays symptoms of pregnancy even though the patient isn't with child.
When God abandoned the world and children stopped being born,
cases like this one became common.
It occurs when a person has
an extremely strong desire to have a baby.
A strong desire to have a baby, huh?
That desire was actually shared by many.
I know.
But I—
Indeed.
You've never even thought of wanting a baby.
That's precisely why I'm not convinced.
You said you've been hearing a voice, correct?
Oh, the one calling out to her?
I still hear it every now and then.
I suspect that voice has something to do with this.
Well then,
be sure to contact me if anything happens, 'kay?
Okay. Thank you so much.
So cute!
Cut that out.
By the way...
thank you for making friends with Kiri.
Friends?
What are you talking about?!
You're friends, all right.
'Cause I said so!
Th-This is the first...
friend I've ever had.
So adorable!
Hey!
Say, Ai!
Do you want to be friends
with the princess in the castle?
Make sure you mind your manners.
The Mistress of Castle Ortus,
Princess Ulla Eulesse Hecmatika,
will now grant you an audience.
Princess, this girl is—
Nice to meet you! I'm Ai Astin!
Wha—
How dare you!
You are not permitted to speak directly to the princess!
Ulla Eulesse Hecmatika.
It's my name.
Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you, too!
Where are you from?
That's what the princess just asked.
Oh, uh...
I'm from a village on the other side
of the eastern mountain range.
Were you raised there?
Yup.
Why'd you leave on a journey?
Well, my village is gone now, so...
Oh, right.
I won't press the issue any further.
Um, are you not able to speak, Princess?
Also, why are your eyes covered?
Are you mocking the princess?!
Her voice and her gaze are too much for mere mortals!
Moreover, you need to learn some manners.
Everything about your lifestyle is crude.
Kiriko's a bit strict.
You should reflect on that.
I keep telling him to call me Ulla,
but he only does it when we're alone.
I see!
He's surprisingly shy.
Manners and etiquette are very important things in life.
Can I call you Ai?
Of course!
You can call me Ulla, too.
Anyway—
Ulla!
Why are you calling her by her name all of a sudden?!
Wait, what? Princess!
He finally noticed.
What kinda relationship do you two have?
I'm both her schoolmate
and her teacher.
How can you be both at once?
In a limited way,
I'm connected to Pox and the others,
so I can access their knowledge.
So you're using secondhand knowledge to act like a teacher? That seems unfair.
Yeah, he's unfair.
Come to think of it,
when I met Kiriko for the first time,
he mistook me for you and called me "Princess."
Why'd he mistake you for me?
He was half asleep!
When he said "Princess,"
he had such a cute smile on his face.
N-Now, just wait a sec!
Wh-What do you think you're saying?!
"Kiriko's really cute when he smiles sometimes," apparently.
So, you made a friend, eh?
Yup!
I think I made two of them in one fell swoop!
Oh, but the van's gonna be ready soon.
I know.
We need to leave this city, don't we?
At least you can always write to them.
That's kinda how I talk to Ulla now anyway.
Why must Ortus be a land of the dead,
and only the dead?
Can't the living stay here too?
The feelings of those here won't let that happen.
Feelings?
After being discriminated against and persecuted by the living, and after years of wandering,
the dead finally reached a land they'd only dreamed of before.
And after a lot of hard work, this place was even recognized as an independent nation.
There's no room for the living here.
But...
Uh...
There is a way, though, isn't there?
A way for the living to live in Ortus...
Oh, so you noticed.
Yes.
Today, Ulla told me I should live here with them.
But I told her I had to continue my journey.
That's when I figured it out.
One just needs to die, right?
Yeah.
Back when I was on the run
with my daughter and my dead wife,
we came here once.
But the three of us couldn't live here.
My daughter was alive.
I just couldn't let her die.
Wh-What's happening?
Don't panic!
I came here to tell you
that we are now under martial law.
Martial law?
Every single gate of Ortus is being closed.
The trade area at the south gate will be sealed off,
and all visitors will be placed under house arrest.
Um...
An acceptance ceremony for the living, is it?
That's right.
Having lost their means of survival,
a group of 105 living is seeking to migrate into Ortus.
Tonight, they will be granted a peaceful death.
That is all.
Are you saying you're gonna kill them?
Yes.
I heard what Kiriko said,
but I don't get it.
I just don't get it.
After meeting Father and hearing all kinds of stories from him,
after speaking to him about all kinds of things,
and after burying him,
I wanted to save the world.
I wanted to give the dead a happy ending.
That was my dream.
But the dead here are plenty happy already.
They don't need a "happy ending" at all.
Still, I don't know if it's okay!
Is it okay for more than
a hundred living people to get killed?!
Well,
that's their decision to make.
Does Ulla...
Does Ulla know about this?
I'm sure she doesn't.
I'm sure Ulla...
Why would you jump to that conclusion?
Because Ulla...
Ulla's alive.
No, wait.
How can the princess of the
land of the dead be a living person?
I need to tell her.
I need to tell Ulla about this!
Hey, wait!
Damn it.
Wait, Ai!
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
"I am the ruler of man."
That is Ortus's dark side.
We were friends,
and it was really fun.
Ai! Come on, Ai!
It's been you this whole time, hasn't it?
No...
Ortus III
It can't be true!