For me, the world is but a tiny community.
And I'm trying to save the world by destroying that community.
I told you that, didn't I?
Yes.
Will you help me out?
All right...
as long as it will actually save the world.
But—
Before that, you have to look for the gravekeeper called Scar.
That's fine.
I'm in no particular hurry.
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
The Birthplace of Gravekeepers
All right.
318 degrees.
That's three degrees north of northwest.
It's dead-on again.
Full speed ahead, Yuri!
Go! Go!
All right! Here we go.
Yahoo! Floor it!
Dear Ulla,
and Kiriko too.
Following my letter yesterday,
this is status report #4!
After we "escaped" from Goran Academy,
we delivered Tanya to her parents safe and sound.
And it seems that for the time being,
most of the Goran Academy students will also be staying at Tanya's place.
They said they'd leave for
their own destinations eventually.
So now,
the rest of us are headed for the wastelands once again!
We're on a journey to find Scar,
who disappeared suddenly at Goran Village.
And showing us the way is Celica.
Boo!
Back in Ortus, Celica called Scar to where she was,
so I'm sure she can find her again.
So, it might be a little late to be saying this, but...
will it really help Scar if we find her?
Wh-Where's this coming from?
It's just...
Scar's a gravekeeper first and foremost, you know?
Gravekeepers travel alone in search of the dead.
When you think about it,
doesn't this just mean Scar went back to the way she's supposed to be?
That... might be true,
but if it is, I want to hear it straight from the horse's mouth.
Or actually,
I really just want to see her!
I'd hate it if I never saw her again.
I know.
Either way, I should've taken better care of her.
After you were kidnapped while we were in Goran,
Scar got kinda unstable.
There were times when I thought she'd keep holding Celica,
but then she'd suddenly put her down.
And times when I thought she was spacing out,
she'd suddenly start trembling in fear.
I knew something was off,
but I didn't do anything to help her!
Damn it!
Yeah, yeah.
Three degrees off northwest again, right?
Scar's nowhere to be seen.
Nowhere.
Yeah.
Huh?
Why didn't you tell us it was your birthday?!
Well, nobody asked.
You're supposed to have a celebration on your birthday!
Good grief.
We're just lucky Dee managed to remember it in time.
So today's your—
Yesterday.
Huh?
His birthday was yesterday.
What?!
What does it matter?
Hey, got anything you need help with?
Hold it!
We're not done here.
We are.
I already said it's no big deal,
so why's it one to you?
But it's your birthday, you know!
"Happy Birthday" and all that, you know.
It's a once-in-a-year celebration, you know!
Maybe so,
but this isn't the time for such trifles.
I'm gonna save the world.
I'll do whatever it takes to accomplish that.
Screw birthdays.
Knock it off—
Don't do that.
Alice...
don't be like that.
You can't throw this kinda stuff away.
You've gotta spend your birthday celebrating with other people.
How old are you now?
Sixteen.
Happy sixteenth birthday, Alice!
Let's celebrate it.
Yuri! Do you know how to bake a cake?
Of course I do.
Then please do!
Whoa!
Let's eat it now, while it's hot—
No, wait.
This is the most important part.
Come on. Blow it out already!
Be sure you make a wish, okay?
It's delicious!
How'd you like that?
Not at all!
Then how about this?
Hey!
How about this, then?
Not there either!
Next!
That's even worse!
Woohoo!
Knock it off already!
Take that.
Come on! Stop it!
He's surprisingly good at playing the dad, isn't he?
Well, he used to be one.
Yuri lost his wife and daughter.
I see...
Everyone changes, don't they?
Humans, and gravekeepers too.
The world is really complex—
much more complex than I could've imagined.
Wh-What is it?
I was right about you. You really are interesting.
I've also had my fair share of journeys,
but I've never met someone like you before.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing bad.
Hey, that's not an answer—
Thanks.
Thanks... for celebrating my birthday.
Yup!
This isn't good.
The road's plenty rough as it is,
and now we can barely see.
Sure is amazingly foggy.
"Amazing"?
More like ominous.
Quit whining and keep going, she says.
Hey, Yuri!
Why'd you stop all of a sudden?
What is this place?
Whatever it is, we should get back inside the van.
If we were to get separated in all this fog...
Yuri!
The wind...
It's gotten awfully quiet.
You two okay?!
Y-Yes.
Was that... lightning?
Nah,
that's...
a gravekeeper.
Huh?
Hello.
Have a nice day.
Is this Story Circle?
This is where gravekeepers are born.
They all looked the same.
That's what gravekeepers are like.
There have been cases identifying hundreds—
sometimes even thousands—
of identical gravekeepers.
As in the cases of the Bezel family and the Deeny family,
researchers have categorized and identified different types of gravekeepers.
Oh, at the same time,
there are plenty of gravekeepers who are one of a kind.
Hana was one of those without a doubt.
Man, we ended up coming to an awful place.
Did Scar want to return to her birthplace?
Maybe so.
Whoa.
This is her strongest reaction yet.
Celica?
Is Scar nearby?
Hey.
Are you guys really gonna keep going?
Does this mean Story Circle
goes on and on down this road?
Well, I'm turning around.
Dee!
This place gives me the creeps.
But...
we've traveled this far together!
Why do you have to—
Don't you know how whimsical I am?
Dee...
What's with that look?
Did that hurt?
Don't let her get to you.
Let's just keep going.
Crap.
It's practically impossible to see now.
I think we're getting close, though.
What now, Ai?
Yeah...
Let's just keep going for now, even if we've gotta go slow.
Y-Yuri?
Alice?!
Celica?!
Yuri!
F-Father!
How?
I—
Wait!
Why?!
How... could you?
You... crushed Mother's dream.
I don't understand anything anymore!
Thanks, Ai...
But this is my dream—and my job.
Remember this.
The only words that can keep you alive are
"I want to live."
Scar!
We came to get you, Scar.
You didn't need to.
I am a gravekeeper that was born here.
Um...
Scar, if you want to live on as a
gravekeeper like you used to, I...
well...
I can't stop you...
But—
Yuri?
Scar!
What about Celica?!
Is this what you want? To leave her like this?!
Please stop!
Take her away!
When she's around, I—
Scar!
I can't!
I'm a gravekeeper!
It is my duty to assist the living...
Look out!
Scar... gravekeepers don't cry.
Celica.
Celica!
Scar,
from now on, I'll take care of you,
so shut up and come with me!
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
All right!
Way to go, man.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
A p-proposal?!
Y-You guys shut up too!
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
I'm gonna do all I can
to take care of you guys, too!
Hope you're ready for it!
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
Whoa!
You're so cool, Yuri!
Well, isn't that reassuring!
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
So what's the town called?
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Ostia.
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
That's where we all were—
nor our future,
mirai mo
where Class 3-4 still is...
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
being held captive.
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
Welcome to our home.
You're sooo soft, Ai!
So are you, Dee.
The calendar says
...it's fourteen years ago...
I don't sense any dead...
I have an enemy...
It's my dream to save the world.
Class 3-4  I