Hell
Bureau of the Peace, Far East Division
Regular Briefing Meeting
of Punitive Force Section Chiefs
With the increase in section chiefs,
we have seen a 230% improvement
Counter-Spirit Bureau Chief
Dokuro Skull
compared to last year's rate of capture.
However, we have been pressured to make further budget cuts,
so things will be more difficult for you all.
Haven't you heard the rumors about
Vintage worming their way into the Loose Souls Team?
In response, I expect all section chiefs to step up.
That concludes this meeting—
I have a question!
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
Goddess Mix
It has to do with the recent decree
to search Earth for the residents of Heaven.
I've heard that those residents of Heaven are goddesses.
I've also heard that Vintage has infiltrated the Loose Souls Team in pursuit of the goddesses.
Is this true, Chief?
What?
Is that true?
Silence!
I am aware of these rumors.
However,
we have not been informed by Heaven that the residents in question are goddesses.
And I see no reason for them to hide that fact.
That's true...
As for Vintage...
We have added several new members to the Loose Souls Team,
but they were all thoroughly screened.
Please refrain from baseless accusations.
Let me remind you.
Our objective is to take loose souls into custody.
I ask that you dedicate yourself to your mission at all times.
Bureau of the Peace Gift Shop
Maybe I'm overthinking this.
Yeah, it was just something I heard from Nora. There's no actual proof.
Right. There's nothing suspicious about the Loose Souls Team.
We have confirmation from Bureau Chief Dokuro Skull, hero of Almage-Machina.
I should trust her.
Our mission is to capture loose souls.
To protect New Hell.
I think I can get him to try these.
They don't look that sweet.
Exit Gate #15 East
Haqua du Lot Herminium.
Public Safety.
Come with us.
What's going on?!
I was just leaving!
Let me go!
Katsuragi-san.
What?
Tenri?
No, Diana...
I sense trouble.
I wish to ask Apollo-neesama to perform a divination.
Please summon the other goddesses.
What's this about—
Katsuragi-san!
Please listen to me.
Must... meet...
They're all here. Satisfied?
Thank you for doing this.
I was sleeping!
I have to get up early tomorrow to shoot a drama!
Everything we say here must be kept secret from our hosts.
When they're asleep, they don't know what the goddesses are doing.
Right now, Tenri is also asleep.
But having the goddesses move around is risky.
So we had Elsie carry the sleeping hosts here with her raiment.
You should have asked Haqua to do it!
She isn't here.
I finally get to see my Nii-sama, and he sends me on an errand.
You have no sense of danger at all, do you?
It's time to wake up, Sisters.
Vulcanus,
Mars,
Minerva.
Mars... Minerva...
I'm so glad you're okay.
N-Nee-sama!
It appears that everyone is well.
We once sacrificed our lives for the greater good,
and now we are reunited here...
How strange destiny is.
Enough with the emotional reunion!
Diana, brief them on the current situation.
Huh? Give them some time, at least...
We can't celebrate every little happy moment!
Hurry up so I can sleep.
I'm still sick...
Oh, you are?
You're Yui's bridegroom, aren't you?
I was initially opposed to her relationship with you,
but Yui seems devoted to it.
I've decided to support her!
Minerva?
Th-This man belongs to Shiori...
Who's Shiori?
Shoo!
Fiend!
You already have Tsukiyo!
Come on...
Nee-sama, this person is Yui's husband.
Do not injure him!
Katsuragi is a scoundrel,
but I must do this for Tsukiyo.
Forgive me, sisters, but you must relinquish any claims.
I cannot do that.
My friend's future is at stake!
H-He belongs to Shiori...
Come on...
Vul-neesama.
Mars and Minerva.
There's no time.
I have something important to tell you!
Something important?
This person belongs to Tenri.
That isn't important!
Just get down to business!
My younger sisters also have their wings.
Huh?
I'm the only one without them.
I have recovered the least power,
despite being the first to awaken...
Uh... Diana?
It's because you've been ignoring Tenri.
Nee-sama, you're scaring me...
You evil man... evil man... evil man... evil man...
She's too clingy.
Come to the second floor with me!
Evil man... evil man... evil man... evil man...
Once you see what's there, you'll stop arguing!
Hydration... That makes this difficult.
We probably cannot undo this spell.
You can't?
That's right.
The spell is very difficult to remove.
And if we fail, she'll turn to water permanently.
Apollo-neesama was ensuring that she would not fall into enemy hands.
What do we do, then?
We must call out to her and ask her to undo the spell herself.
Minerva, you have the ability to amplify our power.
We need your assistance.
Let us call out to Apollo.
Can you hear us, Apollo?
Return to us,
Apollo.
Kanon-chan!
Kanon.
Elsie!
The room's flooding!
Kanon-chan...
Elsie!
Where am I?
This is a world of oracles that I created for divination.
Long time no see, Kanon's beau.
Apollo!
Oh? You know my name?
I can hear my sisters calling.
I'm glad they're all okay.
Can you tell them I'm busy praying and can't go back yet?
Praying?
Yep. Take a look over there.
The city of Maijima is filled with bad fortune,
so I'm working to cleanse it.
Will that get rid of all the bad fortune?
Not a chance.
Huh?
I'm just a holy maiden.
All I can do is change the flow a little.
However, the Weiss are gaining momentum,
while we goddesses remain weak.
The odds are against us.
Any lucky break we catch will be worth its weight in gold.
Don't do anything to disrupt me.
A true conquest does not rely on luck.
I need only make the right choices.
It's that simple.
That applies to games and reality alike.
I'm focusing solely on achieving the best ending.
I believe in you.
Kanon...
I was saved once, thanks to you.
I know that you can find a way.
Sorry, but I can only pray for another three days.
Once those three days have passed, I'll be powerless.
Be careful, Katsuragi.
It's not working.
Apollo-neesama isn't responding.
It appears she doesn't intend to return.
We four sisters assembled here,
but it was all for naught.
Isn't Kanon-chan going to go back to normal?
Elsie.
Huh?
My cold is gone.
Why are you telling us to leave?
The more time you spend outside your hosts,
the more likely Vintage is to target them.
After Kanon, I don't want any more bystanders to get hurt.
I-If you put it that way,
you're a bystander in all of this as well.
This is our battle.
Isn't there anything we can do to help?
The power of the goddesses will be needed.
Just not right now.
I can handle this.
You must protect Tenri.
I-I understand.
Tenri... Now I understand.
I understand why we don't have wings.
Hell   Bureau of the Peace, Far East Division
What did I do wrong?
Bureau, Prison Cell
Why am I locked up?
And why is Public Safety involved?
They're treating me like a criminal!
Hi!
Nora!
Don't tell anyone.
Sure. Take your time.
I can't believe you just blurted it out in the open like that.
Are you stupid?
Everyone needs to know about it.
I thought if word got out,
it would be harder for Vintage to move around.
Let's say that
there is a Vintage member
who holds a position of authority with more influence than we thought possible.
For instance, bureau chief.
You were taken into custody by Public Safety, right?
It takes someone of bureau chief rank or above to command them.
Impossible!
It seems Vintage is more deeply rooted in New Hell than we thought.
Looks like I should lay some groundwork too.
Bye-bye.
Aren't you going to help me?
Huh?
Why would I help a fool with no money or connections like you?
Are you one of them too?
I wonder.
The Bureau Chief is a member of Vintage?
Then what does that mean for the Loose Souls Team?
Maijima Academy Arts and Cultural Festival
Festival Eve is tonight.
Eve
I have to conquer Chihiro and Ayumi here.
I must find the last goddess before Apollo's three-day deadline is up.
Huh?
I'm signed up for the pageant?
Why?
It's for the Prince and Princess Contest that Mai High is famous for.
You're the Princess candidate from our class.
Oh, sounds fun.
Go for it.
Cut it out!
I'm...
in love with you.
Chihiro remembers the conquest.
That means that Chihiro is hosting a goddess
and that there is no goddess inside Ayumi.
But then, why would Ayumi visit me?
I thought perhaps she'd fallen for me without remembering her conquest, until...
Be nice to Chihiro.
...she suddenly put on the brakes.
Was it because she heard Chihiro's confession?
I can't conquer either of them if they trigger flags that I can't anticipate.
I must control all flags.
Maijima Academy Arts and Cultural Festival
Eve
There's no time.
Maijima Academy Arts and Cultural Festival
Eve
I'll have to go with the more likely candidate.
The weather's getting cold,
and meat buns are tasting good.
This year's Mai High Prince and Princess Contest is stacked!
We have handsome boys and pretty girls right across the board.
Grab a ballot now!
The results will be announced during the after-party.
What are you doing, you bastard?!
Only amateurs would exclude game characters from a pageant.
Behold her loveliness!
Yuimi, from Magic Academy Carmine,
is the favorite.
You're so stupid.
You do this everywhere you go.
What does it matter to you?
My PFP is gone...
Where is it?
Huh? Where'd it go?
Sounds like karma to me.
That's what you get for making fun of the festival just because you have no one to take.
You don't have anyone either.
I'm performing this time, stupid!
Oh, that's right.
Thanks for dropping by yesterday.
That's okay. I'm glad to see you're better now.
Found it. This is it, right?
Yeah!
Festival Eve Campfire
Twice as Big as Last Year's
The Flames of Love will Burn.
Hey!
Katsuragi, you'll be dateless at the Mai High Festival, right?
Are you trying to rub it in my face?
In that case...
Why not go with me
to the campfire tonight?
Chihiro beat me to the punch?
Festival Eve Campfire
Twice as Big as Last Year's
The Flames of Love will Burn.
I'd planned to use the posters as an excuse to invite her.
But I have no reason to turn her down.
Well? You coming or not?
S-Sure...
Then I'll see you later.
Everything's going well.
If the final goddess is inside Chihiro, it'll all be over tonight.
But first...
Chihiro may act cynical, but she's more innocent than you'd think.
You have to be nice to her.
I know that.
She's still talking about Chihiro.
Watch this.
Huh?
Katsuragi... Taking out garbage, too?
Yeah.
Chihiro, did you know?
Know what?
They say if two people
bring the same thing to Festival Eve, something good will happen.
The same thing?
But I don't have anything on me now, since I'm in my PE uniform.
Katsuragi.
Huh?
Hold out your hand.
Huh? What was that?
It's a bit worn-out, but would you hold on to it for now?
Is this...
a guitar pick?
Looks like that worked out, Katsuragi.
You're not mad, Ayumi?
Huh?
I just wanted to see how Ayumi would react one last time...
If Ayumi was mad after seeing Chihiro with me,
that would mean she still had some level of affection,
so she could still be host to a goddess.
Huh? What are you muttering about?
I plan on kissing Chihiro today.
There's no turning back.
This is your last chance to get mad at me.
Why would I be mad?
Be nice to Chihiro, okay?
A new song?
We're performing in two days.
Well, we don't have to play this song,
but I managed to finish it.
This is the song she was humming.
A Chihiro original, huh?
Don't play it!
It's embarrassing!
We can't practice without playing it.
Well, I'll see you girls tonight.
Yeah.
See you later.
Ayumi, do you have a minute?
I need to talk to you.
Sorry, but I have something to take care of.
Man...
Chihiro, you have a date with Katsuragi at Festival Eve, right?
Good luck.
Bye!
How does she know?
Welcome to Festival Eve!
The Mai High Prince and Princess Contest will begin at six, on stage!
The campfire's scheduled to start at seven!
There's Festival Eve, the festival, and the after-party.
Why is so much effort put into cultural festivals?
The Mai High Festival has existed since the school was founded.
Ni—
Nikaidou!
Why are you wearing those ears?
The teachers are performing in a Festival Eve play.
I'm playing one of Dharma the Devil's henchmen.
What nonsense.
I swear she's enjoying it.
Katsuragi!
Did you wait long?
Sorry for being late...
It's finally time for the Mai High Prince and Princess Contest!
My conquest of Chihiro is going according to plan.
I'm almost at the ending.
But if I kiss her here and her wings appear, Vintage might notice.
I need to take her to an isolated area and kiss her!
Here she is!
Adorable!
Ayumi-chan!
Our princess contestant from Class 2-B is Takahara Ayumi!
I'm so embarrassed.
I'm voting for her!
Is Ayumi popular?
You didn't know?
Let's go to the campfire!
Katsuragi, did you bring the pick?
Yeah.
I have a feeling that something good will happen at this year's festival.
Time to start my mission!
The crowd is getting to me.
Can we find somewhere quiet?
No way... They just started the fire.
That's why!
Everyone is gravitating here, so other places are emptying out!
The fire won't go out for a while.
How about we go look at the posters outside?
I'm okay with that.
Soccer Club
There are people here too.
Maybe behind the library...
Let's have a look over here.
It seems a little dark...
Not really. There's a good spot—
I'll pass!
I don't want you taking me somewhere deserted and grabbing at me.
I'll have to be pushy about this.
Wait... Katsuragi?
Um...
What's with all these people?
I'm in the middle of an important event here!
K-Katsuragi?
No good. I'll have to start over.
Let's head back to the track field.
It's okay.
Let's find somewhere without anyone else around.
ame ga furu
Rain falls
monokuro no machi ni
on this gray city
narabu kasa
Umbrellas crowd the streets
sayonara wo
Looking out the window reminds me
yokan saseru mukou
that we have to say goodbye one day
kimi no komatta egao
Your smile that day will be so forced
iya da yo
I don't want that
kazasu te de omowazu
With outstretched hands
hashiridasu
I start running before I know it
obieteta kurayami ni
I fear the darkness around us
nukumori ga michiteku
but with our love I can make it my home
tsumetai kaze koboreteku
The cold wind whips my cheeks
hitomi kara yuki
and snow falls from my eyes
The following individual is to be punished for treason:
Haqua du Lot Herminium.
Yeah, give me all of her logs.
That's right. The one who was punished,
Haqua du Lot Herminium.
It's Festival Eve. Location is the school.
All flags have been triggered.
All parameters are go.
The preparations for my conquest are complete.
I'll conquer Chihiro, bring out her goddess, go home, and play games.
I'm not wasting another minute on the real world!
Huh? Did you say something, Katsuragi?