That should do it.
Okay, Ai!
Try it again!
Okay!
It's working!
I never knew!
I had no idea the outside world was this huge!
I can't even see the end of it!
But you know, Ai,
what you see right now is
only a tiny part of the world.
What? Really?!
Wow!
Good-bye.
Let's get going.
Yes, let's.
Okay!
By the way,
what should we do about this boy?
Huh?!
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Ortus I
Who do you think he is?
Huh?!
Why would you take out your gun?
We're complete strangers.
There's no way of knowing what kinda guy he is.
I see.
Come to think of it,
Father was like that too.
I think he's waking up.
Morning.
Good morning.
G-Good morning!
Morning.
He's going back to sleep?!
Hey, wake up!
Looks like he's been drugged.
What?
These are definitely symptoms of falspring poisoning.
It's a nasty deliriant that robbers use.
Hey! Pull yourself together!
What's your name?
Kiriko.
Kiriko, huh?
Kiriko... Pox... Rex... Diva... Oreus... Veruera...
Ulla... Eulesse... Merzagog... Teagle... Amitabars... Gei—
All of that?!
That whole thing is your name?!
You're always like that...
aren't you?
"Always"?!
He's just mixing you up with someone else.
Princess...
Before he wakes up,
let's get things straight.
You gotta keep things quiet about
you being a gravekeeper.
To be precise, I'm half human, half gravekeeper.
Even more of a reason to keep quiet.
Nowadays, just about every dead person out there
doesn't want their "life" to end.
Just you try telling them you're a gravekeeper.
You'll be killed
before you know what hit you.
But granting peace to the dead
is a gravekeeper's duty—
That's what the world is like right now.
That's what it's become...
since that fateful day fifteen years ago.
You get it now?
I get it,
but I don't like it.
Well, as long as you know.
But, Yuri,
if I really have to, I'm definitely going to—
He's waking up again.
What?
Have you come to?
Who are you people?
I'm Ai.
Ai Astin.
I'm Yuri Sakuma Dmitriyevich.
And that's Scar.
What about you?
I'm Kiriko Zubreska.
I'm an apprentice at a government office in Ortus.
Ortus...
So, you were mugged...
and then, you found
the chance to escape and took it?
Yes.
I thought I was being quite careful, too.
Law and order's gone to the dogs all over the place, hasn't it?
Where are you all headed?
We're on a journey!
A journey to save the world that God abandoned.
"Save the world"?
I decided to do it three days ago!
I must say,
this is quite the strange party you have here.
A girl from the final generation
and you.
You two don't look like father and child.
On top of which,
that lady over there is a gravekeeper.
What exactly—
My apologies.
That was a bit out of line, wasn't it?
Well, I guess you could say we're fellow travelers.
Anyway, you can ride with us till we're close to Ortus.
Thank you very much.
"Close to"?
Can't we take him all the way?
Well, it's kinda complicated.
That should hold it over,
but the van still needs some serious repair.
Sorry, but can we ask you to get it fixed in Ortus?
I'll see what I can do.
Thanks.
So we're going to Ortus, right?
Yeah, but we're still not gonna be entering the place.
What?
Why not?
You'll see soon enough.
I sense dead who have not had a proper burial.
Huh?
They're right ahead.
At the very least,
there are a million of them.
Wow, a million?
Wait, what? A million?!
But of course.
The nation of Ortus
is a land of the dead.
It's the world's largest ghost town.
A land of the dead?
That's right, Ai.
And what those dead hate the most
are gravekeepers.
That's why we're not gonna enter.
Honestly, I didn't even
wanna get close to the place.
Take a look at those.
They're graves of murdered gravekeepers.
Lured in by the presence of the dead,
many gravekeepers come here.
Forced to flee their homes,
at the end of the road,
the dead united and
built an eternal place for themselves—
a unified city,
an independent state.
That's what Ortus is.
What's that?
"That" is a lot of things.
It's a gate,
a charm,
a warning to the world outside,
and lastly,
it's a memorial to the
gravekeepers who were killed.
Is that the princess you mentioned, Kiriko?
That's the Idol of Murder.
She's the guardian deity of Ortus.
She has the power to kill any living human.
The Idol of Murder.
Ortus's history is filled with persecution.
Everyone wanted to believe in that kind of god.
"Her eyes are the eyes of Death."
"Her words are the words of Death."
"Her body teeming with Death,
she shall not allow the living to escape."
"She alone became the guardian of the dead."
She's a kind and gentle god.
Um, Scar...
Are they, uh...
They are dead, yes.
I see.
So the dead live ordinary lives here.
I want to bury them.
Whoa now.
Scar...
I understand.
I got approval.
You just need to sign, now.
Can't we go inside?
The only place you can enter
is a section of the trade area we've prepared for the living.
There will also be severe restrictions placed on your activities—
Kiriko!
I'm so glad you're okay!
Why are you two here?!
How rude.
We'd heard you'd gone missing,
so we rushed here 'cause we were so worried.
Oh, allow me to introduce you.
This is Pox, vice-captain of the Ortus Imperial Guard.
And this is Rex, ambassador of special foreign affairs.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Ai Astin.
Oh, right.
Oh!
I thank you for bringing Kiri here safe and sound.
Oh, w-well...
You're a strange one, though.
Even the dead usually find us creepy.
'Cause we're monsters, apparently.
Um...
You shouldn't call yourselves monsters.
That's what I told my father too.
It's just...
It doesn't matter how much their minds or bodies change.
Humans are humans, not monsters!
Oh man,
she's too cute!
I just love it when kids speak words of wisdom!
Come on, Pox!
And you're Kiri's savior, too!
I'll do anything you want me to!
Then...
I'd like to enter Ortus!
Okay, got it.
I'll approve it.
Hey—
Hi, would you excuse us?
Why on earth do you wanna go inside?
Well,
because I want to!
If they find out you two are gravekeepers,
who knows what they'll do to you!
We'll make sure they don't.
But...
Still!
Still, I want to see this place with my own eyes.
My mother dreamed of making a place
where the dead could live ordinary lives.
This is a land my mother herself
wanted to create!
Well, this is your journey.
I'll abide by your decisions.
Yuri!
Scar, what're you gonna do?
If possible, you should head to a different town and stand by.
No.
I would like to go with you two.
But that's too danger—
I hear a voice.
A voice?
Somebody is calling out to me.
Was that all?
We got in so easy!
Despite how he looks,
Rex has a strong sense of duty.
What he said...
I, too, am truly grateful that you brought me all the way here.
However, this is a city of the dead—and the dead alone.
This is no place for the living,
let alone gravekeepers.
I'd like you to leave
as soon as your van gets fixed.
Okay...
It's pretty!
Don't you think it looks just like Heaven?
Heaven?
I want to make this village a place just like Heaven.
In these hellish times, a place like that
would be a beacon of hope for everyone.
Oh, that's right!
I'm in Ortus!
I wanna go see that hill, too!
Ai?
Good morning, Scar!
It's bright and early!
It's already past noon.
Huh?
Oh...
What's wrong?
I'm not sure.
Is this what they call "discomfort"?
My chest hurts.
And I have a headache,
and I'm a little nauseous.
It doesn't seem like you have a fever, though.
I keep hearing this voice.
It keeps calling out to me.
I guess even gravekeepers get sick, huh?
I, too, only discovered that today.
In any case, let's ask Yuri for help!
Yuri went out some time ago.
What?
He seemed rather busy
making arrangements to get the van repaired.
Then, I'll nurse you myself, 'kay?
No, that's quite all right.
Come on. No need to be shy!
You're so noisy, Ai,
that you're actually making it worse.
What?
By the way, Yuri left a message for you.
"Do not go out,"
he said.
My, my.
What a lovely guest we have here.
Kiriko told me about you.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Ai Astin.
I'm Kiera.
I'm the manager here.
Um, where's Kiriko?
He's gone to the castle today,
to meet the princess.
Are Kiriko and the princess friends?
Who knows?
Um, I'd like to go outside.
Well, you'd better not go out like that.
Go check out Masquerade Street.
I'm sure you'll have fun there.
This is the first time I've ever seen so many people in one place!
Come one, come all!
Come and see the new play!
It'll be showing right here,
at this very theater!
It's called "The Idol of Murder and the Princess of the Dead"!
A story about the chosen princess,
full of ups and downs that'll give you goosebumps!
A tale of laughter and tears!
"The Idol of Murder and the Princess of the Dead"?
Huh?
H-Hey—
What do you think you're doing?!
Get out.
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
What?
Get out of here at once.
You know nothing about Ortus's dark side.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
"Ortus's... dark side"?
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
You're saving the world by doing this.
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Yeah...
You're the one who will save the world,
Ulla.
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
Ortus's dark side?
...dead yet seemingly alive.
D-Don't take it off!
Because I liked your smile.
When God abandoned the world...
Your skin's silky smooth!
I hear it every now and then.
There's no room for the living here.
...but I don't get it.
Ortus II
I just don't get it.