What?
Don't kill the goddesses?
Well, I guess there's only one day left.
Don't come crying to me later.
The people at the top are so greedy.
Well, I've done enough work for the rest of my life.
Once Old Hell is revived, I can live in comfort.
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
I'm on my way over...
to confess my love!
What was Katsuragi thinking?
Damn, which one is Ayumi's room?
Katsuragi?
Katsura—
What are you doing?
A-Ayumi?
Why are you taking a bath?
I said I was coming to see you.
I didn't think you'd actually come!
Why do I have to follow you people around?
I never lie!
We can't leave you on your own right now.
You've already lied to me!
Take that, you sick, peeping pervert! Get outta here!
I'm not going anywhere. I have to tell you something.
So what?
I don't get what you're trying to do!
I don't get it either!
I never wanted anything to do with the real world.
P-Panties?!
Those are mine!
S-Stay calm.
And who exactly got those from her?
I did.
That boy has a twisted way of handling things.
I like it.
Idiot! Scumbag! Criminal!
Die! Die! Die! Die! Die!
Ayumi, hear me out!
I've been watching you from the beginning.
I'm sorry I never said anything.
But my feelings haven't changed!
The one I care for most is...
Wha...
What the hell?!
Ayumi!
Come to the Turtle Stones, on the Kozue River.
I'll be waiting!
If you don't show,
you can kiss your panties goodbye.
Give them back, you jerk!
This place has an excellent view and the right atmosphere.
I even gave her the pretext of coming to get her panties back.
You have to come, Ayumi.
Katsuragi!
Vintage will execute their plan tomorrow.
If you don't conquer Ayumi tonight, it'll be too late.
Ayumi's affection level is already high enough.
Otherwise, she wouldn't have considered quitting the band.
I just need one more big event to complete the conquest.
Wait! What is this conquest stuff?
What's Katsuragi up to?!
Huh? I thought my Exalted Brother called me.
Kanon, it's almost time.
Okay!
Right now, we need the power inside Ayumi.
To draw it out, Ayumi has to fall in love.
What does love have to do with anything?
I feel sorry for Ayumi,
but it's necessary to stop Vintage.
Is she talking about the people who attacked us?
Only Katsuragi has the means to rectify the situation.
That's why Katsuragi's putting the moves on Ayumi?
What if Ayumi takes him seriously?
Ayumi, you shouldn't have come!
It's a trap!
K-Katsuragi...
Ayumi, you really came to meet me?
Hardly.
I'm just here to recover my underwear from a thief.
Huh?
I just found them lying on the ground!
D-Don't take them out!
I almost fell in the water.
S-Sorry.
Wh-What kind of pathetic act was that?
I keep causing trouble for you.
No kidding.
You've been nothing but trouble.
You're awful, Katsuragi.
Why'd I even come here?
Did something happen between Katsuragi and Ayumi?
Nora?
Vintage is heading your way.
You should leave.
Katsuragi!
Vintage is coming.
Let's move.
Move? They couldn't wait five more minutes?
Ayumi.
Huh?
Let's go!
There's a place I want to show you.
I'm surprised...
that you picked a park.
I thought you never went outside as a kid.
Even I went to the park sometimes.
Slides and jungle gyms,
sandboxes and seesaws...
I played my games from all of them.
What's the point in that?
I'm glad I could come here with you.
Why?
Katsuragi!
Vintage is here, too.
Distract Ayumi.
Katsuragi!
Hey, are you okay? Katsuragi!
I was so busy thinking about what to say that I forgot I was on a swing.
You dummy.
I took care of it, Katsuragi.
But this place is no longer safe.
Our next destination is Maijima Shrine.
Oh, Ayumi...
There's one more place I want to show you!
What? Again?
Damn, I'm wasting good lines and locations.
Chihiro, we have to go.
If Katsuragi fails, what will you do?
Fails?
That's not an option.
We're still not there?
C-Can we take a break?
Well, if you can't find them, you'll be in for a whole heap of trouble.
Don't contact me again until you've found a goddess.
She's one of them.
Katsuragi, get away from there!
Okay.
I'm rested up, so let's get going!
O-Okay...
Hi.
I don't recognize you.
Which district are you from?
Katsuragi.
That girl was probably a Vintage member.
Find shelter indoors.
You want me to confess in a family restaurant or a karaoke box?
My pride as a gamer won't allow it.
We need to go to Maijima Shrine.
Why do you have to be so picky?
The city is swarming with Vintage's goons.
Hey, someone I know lives up ahead.
Maijima
Happy
Road
Keep going straight.
That was the plan.
Oh? You're downstairs?
Miyako?
Huh?
Ayumi? Katsuragi?
Heya!
I just couldn't stop thinking about tomorrow's concert.
So I thought I'd drop by.
Chihiro?
Whoa, it's the dweeb!
Come on in.
I'll get us some drinks.
Give me a hand, Ayumi.
Sure.
Chihiro just called me out of nowhere.
Oh, really?
Hey, Chihiro. What are you up to?
You need a place to hide, don't you?
Don't interfere!
Five minutes. I only needed one event to finish the job.
These detours aren't helping!
Can you stop talking about this like it's a game?
That's how I operate.
My first priority is to conquer the target!
How long have you been targeting Ayumi?
I heard that you approached her because you need her power.
Sorry for confessing to you at such a bad time.
So I'll make up for it by helping you.
Helping me?
Right now, my school's holding their cultural festival.
Getting everyone to work together isn't easy,
but it's a lot of fun!
Time really flies, huh?
Tomorrow's the big day!
Y-Yeah.
Ayumi, why were you with Katsuragi?
I-I wasn't really with him...
Oh, don't worry about it.
It doesn't matter anymore.
Chihiro, don't turn things in that direction!
You might be trying to let Ayumi have me,
Your glass is empty, Ayumi!
Huh? O-Oh...
but that will make Ayumi feel guilty,
which will only take more time to fix.
Here you go.
I'm not after the best ending right now.
I'm doing a speed run!
Oh, that's right.
Wanna try on our uniforms for tomorrow?
Definitely.
Ditto.
Here! This is Ayumi's.
Okay, no boys allowed!
Hey, wait!
Hey! Let me in!
My next route was about to...
Miyako, tell your friend to keep it down!
Okay!
So, Ayumi...
You're in love with Katsuragi, right?
Huh?
I-It's not like that...
Of course not.
I was just pulling one over on a real girl.
Stupid.
Stay away from me.
Ayumi...
Did you know?
Katsuragi is a liar.
Paused
Playing
Five minutes. I only needed one event to finish the job.
These detours aren't helping!
Can you stop talking about this like it's a game?
That's how I operate.
My first priority is to conquer the target!
Katsuragi's playing a game where the goal is to seduce you.
Huh? But...
He wouldn't have caught you bathing without planning ahead.
How do you know about that?
I was there the whole time.
The stops at the river and the park were also part of his plan.
He was confident about the whole thing.
He's playing a game.
A game where the goal is to seduce you tonight!
Stop it.
Chihiro, what are you doing?
Tough luck.
I just blew your plans to smithereens.
Katsuragi,
what's all this about?
Well—
He'll try to talk his way out of it.
That's how he works.
You were lying to me?
Wait—
Did you return Ayumi's panties?
Didn't you steal them from her bathroom?
What's your problem?!
What? I'm just telling it how it is.
That's not—
Only idiots would be fooled by this scumbag.
Idiots like Ayumi...
and me.
Nora!
Grab her before Vintage finds her!
Wait, Haqua...
Don't let her find out yet.
Guard her without letting her notice!
We're going after her.
Hey!
Clean up before you leave!
What are you trying to do?
If I can't conquer Ayumi, we're in big trouble.
Then you should get serious about her.
I don't like how you're going about this.
Ayumi is an honest person!
So she's probably really confused right now.
Stop lying to her.
If you want to win Ayumi's heart, you have to truly love her!
Okay. I understand.
So what's going on with you guys?
Sorry. I'll explain later.
Okay, I guess.
Let's kick some butt tomorrow.
Yeah!
Haqua, I need a favor.
Why do we forget our dreams as soon as we wake up?
I feel like I received an important phone call before,
but was it just a dream?
I thought that we'd draw attention from the real Kanon
by protecting Katsuragi's disguised sister.
After we drove off Vintage, it seemed like we'd succeeded.
But it appears they realized the truth at the last second.
It looks like most of the goddesses have fallen into their hands.
But there's nothing we can do.
Our only option is to trust Katsuragi.
Jeez...
Why did you do that?
Now he has to start the conquest all over!
But I'm no longer a factor in Ayumi's mind.
Huh?
Ayumi was worried about how I would feel.
Now that I've removed myself from the picture,
it's up to the two of them.
You said all that to destroy the love triangle?
Katsuragi figured it out,
since I didn't tell Ayumi about you guys.
Ayumi will be fine.
It isn't easy to hate someone you've fallen in love with.
As long as he's honest with her, Ayumi will forgive Katsuragi.
Anyway, I have a question.
Why did Katsuragi go on a date with me?
Huh?
Katsuragi was targeting Ayumi, right?
Wouldn't going on a date with me be a waste of time?
That was because...
Has he been lying to me this entire time?
Ever since that day before the tournament?
Welcome home, my princess.
How stupid can you be?!
You should just apologize and confess your love!
The real world means nothing to me.
I live in the ideal world.
I refuse to pretend to be someone I'm not.
So I won't apologize.
I will only show you my ideal.
Come with me, Ayumi.
I understand how you feel now.
So marry me!
If you're serious, you should be willing to do that!
Say what you like, but I know you can't do it.
You're all talk.
Very well.
Let's get married.
However, there are certain requirements.
In games, marriage is the ultimate ending.
It can't occur unless the right criteria are met.
At a minimum, the connection must have begun during childhood,
there must be a dramatic proposal,
and it has to finish with a kiss in a church with the words "Happy End" popping up!
Can you meet those requirements?
It's not like I can change the past!
In other words, you're all talk.
I take marriage much more seriously than you!
You shouldn't use the word "marriage" so lightly.
Daddy! Mommy!
Is this a friend?
Do you realize what time it is?
Daddy, Mommy...
I'm going to be a bride.
This is my future husband.
Ready to give up?
All the better.
I wanted to have your parents here for this.
Sorry, but this is all I can give you for now.
This is my present to you.
A wedding dress?
You are my first heroine,
and my final heroine.
Will you marry me?
I don't get you, Katsuragi.
You're a selfish womanizer who hates women.
Stupid and dumb,
smart and sneaky,
cold and gentle,
kind and mean,
dishonest and honest...
But I trust you.
So...
Say you love me!
If you say those words, I'll believe you.
Do you love me?
H-Hold on!
Calm down, dear!
Ayumi,
I love you.
Not good enough.
That was fake.
It wasn't sincere.
You have to really mean it!
I love you.
You aren't allowed to touch me!
That's against the rules!
I can't force you to believe me,
but I'll keep on saying it.
I love you.
It sounds more and more like an act!
Just say, "I love you."
I love you.
Not good enough!
P.S. I love you.
No good!
How can you propose
This is stupid.
I'm going to bed!
when you can't even say you love me?
So am I.
10 Minutes Later
How many times must I repeat it?
I'm out of lines!
I love you, Katsuragi!
That was a sincere confession.
Get it?
It's your turn now!
Ayumi?
You want to get married somewhere romantic, right?
I'll be waiting for you.
Ayumi!
Nora, she's on the move again.
Follow her!
Roger that.
Hide!
Vintage...
Nora!
Nora wouldn't let herself be killed.
You should be careful, or you'll die.
You're...
Nora's buddy.
I'm here on Nora's orders.
To interfere with Vintage's search,
I've been placing decoy raiments all over town.
The real Nora is currently watching Ayumi.
And these raiments are for you.
You can make yourself invisible while you move around.
Good.
Well, I'll get back to placing decoys.
Adieu!
Okay, let's get going.
Ayumi's headed for the ocean.
Where are you going?
Katsuragi, get a move on.
I'll handle her.
Understood.
Let's go.
You have to protect Chihiro and Ayumi.
Katsuragi, why do you need to put on an act?
Just say the words Ayumi wants to hear, and mean it!
Whenever we see each other
fukakute atsui itoshisa
my burning love only grows stronger
au tabi ni tsumoru no
like white feathers gathering on the ground
shiroi hane no you ni
We passed each other so many times
nandomo surechigatteita
where the roads of love and hate meet
suki kirai daisuki sukuranburu-kousaten
In the morning and during the day
asa mo hiru mo
At night and when I dream
yoru mo yume no
I always want to be with you
naka demo zutto soba ni itai
I want to protect you
anata wo mamoritai no
This is the first time I've felt like this
konna kimochi hajimete no kanjou
Even if you make the whole world your enemy,
sekai wo teki ni shitemo
I will be your only ally
watashi dake wa mikata de itai kara
I can see the ending.
The Memory of My First Love