You looking, Ai?
This is my village.
It's pretty!
I know, right?
Don't you think it looks just like Heaven?
Heaven?
Yeah.
It's a place in the skies, where the dead go.
A dreamland filled with
friendship and happiness.
I want to make this village a place just like Heaven.
In these hellish times, a place like that
would be a beacon of hope for everyone.
I wanna help!
Oh?
Thanks, Ai...
But this is my dream—and my job.
Instead, you should find a dream of your own.
What?
Mother...
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka no sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
The days I spend are meaningless and feel like the beginning of the end
nanika no owari no you ni ukisou na mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
waga tamerai wa hikari wo himeshi
My hesitation put the light out of my reach
saigo no kibou soshite kusari mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and the chains that bind me
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
The Valley of Death III
Where are we going?
You mean to say you're following me
without knowing even that?
You're the one who took me with you!
"Where are we going?" Nowhere.
All we're doing is searching for Hana.
She was strangely ignorant
but always so expressive.
She'd laugh and cry and get pissed off,
and she ate everything in sight.
We were together for almost six months,
and then she vanished without a trace.
Were you abandoned?
Maybe I was.
This all happened over ten years ago, when the world was at its worst.
She'll probably be that much older, now.
What're you gonna do when you find her?
That depends.
If she needs me, I'll do my best to help her.
But if she's found her own happiness,
I'll just look at her from afar
and be on my way.
And then there's always
the chance she's already dead.
There's also something else I'm searching for.
What's that?
In any age, there's only one thing all immortals crave.
I'm searching for a way to die.
A way... to die?
Yeah.
You want to die?
Indeed I do.
I... love humans.
Me? Become the last human alive?
You gotta be kidding me.
The last human...
Yes, "the last human."
Wrap your head around that phrase!
Just you try imagining it!
The last living human!
Does that sound like a good life?!
There'd be no one around. No one.
I'd be all by myself, forever!
Forever and ever... and ever.
Are you scared?
You're scared of becoming that, aren't you?
Is that why you'd rather be a monster?
I'm...
Wh-What's happening?
Tch. I screwed up.
What?
I...
Don't try to talk!
Yuri, you saved me?
Forget that and stop talking!
How did I...
For now, just put this on.
That jerk!
H-Hey!
Hang on! Where do you think you're going?
I'm gonna kill him!
What he did saved you!
What? But...
After he kicked you off the bridge,
that place turned into a battlefield.
Who did that?!
Humpnie did.
What?
If he suspects he's about to be ambushed,
he'll launch a suicide attack...
taking everything with him.
He's so ridiculous!
You can say that again.
But it's true he saved you
from getting caught up in it.
He may seem coldhearted,
but he doesn't commit meaningless acts of violence.
No matter how unfair his actions seem,
he's definitely got a method to his madness.
I find that very hard to believe.
Well, the only reason he turned out this way
is that he was burdened with the fate of immortality.
But even with that fate, he was better off
back when he was with the woman he loved.
M-Mother!
Your dad's called Humpnie Humbert.
He'll come see you someday.
So he really is my father, isn't he?
Where did he go?!
He was kidnapped.
What?
All signs point to it.
He was facing about seven people.
And they were deliberately using
rubber bullets to avoid killing him.
Rubber bullets?
Whenever Humpnie dies,
he resurrects to a completely healthy state.
If you wanna beat him,
you've gotta capture him
without inflicting a fatal wound.
I have to save him!
My spare underwear!
He'll manage to get through it himself, somehow.
I mean, he is an immortal monster.
He's not a monster!
Sure, he may be cruel,
but he can get surprisingly lonely,
and he only pretends to be the bad guy, so...
So... I've gotta save him,
or he'll only get more twisted!
He already seriously considers himself a monster.
In any case,
he is not a monster!
I hear ya.
I'll never call him one again.
I'm Yuri Sakuma Dmitriyevich.
I'm Ai.
Okay, let's get going.
Huh?
You're coming with me?
Well, after he went and called me his friend, how could I not?
What a pleasant surprise, Ai.
Finally up, Humpnie Humbert?
Who the hell are you bastards?
Oh? Did we forget to introduce ourselves?
Guess you did.
Well, whatever!
I'm Hiko,
and I'm a huge fan of yours!
So, is it true that when you
die under extreme trauma,
you lose your memories of it?
You bastard...
Where'd you hear that?
Damn it! I can't remember!
What the hell did these guys do to me?
Fuck off,
you assholes!
Got some new insults, I see!
Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it!
Recognize the outfit?
Should look just like yours.
I'll kill you!
I'm gonna kill you!
This is the first time I've ever
wanted to be someone else.
What the hell is with you guys?!
What do you want?!
Hm... I can probably take care of looking like you,
but that immortality thing's gonna be a bitch.
That's why—
—you died?
You gave up your life just to capture an idiot like me?
You're a real friggin' dumbass!
That spirit of yours is just awesome.
You destroy evil
without even uttering a word
and wield that dark justice of yours
while you kill people.
I know each and every thing about you!
You wanna die, don't you, Humpnie Humbert?
You wanna take back the death God stole from you, right?
Don't worry.
I'll kill you.
Don't get me wrong.
Dying isn't my wish.
Huh?
What do you mean?
Were you lying when
you said you wanted to die?
Did you deceive me?
Oh, I didn't lie.
Phew.
Yeah...
You wouldn't lie to me, would you?
This is something I've never told anyone.
I'll tell you, though.
I don't just want to die.
I... want to die happy.
Just like I've been doing for others,
I want someone to see me off.
S-Stop it.
My friends, my wife, and my kids—
I want to make the people who'll live on after me
cry and lament my loss,
as I leave behind just a little bit of regret
N-No...
No way!
and die.
That's it.
That's your wish?
You wanna die an ordinary, worthless death like that?
Nobody in this world can have that wish granted, though.
That's just...
I wish to live a life of happiness
and die a happy man!
What?
You're betraying me?
After being everything I wanted,
you're gonna betray me now?!
Like I care. Dumbass.
Okay, then.
You can just become our plaything.
I'll kill ya!
Keep provokin' me and I'll keep killin' ya!
Go on, then.
But I'll be the one who laughs last.
Pleased to make your acquaintance, everyone.
I've come to bury you.
A gravekeeper?!
Hey, Scar!
Didn't I say we could barge in
only after checking things out?!
We gravekeepers pride ourselves on our efficiency.
Ai!
Why the hell did you come here?!
To save you, of course!
Are you stupid?!
This has got nothing to do with you!
It does too!
Huh?!
It does have something to do with me!
What're you saying?
My mother was beautiful and childish
and always so expressive.
She'd laugh and cry and get pissed off,
and she ate everything in sight.
She sucked at whistling and at cooking, too,
but she was great at cleaning.
She didn't have a way with words,
she hated cigarettes and perfume,
and she really liked sweets,
and...
she loved you.
Hana.
I'm Ai.
There was a man called Humpnie Humbert
and a gravekeeper called Alfa,
and I'm their daughter.
You're my...
What's with you?
You're the kid of
a human and a gravekeeper,
and you're Humpnie's daughter?
That's just too funny!
You are all filthy.
Father, Yuri, and Scar weren't all that different, were they?
"A place in the skies, where the dead go."
The villagers just didn't want to let go of their Heaven.
That's why they pretended to be alive and made me—
I'm truly sorry.
And I just didn't know
that they'd all died a long time ago, right?
It might sound strange coming from me,
but don't hold it against them.
I would never.
They...
They didn't have a choice!
Sorry to interrupt this touching reunion.
But don't you think it'd make Humpnie real happy if we tortured Ai?
Don't touch her!
Yuri?
Ai, run!
What are you doing?!
Run away!
I won't run away!
Not without saving you first, Father!
You brat—
That's quite enough.
Don't get full of yourselves!
Scar, I'll need some backup.
Sure thing.
I left in search of my lover.
I never thought I'd find my daughter instead.
Either way, damn that Hana.
She just up and vanished,
gave birth to a kid,
and died.
I have a daughter.
It doesn't even feel real.
It's just not me.
I simply can't be
a good father.
You okay?
Yeah.
What about you, Scar?
Father!
Did you forget?
I can't die.
But...
Good grief.
Kids are such a pain.
Ai.
Yes?
I haven't told you my real name yet, have I?
I never even told your mother.
It's Kizuna Astin.
So you're Ai Astin.
Ai... Astin.
What a nice name.
Father!
Damn it.
I've got so many things left to say.
It's no use.
I'm too sleepy.
I don't wanna die.
And thus,
after losing his wife,
making his daughter cry,
being seen off by a friend and a gravekeeper,
and leaving behind regrets,
the Man-Eating Toy (Humpnie Humbert) passed away.
Father then awakened dead.
He loved humans more than anyone else did
and hated the dead more than anyone else, too,
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
but for just one day,
my father abandoned his principles...
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
to grant my wish
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
and to leave me with memories of him.
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
"Father."
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
"Please stay with me forever."
Those were words I just couldn't say.
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
You know what you wanna be
you know what you wanna be
An eternal melody
towa no uta
Here lies a man
who was born a human,
lived his life as a human,
and died as a human.
What do you plan on doing now?
I'm a gravekeeper.
No,
I'll become a gravekeeper.
If God is the one who abandoned this world,
then I'll be the one to save it.
An eternal melody
towa no uta
Next Episode
Good-bye.
...what should we do...
about this boy?
It's a nasty deliriant...
...I'm half human, half gravekeeper.
I sense dead who have not had a proper burial.
"Always"?!
"Her words are the words of Death."
I get it, but I don't like it.
Ortus I