An acceptance ceremony for the living, is it?
Having lost their means of survival,
they're seeking to migrate into Ortus.
Tonight, they will be granted a peaceful death.
Are you saying you're gonna kill them?
Yes.
Does Ulla know about this?
I'm sure she doesn't.
Why would you jump to that conclusion?
Because Ulla's...
Ulla's alive.
"Her eyes are the eyes of Death."
"Her words are the words of Death."
"Her body teeming with Death,
she shall not allow the living to escape."
"The Idol of Murder shall not allow them to escape."
"I am the ruler of man."
"I use the equinox to smite any
who doth sojourn in my realm."
"I am the guardian of all that is dead."
No...
It can't be true!
Ai!
Come on, Ai!
Yuri...
That is Ortus's dark side.
Anybody seen, spoken to, or touched by that princess
will cease to live.
Ulla is the Idol of Murder.
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Ortus III
Come on. Let's go back.
You knew?
Nah, I only heard about it from him right before I came.
Why?
Why would you...
Because you're alive.
And because until last year,
I was alive too.
Ortus, the land of the dead.
Outsiders who wish to live here must die.
However, children of immigrants are exempt from this rule.
They grow up as living beings,
but once they turn fifteen, they're made to choose...
between dying in order to stay here
and leaving this place alive.
I chose to stay
because it was my dream to become a mask maker.
I went through exactly what they did.
There was no pain or suffering.
Yeah, it came pretty naturally to me.
But you... you're an outsider.
I bet you've never given any thought
to what it means to be alive or dead, have you?
I...
Someone like you accidentally getting mixed up in this and dying
just isn't right.
But...
Ulla's the first girl I ever met.
We laughed together.
A lot!
We were friends,
and it was really fun.
It was so much fun.
That doesn't change the fact
that she's the Idol of Murder.
Just stay inside the inn.
Let's go.
Does she know?
Does Ulla know about her powers?
Does she know that she has the power to kill people?
Wh-What are you saying?
She's had it her whole life.
How could she not know?
But if she's had it her whole life,
there's a chance she hasn't realized it.
I mean, everyone around her is dead.
What if they lied to her and told her the dead are actually the living?
Ulla would definitely believe them, wouldn't she?
I see.
So you noticed it, didn't you?
It happened to me.
I grew up thinking the dead
around me were actually alive.
Ulla is me.
She's the person I was until recently.
The me who was surrounded
by kindness and lies in her village,
the me who wasn't told anything about who she was,
the me who was forced into a role,
oblivious to everything.
You and Ulla are not the same.
Your village's lie
was doomed to fail.
Even if your father hadn't come along,
the village would've fallen into ruin eventually.
But Ortus's—
my lie is different.
One day, all of the living will die.
That's right.
If everyone in the world dies,
Ulla's powers will lose their meaning!
You...
My lie needs but to last until that time comes.
And then,
Ulla won't have to be hurt anymore.
When will that time come?
Ulla's alive.
The dead around her don't age.
And neither do you.
What if a really, really long time passes?
Me? Become the last human alive?
You gotta be kidding me.
Ulla will be the only one to age...
All alone...
All by herself!
Even so!
It's my duty to protect her.
She must not be hurt.
I was assigned to be her teacher in order to deceive her.
"Create a world unbeknownst to her."
"Reverse the roles of the dead and the living."
"Make her eyes meaningless."
Pleased to meet you, Lady Ulla.
My name is Kiriko Zubreska.
Kiiko?
Call me "Kiriko," please.
Right then,
I decided to keep her safe no matter what.
I decided to protect her with everything I had.
I love her.
I, Kiriko Zubreska, love Ulla Hecmatika.
She's such a nice girl...
Kindhearted, considerate,
and she has a really cute smile.
Her laughter is so lovely.
And her eyes
are so pretty.
Ai,
what would you have done?
If you had the chance to shelter
a girl like that from this cruel world,
what would you do?
Could you stop yourself from lying?
I don't know.
I might do the same thing you did.
Then—
Even so,
she needs to know the truth!
We've been waiting for you, Ai.
Um, I'm gonna go talk to Ulla.
That's fine.
We'll give you a ride to the castle.
That's right!
I'm sure Ulla will come to resent you if you tell her!
Do you not resent the person
who freed you from your ignorance?
Do you not regret knowing?
Have you not once wished to live forever within the lie those people built for you?
Do you understand
that what you want to do won't help Ulla?
I'm sorry for disturbing you this late.
I came because I wanted to talk to you.
Um...
To tell you a story about you and me.
I'm half human, half gravekeeper.
I was born and raised in a tiny mountain village.
But that village was a village of the dead.
I was raised with that fact hidden from me,
and until recently,
I didn't realize the truth.
And, Ulla,
your circumstances and mine are pretty much identical.
Um...
Please hear me out calmly.
The people around you—
the people you thought were alive—
are actually dead.
The people who were really alive
were the ones in that tower tonight.
But they're not alive anymore...
because you looked at them.
You have the power to kill
anyone you look at, talk to, or touch.
Am I the Idol of Murder?
Yes.
To accept the living in this land, your power was necessary.
Kiriko's been deceiving you all this while.
But he only did that
to protect you.
Is that everything you came to tell me?
Yes.
I'm so sorry.
I thought I was doing this for you,
but maybe I was just doing it for myself.
Kiriko?
You know everything now, don't you?
I guess that's it, then.
It's all over.
I know.
You can't forgive me.
It's only natural.
Kiriko, we have a favor to ask of you.
Deceive her.
That is the only thing the elders wish of you.
The two of you look so sad right now.
I don't want that.
I love both of you.
So please,
don't look so sad.
I didn't need Ai to tell me.
I already knew.
You... knew?
Well, I only knew half of it.
I had the feeling that my eyes had some effect on people.
I also knew that all of you were
desperately trying to hide that from me.
I didn't know exactly what I was doing, though.
So then, why didn't you say something?
Because I didn't really mind.
Since it was something
everyone wanted to keep from me,
I didn't mind not knowing.
But I understand now.
I kill people.
I still don't fully understand what it means to kill someone in this world.
But you know...
one of them had such a peaceful smile on his face.
And another let out a big sigh of relief.
There were those who had weapons but stopped fighting to enter Ortus.
Still others refused to join us
and headed for the wastelands instead.
But all of them looked like they'd been set free.
Say, Ai...
Do you think that death—do you think that I'm evil?
I don't know.
Yeah.
I don't know either.
Ah...
You're on a journey to find that out, aren't you?
Maybe so.
Ai, you and I are really similar.
But we're not exactly the same.
You're free,
like a bird in the sky that refuses to be caged.
But I'm not like that.
I love this cage called Ortus.
On top of which, this cage is home to Kiriko.
Regardless of the time or place,
he's always protecting me.
Thank you, Ulla.
I'm sorry for everything.
I love the person I am.
But there are two things that sadden me.
One of them is being unable to see you, Ai.
And the other is being unable to hold you.
I feel the same.
You're my treasured friend, and yet...
So...
Princess?
Come on.
You two are dazzling.
There's someone I'd like you to meet.
Scar!
And...
Yuri?
Well, uh,
how do I say this?
After you ran off, Scar suddenly showed up.
This is Celica Hecmatika,
Ulla's elder sister.
She's been asleep all this time.
Ulla's mother hated every single thing around her...
She hated the way the world had changed.
She hated the nomadic life
she had to live after she got married.
She hated her dead husband.
And what she hated the most...
were the twins still in her womb.
Driven to the brink of death by the delivery,
she went insane and made an incredibly powerful wish.
Die, humans.
Ulla innocently accepted that desire,
but Celica rejected it.
Scar?
It's been you this whole time, hasn't it?
She's the one who's been calling out to me.
I always felt
that my sister had frozen her time—
waiting for something.
Now I know what it was.
This is my daughter.
Scar,
please take care of my sister.
Ai Astin, huh?
I never imagined there'd be someone else
living the same dream as me.
This world really is something else.
Next Episode
School?!
Goran Academy?!
...you have been accepted...
into this academy.
So you were sold out, huh?
Only because my little ghost here
played a prank on us.
Hey, nice to meet you...
Wh-What are you all doing?!
Goran Academy I