Hey.
There's glass there, you know.
Stop.
You're hurting yourself.
Looking at Alice,
my thoughts from back then come to mind.
"Give it up."
"You'll hurt yourself."
Please...
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Class 3-4  II
While attending school as a member of Class 3-4,
Ai Astin has been investigating.
She's been investigating the day that marks the beginning of this time loop:
July 28th of fourteen years ago—
the eve of the school cultural festival.
She's been investigating what happened that day
and what it was that the students of Class 3-4 strongly wished for.
This world gets reset approximately once a year.
So records of July 28th and onward cannot possibly exist.
However,
before getting reset, I brought in clues that I found in the outside world...
At least, I think I did.
Yep.
On a number of occasions,
you certainly did bring in clues.
But too bad for you.
I got rid of them all.
35,695 people have failed already.
Ai—the 35,696th—shall also fail.
You'll never find a way to get out of here.
Before long, a month passed,
and Ai turned thirteen.
Happy birthday, Ai!
Here. This is for you.
My shovel!
It's sparkling.
It's sparkling!
Well, it was pretty badly damaged,
so I had Scar sneak it out so I could fix it.
Thank you so much!
I didn't even realize it was gone.
And I used to feel so restless if I didn't have it nearby, too.
I see.
There's not a single dead person here.
So sometimes, I forget that I'm even a gravekeeper.
Well, don't.
No matter where you go, you'll always be you.
Yup.
And I'll find a way to save this world soon
so that you can turn seventeen, too.
That is my wish.
Wish?
Stop.
Could you please just stop that?
Huh?
It's just that
I think wishes shouldn't be granted.
They're better off not coming true.
When their wishes aren't granted, people actually put in effort.
It's because they don't come true that people make progress.
But if all their wishes come true,
people won't be able
to move forward anymore, you know?
That's why I'm telling you...
Don't wish to save Class 3-4.
Think of it as just a waypoint.
Still, even if you don't consider it a "wish,"
you've wanted to free Class 3-4 from this world
for over ten years, haven't you?
Yeah.
Well...
Don't you think it's time you told me?
Why you call Dee your enemy, I mean.
She changed.
They call her a witch now,
but originally, she was just a shy crybaby.
A normal girl, you know?
When I found a way out of this world, she just happened to be with me.
For a while after that, she really did help me out.
But then, all of a sudden,
she started saying that Class 3-4 was better off staying in this closed world.
How come?
No clue.
But what I do know
is that these past fourteen years
have changed both Dee and myself.
I hate the outside world.
We don't need to go back there.
This one time, I killed all my classmates with my own hands.
Well, you knew things would get reset, though.
That makes no difference.
I shot them using these hands.
That day,
I probably crossed a line that
no human being should cross.
That's not true.
Alice, you're...
Sorry.
This is no conversation to have on a birthday.
Happy birthday, Ai.
No matter where you go or what happens to you,
please stay the way you are.
I will.
So? How'd it go?
Find any clues?
This world is a really difficult one.
Yeah.
If you're not careful, you might get swept away.
This place is just way too comfortable.
If this keeps up and July 28th comes around,
we'll be absorbed into the loop and reset for sure.
I know.
Well, if there's anything
I can do to help, just let me know.
Silence.
Silence!
Let's go with a show of hands.
Those in favor of a play?
All right. Now, those in favor of a food stall?
There's a difference between you
and the 35,695 that came before you:
you joined Class 3-4.
In the usual loop,
there's a huge argument about the split vote,
after which we decide on the play.
But you just changed that.
So right now, this world is trying desperately to
make things coherent and get them back to normal.
For a while, it likely won't be able to deal with
things that weren't originally here.
"Ostia Coeducational Academy:
One Student Dead,
Seventeen Missing."
July 29th of fourteen years ago.
Where's the name?
What's the name of the student who died?
I didn't know there was one hidden there, too.
And here I thought I'd gotten rid of all of them.
It was you, wasn't it, Dee?
That's why you don't have a physical form in the outside world.
Yup, that's right.
Aww, shucks.
And I was so sure no one would ever find out, too.
When I first got outside,
I had no idea why I didn't have a body
or why I was different from Alice.
So without knowing, I traveled everywhere with him.
I helped him look for a way to get Class 3-4 back to normal.
Ostia Coeducational Academy - One Student Dead, Seventeen Missing
And that's when I suddenly remembered everything...
everything that happened on July 28th.
Hey, there's a spelling mistake on this sign.
Crap, you're right!
Who the hell wrote this thing?!
Oh no! I forgot to get a receipt!
Class Rep, can't you help me out?
Pay for it yourself!
Fourteen years ago, on July 28th,
too preoccupied with setting up the food stall for the festival,
I failed to notice that the window was open,
and fell.
I fell to my death.
That was when Class 3-4 made a strong wish:
"This is terrible. Please,
make it so that it never happened."
"Please let us live our everyday lives forever and ever."
That is why this world came to be.
That is why I've come back from the dead.
That's enough!
I get it already.
If this world were to be destroyed,
you'd also disappear, wouldn't you?
So you...
Do you remember?
At Goran Academy,
Alice and I told you that we were trying to save the world by destroying it.
I remember.
Now you know what we meant, right?
Alice is trying to save everyone in this world by destroying it,
but I don't care if the outside world is destroyed as long as I can save this one.
That's why I became "Whisper."
I whisper.
And I'll keep whispering.
"Destroy."
"Break."
"Be destroyed."
But that's—
The fly won't hurt himself if there's
no world on the other side of the glass.
Huh?
This will also help Alice in the long run.
I understand him.
I've been watching him this whole time, after all.
Um...
Before this world came into existence, I barely even spoke to Alice.
He was the kind of guy who'd help others
as wholeheartedly as he'd do things for himself.
He loved basketball,
but sucked at it.
And despite never even making the team, he worked harder at it than anyone else.
I felt lucky just to see him smile.
You don't understand these feelings, do you, Ai?
I don't.
But I know that smile.
Dee, you love Alice, don't you?
No!
W-Well...
Well, I think you mustn't lose hope.
I mean, there's gotta be a way—some way—
to destroy this world,
to save Class 3-4,
and to let you stay with them—all at the same time.
There may be a way to make that happen!
I wanted to save the world God abandoned,
but that goal started to get
more and more confusing.
But if there's a world Alice wants to save,
I want to save it with him.
So I want to save you too, Dee!
I want to find a way.
Oh, right!
I should talk to Alice—
Don't!
Don't tell Alice.
Alice doesn't know I'm dead
or that I'm the cause of this temporal loop.
Even if he finds out that I'd disappear,
he'll probably just
choose to save everyone else.
No, I know he will.
That's the kinda guy he is.
But you know,
that would mean he doesn't need me!
I'm scared of that.
That scares me more than anything.
I mean,
it's not that I wish to be someone special to Alice.
I can't.
After all,
I've got his blood on my hands.
I wonder when it was exactly...
Alice was desperately looking for a way to save this world,
and having such a rough time...
So much so that it got me thinking he'd be better off
resetting and forgetting about all that,
so I...
That's why I can never be special to him.
Yeah, I'm fine with just being in his world.
I don't care if I only have a small corner of it
or if he never talks to me again,
as long as I can stay in his world!
I couldn't take it!
I couldn't take Alice saying he doesn't need me!
Please, Ai.
Help me,
not Alice.
Save me—
save this world of mine!
Ai didn't say she would help me,
but she didn't say anything to Alice either.
However...
on the day Alice became the Buzzer Beater...
Whether he's in this endless loop
or outside of it,
this is the day when Alice just can't act normally.
Basketball's fun because you can miss.
There's no way a guy
with perfect aim could keep playing it.
In exchange for having my wish granted,
I lost what was dearest to me.
I'm the only one who can catch Alice as he falls.
Today, Alice needs me!
Or so I thought.
What... is this?
What is this?
Um, Alice...
what if maybe, just maybe,
someone had to be sacrificed for Class 3-4 to be freed?
What would you do?
I wouldn't mind.
To free Class 3-4,
I would sacrifice anything.
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
To tell you the truth, I already knew.
I've known ever since that day.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
Great! I'm glad to see you're still all right!
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
nor our future,
mirai mo
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
Tonight, I can believe you,
i can believe you tonight
and tonight, you'll see what I really want,
you see what i want tonight
even though,
eien to
on some nights,
hakanasa no
the contrast between life and death makes me tremble
furueru yoru mo aru keredo
Next Episode
Does it have something to do
with the temporal loop?
I'll make you remember.
Is this really a reset?
We were too weak.
Let's do it all over again...
I'm sure Ai's fine.
What the fuck is going on?!
The world can't handle this contradiction!
Class 3-4  III
But I want to save you!