Vintage is flying around in the open,
and yet I must hide myself...
Will Katsuragi and the others be okay?
Goddesses.
If you are present, show yourselves.
Otherwise, we will begin interrogating everyone here, one at a time.
If you wish to save these girls, reveal yourselves.
Why are you trying to start another war?
Do you have to squeeze my hand so hard?
We're both invisible right now.
If we get separated,
we won't be able to find each other again.
Do you even know where Ayumi is?
Nora's transmitting her location.
Looks like she's at Seaside Park.
Chihiro?
Katsuragi?
I can't see him.
Katsura—
Chihiro, are you okay?
Chihiro?
U-Uh, you only have to put up with me a little longer.
I don't really mind...
What was that for?!
Get off me already!
Let's go.
Katsuragi, why not just tell Ayumi
the truth about what's happening?
That won't work.
If I tell the truth, I can't conquer her.
You're wrong!
Ayumi's waiting for you to come clean.
Is that the strategy you two devised?
Wh-What's that supposed to mean?
I was wondering why Ayumi was being so aggressive.
That explains it.
Ah, this ship brings back memories.
But it's odd that Vintage hasn't noticed her,
given our proximity.
I wonder why.
Well, regardless, this will be the stage for the finale.
Katsuragi...
Ayumi!
Where are you, Ayumi?
He's playing a game.
A game where the goal is to seduce you tonight!
But... He has a reason for doing it!
A reason?
I don't know the specifics,
but whatever it is,
he's desperate to see it through.
If this doesn't make sense to you,
ask him for answers.
You have to decide on your own
what you want to do with Katsuragi.
Katsuragi, why are you doing this?
Just tell me the truth!
It might actually be better to tell her everything.
I'm sure Ayumi would be willing to help.
I give up.
Huh?
I'm out of ideas.
I'll tell you everything.
But on one condition!
Right now, I can only answer one question.
I promise to answer one,
but your other questions will have to wait.
Wh-Why do I have to ask questions?
How long are you gonna drag this out?
Is that your question?
If so, I'll answer it.
Shut up!
If you refuse to accept this condition, we're done.
I'll never approach you again.
So, will you ask me one question?
Or are we through?
Choose.
He wants to keep the truth from her at all costs?
Diana.
What is it, Tenri?
Um... So...
T-Tenri, why did you not say anything before?
Here's my question.
Do you love me?
I do not.
Then you've been lying to me this whole time?
That's a second question.
I can't answer you.
You don't love me, but you chased me around and proposed to me?
That's also a second—
Shut up!
This isn't fair!
I didn't say that I'd never answer it.
You just have to wait—
Answer me now!
You must have a reason for going through all this!
So...
If you need my help, I'll do whatever I can.
No, thank you.
I don't need your help.
Especially not now.
You always insist on doing things your way,
ignoring how everyone else feels!
How could anyone love someone like you?
You're disgusting!
I'm not doing this because I want people to love me.
I'm only trying to reach the ending.
I don't require any rewards or assistance.
I won't let anyone else take this responsibility.
This is a gamer's love.
Ayumi, I adore you.
Take my hand,
Ayumi.
I will guide you to the ending.
As requested, I tried to make it romantic.
But it won't take long for them to find us...
Ayumi, please come with me!
Isn't this enough?
Ayumi.
Fine, I guess.
We can have a wedding ceremony.
Wrong answer!
What do you mean, you "guess"?!
Don't you have anything better?
Do you realize what an ending entails—
Shut up!
We just have to do this, right?
No! I refuse to accept this ending!
You're being too casual about this!
Quiet!
Try to smile, you sick freak.
I don't see you smiling, real girl.
Now, let us exchange vows before the Maijima Sea!
Don't worry about the vows!
Not like I can trust anything out of your mouth.
Y-You're one nasty bride.
But...
I will trust your feelings.
Earlier, I decided that if you really came here,
I would trust you no matter what.
I understand how serious you are.
That's wrong!
That's not what a conquest is at all!
Why do you think I planned out how to trigger all those flags?
Shut up!
Just stop talking about conquests for one moment!
Hey, are you two getting married or not?
A conquest is more important than the world!
I can't let you treat the whole process so lightly!
What do you take me for?
B-Back off!
I gave it some serious thought too, you know!
I won't let anyone manipulate my feelings!
I'm... I'm the one who decided
to fall in love with you!
That's right.
That was the choice I made, too.
If you understand, marry me!
Mercurius!
Hey, wake up!
Thank you, Katsuragi!
Diana? She has her wings?
Diana?
Mer, thank you for awakening.
I need you to do something right away.
But I only just woke up...
Vintage! This is the end of the road!
The Loose Souls Team will face you!
Rimyuel?
Akari?
Katsuragi, I appreciate your efforts in this endeavor.
You have my gratitude.
Some members of the Loose Souls Team still refuse to give in to Vintage.
The time has come to show them what we're made of.
We will rescue the captive girls.
Let us take it from here.
Stay together!
We will help reunite the goddesses!
Wasn't that Akari?
What's going on?
Is it over?
Yeah.
I've done my part.
What happened to that thing inside Ayumi?
It grew wings and flew off.
Oh?
I couldn't see a thing.
Well, I'm going home.
I have a concert to prepare for.
Is it okay for us to just leave?
Probably not.
But there's nothing more we can do to help.
Anyway, why are you coming with me?
I left my guitar at your house!
I can't play in the concert without it.
The sun's up...
Here. This was what you wanted, right?
Thanks.
Later.
Chihiro, thanks for everything.
Huh? Are you trying to creep me out?
I was able to bring out
Ayumi's goddess thanks to you.
You're wrong!
I did everything I could to screw it up!
But you didn't tell her about Hell.
If you had, it would have taken much longer.
That's because...
I didn't understand what was going on.
I'm sorry you had to worry about protecting me
when I wasn't even supposed to be involved.
Those shadowy figures were after Ayumi, right?
I had nothing to do with any of it.
So I'm sorry you had to protect me.
It seems the winds are changing.
That's enough.
You put up a good fight.
I'll let you live this time.
So long.
Katsuragi's sister.
Huh?
Miss Nikaidou?
Looks like it's safe for you to go.
Don't be late for your band's performance.
That's all I had to say.
Bye.
Huh? O-Okay...
Why did Miss Nikaidou say that?
Wait, I'm Kanon right now!
How did she know it was me?
Say, why did you go on a date with me
on Festival Eve?
You wouldn't go on a date for no reason, would you?
Was there something inside me?
Something inside me as well?
No. You weren't involved in all that.
Man, that's a relief!
It'd suck if I were actually involved in this mess.
In that case, I never have to talk to you again.
Yeah...
Chihiro, I'll be listening to your performance today.
Oh, okay.
Prepare to be blown away!
Well then!
Katsuragi...
Bye-bye.
Bye-bye...
Mai High Festival, Final Day
Main Stage: Battle of the Bands
Ellie, Yui, and Ayumi are all missing!
What's going on?
Maybe they're running late?
We'll just have to start without them.
What are you talking about?!
This is the real show!
Well, let's go!
It's our first on-stage performance!
When's Kanon performing?
There's one more band left.
Did you feel the earthquake this morning?
Oh, the next band is up!
Hello, everyone!
We're the 2B Pencils!
This is our first concert,
but something came up, and three of our members couldn't make it!
What happened?
Running late?
I'm gonna kill them!
So it'll just be the two of us!
Do they know what they're doing?
Good luck!
The pick...
You can do it!
Well then, please listen to our song!
Hold on!
Sorry, Chihiro!
We're a little late...
Welcome back.
Quit talking and get changed already!
Please give us a moment!
What's with that dress?
Did you get married or something?
I'm not sure.
Did I do the right thing?
I'm not sure what you mean,
but whatever it is, you decided it yourself, right?
Yeah, I did.
Then it's okay!
Get your guitar out!
Okay, everyone...
Let's try this again.
We're the 2B Pencils!
Glad you could all make it!
Try not to be late to your own concert!
Well, it's not a big deal.
Today's a part of the festival, after all.
The Mai High Festival's almost over.
Did you all have a good time?
As long as we're here,
let's make some great memories!
If there's someone you like, tell them how you feel!
Okay...
What?
Look at that!
Kanon?
No way!
It's Kanon!
Huh? Why's she here?
Wow!
Thank you, Chihiro.
Do you mind if I sing with you?
Huh?
You once said that you wanted to have a contest with me.
So I want to sing with you!
kawariyuku nichijou ni nomikomareta mama
Caught up in this ever-changing life,
ren'ai nante shi nai to omotteta
I never thought that I'd experience love
hito wo suki ni naru no wa rikutsu ja nai mitai
But it looks like there's no rhyme or reason to how it strikes
watashi koi wo shita yo
Because, wouldn't you know, I fell in love
mou ichido ugokidasu
Those precious, fleeting days
awaku itoshii hibi
have begun to stir again
nidonai shunkan to kanshoku wa
That once-in-a-lifetime moment and sensation
kiete ita keredo
have faded away
kokoro ni mada nokoru junsui to
But in my heart, I'll always have those feelings
hajimete koi wo shita kioku
and the memory of my first love
I'm sorry, Chihiro.
That wasn't what I meant to say back then.
nidonai shunkan to kanshoku wa
That once-in-a-lifetime moment and sensation
kiete ita keredo
have faded away
kokoro ni mada nokoru junsui to
But in my heart, I'll always have those feelings
hajimete koi wo shita kioku
and the memory of my first love
The memory of my first love
The Memory of My First Love
koi no shirushi kimi no me ni mitsuketa no ano hi
When I saw the signs of love in your eyes
El!
kizuita toki mune no jishaku mawaridashita
the compass of my heart began to spin
Look at this!
A customer gave me these cyclamens.
Wow, they're so pretty!
sagashiteita tokimeki ni yatto deaeta no
Finally I'd found what I'd been looking for
Aren't they lovely?
Yeah! We should put them in the café!
doko ni itemo mitsukedasu yo mou nidoto
I will find you wherever you are
It's been five days since then.
mayowanai
I won't hesitate again
kitto futari wa unmei da yo nan'oku mo no hito ga ite
I'm sure it was fate that we met
The members of Vintage were all arrested,
and their plan to revive Old Hell came to an end.
deau no wa computer demo muri
Billions live on this planet, and no computer could have led us together
Haqua was reinstated at the Loose Souls Team—
heibon sugiru mainichi ni period wo utta no
You put an end to the dullness of my life
Wait.
You were fired, Haqua?
tameiki sotsugyou
and I could put
A-A lot of stuff happened, okay?
dekiru no yatto
my sadness behind me
Also, in recognition of her help in defeating Vintage,
Nora was promoted to Head Section Chief.
aozora ga mabushii kimi ga iru fuukei wa
A beautiful blue sky is above, and you are somewhere here
That's just wrong!
shiawase no aura afuredasu no tomaranai yo
This the happiest world I can imagine
And...
my Exalted Brother...
ekimae no funsui niji wo tsukutteiru yo
The fountain in front of the station is casting a rainbow
kimi wo matsu jikan sae mo kakegaenai precious na toki
Even the time I wait for you is precious and irreplaceable
is back to normal.