What I saw right then
was a newborn world.
A world I could never enter.
So I decided
I'd create a world of my own...
by destroying everything.
Please, my God
Tell me, what should I do?
The
Sunday
God
without
The
Sunday
God
without
dareka ga sashinobeta te wo furihodoite susumu
I'll shake off the hands others hold out to me and advance
jiyuu na fujiyuu habikoru basho de
past a world of false freedom
I live like any day could be my last, as though something were chasing me
nanika ni owareru you ni ikiisogu mainichi
shinjitsuzuketa shinjitsu mo wakaranaku naru
Here even the truths I had faith in begin to stop making sense
nani ga hontou no shiawase nan darou
What is true bliss?
sono kotae wo shiru mono nado
There is nobody here
koko ni wa inai
who knows the answer to that
where is my God?
arehateta yume ga nemuru daichi de
Blighted dreams lie dormant and ravaged in these lands,
shinda you ni ikiru nante boku ni wa dekinakute
and I refuse to live like I am already dead
umarekaware ima hikari wo himeshi
Be reborn now unto a light kept hidden for so long
saigo no kibou soshite kiseki mou ichido sekai ni
I'll let the world see my last hopes and miracles
kagayaki wo hanate
I'll let them see my radiance
Class 3-4  III
Morning, Ai.
Dee.
I've decided to tell Alice everything,
including what caused this loop
and that I'm dead.
After the last time we spoke, I put a lot of thought into it and reached this decision.
Thank you, Ai... for keeping my secret all this time.
But, well...
Dee, you'll...
It's okay now.
I spoke to Alice just now.
I asked him to meet me later
so that I could tell him something.
But...
Ai, can I ask you for just one favor?
All right.
I want you to go with me.
Dee...
When I tell Alice,
I want you by my side.
Okay.
Wait for me behind the school, at the basketball court.
I'll be right there.
What, you're here too?
Yeah.
I wonder what she wants to tell me.
I told her to stop beating around the bush,
but she refused to say.
She does want to tell you, though.
You know something?
What is it?
Does it have something to do
with the temporal loop?
Um... I can't tell you.
The hell?
It's just, well...
You should hear it from Dee.
Good morning, everyone.
Well, aren't you late.
Huh? Where's Alice and Ai?
They not with you?
Huh?
What's the matter?
Dee?
Menhim,
forgive me.
What the hell are you doing?
Just watch.
What the fuck?!
Huh? When'd I fall asleep?
What is it?
What's with you, Mu?
What's gotten into you guys?
What...
What the fuck is going on?!
I know, right?
Weird, right? Completely incomprehensible, right?
A total mystery, right?
I'll explain it all.
Actually...
you all know everything already.
You've just forgotten, is all.
So...
I'll make you remember.
Dee's pretty late.
Hey, thanks for yesterday.
Huh?
For listening to me.
You're a total mystery to me.
I've never met someone like you before.
You left me speechless on your birthday, too.
Man, I'm such a pushover.
Why do I get like this whenever you're around?
And why is it that you're the only one?
D-Don't say things like that!
You know, if something's troubling you,
you should talk to everyone about it.
I'm sure they'll listen.
You really are a total mystery.
Well?
Finally starting to remember?
It's all coming back to you now, isn't it?
That day...
That's right. That day...
I remember now.
We just couldn't accept it!
It was too much.
There was... so much blood...
...and a dead body!
No!
We couldn't believe it.
We wanted it to be a lie.
And then?
Then... We made a wish.
That day... that very evening, we made a wish.
Looking down at that corpse, we made a wish.
"This can't be happening."
"This is terrible."
"Please, make it so it never happened."
"Give us back the fun lives we had before."
"Please let us live them forever and ever."
"Please come back to life"...
If only you'd wished for that instead...
That's right.
You all wished for eternity.
And you still do, don't you?
But then you remembered everything.
So you want to start over, don't you?
You want to forget all about it again, don't you?
To forget all about that day.
Come on, then.
Let's do it all over again...
from the very beginning.
What's happening?
It's Dee.
She's trying to reset this world!
Alice!
She brought back Class 3-4's memories!
The world can't handle this contradiction!
Hey, there's a spelling mistake on this sign.
Crap, you're right.
Who wrote this thing?
Oh no. I forgot to get a receipt.
Class Rep, can't you help me out?
P-Pay for it yourself.
I'm gonna reset both this world
and myself.
Scar!
You okay?
Yuri!
Both of us are all right.
Fog's starting to swallow the whole town.
Is this the "reset" he was talking about?
Look.
Ai...
This is my first time.
So these last fourteen years
are just gonna disappear, huh?
Fourteen years spent with Alice,
with that smile of his that only I knew.
But I've got to start over.
I'll fall from the window once again,
just like I did that day.
And just like that day, I'll die.
After crashing into the ground.
After getting broken so badly
that I can't come back to life as one of the dead.
What?
No!
The fog!
It's retreating...
I finally figured it out.
It wasn't Dee, was it?
It was you...
Wasn't it?
Bingo.
That day, I tried to save Dee
and fell.
I fell to my death.
Sorry I didn't realize until just now.
I never once considered the possibility
that you mistakenly thought you
were the one who died.
I'm so sorry.
It must've been so hard for you.
You've been fighting all this time
because you didn't want to disappear—
No!
That's not it, Alice.
I...
I just...
Don't worry.
You won't disappear.
So just relax and go back to the outside world.
No!
I can't!
I can't go back without you, Alice!
Reset...
Let's reset this world one more time!
Come on!
Stop it.
That would make it so everything had never happened.
Including our travels all over
the outside world together.
Including all the fights we had
and all the laughter we shared.
All of it.
All of it would disappear.
This last year I spent with
all of you would disappear too.
You must be kidding if you think I'd want that.
So come on, guys.
Get out.
Go outside and turn seventeen.
Turn eighteen, turn nineteen,
celebrate your birthday every year,
and grow up.
But...
while you're doing all that,
please remember me.
Don't forget about me.
Even if it's just once in a while,
please think of me.
That way, I'll be able to stay with you guys...
forever.
But...
But there's got to be a way.
There must be some way you can
come with us to the outside world!
But!
It's useless, Ai.
This is just the kind of guy Alice is.
He helps others as wholeheartedly as he does things for himself.
Even though Alice knows he'll disappear,
he'll choose to save everyone else.
Thank you, Dee,
for being the one who came outside with me
and traveled with me all that time.
I'm really glad it was you.
All right, it's time to go back.
Once you go through this door,
you'll be back in the outside world.
Mu, you first.
Mu.
Menhim.
I won't forget about you, ever!
Go on.
Get going, all of you.
Can I ask you for a favor?
Anything.
Smile?
Bye.
Yeah.
Hurry, everyone!
Remain calm, and exit the way you came in.
This way!
Wait.
Is this really a reset?
No.
The town itself is vanishing.
Something must've happened in the school.
Hey!
Save it for later! Hurry up and get over here!
In any case, we should get Celica somewhere safe.
I'm sure Ai's fine.
Okay!
Come on, you should get going too.
Do you remember when I talked to you back at
Goran Academy about the concept of observers?
Well, you're the only observer left in this world.
By leaving, you can put an end to everything.
Alice, you're horrible.
You brought me here just to make you disappear.
Sorry.
You're awful.
You're an awful person!
Yeah.
Alice!
You want to live with everyone, don't you?!
You want to turn seventeen, don't you?!
You don't want to disappear all alone, do you?!
Hey, Alice!
I started singing a never-ending melody
owaranai melody wo utaidashimashita
It's impossible.
I died fourteen years ago.
I loved it,
totemo daisuki de
I have a grave in the outside world.
My body's lying there after being given a formal burial by a gravekeeper.
but it made me a little sad as well
sukoshi setsunakute demo
But I want to save you!
I sang it for so long that I began to dislike it,
tomaru koto ga dekinakute kirai ni narimashita
I...
I... want to save your world!
even when I stood next to you, my love
tatoe taisetsu na kimi no soba demo
Even if the whole world rejects it...
Life on the planet
life on the planet
and the way we see the world
mieru keshiki wa
I want to save you!
will never be the same
onaji ni wa dekinai no desu
Nor will our hearts,
kokoro mo
Alice...
nor our future,
mirai mo
Alice!
nor our smiles
egao mo sou
What will my love be like?
mada minu ai
So, in this world full of sweet love...
mo sweet love in love world
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
Good-bye.
you know what you wanna be
You know it
wakattenda
In this world full of sweet love,
sweet love in love world
You know what you wanna be
you know what you wanna be
An eternal melody
towa no uta
Why the hell did you have to go and save me?