Goddess Search, Day 4
I was told to pump her for information, but...
I can't trust her.
Well, I'll be heading off.
Huh?
Tell Elsie to come see me when she gets back.
Hey, wait!
Buh-bye!
What is this?
Is it... Kanon?!
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
Where's Shiori?
Shiori
This notebook...
Shiori?
Is she giving me permission to read it?
Looks like she scrapped a lot along the way, though.
Guess I'm not allowed to read those.
"On the eve of the French revolution,
oppressive nobles, wars, and poverty ravaged the countryside,
causing the people much suffering."
"I, Simone, have inherited the
Mask of Justice my late father protected!"
"I am the swordswoman who upholds justice,
Étoile de Shooting Star!"
Shiori
What happened to the sci-fi setting?
And this is horrible. Awful, even.
Shiori
Staff
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
It's really interesting!
Can I read the next chapter
if I come back tomorrow?
Please read the rest of my story.
I guess I chose the right option.
But it's really hard to not criticize that story...
Huh?
Why did it suddenly get dark?
Is it closing time already?
Whatever.
Next up is Ayumi or Chihiro...
The miasma is definitely getting stronger!
Her defenses are breaking down.
Hang in there, Kanon!
What's with this disgusting miasma?
Nora? Didn't you leave?!
Did you really think I wouldn't notice miasma seeping into the hallway?
What's going on?
I want an explanation.
Come on, spit it out.
Vintage put a curse on her.
The fate of New Hell
rests on whether she lives or dies.
Only a demon could do this.
Could it be one of the demons who stabbed Kanon?
Vintage?
No...
They're not trying to kill me?
Then I'll make my move!
There is someone capable of doing this who isn't a demon!
Luna! Tsukiyo's doll!
Is she a goddess?
Stay away from Tsukiyo.
I'm being crushed!
There's a goddess inside Tsukiyo!
But those who wish her harm may be around.
I have to pretend that I know nothing.
Is this some kind of prank?!
What did I ever do to you?!
I am Vulcanus,
a goddess who values justice and intricacy.
Vulcanus!
She's one of the sisters Diana mentioned!
But why is she revealing her name?
Doesn't she understand how much danger she's in?
This is a warning.
Never go near Tsukiyo again.
Tsukiyo is a beautiful girl.
More beautiful than anything I have ever seen.
I will not allow an unfaithful, dirty, and dangerous man like you to associate with her.
Who's the dangerous one here?!
What have I done—
You were getting quite friendly with the library girl.
I saw you with my own eyes.
She's pretty observant for a doll.
Was Tsukiyo watching through Luna?
If so, I absolutely cannot let them see Shiori's letter.
Goodbye, evidence!
I was aware that you had received something from that girl.
This is undeniable proof.
Tofu and
vegetable
chowder
Tofu and
vegetable
chowder
What is this?
He's gone!
Hey!
You'd better clean up the mess you made!
She's still just a doll, given that she fell for such a cheap trick.
But she certainly made quite a disturbance.
What if Vintage finds her?!
The only one who can stop Vulcanus is...
She's not here!
Which means...
Tsukiyo...
No, she's got a halo.
I am a weak goddess.
My vision and hearing are poor.
I cannot walk.
However, I can manipulate objects.
I send my soul into other things,
turning them into my eyes and limbs.
Objects are all I need
to protect Tsukiyo.
Let me talk to Tsukiyo!
Tsukiyo!
I feel the same way Luna does.
You never came to see me again.
That's right.
Since she hosts a goddess,
Tsukiyo remembers everything from her conquest.
No wonder she's angry at me.
On top of that,
you've been spending a lot of time
with that singer and the library girl.
You mean nothing to me!
I hate you!
Luna, get rid of him!
Hey, come on!
You creepy doll!
Let me through!
I want to talk to Tsukiyo!
Tsukiyo says that she doesn't want to see you.
If you wish to speak to her,
you'll have to get past me.
Tsukiyo refuses to come out.
It sounds like she doesn't want to hear what I have to say.
In that case...
I'm the one who should be angry!
Why are you doing this to me?!
"Why?"
You know why!
You cheated on her with that singer, Kanon,
and then you had the audacity to
make a move on the library girl too!
She's way too close!
I have no idea what you're talking about.
You must be confused.
Liars like you get buried by benches,
crushed into paste,
and plunged into the depths of Hell!
That's not very beautiful at all.
Aren't you supposed to be Tsukiyo's partner?
But I can't let this event end without a fight.
Unpleasant situations are important steps in a conquest.
This is where I must make my move.
Don't you trust me, Tsukiyo?
How could she trust you, you demon?
Leave at once!
I refuse!
I won't leave until I've talked with Tsukiyo!
I was happy being alone.
So why did this cruel man
have to come back into my life?
I'm ashamed of myself.
It was inevitable.
Inevitable?!
How can you say such an irresponsible thing—
It really was inevitable.
We were brought together by fate.
How can you say it was fate?
You're the one who approached me!
Why did you come back?
Why?
I was so close to forgetting about you...
Tsukiyo!
Kiss me!
Huh?
A kiss will solve all of our problems!
What?
In the end, it comes down to the kiss!
Glory to all dating sims!
You shall move no further.
Freedom!
Being with you will corrupt Tsukiyo.
I will not let you see Tsukiyo again.
You should hurt me more than that.
You're absolutely right.
I've hurt Tsukiyo.
And I can't guarantee that I won't make her unhappy.
How dare you speak so indifferently?!
Leave before I drop these on you.
I'm willing to accept any punishment.
I need you to love me for just a little longer!
Otherwise,
I won't be able to protect you!
Nonsense.
Luna! Stop!
Tsukiyo?
Can I trust you?
Can I really trust you, Keima?
This world is filled with beautiful things.
Let's search for them!
You and I, together!
Keima!
Luna, are you trying to kill Keima?
I lost control because you interfered.
This man just doesn't know when to give up.
Luna, we should talk to Keima about your sisters.
My existence must remain a secret.
How can you say that after everything you did?
Do you really trust this man?
I need you to love me just for a little longer!
Otherwise,
I won't be able to protect you!
Tsukiyo!
A Vintage curse, huh?
So why did they target this girl?
I can't say right now.
If you wait too long, they'll revive Old Hell.
The Loose Souls Team won't allow that to happen.
You think the Loose Souls Team are the good guys here?
What do you mean?
Haven't you heard the rumors
about Vintage worming their way into the Loose Souls Team?
They're within the Loose Souls Team?!
The order to search for the goddesses
is essentially an order to capture the goddesses.
I wonder who issued the order.
Capture the goddesses?
Know your place.
Wh-What is this doll?
So, Apollo is inside this girl...
Are we all living inside human girls right now?
Wait, is this...
Yes. A goddess.
Katsuragi?
A goddess?
You said you were Vulcanus, right?
Vulcanus.
The third goddess.
Who are you?
I am Diana.
It's been so long, Nee-sama.
Ah...
Our appearances may have changed,
but I am overjoyed to see you again.
It appears that the time has come for us to be reunited.
Let us join our powers together.
By the way, Nee-sama...
What are those things on your back?
On my back?
These are my wings.
What about them?
N-Never mind.
However, I still find it hard to believe that we are being targeted.
Apollo was even brought to death's door.
Right, I need the two of you to remove Apollo's curse.
I need you to come upstairs.
I cannot walk.
Carry me.
You could have just turned back into Tsukiyo.
I don't see a problem.
You've carried Tsukiyo around before.
This is getting interesting.
Katsuragi-san.
Hmm?
Nee-sama has her wings back.
What?
I only have my halo.
This means that Nee-sama has recovered more power.
Did you engage in a special act of love with her?
Huh?
One that you didn't do with Tenri?
I didn't do anything.
Now, enough of that hushed chatter.
Diana may be my sister,
but you should not speak so freely to other women.
After all, you are an important source of power for Tsukiyo and myself.
Speaking of which, Diana...
How did you recover your power?
Well, a lot has happened.
We can talk about this later.
We have more important matters to deal with right now!
Then get a move on!
It pains me to see her like this.
I wasn't able to remove the curse by myself.
Then let us join our powers to remove the Weiss curse.
Their powers have been combined...
Incredible! This should be enough!
It's out!
Kanon! Are you okay?
Kanon?
Hey, she's not waking up!
What's wrong?!
This is very bad. She's taken a dive.
A dive?
Hydration.
It's one of Apollo-neesama's defensive measures.
She altered the body's state and dove deep inside.
However, this merely buys her some time.
She must have been desperate.
I don't need the commentary.
Get to the point!
Our spell succeeded.
The curse is gone.
However, Apollo also cast a spell on herself.
We are not able to remove this spell.
We need Apollo-neesama to recover her power.
It's possible that Mercurius might know what to do.
Of course. Mercurius...
But we don't know where she is.
Don't turn this into a crappy RPG!
I saw Mercurius in Westville.
You must pass through
the Valley of Dragons to reach Westville.
Why don't you try going on this wild goose chase?!
You could make it if you had an airship...
Well, at least we don't have to worry about Kanon dying any time soon.
I didn't expect to find a goddess so soon.
If I report this to the bureau chief, I'll get more than just a medal!
Nora!
Are you interested in working with me?
Huh?
Can you hide this information from your superiors for one week?
What? Why?
I'm not asking you to do it for free.
Hey!
Once New Hell is saved, you can take all the credit.
Now you're speaking my language.
Huh?
The door's open.
Is anyone in here?
What are you doing, Haqua?
What's wrong?
Where's Nora?
She left. We made a deal.
U-Um...
Sorry!
I haven't been any help at all.
That's not true.
Why did you ask Nora to work with you, then?
I didn't have a choice.
We need information right now.
I felt so proud when I got assigned as a section chief in the Loose Souls Team.
But now...
Haven't you heard the rumors
about Vintage worming their way into the Loose Souls Team?
That's just something Nora said.
You shouldn't believe everything you hear.
You're indispensable in your own way.
Okay, all done.
Say it to me straight!
Tell me how you feel!
Say that you need me!
Diana?
K-Katsuragi-san, could you please... kiss me?
Wh-What?
D-Diana?
Hey...
No, I can't do this!
Stay away from me, you animal!
This is too hard for me!
The hell are you trying to do?!
I-Is it my fault?
What?
Vulcanus-neesama has recovered her wings.
That cannot be right!
A goddess's power comes from love!
Nee-sama's host cannot have more love than Tenri!
That would be...
unfathomable!
The facts seem to say otherwise—
That's impossible, you insensitive jerk!
Tenri has loved you for ten years!
It must be my fault.
It's...
because I think of you as a sleazy creep who chases skirts like a madman...
Where did all this come from?
But I've realized my mistake.
I will do my best to love you...
So you must engage in the ritual of love with Tenri right away!
Wait, wait, wait...
Haqua-san?!
This doesn't seem like the right way to go about it.
Please do not interrupt our conversation!
Right back at you.
I was here first.
What were you talking about in this room?
Huh?
N-Nothing important!
Then you should leave!
I didn't choose to—
This is so stupid.
A goddess is above petty quarrels.
Diana.
It's my fault that you haven't recovered your power.
I realize that you and Tenri have it harder than the other girls,
because both of you know
everything that is going on.
I truly am sorry.
No, I am the one who asked you to do this.
I do not feel as much disgust toward you now.
I believe that you are a dependable person.
D-Do your best, Keima-kun.
He didn't need to apologize...
Whenever we see each other
fukakute atsui itoshisa
my burning love only grows stronger
au tabi ni tsumoru no
like white feathers gathering on the ground
shiroi hane no you ni
We passed each other so many times
nandomo surechigatteita
where the roads of love and hate meet
suki kirai daisuki sukuranburu-kousaten
In the morning and during the day
asa mo hiru mo
At night and when I dream
yoru mo yume no
I always want to be with you
naka demo zutto soba ni itai
I want to protect you
anata wo mamoritai no
This is the first time I've felt like this
konna kimochi hajimete no kanjou
Even if you make the whole world your enemy,
sekai wo teki ni shitemo
I will be your only ally
watashi dake wa mikata de itai kara
I trust you
shinjiteru
Punch and Date
Three goddesses left. The conquests are going almost too well.
But the next target is Yui, the one I have the most trouble with.
Katsuragi-kun, how about you wipe that scary look off your face and go on a date with me?
Sure, I'll go on a date.
But I'm only doing this to bring out the goddess!
I-I'm not doing this for your sake or anything!
Why are you going tsundere?