Well, that was easy.
You dare to attack a goddess?
You can kill me,
but my sisters...
will not fall!
I suppose I should finish the job.
Kanon-chan!
Hey, Kanon!
Why?
Kanon-chan...
Kanon-chan!
Look up at the sky
Like a bird without wings
If you want to fly
Feel your breeze, release yourself
Why do you sigh?
Just count your blessings
Every time you try
Find something, believe yourself
My mission is gonna be a tough one
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Can you hear? I'm calling you
I just wanna feel you
Don't forget to remember
So please remember
I hear you are calling me
I want you to feel me
You know I won't surrender
Never surrender
My mission I've got to execute
I know it's not a game anymore
I swear that I'll never fail again
'Cause don't wanna regret anymore
Secrets of the Goddess God only knows
Scramble Formation
Haqua...
Please help her!
I'm working on it.
Apollo-neesama was inside this girl.
I was so close to seeing her...
How could this happen?
All right.
Watch out!
Ow...
What is that?
It's the magic of Old Hell.
What?
The power instilled in this sword
is assassination magic used by the Weiss my sisters and I sealed so long ago.
But magic from Old Hell is forbidden!
Anyone caught using it
will wish they got thrown in jail!
Does this mean some of the Weiss have revived?
What is it?
This is the insignia of Vintage.
Vintage?
A cult of modern demons who seek
to revive Old Hell by any means necessary.
They wouldn't think twice
about using magic like this.
There is assassination magic in today's Hell,
but this is far stronger.
An ordinary human would instantly be drained of their energy and die.
The power of the goddess is sustaining her for now,
but it won't last. Eventually, she'll...
Don't just stop there.
Tell us how many days she has left.
From here on,
let's focus on the information we have.
Huh?
That information will determine the options I have available.
Options?
How can you talk about this like a dating sim?!
Nii-sama, you have to help her!
Kanon-chan is in love with you!
Provided the conditions are met.
First, I'll need information.
Conditions?
Her life is on the line!
This isn't a game!
Indeed. This is no game.
That's why...
I have to save her!
Time is of the essence.
In order to do what's best,
I need information.
Haqua.
Huh?
How many days does Kanon have to live?
M-Maybe a week?
Once the miasma spreads throughout her body,
she'll die.
One week.
Got it.
The goddesses are the strongest weapons we have against the ancient demons.
They're the ones who sealed
the Weiss once before, right?
Yes, but I do not currently possess sufficient power to extract this.
What if you had another goddess to help you?
Well...
If my other sisters were here,
we could do anything.
Understood.
I'll find the goddesses before the week is over.
We need to hurry.
This Vintage cult is likely
targeting the others as we speak.
They will be fine.
Apollo-neesama sent out a warning.
It's written in the ancient language of Heaven.
"We have been betrayed by Hell.
Trust no one."
My sisters will be on their guard,
though that means they'll be even further from our reach.
That's for the best.
It's one less thing to worry about.
It seems like you have a plan in mind already.
For the time being, I shall go into hiding.
Don't contact me unless absolutely necessary.
One last question.
How many sisters do you have?
There are six of us.
Vulcanus
Vulcanus.
Apollo
Apollo.
Diana
Diana.
Minerva
Minerva.
Mars
Mars.
Mercurius
Mercurius.
We are known as the Jupiter Sisters.
Six... Got it.
I am counting on you.
Tenri, go home.
Don't let Diana out.
Okay.
One week to find four goddesses.
Well?
Where do we start?
Idol training.
Huh?
Narusawa TV
She's late!
I'm so sorry!
U-Um...
I'm Kanon-chan...
Stop fooling around!
Nii-sama told me to do this!
Do you know how many times I called?
Everyone's waiting for you!
Hurry up, Kanon.
Okay, coming!
She used her raiment to change her hair.
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
What
Manager
Okada
Sees
The rest is an illusion spell.
To other humans, she looks like Kanon.
But to us, she just looks like Elsie in disguise.
Seems like it worked.
That takes care of Kanon's absence.
Which leaves only...
Hello. Katsuragi residence.
Oh, you work with my husband?
Your husband is at death's door.
What?!
Katsuragi
Darling!
I'm off
to South America!
...........................Mari
That gets Mom out of the way for a while.
Now I can focus on the problem at hand.
You're quite forceful, aren't you?
Haqua, come to my house tomorrow morning.
Huh?
You and I will search for the goddesses.
For the next week, you'll be my buddy.
What?
The Next Morning
Goddess Search, Day 1
So, how do we go about searching for the goddesses?
There's no need.
The goddesses are inside the targets I previously conquered.
Huh?
How do you know that?
Diana is in Tenri, and Apollo is in Kanon.
They were both targets.
Also, according to Diana,
a girl who is host to a goddess will remember the conquest.
That was true with Kanon.
Th-That's all you've got?
Just watch.
Kanon left us a present that should do the trick.
A present?
Over there.
That's Kanon-chan's boyfriend?
No way!
Isn't that the dweeb?
Kanon-chan confessed her love to him.
Everyone's staring at you.
Perfect.
The more the rumors spread,
the easier it will be to flush out potential goddess hosts.
What do you mean?
It's simple.
If one of my targets hosts a goddess and remembers the conquest,
she'll still be in love with me.
How can you be so calm about this?
After hearing about Kanon's confession, she won't be very happy.
In other words...
If any of my targets are mad at me,
they're a potential host.
Oops. Sorry.
Chihiro?
My hand slipped.
Oh? Ellie!
You changed your hairstyle?
Oh! Um, well...
This Is How
She Looks
Hey, how does Elsie usually act at school?
Exactly as you are now.
Just flounder around.
Ayumi.
Morning, Katsuragi-kun!
"Kun"?
I can't go in with you standing there.
Move it or lose it!
Chihiro and Ayumi are both angry.
Maijima Academy Middle School
Hello.
Long time no see, Minami-chan.
Um, have we met before?
So you're working here now.
That's great.
Who are you?
Huh?
What's that?
A list of the girls I've conquered.
It's grown quite a bit.
After today's investigation,
I can narrow it down to five.
How?
My theory is that the girls most closely related to me
are host to goddesses.
Huh?
Tenri
Tsukiyo
Rieko
Keima
Ayumi
Shiori
Kusunoki
Sumire
Chihiro
Yui
Akari
Nagase
Nanaka
Kanon
Mio
Minami
Hinoki
These names are listed
in the order of most to least close to me.
Tenri
Tsukiyo
Rieko
Keima
Ayumi
Shiori
Kusunoki
Sumire
Chihiro
Yui
Akari
Nagase
Nanaka
Kanon
Mio
Minami
Hinoki
Ayumi
Shiori
Confirmed goddesses:
Tenri, my childhood friend and neighbor,
Keima
Kusunoki
Rieko
and Kanon, my classmate.
Mio
Rieko
Akari
Kusunoki
Keima
Akari
Two more of my classmates, Ayumi and Chihiro,
Rieko
Keima
Akari
Shiori
Yui
Akari
Keima
Ayumi
Sumire
Keima
Ayumi
Nagase
Keima
Ayumi
Mio
were clearly upset with me today, so they're suspect.
Tenri
Tsukiyo
Rieko
Keima
Ayumi
Shiori
Kusunoki
Sumire
Chihiro
Yui
Akari
Nagase
Nanaka
Kanon
Mio
Minami
Hinoki
I confirmed that Kusunoki in third year
Keima
had her memories wiped during my conquest of Hinoki.
Minami
And today I determined that Minami, who's a grade below me,
remembers nothing either.
In other words,
it's likely that no girls outside of
my own grade are host to goddesses.
Kusunoki
Tsukiyo
Kurakawa Akari also falls under that category.
The remaining girls on the right are also unlikely hosts,
given their low encounter rates.
Tenri
Tsukiyo
Rieko
Keima
Ayumi
Shiori
Kusunoki
Sumire
Chihiro
Yui
Akari
Nagase
Nanaka
Kanon
Mio
Minami
Hinoki
So I can disregard those to the
right of the line for this mission.
Tenri
Tsukiyo
Rieko
Keima
Ayumi
Sumire
Chihiro
Nanaka
Kanon
Mio
Hinoki
I also confirmed that Mio doesn't remember.
Which means that, including the suspicious ones, we have:
Ayumi, Chihiro, Tsukiyo, Shiori, and Yui.
Ayumi
Chihiro
Ayumi, Chihiro, Tsukiyo, Shiori, and Yui.
Tsukiyo
Shiori
Ayumi, Chihiro, Tsukiyo, Shiori, and Yui.
Yui
Those five must hold the four remaining goddesses.
All four remaining goddesses?
But aren't you just going off their relationships to you?
I may have had this all backwards.
Kanon
Chihiro
The goddesses need love to restore their power.
Ayumi
We've determined that two of them reside within my prior conquests.
Tenri
Perhaps I was chosen as a buddy
in order to help revive the goddesses.
My purpose is to provide the love that's required to awaken them.
Th-That's crazy...
If that's not the case,
then the one arranging this scenario
Narusawa TV 2F Entrance
sorely lacks in competence.
I can't keep up with all your leaps of logic!
I have but one week to complete my conquests.
I need only rely on what's most probable.
Time to go home.
Oh... See you tomorrow.
Haqua...
Starting today, you should stay with me.
H-Hold on...
No one else is there right now!
I can't be there alone with you!
We won't be alone.
Kanon's there.
Her condition hasn't changed.
She should be okay for now.
I see.
I've never seen Katsuragi so serious before.
How am I supposed to bring out the goddesses within this time limit?
Furthermore, once the goddesses are revealed,
Vintage will go after them.
I can't let anyone else end up like Kanon.
What can I do?
Is there anything I can do?
I have to be there for Katsuragi.
As I thought.
But that's...
Oh, you're taking a bath?
Perfect timing.
I've made my decision.
Haqua, I will cease to be a god.
I will...
become the gaming world's devil!
Goddess Search, Day 2
Ayumi.
Wh-What is it?
I don't care what anyone else thinks,
but I don't want you to get the wrong idea.
Huh?
Ayumi...
You're the one I...
A-Are you insane?!
You stupid idiot jerk!
Chihiro should be back soon.
She just went to the store
to get some of their new pork buns.
Time to move.
Why are you confessing your love to everyone?
If we simply revive the goddesses and nothing more,
Vintage will come after them.
Goddesses need love to fuel their power.
At the moment, the rumors about Kanon have the girls feeling down.
But when they overcome mishaps and misunderstandings like these,
their love parameters will skyrocket.
I need the girls to fall in love with me once more.
I have to reach their endings again
to give the goddesses back their powers.
But there are five potential hosts.
I'll just have to conquer them all at the same time.
At the same time?
You're disgusting!
Chihiro...
Well... I'm sorry.
Huh?
You're probably mad about Kanon.
No idea what you're talking about.
It's not what you think!
What?!
He's following this script to the letter.
I don't want you to get the wrong idea.
Chihiro...
Y-You're the one I...
Wait for Chihiro to react.
If she says something, move to the next line.
When you meet her
Oh, xxxx... Well... I'm sorry."
Her:  "(response)"
Wait for her to respond,
and make sure your eyes
Keima: "You're probably mad about Kanon
Otherwise, act embarrassed, and leave.
Wha... What's this?
How can you say that with a straight face?
If she treats it like a joke...
Get away from me, you cockroach.
You could at least vary your lines a bit.
Her anger hasn't subsided,
and I set up our next encounter.
Not a bad start.
I'll need your help with the next one.
Huh?
Walk home with either Chihiro or Ayumi,
and make sure they don't run into each other.
Ellie, wanna grab some cake before we go home?
S-Sure!
Astro
nomy
Club
Astronomy Club
Nothing has refuted my theory,
but nothing has proven it either.
It's easy to tell when Ayumi and Chihiro act differently from usual,
Astronomy Club
but it'll only get harder from here.
Luna, the next full moon isn't for a while,
so there's no point in looking at the sky.
Tsukiyo...
Sorry.
Are you upset about Kanon?
Who are you?
Does she not remember me?
Or is this how she shows her anger?
There's nothing between Kanon and me!
I don't know what you're talking about.
Who is Kanon?
Is it safe to assume she doesn't remember me?
What was that all about?
She's coming this way!
Over here!
That was so dumb.
I can't let them meet!
If this becomes a love rectangle,
it'll become harder to trigger the right flags.
What do you think you're doing, you animal?!
I never want to see your face again!
"I never want to see your face again."
That's not something you say to someone you've just met.
It's likely she remembers everything.
And she's definitely angry.
Tsukiyo is also suspicious.
Two more to go!
H-H-Here you are.
Cheers.
I'd like to borrow this.
S-Sure.
It's due back in two weeks.
I'd like to borrow this!
This Dating Sim
Is Amazing
She appears to remember me.
This Dating Sim
Is Amazing
The question is whether she still loves me.
This Dating Sim
Is Amazing
No matter.
Library girls can always be found in one place.
I can trigger events with her anytime.
Yo.
You're Katsuragi-kun, right?
Elsie's older brother?
I see you all the time during band practice.
I'm Goidou Yui, from class A. Nice to meetcha.
Y-Yui?
I wasn't expecting her to approach me.
She started off as a shy rich girl.
But it seems like our body switch,
due to the loose soul, may have influenced her.
Now she's turned into a confusing character: a girl who dresses like a boy.
Since there were lingering effects,
I assumed she was a likely host.
However, she's introducing herself,
which suggests she's completely forgotten me.
In other words...
Goodbye.
Yui isn't a host.
Hold up.
I wanna talk with you some more.
I wanna know more about you.
Wh-What is this feeling?
Is this a side effect of
Yui conquering me when I was a girl?
I love you!
Wh-What?
Male  Partners
I knew from the moment I saw you
that you were the one for me.
B-But...
Haven't you heard about Kanon and me?
I don't care about that.
R-Really?
Th-This is bad.
I can't think—
What do you two think you're doing?!
Elsie, don't we have band practice today?
Huh?
Chihiro and Ayumi didn't show up, either.
The Mai High Festival is coming up,
so we need all the practice we can get!
Th-That's right...
Well, I'll see you around, Katsuragi-kun.
Is that... Goidou Yui?
P-Plea—
Huh?
Please be quiet in the librarian!
"Librarian"?
Please eat this.
For Kami-nii-sama.
I'm leaving my cell phone here!
Elsie
She doesn't remember the conquest itself,
but her love is still in effect?
Since she confessed to me,
she's a potential host.
This sucks.
Then the five possible hosts are
Kujou Tsukiyo,
Goidou Yui,
Takahara Ayumi,
Kosaka Chihiro,
and Shiomiya Shiori.
Four of them are hosting goddesses.
That's right.
Incoming Call
Chihiro-san
Now Talking
Hey, Ellie. You called?
Hello?
Gah!
Katsuragi?
Why did you pick up?
Elsie can't come to the phone right now,
so I said I'd pass on a message for her.
What is it?
She said she wants to walk home with you tomorrow,
and to wait in the classroom after school.
What? Why?
No idea.
That's just what she said.
I don't get that at all, but fine. Bye.
Chihiro!
I'm sorry about today.
Katsuragi, what was that all about?
Preparation for tomorrow's
"leaving school simultaneously" event.
Huh?
I'm done looking for hosts.
It's time for the next stage.
Thank you very much!
Whenever we see each other
fukakute atsui itoshisa
my burning love only grows stronger
au tabi ni tsumoru no
like white feathers gathering on the ground
shiroi hane no you ni
We passed each other so many times
nandomo surechigatteita
where the roads of love and hate meet
suki kirai daisuki sukuranburu-kousaten
In the morning and during the day
asa mo hiru mo
At night and when I dream
yoru mo yume no
I always want to be with you
naka demo zutto soba ni itai
I want to protect you
anata wo mamoritai no
This is the first time I've felt like this
konna kimochi hajimete no kanjou
Even if you make the whole world your enemy,
sekai wo teki ni shitemo
I will be your only ally
watashi dake wa mikata de itai kara
I trust you
shinjiteru
You're good, but even you can't conquer five girls at once.
If you can't court multiple girls simultaneously, you can't play dating sims.
I'd like to say it's a cakewalk,
but in the real world, it takes time to move around.
Can't I just load from a save point?
You're just realizing this now?
Huh? What's this notebook?
Could you give that back?