They seem strange and alien.
Primitive and peculiar,
they are unlike any flora or fauna known to us.
From time immemorial,
men have feared these shapeless entities,
which came to be known as "mushi."
Mushi
Although the two once lived together in harmony, that faded with time,
as did the warmth of understanding...
and the precious light that came with it.
Mushi-Shi            Special Episode
Just one more month...
The Shadow that Devours the Sun
It's Doctor Adashino.
Whatcha looking at?
Hmm?
Oh, there's gonna be a solar eclipse one month from today.
What's a solar eclipse?
It's when the sun hides behind the moon.
Is it gonna be any fun?
Yeah.
It's gonna get dark around here for a while,
and according to my mushi-shi buddy,
the mushi should become really active.
So even those who can't normally see them may get a chance to.
That's why I'm kinda looking forward to it.
You never change, Doctor.
Be quiet.
Will that mushi-shi come by again?
I sent a letter inviting him, but he responded
saying he's gotta take care of something first.
Maybe he's busy 'cause
the mushi are gonna act up.
Maybe.
Who knows what he's up to?
Miss Tanyuu.
Yes?
These are the last of the
records we have on eclipses.
Thank you.
These are records of the behavioral changes
said to occur in mushi when the sun is eclipsed
as well as how to deal with those changes.
Many mushi favor the altered light and gain strength from it,
which thereby increases the number of
people under their influence.
These records mention the following incidents.
One: the formation of a pillar of mushi.
Mushi may gather to form a column.
One must not linger near the pillar lest they fall under its influence.
The pillar should disperse
not long after the eclipse passes.
Should it not disperse,
the mushi-sending ceremony should be performed.
Two: people with a fear of sunlight.
Following the eclipse,
there may be those who fear sunlight and no longer behave normally.
This is due to being possessed by
Yain, or "Night Shadow" mushi.
Curing them will require three tenths more than the normal amount of the mushi-purging drug.
Three: those who cannot sleep.
Some people may have damaged their eyes from
excessive exposure to the sun during the eclipse.
Their condition may persist even after sundown,
and they may be unable to sleep.
This anomaly is caused by
Shirayami, or "White Darkness" mushi.
The afflicted can be cured by continued exposure to the River of Light or to light emanated by mushi.
Four: people who vanish.
There may be those who
become invisible after the eclipse.
This condition is limited to those who
possess the innate ability to see mushi.
Those under the mushi's influence often wander into the mountains
and may reappear atop an elevated place.
It is also common for the afflicted to remain invisible forever.
If they manage to retain their form, the only cure is
to bring them back and treat them with great compassion.
However, many end up wandering
back to the mountains, never to return.
Did you discover something?
Yes. Most of the incidents in our records
were caused by well-known mushi,
so this eclipse shouldn't cause much confusion.
However, there is one
phenomenon that concerns me.
If it should come to pass,
it will prove troublesome if we
do not make appropriate preparations.
Indeed.
But as these are the only records that remain,
Hihami
it will be difficult to predict
where the phenomenon may occur.
It's finally time.
I hope I'll be able to see it despite the clouds.
In any case, that Ginko...
I ask him to teach me how to
capture mushi during the eclipse,
and instead, he just sends me these packets of medicine.
Doctor!
We told everyone that there'd be an eclipse soon and not to panic.
We also told them not to look at it for
too long, 'cause it could hurt their eyes.
I see.
Good job.
You kids better not look either.
What?!
But we really wanna!
Yeah!
On the other hand, I have these, so I can look all I want.
Hey!
That's not fair!
How come you get to?
Lemme see 'em!
C'mon! Give it to us!
Hey, don't break it!
Miss Tanyuu.
You should seek shelter in the cellar soon.
You need to protect yourself from the light.
I should be all right.
I'd like to see it for myself at least once.
Your health is of the utmost importance.
I understand.
I hope everyone will be okay.
Looks like it's starting.
Look! The sun!
It's missing a piece!
Whoa, it really is!
Thanks to the clouds, you can see it with the naked eye.
This is so frightening.
What are you talking about?
Something just like this happened when I was a boy.
Everything will be back to
normal before you know it.
It's so cold.
What are these?
Where are they?!
There. And there too.
Damn it!
I still can't see 'em!
The sun's completely gone.
Nah, it's only hidden.
The sun will be out again in no time.
But you kids should remember this fear.
After all, without the sun,
none of us can continue living.
Here it comes.
Wow! It's so warm!
Thank goodness!
Well, that was a surprise.
It certainly was.
Huh? What's that?
So it came?
What in the world is going on?
I've never seen anything like this before.
The sun's disappearing again.
Strange things are gathering near it, too.
Huh? What strange things?
Those strange things! They're floating up
and making that shadow bigger and bigger.
He's right.
Huh? I don't see anything.
Please, everyone, remain calm.
Just the other day, this man here—
What was your name, again?
I am Ginko, a mushi-shi.
Yesterday, he came to me
and told me that strange things
may occur here during the eclipse.
Today, what he said has come to pass.
Now, he needs all of your help to set this right.
At the center of the shadow obscuring
the sun is a Hihami, or "Sun Devourer" mushi.
It is calling smaller mushi to it and causing them to multiply, thus expanding the shadow.
Although a Hihami typically
remains hidden deep underground,
during an eclipse, it separates into a "core" and a "root,"
and its core ascends into the sky.
It is said that in order to vanquish it,
we must search the nearby grounds, find the Hihami's root,
and expose it to the sun.
However,
the exact location of the root is unknown.
All we can do is dig in areas
that feel different from usual.
How are we supposed to find
anything with a description like that?
Have you seen anything unusual?
I'm not sure.
Will you help him, everyone?
We can't just stand idly by.
How about splitting up and searching?
Anything?
Nah, nothing out of the ordinary.
Nothing here either!
I see.
Well, please continue searching.
We searched all day and didn't find a thing.
Yeah.
Well, maybe come tomorrow,
the sun will be back out like nothing happened.
Yeah, maybe.
Must be from Tanyuu.
The eclipse ended without incident here.
The mushi-shi that I sent to the areas
in which I suspected a Hihami might appear
have all reported that nothing was out of the ordinary in those areas.
How are things on your end?
You were right on the money.
Even though it's morning, it's still so dark.
It's a little depressing.
Hey, you find anything over there?
Nope, nothing.
Does this "root" even exist?
How many days has it been already?
We haven't found a damn thing.
I've had enough of this too.
Hey, you!
Tell us in detail what this
root of yours looks like!
Its location and appearance vary
each time it is mentioned in the records.
I know this must be unsettling,
but please remain calm and continue searching.
How can you possibly expect us to believe you?
We're done for.
Without the sun, all our
rice paddies and fields will dry up.
Unless we manage to stock up on food now,
none of us will survive the winter.
After losing something
central to their daily lives,
after losing something
they never thought they would,
what do people draw on for strength?
And in place of that original something,
what do they base their life around?
The shutters are closed,
even in this darkness?
The place doesn't seem abandoned, though.
White hair, pale skin, and pale eyes.
This must be...
Hiyori! What are you doing?!
It's still day!
But the sun's completely gone.
Now even I can go outside.
But, Hiyori!
Who are you?
Your hair...
Do you have the same sickness as me?
No clue.
I don't know why I look the way I do,
but I'm fine in the sunlight.
Oh.
Hiyori, are you sure you're okay outside?
I'm fine.
See?
Nothing's happening!
Oh, I know!
Come on, Hinata.
Let's go see that
meadow you told me about.
I can't.
Everything in our fields died,
so I have to go into town and sell something.
Hiyori!
What are you doing?!
Your marks are gonna come back!
Get back inside.
Do these "marks" look like black spots?
You're that mushi-shi the elder introduced to us.
What's it to you?
I've heard that the subspecies of mushi responsible for this eclipse can also cause symptoms like hers.
Can you cure her?
Unfortunately, a treatment has yet to be found.
Do you think you could tell me more?
I just remembered something from what you said earlier.
Back when my wife had just become pregnant with our daughters,
we saw something similar to the eclipse today...
except that time, it was the moon.
Look at the moon, dear.
As with this eclipse, the moon
disappeared right before our eyes.
I remember finding it strangely ominous.
Hey, what's wrong?
Are you all right?
I'm okay. I'm not sure
what just happened.
I felt faint all of a sudden.
My wife safely gave birth to our twin daughters,
but one of them was born with
white hair, pale skin, and pale eyes.
My wife never recovered after giving birth to them,
and she soon passed away.
What's the matter, Hiyori?
Please don't cry.
Hiyori had a high fever and was bedridden
until a few days later, when the marks disappeared.
However, the marks would reappear at the slightest exposure to sunlight,
so we had to keep the shutters closed during the day.
Since then, Hiyori has rarely left the house
and has spent most of her life in the back room.
The lunar eclipse you and your wife saw
must not have been a real lunar eclipse.
It was likely caused by a subspecies of Hihami
known as Tsukihami, or "Moon Devourer" mushi.
When an expectant mother is exposed to the light of a false lunar eclipse like that one,
her unborn child is drained of color.
Once the child is born, exposure to
sunlight causes marks resembling a burn.
In your case, one of your daughters
must have avoided the eclipse's influence
thanks to the other daughter shielding her from the light.
You protected me, Hiyori.
I will do my best to find a treatment for Hiyori.
In return, would it be possible to ask
for your help in ridding us of this eclipse?
How come I'm the only one who can't go out?
Hinata's allowed to!
Hiyori, you're unwell.
If you're exposed to sunlight, you could die.
Look! All the things you like are right here.
I don't want them!
I wanna go outside and play with Hinata!
Hiyori?
Look at this!
Wow, they're amazing!
This is so nice.
There are so many pretty things outside!
Hey, I found a place with lots of flowers.
It's a secret place that only I know of!
I'm sure it'll be fine if we
go there on a day the sun isn't out.
I'll take you there sometime!
'Kay!
It's so bright...
What's wrong?
I'm okay.
Hiyori! Your face!
I told you not to take her outside!
Why didn't you listen?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Hiyori.
Stop telling her stories
that make her want to go outside.
It will only make things harder for her.
Okay.
They're almost gone.
Yeah.
Hey, Hinata?
Can you pick me some flowers from that meadow?
Huh?
Oh, um...
Sorry. I forgot where it was.
I see...
Let's put these on her next!
'Kay!
Hinata!
Let's play!
Sorry.
I'll come some other time.
What?
But it's no fun without you!
Sorry about that.
You can go, you know.
But I like being with you more, Hiyori.
Liar.
You love playing outside.
That's...
Is it because you feel guilty since
you're the only one who can go out?
Is it because you feel sorry for me?
I don't want your pity.
But...
what should I do, then?
Trade places...
Trade places with me!
Is that... even possible?
If you can't,
just go away already.
When you're next to me,
I can't help but think that I
should've had a life like yours instead.
Hiyori? I'll leave your food here, okay?
Hiyori...
We'd like to talk to you.
It seems your condition is caused by something similar to what's causing the current eclipse.
But you don't know how to fix it, right?
I heard you two talking earlier.
I see.
But if we can fix the eclipse,
we might also find a way to make you better.
Hinata and I will go and help Ginko search.
I'm sorry to leave you here alone,
but it'll only be for a little while.
I wonder how long it's been
since I've walked outside during the day.
This feels great!
Wow, what a pretty bird.
I wonder what kind of bug this is.
Everyone looks so gloomy
just 'cause they can't be in the sunlight.
At least now they have some
sense of how I've felt all this time.
Serves them right.
I hope this eclipse never ends.
The meadow that Hinata
told me about should be this way.
Back then, I think we got about this far.
Afterward, Hinata carried me all the way home on her back.
That must've been really hard
on a mountain path like this one.
I can't find it.
Here it is!
So this is where it was.
They're so pretty.
I wonder what these flowers are called.
They're shining.
Wow!
It's just like Hinata said.
I wish we could've seen this together.
Hey, get him to be quiet already!
He's making me even more nervous.
He can't help that he's hungry!
You came outside again?
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
How did you get those?
"How?"
I found them.
There were so many. It was beautiful.
Those flowers don't usually bloom this time of year.
That could be where the Hihami's root is.
Can you tell me where you found them?
No.
If this eclipse is left unchecked,
the shadow will continue to grow.
The darkness will spread,
bringing with it a barren land
hospitable only to the mushi.
If we don't do something about it soon, there won't be anything we can do.
But I want things to stay this way!
You are human, just like everyone else.
You need to eat food.
You may not be able to tolerate direct sunlight.
You may hate the sun.
But you are able to live because of its light.
You are just like that mushi.
The Hihami can only come
to the surface during an eclipse.
Otherwise, it must hide deep underground.
Why do you suppose it comes to the surface?
There are mushi that spend their entire lives in darkness and have no need of light.
The Hihami may come to the surface
because it needs sunlight.
Perhaps it cannot live if it
always remains underground.
And yet, its root disappears
if exposed to that same light.
That's why its core creates a shadow
of mushi to protect its root from the sun,
even as the core itself basks in it.
You're the same, aren't you?
That's why you're happy even
in a world as dimly lit as this one.
However,
if you close yourself off just like
you were closed off in that room,
even this faint light will become engulfed by darkness.
One of your daughters
must have avoided the eclipse's influence
thanks to the other daughter shielding her from the light.
Trade places with me!
...just go away already.
I should never have been born, Hiyori.
Hiyori,
have you seen Hinata?
She's not back yet.
I'm gonna go look for her.
I hope nothing happened to her in the mountains.
Let's hope she wasn't influenced by the eclipse.
Occasionally, people vanish during an eclipse.
They sometimes become invisible to everyone except those who can see mushi.
You can see them, can't you?
Don't ask me.
I'm sure she'll be back soon.
Hinata!
Please respond!
It's already been three days.
Hinata, where are you?
You didn't really vanish, did you?
Where'd you go?
When I told you to go away,
I didn't really mean it!
What are we gonna do?
It never even crossed my mind that the sun could vanish.
Yeah...
I took for granted that it'd rise every day.
That's right.
Because I thought Hinata would always stay by my side,
I said all those horrible things to her.
To me,
Hinata was the sun.
And yet...
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Hinata.
Please come back!
Hinata, where are you?
Hinata!
I know!
I knew you'd be here!
Hinata, what's wrong?
I'm so sorry.
This is all my fault, isn't it?
I won't say mean things like that anymore.
So please!
Please go back to being the cheerful,
kind sister you were when we were little!
Ginko!
I found Hinata!
She's already become invisible to the human eye.
Ginko, how can we get Hinata to go back to her old self?
For starters, we need to end the Hihami eclipse.
That should scatter the mushi and lessen their influence.
The rest will depend on you staying by her side
and talking to her as much as you can.
This is it!
The root is probably under these flowers.
Please start digging right away!
I think I hit something.
Dig here!
What the heck is this?
That's it.
Now we just have to get it to a place where the sun's still shining.
Heave-ho!
Careful!
The sun's shining on that hill.
We've gotta take it over there.
Got it!
Damn it!
We're already past the hill!
How come we're still
under that thing's shadow?
The shadow must be chasing us.
Let's try to pick up the pace!
Okay!
I wonder how the men are doing.
I hope they're okay.
Look!
Hey, look!
The light!
Hiyori! The sun's back!
That's great!
Yeah...
We can get our lives back on track.
It doesn't feel bright anymore.
Hiyori?
What are you...
Dad, what's happened to me?
Even though I'm in the sun,
I'm perfectly fine!
Just a bit farther.
Just a little more till we're out of the shadow!
Sunlight!
Get the lid off!
It vanished.
Hey, look at the sun.
The shadow's going away too.
Hooray! Hooray!
Phew...
We made it.
That's...
Ginko!
Hiyori?
Hmm...
The Hihami's light is typically comprised of wavelengths
that have an ill effect on one's mind and body,
but they seem to have beneficial effects on those affected by the Tsukihami.
That may explain it.
I see.
Well then, I guess you no longer need this.
It's a shard of the Hihami's core.
It's powerful and able to increase vitality.
I thought that it could help humans too.
Can I give it to Hinata instead, then?
Why not?
You don't want it?
Given how responsive she is,
it's only a matter of time
before she goes back to normal.
Just stay by her side until that happens.
Okay, I understand.
It's my turn to shine on Hinata.
Now, what should I do with this?
Oh, you're finally here, huh?
It doesn't seem like your wish came true.
It didn't!
I didn't get to see a single mushi!
It began and ended just like any old eclipse,
and it was over in a flash!
Nothing out of the ordinary happened!
That's good to hear.
It's best when nothing unusual happens.
Well, I guess you have a point there.
You didn't notice a slight increase in patients?
Now that you mention it...
After the eclipse, some people were afraid of sunlight,
and others said they couldn't sleep.
And? Are they better now?
Well, I gave them medicine,
but it hasn't had much of an effect.
You didn't read my letter, did you?
Their symptoms are caused by mushi.
They'll get better once you
give them the medicine I sent you.
You stay put and wait for me.
When I get back, I wanna hear
what you were up to during the eclipse!
Nah, I've gotta get going.
What?!
There's someone else I should tell that story to first.
You could at least tell me some of it. Just wait for me!
Some other day.
Miss Tanyuu, you have a letter from Ginko.
The incident appears to have been safely resolved.
I see.
He plans to come here soon and tell you about it.
He also has something he'd like to show you.
"Soon," he said?
His words are never very reliable.
Well...
I am patient.
Looks like I slept a bit too long.
Up we go.
Ah, what a fine day.
Let's hope nothing unusual happens today.
Mushi-Shi: The Next Chapter.
Mushi-Shi: The Next Chapter
April 2014