Kiss!
What?!
Wai—Wh-What are you saying?!
What do you mean?
Oh!
N-No, that's not what I meant!
I was saying you should kiss Manaka-san!
What?! Either way, why should I do that?
Because it could help her wake up!
You're making no sense!
And what's a k-kiss got to do with anything?
I already explained it!
That's not an explanation!
Hii-kun!
You shouldn't yell at girls like that!
Shut up! It's all 'cause she—
Huh?
Who are you?
Hii-kun.
M-Mom...
Mom!
furitsumoru konayuki ga mau
Little snowflakes dance in the air
akiramekaketa yume ga mata namiutsu
I'd almost given up on my dream, but it washes in again,
ano hi no mama de
like it did so long ago
kawaranai egao mitsumeta
I watched your frozen smile,
somaru hoho ni fureta kaze ga
and the wind turning my cheeks red
sora takaku nuketa
disappeared high into the sky
I was always looking at you, never far away,
and yet you seemed out of my reach.
doushite
Why?
to toikaketa koe mo yureru
Even your voice is rough as it asks me
yurayura minamo ni ukanda
The moon's reflection quivered on the waters,
tsuki wa nanimo kataranai
and it told us nothing about the future
tada no boukansha
The moon merely watched us
onaji ne nigiru te ga itai
We hold hands even though it hurts
Episode
Twenty-One
The Messenger
from the Bottom of the Sea
Bye!
You're going out, Miuna?
Huh, she already left.
What's with her?
She's not coming with us?
She left in a pretty big hurry.
Hii.
Hii-kun, wait!
Don't leave without me.
Why would I do that?
See ya.
I wanna come...
We'll see you later.
We're only going out for a bit, okay?
I wanna come!
Hikari, don't push Manaka-chan too much, okay?
I won't.
And don't go dragging her around.
You have that habit of always running ahead of her.
I won't.
And if she starts feeling tired or sick—
All right already.
Manaka-chan, make sure you ask Hikari to do whatever you need him to, okay?
'Kay.
Namaka, I wanna come!
I know it's been a while, so take your time and have lots of fun today.
Akira, you're staying home with Mommy.
Namaka!
Namaka! I wanna come!
We'll be back soon, okay?
Namaka! Namaka!
Namaka!
He sure does like you a lot.
He likes me?
Come on.
'Kay.
Saya Mart
For real?
Finally together again, huh?
Huh?
The Four from Shishio.
It's great she woke up.
It ain't quite the same unless you guys are all together.
So anyway, here's a present for you.
Eat up.
See ya!
Tell Mukaido I said hey!
Oh.
There are five in here.
We're going to have one left over.
Chii-chan!
Kaname!
Manaka...
Chii-chan, it's cold today, isn't it?
We haven't seen each other in so long, and that's the first thing you say?
Huh?
But it really is cold.
And it's supposed to be summer, too.
I suppose you're right, but still...
It's too weird.
I know, right?
No, not that.
I mean, normally people would be more surprised,
especially considering how much some of us have grown up.
What do you mean?
Chii-chan's the same as always, isn't she?
Tsumugu's not coming?
He has to do field work today.
So he's on top of the ice, huh?
Wanna go see him?
He's busy, isn't he?
We can see him another time.
Hey, more importantly,
let's all go to the harbor!
S-Sure.
Come on, let's go!
Okay...
Sorry about this, Sayu.
My body suddenly got all crackly.
It's freezing!
No worries.
So when your Ena gets dried up, it gets crackly?
I don't know if it's quite "crackly." It's also sort of hard to breathe.
This is the first time it's happened.
Well, it sounds like a real pain.
Didn't Hikari and everyone else
tell you about it?
They did, but...
You should've just gone with them today.
Hikari invited you, didn't he?
I can't go with them.
Why not?
I don't have the right.
The right?
The right to do what?
I guess... the right to go.
Of course you do!
How could you say that after you did all that research?!
What's with you?
You're not happy Manaka-san woke up, are you?
I am too!
The moment it happened...
I thought to myself, "She finally woke up,"
and I was even happy that I was happy about it.
But something was off.
It was different from how I thought it would be.
I have no clue what you're saying.
It's just...
I don't know how I'm supposed to talk to her.
You should see the look on your face!
Jeez...
Take this!
It's cold!
Hey! I don't have any Ena, you know!
Wow!
It really is frozen.
You could already see that from the house, you know.
Huh?
Still, when you see it up close,
it's really surprising.
Right, Chii-chan?
The Boatdrift Ceremony was just the other day for you, wasn't it?
Yup.
Whoa!
What now?
Look at all the saltflake snow!
There wasn't this much before.
Yeah, that's true.
It's like playing "Spot the Difference" or something.
"Spot the Difference"?
Yeah.
So cold!
Each time I close my eyes
and then open them,
I spot things that are different from before.
Saltflake snow here.
Saltflake snow there!
Saltflake snow everywhere!
What the heck? You're only pointing out the saltflake snow, aren't you?
Manaka!
What are you doing?
Hii-kun.
Hii-kun's being nice!
Wha—I've always been nice!
Hii-kun, your face is red!
Shut up!
Save me, Chii-chan!
Hey, there's saltflake snow over there too!
Manaka, you shouldn't run like that!
It sort of makes you wonder why we tried so hard, doesn't it?
Huh?
I mean, even without Uroko-sama's help,
Manaka woke up all on her own.
Yeah, it all worked out.
I suppose you could say that,
but it's sort of anticlimactic too...
what with the way she's acting.
Manaka!
Yeah, she's so full of energy...
Chii-chan, look!
even though she only woke up yesterday.
How did you act, Hikari?
Huh?
When you first woke up.
Personally, I was scared.
Although the town looked familiar,
everything was just a little off.
I thought to myself, "If everywhere looks the same,
but I don't know a single person,
what am I going to do?"
I was terrified.
I just can't take seeing any more things that have changed!
I don't wanna think about all of this!
I don't even wanna know about 'em!
Whee!
I don't really get how she can laugh so much.
It's because you're here, Hikari.
Huh?
And so are we.
And I was so sure she'd wanna go see him first.
You know, she says she can't remember.
Wake up, Manaka
Hey...
Right before the Boatdrift Ceremony, you—
No. I mean, what happened after the Boatdrift Ceremony?
You got pulled down to the bottom of the sea.
What happened after that?
Um...
I think... I heard someone's voice—
A voice?
Whose was it? Was it Uroko-sama's?
It wasn't Uroko-sama's voice.
Was it the sea god?
Maybe...
Did you see him?!
Did you meet him?
I can't remember.
I think he said he'd give me something
or he asked me to give him something...
What'd he ask for?
I can't remember.
Wait! Manaka, wait!
Even the school is...
covered in saltflake snow!
Whoa, it's so fluffy!
She doesn't have Ena anymore.
She can't ever go back to the sea now.
So how can she be like this?
Hikari!
It's true, though.
How can she...
Because she's still Manaka.
Yeah.
You're right.
This side's mine!
Hey! Okay, I'll help.
Nope! You can't step on this side anymore!
Here, here, here, and here are all mine!
No! You can't have all of it!
What are you doing over there?
Huh?
Huh? You guys...
What the heck?
Why are you at school on a Sunday?
Look who's talking. What are you doing here?
Well?
S-Studying!
What?
We decided to study for our exams.
Didn't you know? Finals are next week.
Why'd you have to go and bring that up?
Studying is important, you know!
Yeah, very important.
What are you guys studying?
In math, we're learning about simultaneous equations.
And in English, we're learning about conjunctions and verbal nouns.
Wow, I'm really bad at both of those.
Man, talk about a buzzkill.
You know, besides simple arithmetic,
math is pretty useless anyway.
Right on cue, the excuse of a true idiot.
Yeah, I'm in total agreement.
What?
I think studying is important too.
I don't wanna hear that from you!
Huh?
Studying's important! Right, Chii-chan?
Yeah, it's much better to study properly.
See?
It'll be too late to regret it later.
It'll be too late!
Oh, I have to start heading to the hospital.
What are you going there for?
Tsumugu's grandfather isn't well.
Huh?!
Well, he's pretty old now,
and a lot has happened.
Oh, I nearly forgot.
Eat these.
Sayama-kun gave them to us.
Salted Cream Puffs
A Good Source of Minerals! Made with Salt from Oshiooshi!
Just enough for each of us!
Chisaki-san's so nice!
Yeah!
Who wants one?
Me! Miuna, you want one too, right?
Yeah.
Me too!
We all want one!
Public
Hospital
I didn't think you'd be here yet.
Oh, um... I had a little time.
What about you?
Yeah, me too.
I finished up early.
You should've gone to see Manaka, then.
I thought that she might get overwhelmed if she saw too much.
What's that all about?
How is she?
She's good.
I couldn't get over how full of energy she was.
She said she'd come visit us soon, too.
I see.
Want a tangerine?
Oh, sure.
There's coffee jelly in there too.
You were awake?
Gramps remembered my two favorite foods.
It's nice and sweet.
I might like this even more than cream puffs.
Why'd you bring up cream puffs?
Just 'cause.
At the end of the month,
I have to head back to campus.
The university is getting on the professor's case to put together our data and conclusions.
I see.
When will that be?
I just said the end of this month.
What's wrong?
I screwed up.
It tastes really sour because I ate that sweet jelly first.
I'll be sure to send tangerines to your apartment, okay?
Eat them with all the people in your lab.
Okay.
It's not that far, you know.
I know.
I'll come back as soon as I can.
Okay.
And I'll call, too.
And if I find some new information, I'll let you know immediately.
What is it, Tsumugu? You gonna be lonely?
It's not me I'm worried about. It's you.
Wh-What are you talking about?
I'm busy too, you know!
Are you sure you're okay?
Of course I am!
Everyone's back now.
And I'll have to keep an eye on Manaka, too.
She can be so helpless.
Manaka really hasn't...
So you don't need to worry about such trivial things, Tsumugu.
Just focus on your research at your lab, okay?
We need you and Professor Mihashi to figure all this out, you know.
There's still so much that we don't know.
Although Manaka woke up and Hikari and Kaname seem fine,
there's so much we don't understand.
We don't know what will happen to the sea or the surface,
or to the weather or the tide.
If only we could ask Uroko-sama.
Uroko-sama? Why him?
Because he seems to know
everything about the sea.
You think so?
I have a feeling he'd just say something random and useless.
But he's a scale of the sea god.
Supposedly.
Supposedly, huh?
Besides, I don't know if he'd tell us anything even if we found him.
He's always so perverse,
not to mention perverted.
Maybe we could bribe him.
Bribe him? With money?
Nah. Maybe with porn mags.
What are you—
Actually, that might work.
That really just might work.
I knew it.
Sorry I'm late.
Welcome back.
Perfect timing.
What? How come?
Well, I won't insist if you guys really can't come, but...
Dadda! Where's Dadda?
All right, I'll spend the night here.
Akira, be careful.
Dadda's working late tonight.
Hey, you can't put the fish in like that.
Huh?
It's fine. The flavor comes out better this way.
What'd Tsumugu say?
It seems neither of them can make it.
What?
That's too bad.
Why not?
Crab!
No touching the crab, Akira. It's very hot.
Something came up with Tsumugu's grandfather. They apologized.
Chii-chan must be really busy.
Tsumugu is too.
Yeah, both of them actually study.
What the heck's that supposed to mean?
You make it sound like I don't—
You never study.
Yeah, and the entrance exams are coming up.
Man, maybe I should go and hibernate again.
Don't say stupid things like that.
Sayu-chan, help Hikari with his studies, will you?
I hear you're at the top of the class!
Oh... Sometimes.
It's not sometimes. It's all the time.
That's really amazing.
Not really.
Anyway, everyone's applying for Hama High School, right?
Yeah, it's not as though
Shishio has a high school.
Ugh, I like things the way
they are now, though.
Here's your crab, Akira.
Blow on it a lot before you eat it, okay?
Akira!
Does it still feel hot?
No...
Are you okay? It doesn't hurt anywhere?
No... I'm cold.
Jeez...
Sorry about that, guys.
He's all right now.
Is all this because the sea god is angry?
Manaka!
Come with me for a sec.
Huh? Why?
Just come on.
Hii-kun?
Hii-kun, what's wrong?
Are you mad about something?
You said you had something to tell me
after the Boatdrift Ceremony.
The Boatdrift Ceremony...
I'll tell you when it's over.
Tell me now.
What was it you were gonna say?
Why are you making such a scary face?
Was it about Tsumugu?
Huh?
It's about Tsumugu, isn't it?!
What are you talking about?
Hii-kun?
Good morning.
Huh?
Oh... it's you, Tsumugu-kun.
You're here early.
Can I please talk to Mukaido?
Good morning...
What's everyone doing up so—
Huh?
Tsumugu, what is it?
Fishy!
Tsumugu-kun, isn't that...
I was cursed by Uroko-sama.
A curse?
He's the type of person
that puts curses on people.
Though I dunno if I'd call him a "person."
But this means...
Uroko's somewhere close by.
mugon no kotoba de ayatori shite
I play a silent cat's cradle with my words,
jouzu ni dekita to warattemiru
and decide to grin in satisfaction
tokui na no wa dare ni mo kizukarenu you ni
The only thing that I am truly good at
kokoro oshikorosu koto sore hitotsu dake
is stifling my love so others won't find out
demo torimaku kirei na loop wa
It would be nice
yawai chikara de
if the love of those around me
taguriyosetekureru kara
drew me in gently
azayaka ni
Innocently
musunde kono kimochigoto
I tie my feelings into a rope
hanarenai you ni kataku kataku
so that we will never be apart
hitomusubi hito wo musunde
The knots tie us together,
kitai no yamanai saki he asu he yukou
so let us approach the future with hope in our hearts
You pushed a lady, and now you're just gonna leave her?!
I told you not to come, didn't I?!
It's no good...
Maybe I should try asking her out again.
Episode Twenty-Two
Something Lost
Asking her out, huh...