Pardon me.
Could you please tell me the date today?
We're home.
Miuna! Hikari!
Huh? What's wrong?
Kaname woke up!
Where is he right now?
He's at the fishery cooperative.
Akari, I can watch Akira,
so you can take Hikari and—
Hikari!
Kaname?!
Wait up, Hika—
Hey. Good morning.
furitsumoru konayuki ga mau
Little snowflakes dance in the air
akiramekaketa yume ga mata namiutsu
I'd almost given up on my dream, but it washes in again,
ano hi no mama de
like it did so long ago
kawaranai egao mitsumete
I watch your frozen smile,
somaru hoho ni fureta kaze ga
and the wind turning my cheeks red
sora takaku muketa
disappears high into the sky
I was always looking at you, never far away,
and yet you seemed out of my reach.
doushite
Why
kou toikaketa koe mo yureru
Even your voice is rough as it asks me
yurayura minamo ni ukanda
The moon's reflection quivered on the waters,
tsuki wa nanimo kataranai
and it told us nothing about the future
tada no boukansha
The moon merely watched us
hora boku nigezu ni tada itai
I want to stay here with you
Episode Seventeen
The Sick Two
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
Kaname?
So you really did stay up here on the surface.
Kaname...
You look well, Chisa—
It's been a while, Kaname.
Tsumugu?
Yeah.
Kaname? Is something wrong?
It's nothing.
Good morning, Chisaki, Tsumugu.
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
To be honest, I don't quite remember.
When I came to,
I was being carried by the current.
Does that mean you don't know how the others are doing?
Yeah.
Manaka...
Did you notice anything else?
Now that you mention it,
I think I may have heard a strange sound.
Huh?
A sound? What kind of sound?
It sounded a bit like sand flowing.
I didn't hear anything like that.
I heard it too.
When?
Today when I accidentally fell into the sea.
I heard it then.
What happened? Are you okay?
Apparently, she can swim now.
What?
Yeah, it wasn't hard for me to breathe at all.
You could breathe underwater?
It seemed like it.
If I recall correctly, your mother was from Shioshishio, wasn't she?
Her birth mother was, yes.
I see.
Does that mean something?
Not necessarily. I'm probably just overthinking things.
But if it's all right with you, I'd like to talk to your daughter again sometime.
Okay...
Well then, Tsumugu,
that should be enough for today.
Okay.
Thanks, Kaname.
You've been a big help.
I'm not sure I was of any help at all.
It was plenty, I assure you.
First Hikari came back,
and now you've returned as well.
It may not be long before everyone else in Shioshishio wakes up too.
Really? Does that mean we'll be able to get into Shishio soon?
We can't say for sure,
but I believe that in order to fully understand the various weather phenomena of the last few years,
we must first go to the village of Shioshishio.
To that end, we've collected quite a bit of data.
It shouldn't be long now.
We look forward to it!
I wanna know if Dad, Manaka, and the others are safe.
It'd probably be better not to forcefully awaken those who are still asleep.
There's still a lot that we don't know.
I know that.
Are you okay, Kaname?
Yes.
Or rather, none of this feels quite real yet.
Well, a lot has changed,
so you're probably just in shock.
That's true.
But...
there are also things that haven't changed.
Distribution of
My Keepsakes
Kaname
gloves + four-leaf clover
I found near Miuna's house
Long-Hair Lady
sea-slug pendant
Boob Lady
dolphin pencil board
Good girl.
Precious
Notebook
Sayu! Miuna's on the phone!
Okay!
Make yourself comfortable.
Thanks.
So you really are living here, Chisaki.
Didn't I say so?
When you guys came to the fishery
cooperative together, I was a bit surprised.
So I may have jumped to conclusions.
You dummy.
Come on. Make yourself at home.
Right. Thank you.
You'll have to share a room with Mihashi.
That's perfectly fine.
The tea will be ready in just a moment.
Huh?
Here you go.
My pajamas should be okay for you, right?
I laid them out already.
Kaname, yours are the blue ones.
Okay.
You okay?
Huh? What do you mean?
Well, Mihashi is here too,
so I thought there might be a lot to do.
I'm perfectly fine.
I see.
Now then,
another student from Shioshishio woke up yesterday.
We heard! Isaki, right?
He's good-looking, isn't he?
Yup, and totally cool.
Hold up!
Weren't you guys just saying I was
"totally cool" when I wore the happi coat?
Is Isaki going to join this class too?
When is he coming?
Hey, are you guys ignoring me?!
Man...
Just when I decided I'd live alone for the rest of my life,
he goes and wakes up all of a sudden.
I know...
But...
I know. You're happy anyway, right?
When we were younger,
I always just admired him from afar.
Even when we were together,
it always felt like he was so far away.
And the closer I got to him,
the further away he felt.
What's with you?
Oh...
I was just thinking that you were
feeling exactly like I was back then.
But now, we may be able
.to reach them, you know.
Things have changed.
Hey, why don't we go see Kaname?
Huh?
After he's gotten the chance to settle down a bit, I mean.
Oh, b-but...
Sayu!
Oh, r-right.
I wonder if things really haven't changed...
See ya.
Let's give it our all, Sayu.
Yeah.
Give what your all?
It's a secret.
That's pretty rude.
I'll give it my all.
Come here.
Yo, Kaname!
I heard you were back!
You haven't changed a bit, of course!
Um, could you be...
What? Can't you tell?
It's me, Sayama. From Saya Mart.
Oh, it is you.
Once you get settled in,
let's all catch up sometime.
Well, see ya later!
Oh, uh...
I guess you don't recognize me...
Um...
Could that have been...
Kaname?
Is something wrong?
It's nothing...
Is school enjoyable?
Yeah, more or less.
I never knew you wanted to be a nurse.
Well, I didn't give it much thought until recently.
So it happened while I was sleeping...
Did you do anything interesting today?
I thought I'd go out and take a look around...
at what has changed, and what hasn't.
Have you changed, Chisaki?
Well, I did age five years.
That doesn't matter.
I like older women.
What the heck?
What about you, Kaname?
I love you, Chisaki.
I have for a long time.
Have you changed, Kaname?
Not in the least.
I was sleeping, after all.
That's true...
There's no way I'd change.
A few days after Kaname came back...
Huh?
Miuna has Ena?
After close examination,
we've confirmed that she possesses an extra membrane that is approximately fifty microns thick.
Although we can't say for sure just yet,
this membrane has all the characteristics of Ena.
But I thought kids with one parent from the sea and the other from land don't have Ena.
I thought so too.
This is my first time seeing a case like this one.
If possible, I'd like to examine Akira once too.
I still can't wrap my head around it.
Hey, quit touching me.
Still, I sure am surprised that Miuna has Ena.
Miu has Ena?
Yeah, just like I do.
She's the same as me.
Ena, Ena!
Good morning.
Good morning!
What's wrong?
What do you mean?
You seem sort of down.
I'm fine.
I see.
When did you want to go see Kaname?
I'm not going.
Huh?
Sayu...
I wonder where she disappeared to.
Miuna!
Let's go home.
Sorry, but could you go ahead without me?
Man...
I don't get girls at all.
Seriously.
I finally decided to come back
to school and check things out,
but it looks like things haven't...
Oh!
They kept it around so it would be here when we got back.
Miuna and everyone else
have been keeping it clean for us.
Really?
Speaking of, Miuna's grown up quite a bit.
Not so much on the inside, though.
Whatever you say.
I'm serious.
I understand where you're
coming from, though.
On the outside, she does
look like she's changed.
So much has changed,
and at the same time, so much hasn't.
Honestly, it's pretty overwhelming.
Are you, by chance,
trying to cheer me up?
Well, I am your senior, since I went and woke up before you.
You've grown up too, Hikari.
Shut up!
I had tried to prepare myself...
ever since I heard we'd have to go to sleep.
But now that it's actually happened, it's harder than you thought, huh?
You really have changed, Hikari.
Even though you woke up
right before I did, you've changed a lot.
You think so?
Yeah.
If you could change so much in such a short time,
I can't imagine how much has changed in five years.
I see.
You might be right.
In that case, I won't change any more.
'Cause if I do,
Manaka might get too shocked
once she wakes up.
I mean, now that you've woken up,
she might soon too.
When she does, she probably won't
have changed at all since back then.
She'll probably still like Tsumugu, too.
But even so, I'm not gonna change.
No matter what.
Hikari...
Sayu!
Do Not Enter
I thought it was finally possible to get a little closer...
...but we're still so far away.
Man...
I guess I'm on my own after all.
But you know, nothing ever comes from childhood crushes anyway.
I'm bound to forget these feelings one day.
You really think so?
Absolutely.
Though I may try to be tough and independent,
I'll probably come to like some other guy eventually.
Or maybe I'll wind up with someone I don't like,
just to avoid being lonely.
That's just how things are.
Feeling the same way about
the same person after all these years...
It's ridiculous!
That's just something
out of a manga or a drama.
I can't believe I've felt this way
for five whole years.
I've been so self-absorbed.
It's gross and pathetic and horrible...
I must be sick!
That's...
That's not true!
Yes, it is!
Is not!
Is too!
I've made up my mind.
I'm not going to change.
Huh?
I don't care if I'm sick or if I seem
like some character out of a manga.
Even if it's gross,
even if it's pathetic,
I'm not going to change!
I refuse to!
You refuse to change? Are you kidding?
Come on, Miuna. You're not making any sense.
What's this? Are you on your own today too?
Come here.
I guess you still won't come near me—
Sayu.
Wh-Who are you?
It's been a while, Sayu.
Uh, um...
Y-Yeah! It has been a while!
Then again, maybe it hasn't exactly been a while. For you, I mean—
You haven't changed.
Oh, sorry.
We're the same age now.
I'm sick too.
Hikari! Hold on!
Sorry!
Wait, where are you going, Hikari?
There could be a way for me
to get into Shioshishio!
Jeez...
The key is the sound that Isaki
and Shiodome said they heard.
I believe that the sound might
be caused by an unknown current.
Keeping that in mind,
we rewatched the video footage
from our underwater expeditions
and were able to pinpoint that current,
which seems weaker than those nearby.
The current originates
from somewhere around here.
It's right where the village
of Shioshishio should be.
This current may be the first sign that
the power encasing the village is failing.
So all we have to do to get to the village
is get through that current?
Right now, this is all just theory.
In other words, we won't know
for sure until we actually try, right?
Right.
Which is why we wanted to
ask you and Hikari to help us out.
Of course we will!
Just leave it to us!
Sure, I'll help, but...
you said that that sound
is the key to all this, right?
Hikari's going back to Shioshishio...
Right, though we don't yet
know exactly what it means.
To the world he used to live in.
Kaname, you heard that sound, right?
Then, I'll leave it to you to lead us.
I didn't hear it that clearly, though.
Really? What are we gonna do, then?
To where Manaka is.
I want to help too!
I heard the sound clearly.
I'm sure I'll be able to hear it again!
You said I have Ena, didn't you?
Then I should be okay in the sea, right?
That may be true, but...
Miuna!
I know you want to help,
but won't it be dangerous for you?
Your Ena's not really complete.
I know...
Why don't we let her?
Kaname and I will be with her, after all.
There'll be nothing to worry about.
We're counting on you, Miuna.
Okay!
Are you sure it's all right if I don't go?
Yeah, it's fine.
See you later.
The water temperature's pretty low.
Don't underestimate our Ena!
We'll be just fine.
If anything unexpected happens, come back right away.
Okay.
Here we go!
Is it too cold?
It's fine.
You sure you can breathe okay?
Yeah.
I practiced a lot before today.
Still, make sure you don't
push yourself, all right?
All right.
So can you hear that sound right now?
I don't hear anything.
Me neither.
I hear it.
I can hear it!
This way!
Hey, wait up, Miuna!
To a world completely unknown to me...
To the mysterious world Hikari is from.
mugon no kotoba de ayatori shite
I play a silent cat's cradle with my words,
jouzu ni dekita to warattemiru
and decide to grin in satisfaction
tokui na no wa dare ni mo kizukarenu you ni
The only thing that I am truly good at
kokoro oshikorosu koto sore hitotsu dake
is stifling my love so others won't find out
demo torimaku kirei na loop wa
It would be nice
yawai chikara de
if the love of those around me
taguriyosetekureru kana
drew me in gently
azayaka ni
and free of blemish
musunde kono kimochigoto
I tie my feelings into a rope
hanarenai you ni kataku kataku aa
so that we will never be apart
hitomusubi hito wo musunde
The knots tie us together,
kitai no iu mama ni saki he asu he yukou
so let us approach the days to come with hope
We're home.
This is Shioshishio.
What are you so afraid of?
This is the world I don't know.
This isn't how it's supposed to be.
We're in the sea.
I wanted to show her...
The Shioshishio that I dreamed of...
Episode Eighteen
Shioshishio
our Shioshishio.