I love you, Chisaki.
I have for a long time.
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Eleven
The Changing Times
Um, uh...
Here.
Thanks.
I'm sorry for causing a stir so early in the morning.
I just confessed my feelings to your daughter.
Oh my...
How polite.
It's not that I want a reply.
I just couldn't let it remain unsaid.
Remain unsaid?
Come on.
If you don't hurry, we're going to be late.
R-Right.
What's wrong?
You're keeping your distance.
I-I'm fine!
Really? Okay, then.
Looking back at it now,
I think that Kaname and Chisaki were acting a little strange that day.
But at the time,
my mind was filled with thoughts of our
upcoming hibernation, the Boatdrift Ceremony,
and most of all, Manaka.
And I think Manaka had
the same things on her mind.
That's why Manaka and I could never have caught on to those two at the time.
Hey.
You're late!
Good morning!
The fact was that, in the few days that followed,
the world around us changed
at an unbelievable pace.
Day in, day out,
the saltflake snow continued to fall.
Before we knew it, our village had turned completely white,
like somewhere from a snowy country.
Meanwhile, the preparations for our sleep continued on.
Closed to Prepare
for the Sleep
Everyone stopped eating,
and their Ena got thicker and thicker.
At first, it was hard to imagine that we'd actually fall asleep one day,
but that day crept closer and closer until it was right in front of us, undeniably real.
On the surface, the saltflake snow had only fallen once more,
but that summer was much colder then usual,
and I think everyone started to work a little more seriously because of it.
But...
According to Lord Uroko,
at the rate our Ena are progressing,
we will most likely fall into
our sleep on the 21st.
Wha—
Men's Club
The 21st?
That's the day of the Boatdrift Ceremony!
So on the day of the festival,
we'll be waving goodbye to
everyone on the surface.
They can all just cool off for a bit in the snow.
Those ungrateful, thick-headed jerks!
Well, I think we're the thick ones right now, with our Ena and all.
True, that.
Men's Club
Still...
The guys on the surface right now might not even be there anymore when we wake up.
Thanks for the meal.
Is something wrong?
I'll be going now.
Have a good day.
How are you feeling?
Same as usual, really.
It might be because I've been out of the ocean for so long,
but I haven't been affected like the others.
I should hold off going on any diets for a while, though.
Marriage Registration
Here. I filled it out.
Husband-to-be
Wife-to-be
Name
(Pronunciation)
Sakishima Akari
Is this what you really want?
Please accept me, to have and to hold, despite my faults.
P-Please accept me too.
Oh, and about the ceremony...
What do you want to do?
I was thinking there's probably no need.
Given our situation,
I doubt my dad would attend even if I invited him.
Yeah, but...
don't you think that's exactly why we should have a proper ceremony?
I'm sure your dad would like to see you as a bride as well.
So let's think about it.
We should have a ceremony that fits us,
and I'm not ready to give up yet on getting your dad's blessing.
All right, Itaru.
This country originally had a humid, temperate climate.
It was best known for the changes in weather that came with the seasons,
which were brought about by what we call the seasonal winds.
And...
Sounds like it's time.
You four can go ahead.
It's not even midday yet.
Our Ena's fine.
These instructions came straight from Shioshishio, though.
We should respect them.
Your hibernation is thought to be a biochemical reaction
brought about by a combination of environmental factors.
However, it hasn't happened for centuries, so we're not sure.
But Teach, we're fine—
Huh?
Seriously?
See?
Your Ena's become thicker,
and it needs water more often.
Don't dawdle, now.
Damn it!
Dry as a bone already.
We really are going to sleep.
You don't want to?
I've been thinking.
Even when we go to sleep at the same time each night,
we often wake up at different times, right?
So are we all really gonna be able to wake up at the same time?
Isn't everyone going to sleep together and waking up together?
There's no guarantee.
After our hibernation, not only will the surface be different, but so will we.
The only time we can be sure we'll spend together is right now.
It's a fleeting thing.
What did you guys want to do about lunch?
Teach said I should ask you just in case.
You really do have amazing timing, Tsumugu.
I'm gonna eat.
Y-You'll get in trouble.
Like I care!
I'm not just gonna quietly go to sleep
when we don't even know
what'll happen afterward!
Manaka!
I...
I'm going to eat too!
I mean... I don't want all that to happen.
I don't want to go to sleep and wake up
to find everything has changed.
Manaka...
All right.
Come on.
Okay, Hii!
Manaka really is a fast runner.
She's usually pretty slow,
but sometimes she leaves us behind.
If you don't hurry, Egawa and the others are going to eat it all.
Shall we?
Yeah.
Saya Mart
Now I truly understand how much the people from Shioshishio helped out our store.
Produce and fish prices have gone up due to the weather, and they're staying there.
Maybe the world really is ending.
Let's tough it out, boss.
This is the time to hit 'em with our best deals!
You saw, didn't you?
Get lost!
Yeah, get lost!
Go get lost somewhere, Aka!
I said to get lost, you fake mom!
Miuna!
This'll upset Aka, right?
This'll make her go back to the ocean, right?
She'll go to sleep, right?
She won't die, right?!
Don't cry, Miuna!
We're doing this for her own good!
We don't have a choice!
Get
Thanks, you two.
But I've already made up my mind.
Um, Sakishima?
Yes?
We're from the Fishery Cooperative Men's Club.
We've got a request for your brother.
For Hikari?
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
What?
Really?
Yeah.
Is there any way we can get you guys to do the Boatdrift Ceremony?
Come on, Dad.
I know.
Sorry about what happened at our last meeting.
We, uh...
let our tempers get the better of us.
That doesn't matter right now.
The most important thing is:
are you guys serious?
Yeah.
When you first told us about the winter,
we weren't really sure what to think.
But then the saltflake snow started falling, and the weather cooled down,
and everyone realized it was real.
So please!
We beg of you!
You know, Hikari...
These people laughed at you in the past,
but now that fishing's declined and they can see what's happening,
they want to work with you instead.
You have every right to turn down such a self-centered request.
But if possible, please accept their plea.
The surface is a very important place to me.
Please help us.
So everyone on the surface is gonna help us out, right?
Of course. We'll do everything we can.
That is what we've decided as the Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative.
All right.
Just leave it to me!
And so...
Everyone from the fishery cooperative said they'd help with the Boatdrift Ceremony!
Oh, I see.
Very well done, indeed.
However, even if you go through with the Boatdrift Ceremony, nothing will change.
What?!
But...
That's not what you said before!
Oh? I was just wondering if you could sway the feelings of the surface dwellers.
Did I ever say anything further would come of it?
Please!
Save the surface people!
I beg you! Save them!
I am but a scale of the sea god.
My powers cannot reach beyond the sea.
There's nothing I can do about the surface.
But...
Lord Uroko...
You knew all this yourself.
You knew that the Boatdrift Ceremony had no meaning or power.
And yet...
Apparently the humans weren't a total loss.
What am I supposed to tell them?!
We all worked so hard!
And they're still giving it
their all as we speak.
Hikari...
I know those guys must've hated
bowing their heads to a kid like me.
But they did it anyway.
And I said that we'd do whatever we could, and to leave it to me...
You did your best.
It's fine. Everyone knows that.
Sis...
Hey, Hikari.
I've been thinking about something.
I brought them.
Unhand me!
This is a violation of human rights!
I'll sue!
Right, right.
Um...
Thank you all for gathering here today.
I have something I'd like to ask of all of you.
You're all probably aware of this by now,
but Shiodome Itaru and I
are getting married.
And so...
I was wondering if we could combine the Boatdrift Ceremony and wedding into one ceremony.
One ceremony?
I was wondering if you'd let me take the Wooden Maiden's place on the boat that drifts out to sea.
But does that mean...
You're going to be the sacrifice?
The maiden who calms the sea god's rage?
But Lord Uroko said there was
no point to the Boatdrift Ceremony.
Right.
I'm sure nothing will happen, just as Lord Uroko said.
There may well be no point in me doing this.
But if there's nothing else we can do,
I want to try everything we can just in case.
I'll be the Wooden Maiden.
And when the Boatdrift Ceremony is over,
I'll marry Itaru, just like the maiden married the sea god.
Will you... forgive me?
No!
I mean, if you go to sleep in the ocean,
you can keep living, right?
Then I want you to keep living, Aka!
But I need you and Itaru in my life right now.
There's no point in me living without you two.
So, I'm sorry, but I'm never, ever
going to get lost.
I'm going to live my life in the same place and time as you, Miuna.
Aka!
I'm so sorry!
I don't care if it's pointless.
I just wanted to do something myself
after seeing you all work so hard.
Because I don't want to say
goodbye to all of you
without doing everything I can!
I...
I think that's a great idea!
I, um...
I want to take part too!
In the wedding!
Sounds good.
Let's do it.
We can't just roll over and give up.
Yeah!
Just you watch, sea god!
We'll put on a ceremony that not even you can ignore!
Yeah!
And so, the Boatdrift Ceremony was put into motion again.
Just like the very first one our ancestors held for the sea god.
With the assistance of the fishery cooperative,
the fishermen started helping us out as well.
They let us use their shipyard,
and the adults joined in to help us with our preparations.
Thanks for your hard work!
Thank you too!
See you tomorrow!
Thank you, everyone!
Akari!
Could you check the fireplace and the door?
That was amazing. I really admire her.
In fact, it's not just Akari.
Hikari and Manaka are
trying so hard to change.
Not only have they changed, but they're also changing everyone around them.
I just couldn't let it remain unsaid.
I'm sure Kaname has changed too.
Akari.
I'm going to confess my feelings to Hikari.
It might be futile,
but I can't let it all end like this,
everything unspoken.
In the end, I'm the same as the others.
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
I love Manaka.
I don't understand any of that!
This is the best that I can do.
Don't talk to me!
I won't forget.
Episode Twelve
I Want
to Be Kind
We won't... see each other anymore...