I'm not sure whether to say he's transferring or coming back from academic break,
but say hello to our
newest student, Sakishima Hikari-kun.
Sakishima Hikari
I'm Sakishima, and I'm repeating this class.
Please call me Senpai and show me lots of respect.
Well, as you all can probably tell,
you don't need to hold back too much with him.
Anyone who doesn't wanna show me respect,
meet me behind the gym!
furitsumoru konayuki ga mau
Little snowflakes dance in the air
akiramekaketa yume ga mata namiutsu
I'd almost given up on my dream, but it washes in again,
ano hi no mama de
like it did so long ago
kawaranai egao mitsumete
I watch your frozen smile,
somaru hoho ni fureta kaze ga
and the wind turning my cheeks red
sora takaku muketa
disappears high into the sky
I was always looking at you, never far away,
and yet you seemed out of my reach.
doushite
Why
kou toikaketa koe mo yureru
Even your voice is rough as it asks me
yurayura minamo ni ukanda
The moon's reflection quivered on the waters,
tsuki wa nanimo kataranai
and it told us nothing about the future
tada no boukansha
The moon merely watched us
hora boku nigezu ni tada itai
I want to stay here with you
Episode
Sixteen
The
Whispers
of
the
Faraway
Waves
The
Whispers
of
the
Faraway
Waves
Senpai, please show us your Ena.
I wanna see it too!
I remember the Boatdrift Ceremony!
Yeah, thanks to that ceremony, happi coats were totally in.
Happi coats were popular? What the heck?
Tsumugu-senpai was so cool!
This is too weird.
What?
Being in the same class as that octopus.
I haven't heard that nickname in a while.
Huh?
Well, once an octopus, always an octopus.
It's not like he's changed any.
Sorry, but do you guys mind if I sit down?
An old man like me gets tired kinda easily.
This octopus head over here isn't feeling well just yet,
so you guys shouldn't tease him too much.
Whoa, I haven't heard
that nickname in a while.
You two had the exact same response.
By the way, Senpai, aren't you
technically Shiodome's uncle?
So Miuna's your niece?
Yeah, but just don't call me "Uncle."
Hikari was his usual self.
He was acting the same
as he always had before.
So I figured I, too,
would act like I always had.
Sensei's voice is all hoarse and raspy now.
It wasn't like that before?
Nah, though I think he used to speak a little faster.
Hey, how much have you grown?
Huh? I'm fourt—
Not your age. Your height.
I'm 158 cm now.
Crap, you're gonna be taller than me!
What?
No way. That will definitely not happen.
But I haven't grown at all
in five years, you know.
What am I gonna do if I'm stuck at this height forever?
Well then, you can have all my milk.
Watch out.
Where'd that guy learn to drive?
I'll be right back.
Minegishi!
What?
Um... about what I told you...
It's okay. You don't have to say it.
I already know.
Bu— How did you...
I won't say anything.
Thank— Sorry...
But you know...
That guy's in our class, isn't he?
What's with you?
I'll keep it a secret from your dad for you.
K-Keep what a secret?!
You gotta tell me one thing, though.
Do you like him, or does
he like you? Which is it?
What?!
Got it. Forget I asked.
I understand now.
Understand what?
Ah, I see... So that's your type.
No!
You've got it all wrong!
Yeah, sure. No worries,
I completely understand.
You don't understand at all!
Welcome home.
I heard you started school today.
Yeah, I did. I was quite the senpai.
Tsumugu-kun brought his old
Mihama Middle School uniform for you.
His uniform?
Well, you don't have one.
And you can't very well keep wearing clothes like those to school.
Huh?
Come to think of it,
before the Boatdrift Ceremony,
the guys from the fishery cooperative
took my Namiji Middle School uniform.
What happened to that one?
How should I know?
Just try on this one for now.
If it fits him, feel free to keep it.
It's from when I graduated, though,
so it might be kinda big on him.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Yeah.
It's huge!
Huge!
Man, Tsumugu grew way too much!
Should I try to take in the pants again?
Yeah, I guess.
Hey!
Oh, shut up!
Let's just go get you a new uniform.
Huh?
No need for all that.
Don't fret about it.
It's no trouble.
Seriously, I can just wear this one.
We'll all take the train, go to the department store, and then eat omelet rice before we come home!
Omelet!
Receipt
Sazanami Pharmacy
They say a boy's bravado is a sign that he's healthy,
but I'm worried about Hikari.
Well, he is a guy.
Why don't we let him keep up his façade?
I guess you're right.
Itaru-san, thank you.
Huh?
For letting Hikari stay at our place.
You don't have to thank me for that.
He's your little brother.
Besides, having such a young brother makes me feel younger myself.
Itaru-san...
Tomorrow's my first day off in a while,
so let's all have some fun.
Thank you for always working so hard.
Not at all. I should be the one
thanking you, my responsible wife.
What's wrong?
Omelet...
Omelets are tomorrow.
"Tomorrow"?
When's that?
When you go beddie-bye and wake up,
that's when tomorrow is.
'Kay.
Today's special, so let's open another bottle.
It's all right. We'll have omelets next time, okay?
No next time!
Mama!
Mom?
Can you bring me a cooling patch for him?
S-Sure.
Here. This is for your new uniform.
It's okay. We don't have to go today.
Yes, you do.
I mean, we don't have to get it made.
I can just go to Saya Mart and—
They don't have uniforms there.
Miuna, you know where the tailor is, right?
Yeah.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
See you two later. Be careful.
We should get going too.
We have a train to catch.
Can we just not go?
Huh? How come?
"How come?"
Because it's not like
I need a new uniform.
That's not true. Of course you need a proper uniform.
Man, you're starting to sound just like Akari.
We're going!
So you keep saying...
but what'll we do if we get lost?
We won't get lost!
Well, I might.
What are you doing?
We'll hold hands so we don't get separated.
Are we going on a date?!
You've got that guy from yesterday.
That's not—
All right then, I'll invite Sayu to come with us!
Huh? Why would you do that?
I'll go call her. Stay right there.
Did you bring a bottle of salt water this time?
Of course I didn't!
Miuna!
Don't bring up things from five years ago.
It was just the other day for me.
Well, things are different now!
I've changed!
All right already. Now quit spitting on me.
I'm not spitting on you!
Sayu!
How is it that you're the one who invited me
and yet I had to wait on you?
I'm sorry!
It's fine.
What should we get for lunch?
Omelet rice?
Eh, I'm not really hungry yet.
Remember those squid-ink chips we had last time?
You know, the black ones.
Those were awesome.
Do they still make 'em?
Hmm... I don't think I've seen them recently.
But they have a new flavor: stuffed squid!
Stuffed squid?! Are you serious?
That sounds gross.
Whoa!
This place has changed a lot too!
Come on, let's go.
By the way, have you noticed it kinda smells like something keeps farting?
Huh?
That was not a fart!
You sure?
Maybe there's a pig around, then!
No, there isn't! That's not it either!
My shoes just keep
making this weird noise!
Don't listen to her.
Those are Miuna's best dress shoes.
Your best dress shoes
make pig noises, and fart?
Farting pig shoes!
Stop saying that! They don't fart!
Ow! Quit hitting me! It hurts!
Hey, didn't you guys
have something to do?
See? We got yelled at.
That's because you—
Yeah, whatever you say.
Better hurry or we'll leave you behind.
Could you remove your shoes
and step onto the platform behind you?
I need to take your measurements.
Sure.
It's been a while since I've made
a school uniform for someone from the sea.
I hope you'll be the first of many more.
Yeah...
I'll be right back with the fabric.
What am I even doing here?
Compared to five years ago, there seem to be fewer
students altogether, including those from the surface.
Um, I didn't want a Mihama Middle School uniform...
So why are you wearing Mihama's?
Not a Mihama Middle School uniform?
Oh, um, actually...
one for Mihama Middle School is fine.
No! He wants one for Namiji Middle School!
Please make it a Namiji Middle School uniform instead!
Namiji Middle School?
I thought that school closed down—
But he used to go to that school!
I see... Please wait here a moment.
Why did you—
Namiji Middle School is fine!
I'll wait outside.
Aren't you causing the tailor trouble?
Weren't you listening?
He hasn't made a uniform
for someone from the sea in years.
B-But...
It's whatever.
Sorry for inviting you on such short notice.
No big deal.
Hey, did you know?
What?
On second thought, I'd better not say it.
What is it?
But I don't wanna get you mad.
I won't get mad!
In that case,
did you know a niece can't
get married to her uncle?
Since they're close relatives and all.
I know that!
But...
But it doesn't matter,
because he's your step-uncle.
Sorry. I didn't mean to stick my nose in.
It's okay.
Forget I said anything.
How could you?
How could I what?
Weren't you happy for me?
Didn't you say you were happy for me, Sayu?
So how could you?!
This and that are completely unrelated.
No, they're not!
You're being mean, Sayu!
You're the one being mean, Miuna!
Huh?
Why did you invite me to go
shopping with you two?!
You should've just gone by yourselves!
Did you just wanna flaunt
your flirting in my face?
"Flirt"— We're not flirting!
You are!
Must be nice, huh?!
The person you like woke up.
It's always you.
All the good things always
happen to you, Miuna-chan!
It's not fair!
Why'd I even come today?!
Since I have to make it
from the Namiji Middle School pattern,
it might take a while.
On second thought, never mind.
Huh?
I don't need a new uniform after all.
I'm really sorry!
Sayu, you're being a jerk!
No, you're the jerk, Miuna!
H-Hey!
Sorry, I'm going home!
Wh-What...
Hello. Shiodome residence.
Oh, hi, Hikari.
Akira?
Yeah, he has rubella.
We got him some medicine,
though, so he'll be fine.
I see.
That's good to hear.
By the way, I got separated from Miuna...
If she called?
No, I haven't heard from her.
Something wrong?
She's not somewhere close to you?
Nah, she's not...
Well, I'll start heading back now. See ya soon.
What a pain.
Sorry...
Oh, that's not what I meant.
I'm just trying to figure out what we should do
to kill time till the next train.
But we missed it 'cause of me.
You two haven't changed at all.
Come on now! You can't be
making girls cry like that.
Always Smiling
Saya           Mart
Sayama!
Was that all? You gave this old man
quite a scare, you know.
You? An old man?
Quit trying to act all mature.
Well, you know,
I know about all sorts of things now.
I take it back. You are a geezer.
So since the store isn't as busy as it used to be,
we went back to selling stuff door-to-door.
Oh yeah, this shipyard we're passing...
About three or four years ago, there were talks about demolishing it and putting up a parking lot.
But who'd even use it, right?
Stop the car, Sayama.
What? Here?
Could you take her home?
Thanks.
Careful on your way home.
Do Not                           Enter
You know, you haven't grown at all.
Why are you...
You didn't have to come after me, you know.
Wow, someone's self-absorbed.
I just came to find my old uniform
from during the Boatdrift Ceremony.
Just kidding.
You two got in a fight, right?
Girls are always so quick to fight.
But then, they're quick to make up too.
It's beyond me.
I'm not sure we'll be able
to make up this time...
Of course you will.
You don't know that!
Manaka and Chisaki used to
fight all the time too, you know.
Manaka-san and Chisaki-san?
Yeah.
Usually, Chisaki would stop talking to her.
And then Manaka would cry.
How'd they make up?
Hmm... Who knows?
Kaname probably used to help 'em out.
All right, guess I'll just have to play Kaname's role.
U-Um...
Your nose! It looks like a red pig's!
You jerk!
C'mon, don't be mad.
Jerk!
Miu—
Miuna!
It's so cold.
I can't breathe.
It hurts.
Hikari...
What's that sound?
I can breathe?
Miuna?!
Seeing Hikari underwater,
he shouldn't have looked
any different from usual.
Yet somehow, he seemed brighter... and extraordinary.
What were you doing?!
I was swimming!
I could breathe!
The sea is so beautiful! It was amazing!
Come on, quick!
What are you...
I have to go tell Mom I can swim!
It wasn't even difficult!
Sayu?
I'm so glad you're okay...
I found this lying on the ground.
Sayu!
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Darn it!
Is a pig living in there or something?
Of course not!
How many you got in there?
None! Quit it already!
Jeez!
–—–
–——
———
========
—-
-|||||||||||||-
Triangle
Pardon me.
Could you please tell me the date today?
mugon no kotoba de ayatori shite
I play a silent cat's cradle with my words,
jouzu ni dekita to warattemiru
and decide to grin in satisfaction
tokui na no wa dare ni mo kizukarenu you ni
The only thing that I am truly good at
kokoro oshikorosu koto sore hitotsu dake
is stifling my love so others won't find out
demo torimaku kirei na loop wa
It would be nice
yawai chikara de
if the love of those around me
taguriyosetekureru kana
drew me in gently
azayaka ni
and free of blemish
musunde kono kimochigoto
I tie my feelings into a rope
hanarenai you ni kataku kataku aa
so that we will never be apart
hitomusubi hito wo musunde
The knots tie us together,
kitai no iu mama ni saki he asu he yukou
so let us approach the days to come with hope
Hey there. Good morning.
Kaname...
When would you like to go see Kaname-san?
I'm not going.
A lot's changed, so it must've been surprising.
Kaname's changed?
No way that things have changed since then.
Episode Seventeen
The Sick Two