Sorry about that.
There's a pickled plum in it.
Why are you crying?
Because of the sun.
Because you're the sun, Tsumugu.
Even though it's night?
Maybe that's why.
You're even brighter.
When I was little,
I was told I couldn't go up to the surface by myself yet.
But I still always looked up to the sky.
I admired the sun.
Beyond the ocean, beyond the sky...
and ever so distant.
It was so bright.
It shone down on me.
It sparked a flame in me
and made my heart race.
But...
But?
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode
Thirteen
Fingertips
Beyond
Reach
Fingertips
Beyond
Reach
It's really quiet.
Was it always this quiet at night?
I always thought everyone would be more restless.
Is it because it's right before the hibernation?
Is it because the saltflake snow has piled up?
Oh, I see.
I was the one who was restless.
When it was decided that Namiji Middle School would be closed
and we started going to school on the surface...
That was when it began.
I can't let anyone see this!
Anyone?
But you're showing it to me.
It's fine if it's you!
Manaka had said that,
but she showed Tsumugu too.
At that time, restless ripples began to form in my heart.
It grew stormy,
and before I knew it,
I felt like a ship adrift in the turbulent waters.
Get
But I'm sure it's not just me.
Everyone cares for someone else,
even though some of us
don't realize our own feelings
or know what to do with them.
And even though someone cares about us,
we're unable to notice it
or respond in kind.
We're thrown about by the waves and battered against the rocks,
and it takes everything we have to stay afloat
as we try to make it to the other side.
And despite that...
No, because of that...
Manaka.
Hii.
Sorry for showing up so suddenly.
I'm sort of glad you were outside.
Were you out on a walk?
Um... Something like that.
I see.
The moon does look pretty tonight.
Yeah, it really does.
So, uh...
Um...
About earlier...
So—
Go ahead!
R-Right.
I'm sorry I just blurted all that stuff out earlier.
I kinda got swept up in the moment.
The blood rushed to my head, and I just said it.
I guess I haven't really grown up after all.
So I wanted to say it properly.
Properly?
I... really do love you, Manaka.
I love you, and you're precious to me.
That's one thing I'm sure about.
But Chisaki, Kaname, and Tsumugu...
Akari, Miuna, and Sayu... even Dad...
You're all precious to me.
Whether or not you love me in return,
you'll always be precious to me,
no matter what.
So... What were you going to say before?
The Boatdrift Ceremony...
I'll tell you when it's over.
Huh?
Hii, wave the flag.
Wave it as much as you can.
That way, no one will get lost.
Yeah.
I'm heading out, Dad, Mom.
So you're going up there?
Yeah.
You do realize today's the day of the hibernation, right?
But...
Just don't stay out too late.
We'll do our best to stay awake until you get back.
I thought you'd try to stop me.
You were secretly eating while you were up there, weren't you?
Did you think we wouldn't notice?
Dad...
Go on.
I hope the festival goes well.
Mom...
All right. I'll be going.
Morning, Chisaki.
Kaname...
So they gave you their blessing, huh?
Yeah. They said to do my best at the Boatdrift Ceremony.
Thank goodness. I was worried.
What about you, Kaname?
Did everything go okay?
That was our first big fight.
We managed to work things out in the end, though.
I see.
But I'm glad.
You were working really hard to prepare for the Boatdrift Ceremony.
I was just doing whatever I could to spend more time with you.
Huh?
You know, Chisaki...
You might have had too much on your mind
with your feelings for Hikari,
but I did confess to you too.
I-I haven't forgotten, of course.
I really am thinking about it.
Even if we do end up going to sleep,
and then we wake up at different times,
I'll always love you, no matter what.
Don't forget that, okay?
Kaname...
Yo!
Morning, Hikari.
Morning.
Where's Manaka?
Looks like she isn't here yet.
And we took our time getting up here, too.
W-Wait!
Of all the days to be late...
You really are unbelievable, Manaka.
Huh?
Seriously. She might be the most unbelievable one of us all.
Um...
You guys aren't complimenting me... are you?
Duh.
Jeez...
But Grandma was practically falling out of bed.
Well, well.
You're all quite lively for people who are meant to be getting ready to sleep.
Lord Uroko...
We came to pay our respects.
We're about to participate in the Boatdrift Ceremony.
You said it'd be pointless,
but we're gonna do it anyway.
Do as you wish.
There's nothing I can change on my own.
However, the four of you are a different story.
Maybe you can do it.
Yeah.
Looks like you grew up before I even realized it.
Dad...
Go.
I have nothing more to say to you.
Except this.
You set this in motion yourself,
so make sure you follow it through to the end,
no matter what happens.
You don't have to tell me that.
Tell Akari to lead a happy life.
Boatdrift Ceremony
It's finally here.
A lot has happened,
but who knew it'd get this big?
It's all thanks to you guys.
I really appreciate it.
What are you being all serious for?
You're embarrassing us! Jeez.
More importantly, Hikari,
are you planning to guide everyone in the Boatdrift Ceremony dressed like that?
Why not?
It's just my school uniform.
Nope.
You're a man of the sea now.
And men of the sea wear...
those!
What's up?
Uh, I'm from the sea,
but I'm not a man of the sea...
Shut up. We're taking you in.
Hey, Pops. Could you turn this guy into a proper man of the sea too?
Huh? What?!
Mo-Mom... M-Mo-Mom...
M-M-Mom!
I'm sure that'd make Akari really happy.
You... think so?
Yeah!
Miuna! You won't believe this!
Akari transformed!
It's amazing, Miuna! Look!
I'm looking...
Miuna, Itaru, thank you so much for listening to my selfish wish.
It's fine.
We're going to be together forever now anyway, right, Aka—
M-Mo—
I can't!
I know this is just for show,
but if I look at you now,
I won't be able to let you
go marry the sea god.
So I can't look! I'll never look!
D-Daddy?!
Aka!
Once this is over, I have something
I want to tell you.
So...
All right.
I'll see you later then, Miuna.
Lord Uroko.
Let us begin.
Let's go!
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
Akari, accept this.
It is our gift to you.
The ocean...
Dad...
Wow.
They're being guided by spirit fire.
Akari...
Are you watching, Sea God?
We may only be mere drops in this vast ocean.
But the people of the ocean
and the people of the surface
are all doing their best to live.
We all want to be together.
We all want to stay with the people who are precious to us.
So, Sea God, if you're really out there...
Please, Sea God.
Please...
Hear our wish!
Wh-What is that?
Could it be...
Has the sea god really...
...come to take Akari?!
Akari!
Mukaido!
Tsumugu!
Akari!
It's no use.
It's like my body won't listen to me.
Ah...
It's so pretty.
Lord Uroko! What's going o—
Forgive me.
In the end, I am but a scale of the sea god.
Hurry!
If we don't get up to the surface soon, Tsumugu will...
Kaname?
One, and...
Tsumugu!
Look! The bridge pier!
No!
Please stop!
Akari has people waiting for her!
Please!
Don't take her away!
Everyone...
is precious to someone else!
Please don't take them away
from their loved ones!
If you have to take someone...
Take me instead!
Manaka!
Hii.
Manaka—
Look over there!
There's someone floating!
Get the boat out!
Hurry!
Mom!
Akari!
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
Even now, I look from here...
To the sea where Hikari and the others are.
Episode Fourteen
The Promised Day