Manaka-san...
There you go again, making that depressing face.
There's no need to worry, you know.
But—
I'm telling you,
she's gonna wake up soon, just like Kaname and I did.
No doubt about it.
You're right.
It's been one week since Manaka-san came back.
Come on, let's get going.
Somewhere in their hearts,
everyone was sure of it.
Okay.
Why the heck does English gotta be first period?
They were sure it'd be the same with her as it was with Hikari and Kaname-san
and that she'd wake up soon.
But...
Manaka-san still showed no signs of waking up.
furitsumoru konayuki ga mau
Little snowflakes dance in the air
akiramekaketa yume ga mata namiutsu
I'd almost given up on my dream, but it washes in again,
ano hi no mama de
like it did so long ago
kawaranai egao mitsumeta
I watched your frozen smile,
somaru hoho ni fureta kaze ga
and the wind turning my cheeks red
sora takaku nuketa
disappeared high into the sky
I was always looking at you, never far away,
and yet you seemed out of my reach.
doushite
Why?
to toikaketa koe mo yureru
Even your voice is rough as it asks me
yurayura minamo ni ukanda
The moon's reflection quivered on the waters,
tsuki wa nanimo kataranai
and it told us nothing about the future
tada no boukansha
The moon merely watched us
onaji ne nigiru te ga itai
We hold hands even though it hurts
Episode
Twenty
The
Sleeping
Beauty
The
Sleeping
Beauty
All right, then. That ends our class today.
Those who finish their cleaning duties first
can go home sooner.
I know I gave you lots of homework, but be sure to do it all.
All right!
What?
Let's hurry up and finish cleaning the bathroom!
For real?
Today's the day I'm gonna catch that Uroko!
Because Uroko-sama may know a way to wake up Manaka, right?
Yeah, especially considering that he's the one who put everyone to sleep.
Kaname, come on!
Oh, sorry. I'm coming.
What's taking so long?
I'm gonna start without you.
I thought that Hikari would be pretty anxious since Manaka-san hasn't woken up yet,
but he seems upbeat.
Is Manaka-san alone in your house during the day?
My mom's been taking days off from work to look after her.
Really?
Damn it.
Where the hell is he hiding?
The water's been getting colder.
I hadn't noticed.
It seems a lot colder than the day we found Manaka in Shishio.
Is all this because the sea god is angry?
Because we're taking Manaka back?
So what?
All we gotta do is come up to the surface once in a while and warm up.
Hikari, wait!
You haven't had a chance to warm up yet!
See? I'm totally fine.
It seems that way, but...
I'm telling you.
Huh?
That's Chisaki's bag, isn't it?
Well, she said she'd be late because of her internship,
but maybe we just missed her.
Sorry I was late.
Um, is something the matter?
I'm gonna go take another look.
Uh, I'll go join him.
Don't you wanna go to Shishio with them, Miuna?
I've decided to leave Shishio to Hikari and the others.
Is something wrong?
I was just thinking...
Since we're all the same age now,
it'd be nice if we could hang out with them more often.
And it'd be even nicer if we could manage to join their circle of friends too.
Yeah, it would be.
Hey, about Manaka-san,
maybe we could try stimulating her senses.
Yeah, maybe we could stimulate her ears by playing a song.
That's a good idea!
Uroko-sama's nowhere to be found.
Well, Miuna-chan said she
definitely saw him down there.
Let's widen our search to the
far edge of the village tomorrow.
Okay, Hikari?
Yeah.
They changed the song, didn't they?
This always reminds me of the day of the Boatdrift Ceremony.
Yeah, they did.
Every day at this time,
I remember that day.
That's it!
Manaka will remember this song too, right?
I think I just thought of a way to wake her up!
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
Ideas for Local Mascot:
Oshiosshii
Sea Slug
Narunamimaru
That's a great idea.
Right?
If we play her a tape of people singing from the festival, then somehow...
...she may remember scenes from that day.
And that, in turn, might just wake her up.
But a lot of people have moved away since then...
That's okay! You can just gather as many people as you can!
Please, Itaru-san, we're counting on you!
Please?
You guys...
Local Mascot Character Name Ideas:
Oshiosshii
Sea Slug
Narunamimaru
All right.
I'll go make some calls and do what I can,
so just wait a bit, okay?
We're back.
We're home!
Welcome back, you two.
Hi, Tsumugu. We just got back.
Welcome back.
The bath's ready for you.
Okay. Thanks.
Be careful.
Sorry I kept you waiting. We can go now.
You two are so complicated.
Hikari's sort of late, isn't he?
He's with Chisaki-chan and Kaname, right?
Yeah.
At first, I was a little worried about them getting along, but...
Chisaki-chan's been coming by a lot more often lately.
Now if only Manaka-chan would wake up...
Wake up, Manaka
Yeah...
Speaking of those three, I heard they asked the fishery
cooperative to record the Boatdrift Ceremony song for them.
- Stimulating sounds...?
- _____ from the sea
- Nostalgic music...
like the song from the
Boatdrift Ceremony
What?
He's asking for help from those who sang it five years ago,
hoping it'll wake up Manaka-chan.
Itaru-san was so excited that he called to tell me all about it.
Although he wasn't the one who came up with the idea, he's really into it.
I see...
Welcome home.
Hikari?
Oh, hey.
Damn it.
We had no luck catching Uroko today either.
Oh, I meant to ask you...
since we have so much homework today,
wanna do it together?
Okay.
That's right... Everyone was
complaining about it earlier.
There really isn't enough time in the day.
Maybe I should take some time off from school.
What?!
I'd have a lot more time that way,
and I'd be able to do a lot more.
Y-You can't do that!
Why not?
Well, I mean...
we're still required to go to school!
What are you getting all serious for?
P-Plus, Mom will be really worried about you!
Akari's not my mom.
Well, I know that,
but you can't just ditch school like that!
What if she never wakes up?!
What the hell do you mean by that?
I-I didn't mean to—
All right already! I got it.
You'll shut up if I go to school, right?
H-Hikari!
Wai—
No...
That's not what I wanted to say.
Damn it!
Hii-kun.
Manaka,
you're...
I was happy with the way things were.
Thanks to me leaving,
the sea and the surface kept freezing over...
And I...
Wake up, Manaka
Where's Hikari?
He left early to check the sea again.
He said he'd go straight to school after.
Ketchup!
Come on, Akira!
What do you think you're doing?
With this, the Warring States period finally came to an end.
Finally, after nearly 260 years—
Library
People who force their feelings onto others suck, don't they?
What are you talking about?
Oh, I was talking about
the main character of this.
You're not supposed to be reading books
that won't help Manaka-san!
But we've already been sitting here for three whole hours!
Even I can't keep my focus for—
Wait, what the heck are you reading?
This book is relevant.
Learning About Sleep
The True State of Hypnosis
Isn't that topic a little off?
There's no telling where we might find a clue to help wake her up.
You sure you're putting thought into this?
Of course I am!
So how is your book relevant?
Well...
I've just been thinking...
Isn't it common for a prince to kiss a sleeping princess to wake her?
I was thinking that maybe Manaka-san would wake up if someone kissed her.
Wh—A-A kiss?!
I don't think it's that strange.
I believe that really strong feelings
have the power to make big changes.
Strong feelings?
There are people who have feelings like that...
Hikari, for example.
B-But it's not okay to just kiss her if we don't know for sure that it'll help.
Well, do you have a better idea?
No... not yet.
Then why not?
But that's—
Miuna, it sounds like you don't actually want Manaka-san to wake up.
You're the one who just said there's no telling where we might find a clue!
It really could work, I'm serious.
Is that true?
Do I not actually want Manaka-san to wake up?
The Boatdrift Ceremony Song
It's not working.
Guess I'll go look for Uroko-sama again.
The Boatdrift Ceremony Song
Hoi, hoi!
Ow!
The Boatdrift Ceremony Song
Hoi, hoi!
Come on, Akira!
"I want Manaka-san to wake up."
That's what I should've been thinking this whole time.
Was I the only one that was on a different page?
Manaka!
When did you wake up?
Oh, it's you, Miuna.
My bad.
Hikari?!
Hikari?
He must have been exhausted.
I'll make him stay home from school tomorrow.
You should get to bed too, Miuna.
It'll be no good if everyone keels over.
Miuna?
You're still in bed?
Shouldn't you be leaving for school soon?
Miu has a fever too?
Well...
let's just say that she does.
Good morning!
Good morning.
Oh, good morning.
Miuna and Hikari have a cold.
They're both absent today?
Yeah.
Um...
are you okay, Kaname?
I mean, you've been diving into that cold water with Hikari, haven't you?
Yeah. I'm fine, though.
I see.
That's good.
Hikari pushed himself way too hard...
as if Miuna and I and everyone else weren't here with him.
Take your seats, everyone.
Class is about to start.
I have to take notes for three people today.
For three?
Miuna's been taking notes for Manaka-san
for when she wakes up.
Oh, so that's why.
I can help you take notes for them.
Huh?
I'll help too.
Miuna,
Hikari's sleeping soundly,
so I'm going to take Akira and go shopping.
Okay.
Keep an eye on the house, okay?
And I told Hikari not to rest...
Do I not actually want Manaka-san to wake up?
The Boatdrift Ceremony Song
This is...
Ow!
Come on, Akira!
Hikari, you're all hot.
Get off me.
The Boatdrift Ceremony Song
Hikari, you have a fever.
I have to go find Uroko-sama!
I'm gonna be the one who wakes her up.
It's gonna be me.
Hikari is always so focused,
and he always shines so brightly.
The Boatdrift Ceremony Song
I'm certain that it's thanks to his feelings for Manaka-san.
And yet, I...
I...
Public
Hospital
According to studies done about activities like mountain
climbing and free diving, there exists this rare phenomenon.
Water
Sometimes, when you're
in a dangerous situation,
dormant survival instincts may kick in and change your body so that you stay alive.
To figure out why Mukaido-san is still asleep and why Shiodome-san has Ena...
We believe your Ena is the same.
As you were pushed to your limits,
it's possible that your
dormant abilities awakened.
That's what we've surmised.
The professor would like to talk to you again.
Is there a day that works best for you?
What did she say, Tsumugu?
Can we see her sometime soon?
Just a sec.
Miuna,
can you meet up with me right now?
You awake?
Yeah. What...
You had a really high fever,
but it's gone down now.
Make sure you thank Miuna.
She was watching over you
nearly the whole time.
What about Manaka?
There still haven't been any changes.
Hikari, I can understand how you must feel,
but you should look to those
around you a bit more.
What the heck?
You're lecturing a sick person?
You're not the only one who cares about Manaka-chan, you know.
Of course I know that.
I'm not sure you do.
Oh, those...
Kaname-kun and Sayu-chan brought them by.
They're so you guys won't
fall behind in your studies.
Corn Soup
Here.
Thank you.
Tangerine
Juice
Are you sure you're okay with that?
Yeah.
I like this flavor, actually.
I guess I really am hard to read.
Huh? What do you mean?
It's just...
everyone from Shishio is
overflowing with emotions.
I've always been a little envious.
You're like them too.
I'm not too sure about that.
I'm not sure it'd be a good thing, either.
I mean, I'm not like Hikari and the others.
When Hikari first saw my Ena,
he said I was just like him.
But I have to wonder...
how come Manaka-san is losing her Ena,
and how come I'm gaining it?
I'm the only one with different feelings toward Manaka-san.
Because of that, I said something to Hikari and upset him.
What if she never wakes up?!
I thought of the worst possible thing.
Is that true?
Do I not actually want Manaka-san to wake up?
I was like that.
At first, I thought it'd be better if they never woke up.
Huh?
I was scared because I thought Chisaki would disappear on me.
But it turns out
I was really happy when they woke up.
"Happy"?
Yeah, it's weird, isn't it?
But I really was happy.
You were scared but still happy?
Yeah.
I wonder...
if I'll manage to be happy too.
It's hard for you because both of them are precious to you.
Both Hikari and Mukaido.
I want to be able to be happy.
I want to be able to say I'm glad from the bottom of my heart.
You'll be able to.
Apparently, they've been taking notes for you while you've been asleep.
Wake up, Manaka
Miuna and the others took them for you.
Hikari?
She's gonna wake up for sure, right?
Yup.
She will, no matter what.
Wake up, Manaka
Yeah.
Speaking of, Hikari,
Sayu mentioned something to me earlier.
She thought of something?
Yeah.
She said that strong feelings have the power to make big changes.
She's pretty sure that your feelings have powers like that, Hikari.
So she suggested...
U-Um...
Kiss!
Huh?
What?!
Wai—Wh-What are you saying?!
What do you mean?
Oh!
N-No, that's not what I meant!
I was saying you should kiss Manaka-san!
What?! Either way, why should I do that?
Because it could help her wake up!
You're making no sense!
And what's a k-kiss got to do with anything?
I already explained it!
That's not an explanation!
Hii-kun!
You shouldn't yell at girls like that!
Shut up! It's all 'cause she—
Huh?
Wake up, Manaka
mugon no kotoba de ayatori shite
I play a silent cat's cradle with my words,
jouzu ni dekita to warattemiru
and decide to grin in satisfaction
tokui na no wa dare ni mo kizukarenu you ni
The only thing that I am truly good at
kokoro oshikorosu koto sore hitotsu dake
is stifling my love so others won't find out
demo torimaku kirei na loop wa
It would be nice
yawai chikara de
if the love of those around me
taguriyosetekureru kara
drew me in gently
azayaka ni
Innocently
musunde kono kimochigoto
I tie my feelings into a rope
hanarenai you ni kataku kataku
so that we will never be apart
hitomusubi hito wo musunde
The knots tie us together,
kitai no yamanai saki he asu he yukou
so let us approach the future with hope in our hearts
How was she? How was Mukaido?
She was so energetic that it startled me.
This feels so weird.
Manaka's still Manaka.
Looks like you're together again.
The Four from Shishio.
Episode
Twenty One
The Messenger
from the Bottom of the Sea