I can't hear what they're saying.
Did Uroko-sama just pass gas?
That was all you could hear?!
Shh!
Hikari!
We heard about Akari-san!
Shh!
Akari...
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Three
The
Tradition
of the Sea
The
Tradition
of the Sea
Thank you, Namiji Middle School
There's saltflake snow
inside the school, too.
99th-Term New Students
Entrance
Ceremony
99th
Namiji Middle
School
Old Man Hayakawa is normally so nice.
I wonder why he was so mean today.
Well, he was talking about
the rules of the village.
Maybe there's some reason
people get banished.
Who the hell cares about that?
That guy Akari was with
is the one to blame here.
But he seemed so nice.
Chisaki, you've got crappy taste in guys.
You can say that again.
Damn it.
Guess I'm gonna have to play it safe and look into this guy.
If I find out he's an asshole,
I'm gonna punch his lights out!
And if he's actually a decent guy?
Then I'll just punch him gently!
V-Violence is wrong!
It's his own damn fault for daring
to lay a finger on a girl from the sea!
But...
You stupid girls go somewhere else.
This is now a planning
meeting for guys only.
Let's go, Manaka.
Yeah.
Music  Room
I hope Hikari calms down a bit.
When he gets like that, he's impossible.
Manaka?
Look, Chii-chan! A sea slug!
Wow, it's one with a red belly, too!
They say if you tell a red-bellied
sea slug your most private feelings,
it'll tell you what will come of them.
Yeah, if it spits up a dull rock,
it means your feelings are
bound to end in grief and failure,
but if it spits up a pretty rock...
...then those feelings will last forever, shining like a beautiful jewel.
Hey, Manaka?
Yeah?
Do you like Tsumugu-kun?
Wh-Why would you—
What are you talking about, Chii-chan?!
I'm not really sure.
Okay, so we're gonna do this tomorrow.
But how do we know if it'll even work?
Well, that car had the logo of
a fishery cooperative on it, right?
So if he tries to run—
But if I were to like him,
I'd probably want to go out with him.
And if I went out with him, um...
maybe, just like Akari-san,
we'd kiss.
Did that make me sound like a pervert?
No, not at all.
Go on.
And I guess if I thought about marrying him,
then I wouldn't be able to come back here.
Well, you don't have to worry about that yet.
I mean, you're not even sure
whether you like him or not, right?
Yeah.
But I do like you and Hii-kun and Kaname.
I know that much, at least.
But with Tsu—
with Kihara-kun, it's a little different.
I don't really understand how I feel.
I see.
Hikari...
We're going home, Manaka, Chisaki!
Oh, Hii-kun,
you two are done already?
Th-That was pretty fast.
That night...
Welcome home!
Dinner's ready.
R-Right.
Dad and Akari acted
like everything was normal
and didn't say a word about
what happened at Uroko-sama's.
What an idiot.
But...
all through the night, I could hear this really, really soft crying.
I could only remember
this happening once before.
When I was really little,
I used to call Akari "Nee-chan."
O sea, filled with compassion, with your fluttering waves and your bright light,
O sea that nurtures all life,
O surging storm, O tide that takes all,
Mom!
O abyss that is the gateway to Agito,
Mom! Mom!
O great sea god, master of the sea,
exalted one from whom we are born,
we beg you to deliver the soul of Sakishima Hokage.
Nee-chan!
We beseech you to guide her, along with the holy spirit fire, to where you are.
She didn't cry at all.
Now, let us remember and praise all the good she did in this life.
Nee-chan?
I never understood it.
She was acting so grown-up and wasn't crying, even though she was just a kid herself.
That's why...
Akari!
What's going on?!
Didn't I tell you?
I'm going to start working at Oshiooshi's Saya Mart.
Why?! You said you wanted to be a manga artist!
You were even gonna go to a school for it on the surface!
Oh, but you know, they said they'd let me draw the signs at the shop.
I'm totally gonna design a famous
mascot for them and bring in the sales!
Cut the crap, Akari!
Quit trying to dodge the issue!
We don't have enough money for both of us to go to college.
I don't even wanna go to college!
But you do!
You don't know that for sure yet.
You might change your mind once you're in high school, you know.
Then I won't go to high school either!
I hate studying anyway!
Wha—
Q-Quit it, Akari!
I love you, Hikari.
Nothing changed when I called Nee-chan "Akari."
Although I called her something different, things between us stayed the same.
I realized then that she grew up as fast as she did in order to take care of me.
I am pissed off at her stupid boyfriend.
But even though I still don't really understand why,
I was sort of relieved.
I was relieved because it meant Akari had finally started thinking about herself.
And then there's...
And I guess if I thought about marrying him,
then I wouldn't be able to come back here.
I was irritated because of Manaka too.
But I knew that, because of the relationships between people on the surface and the people of the sea,
Manaka was probably even
more irritated than I was.
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
All right, let's do this.
Hey, you won't just start punching him out of the blue, will you?
I see your point.
I'll talk to him for a bit first,
and then I'll punch him.
You missed my point entirely!
Hey, that's—
I-It's him!
Wait, you cheater!
Trying to run away, huh?!
It's not like we made any
plans with him, you know!
Hii-kun?!
Hikari!
We've gotta stop him!
Just how far did he go?
Hii-kun...
Hey, this is
Kihara-kun's house!
Okay, so that'll be the date I'll come
to pick up the fish starting next month.
See you then.
That bastard!
Hii-kun!
You said you wouldn't start
punching him out of nowhere!
Hey! You!
Damn it! The hell is this?!
Who the hell are you, old man?!
These eyes...
This one's a storm.
U-Um... who are you?
Hii-kun!
Hikari!
"Hikari"? Are you Akari's younger brother?
Why are you—
Akari's crying because of you!
And everyone in Shioshishio is
on her case because of you, too!
What?
Didn't she tell you?
Tell me what?
When someone from the surface
and someone from the sea get together,
it's not just some ordinary thing.
Old man...
I'm aware of that already.
There's the rivalry as well as the issue with the fishing grounds.
But that has nothing—
That has nothing to do with it.
Are you two trying to have babies?
Wh-Wha—
Has this old man gone off the deep end?!
That's the issue here, though.
Kihara-kun...
The biggest difference between the people on the surface and the people of the sea
is the Ena that protects the people of the sea.
Ena is similar to the amnion that protects a fetus,
which the people on the surface
break through when they're born.
On the other hand, the people of the sea are born with it as part of their skin,
just like the scales of a fish.
The people of the sea are able to breathe underwater because they have Ena.
But a child born from the union between someone from the surface and someone from the sea
is born without Ena.
Th-Then, if Akari-san had a baby with him,
that baby wouldn't be able
to survive underwater?
No wonder.
I mean, we could go extinct that way.
So this is why if you marry
someone from the surface,
you get banished from the village.
Banished from the village?!
Why...
Why didn't Akari say anything about this?
Listen, you!
Please believe me, Hikari-kun!
I'm not just messing around with Akari!
What? So you plan on marrying her?
Well...
What?!
You're dating her, and yet you have no intention of following through?!
Are you even a man?!
Hii-kun!
Hikari!
I don't entirely remember
what happened after that.
He let me punch him for a while,
No!
and when I finally came to...
Morning.
Just stay down.
Your friends went to soak in the water.
You need to keep wet, don't you?
Still! Don't just do that out of nowhere!
Since you have to come
up to the surface all wet,
I always wondered what
happened to your clothes.
When we're not underwater,
our Ena sucks up any
extra moisture and stores it.
That's convenient.
Really?
Yeah, I wish I had it too.
I was wondering about this earlier,
but how come you know
so much about Shioshishio?
Because I think it's great.
I'm asking you why you think it's grea—
Is it weird?
I'll go get some more water for you.
Oh, don't worry about it.
I'm fine.
I'm leaving now anyway.
Then make sure you take it easy, okay?
Kihara Tsumugu is a good guy.
I knew that already, but...
U-Um...
Thanks a lot.
I'm the one who made you pass out, you know.
R-Right.
Yeah, I guess it's weird
for me to be thanking you.
Ena?
Old man... are you from Shioshishio—
Oh, Hii-kun!
Thank goodness. You're awake.
Welcome home.
I heard you got beat up.
How the hell do you know about that?
That stupid guy contacted you?!
Yeah. He called me.
Akari, just give up on that guy already!
He's totally not—
Yeah, I'm going to.
Huh?
It wouldn't have worked out with him anyway.
H-Hey, you're giving up that easily?
It's fine.
No, it's not!
You can just worry about the baby once you actually have one—
Oh? You're supposed to learn that in health class during your last year in junior high,
but you already found out?
It's fine. Really.
People from the surface
and people from the sea
shouldn't be together anyway.
Akari...
But you know,
there aren't that many single guys in the village right now!
So it's tough finding someone to get married to.
How can you be laughing right now?
Since it's so tough, I suppose I can always resort to forbidden love!
Akari! Quit messing around! Let go of me!
You're so cute!
Hey! What are you—
Akari...
Good morning!
It's Kihara-kun!
Good morning.
Morning.
How are you feeling?
O-Oh yeah...
Tsumugu, thanks for yesterday.
Huh?
I-I was trying this whole time
not to call him by his first name!
Because you said it was perverted, Hii-kun!
It's fine if it's between guys!
What?!
I see. Then I'll call him that too.
Tsumugu.
Hey! No fair, Kaname!
I wanna do it too!
That's okay with you, right, Tsumugu-kun?
Huh? Uh, sure.
Oh, you guys...
It's decided, then!
Thank goodness.
I'm glad you and Tsumugu-kun
are a little closer now.
You're calling him Tsumugu now, too?
Well, Tsumugu-kun is really nice.
And I just knew you two would become friends eventually.
You really do worry too much.
You're just like my sister.
S-Sorry. I didn't mean to act all grown-up again...
Sorry for making you worry all the time.
I'll try to grow up a little more myself.
Hikari?
Wood Shop Room
What's all this?
Looks like you kids are making great progress!
Yup!
If you guys keep it up, you'll be done in no time.
I know!
Since you did such a good job,
why don't I treat you guys to some ramen?
You see, I've always wanted to do that for my students.
Seriously?! Awesome!
I want miso ramen!
But...
It's almost five.
Oh, right.
Sorry. Then, next time—
Wait.
It's done.
Hey, this is...
Tsumugu-kun made this for us so that we could get work done without worrying about the time.
Tsumugu-kun made this?
I thought the fish might
want to breathe too.
Thanks, Tsumugu.
You're welcome.
Hey, Manaka?!
Manaka?
I'm sorry!
Huh?
I was lying!
Your curse was lifted?
Curse?
But... if Uroko-sama curses me again—
Um, you see, that was just a curse!
He cursed me because I threw food at him.
But then he didn't curse
me the last time I did it.
But if I do something bad
to him again, I'm sure—
I'm sure we'll meet again.
Manaka... what are you doing?
I'm impersonating the fish from the curse.
That's not what I mean!
Huh?
Come on now, Hikari!
Thanks a lot!
You're welcome!
Me too!
You're soaking wet now!
Um, what about the ramen?
Your clothes really do dry up.
But you're all soaked, Tsumugu-kun.
Hikari?
I forgot I was supposed to stop by somewhere.
You guys head home!
What the hell?
Oh, it's you guys again.
Huh? But on TV, they
always pass out after that.
Something's not right!
It's gotta be soaked with chloroform first.
It doesn't work with just a handkerchief!
The damn media's got me dancing to their tune.
Yeah, dancing like an octopus.
You're the octopus, octopus head!
Hey.
What is it now?
If you're this idiot's friend,
you gotta do something about—
Help me.
Huh?
Help me break up my dad and that woman.
D—
Dad?!
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
That's a pretty straightforward
admission of guilt.
Let's pretend we didn't see it, Kaname.
That's really playing dirty!
Are you saying I'm
the only one at fault here?
Please forgive him.
Episode Four
Because We're Friends