Wait! Don't leave yet!
Mukaido
Ouch!
Why didn't you do that last night?
Well, because...
Ouch!
Well, it's not like we've ever had to buy or wear swimsuits before.
Yeah, what a pain in the ass.
They don't even have 'em at Saya Mart.
And I was so sure I could
get one by asking Akari.
Saya Mart doesn't have everything, you know.
Why wouldn't they?
They have slippers!
And shorts, even!
Relying on Akari for everything again?
Why not? I mean, she's already there.
Hikari, you really never change.
What's that mean?
Are you trying to say
I haven't changed at all?
Sorry I took so long!
C'mon, let's go!
R-Right!
Well, whatever.
This'll probably do.
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Six
Beyond Tomoebi
Eww, you pervert! Gross!
What the hell? Then don't look!
Yeah, just leave already.
Girls should change in the locker room.
Huh?
Were you planning on
changing in front of the guys?
Girls'
Locker Room
Man, I've gotten so fat. Bummer.
Ugh, me too.
Egawa's probably gonna make fun of us for it.
So that's how they change.
Yeah, those towels are really nice.
You don't have swimming class
in the ocean village?
Y-Yeah, we don't. This is our first time.
Lucky!
Better be careful, Hiradaira.
Huh?
Man, our class has, like, zero babes.
Oh, right! There's Hiradaira!
She's stacked!
Yeah, for real.
Hey!
Hikari, it's o—
They really are big, Hiradaira.
C'mon, lemme touch 'em.
That looks fun!
Wait, I wanna try!
Is that how girls become friends?
Girls are crazy.
I'm gonna be timing you guys today!
What's with the whining?
You were timed last year too.
Okay, time to warm up!
Out of the towels now, girls.
No way!
That's sexual harassment!
Sorry, girls, but you're not my type.
But it's so cold!
Well, you're in luck.
It's actually warmer in the water.
Okay, time for knee bends!
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight!
Okay, after knee bends come bunny hops!
What the hell's the point in warming up?
What?!
No complaining!
Well, don't people from
Shioshishio ever get cramps, too?
Two, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight!
You're not gonna join in, Hikari?
I don't need preparation to breathe.
Be sure to let me know
what stroke you'll be using!
It can be the front crawl
or even the doggy paddle.
Tsumugu, what stroke'll you be doing?
The front crawl.
Okay, then I'll do that one too.
Let's swim together.
All right.
Looks like Kihara and Sakishima are gonna swim together!
Which one are you gonna root for?
Well, Kihara was super fast
last year, wasn't he?
Yeah.
But someone from Shioshishio might be faster.
So are you two gonna root for Sakishima?
Huh? O-Oh, I'm not sure.
Um, there's Kaname and...
Hii, right?
I guess.
Right, I guess it makes sense that
you'd cheer on your Shishio friends.
Then I'm gonna root for 'em too!
No way!
It's Kihara all the way for me!
Everyone in position?
Ready?
You can do it!
That's weird. Sakishima's
slower than I thought he'd be.
Oh, it's probably because he's not used to it.
To swimming?
Well, it's sort of weird swimming right on the surface of the water.
Plus, he's not used to doing the front crawl.
Oh, is that why?
Damn it! This is harder than I thought!
If I don't love anyone, I won't be so sad!
I don't wanna believe it's hopeless or useless to love someone.
Ow!
Hii!
Are you okay, Sakishima?!
I'm fine.
Hii got hurt—
Shut up, Manaka.
In any case, both of you come on
and get out of the water.
Hii, let's get out.
Oh, you injured your toe.
Who's on duty today?
I am.
Oh, that works out nicely.
Take him to the nurse's office, okay?
What?
Can Chi— I mean,
can Hiradaira come, too?
Teach.
I'll go next.
What?
'
Nurse's Office
Excuse me...
What should we do?
The nurse isn't here.
Why are you asking me?
Oh, I know!
Where's the disinfectant?
Forget it. I don't need any.
But our teacher said...
Ow!
S-Sorry!
Damn it.
Sorry.
I'm not very good at this.
Hii, are you mad?
No, not really.
Ugh, I reek of chlorine!
Seriously...
Huh?
He's way too fast.
That's just because we
hardly ever do the front crawl!
That's all it is!
If we had been in the ocean,
you definitely would've been faster, Hii!
Man, that stings...
Sorry.
Having to be cheered up by you of all people really stings.
B-But everyone else knows you're really amazing, too.
Chii knows it too!
Why the hell are you bringing up Chisaki?
Just go back to class.
I can do this myself.
So lame...
Chii!
I, um...
That sure took a while!
What were you two up to
in the nurse's office?
"Stop, you perv!"
What?
Nothing happened! Really!
She looks guilty!
What?!
Yeah, really guilty!
You guys are such perverts!
Mukaido, go ahead and change.
We can take care
of cleaning up.
O-Okay.
I can take that.
You don't really seem like
you're from the ocean village, Isaki.
Well, I don't think I seem like
I'm from the surface either, though.
Oh, I didn't mean it like that.
Sakishima can be a little scary.
You think so?
But he's really not.
Don't you two agree?
How'd he know we were here?!
You kids are from
Hama Elementary, aren't you?
We're not kids!
Are you done with school for today?
W-We were thinking we could maybe help out.
So here we are!
Help with what, though?
Um, with the Wooden—
You guys are still making
the Wooden Maiden, Isaki?
Why? Do you wanna help too?
Yeah, I do!
U-Um...
Of course you two can help out.
Y-You're lucky to have such awesome help!
What the heck?
Tsumugu, are you going home?
Yeah. I need to help Gramps today.
Oh, I see...
Is your injury any better?
Yeah.
I brought in the cans of veneer.
I coulda done it.
Not with your foot in that condition.
See ya.
What the hell's with him?
Huh? What is it?
Nothing.
Oh, there he is.
Hey, Sakishima!
What the heck, Sakishima?
You sure took your time.
Now there's nothing left for you to do!
Nothing left!
You're the one who destroyed it, you know.
Boo.
Everyone wanted to come and
help rebuild the broken Wooden Maiden.
Except those two. You guys are just here 'cause of Hiradaira, isn't that right?
Wh-What the hell are you saying, you idiot?!
W-W-We'll never finish at this rate!
In that case, all of you are now my minions.
Like hell I am!
I'm a pro at the Boatdrift Ceremony!
What do you mean, "pro"?
Well, we also gotta make offerings—
not just the Wooden Maiden.
Offerings?
Like a dresser, a stand, and a table.
And we need the car, too.
And a TV and video games.
The Wooden Maiden's a gamer now?
You idiot!
The Wooden Maiden nowadays is totally hip!
Yeah, totally hip!
They're fitting right in.
Yeah, a little too much, if you ask me.
Ow!
Hii! You shouldn't be walking around on your own yet!
Right, Chii?
Oh, I just remembered.
Sorry.
My mom asked me to
stop by the post office.
What time does it close, again?
Four o'clock.
Thanks, Miuna.
Okay, I'm off. See you guys later!
Chii, wait!
U-Um, I—
Didn't I ask you to forget about it?
I-I'm sorry!
But you know, Chii, I—
Didn't you promise?!
Why do you always do things like this?!
B-But if things stay the way they are,
I thought it might not be good for you.
Who are you to decide
what's good or bad?!
Sorry. I'm gonna go.
Hii!
Why?
I hate this!
Aw, too bad for you, boys.
Hiradaira already went home.
Oh, shut the hell up.
We came 'cause we really
wanted to help out!
Looks like Manaka's not coming back either.
Yeah right!
So it really is Manaka.
She's our center.
Mukaido?
You're not with Hiradaira?
Huh?
That's unusual.
It's 'cause...
'Cause Chii...
said she didn't want to talk to me.
And before, Hii... he...
Tsumugu, take her to the wharf.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go check the cages on the east side.
Okay, got it.
Why don't you get on?
Gramps...
was saying that today seemed
like the perfect day for Tomoebi.
What's "Tomoebi"?
W-Well, when the weather's really nice and there's a lot of saltflake snow,
and then a cold current passes through,
it looks like there are three suns
because of the refraction or something.
But I've never seen it myself.
Chii and the guys saw it once,
when we were all in elementary school.
They came to get me,
but since I couldn't understand what Chii was saying, I just zoned out.
Stupid Manaka.
No.
I'm the stupid one.
Stupid!
I'm really done with you this time, Manaka!
There's no point unless
we all see it together!
Don't make such a big deal out of it.
What? Doesn't it matter to you too, Hikari?
Stupid, stupid Manaka!
Chii got really mad,
which surprised me, so I started crying.
She didn't talk to me for a while after that.
Is it really such a big deal?
She said that if we didn't all see it together,
it would have no meaning.
I kind of get that.
Huh?
I can understand the desire to share something
you enjoy with the people you really care about.
But...
maybe Chii doesn't care about me at all now.
Why wouldn't she?
Because...
You know...
Huh?
Why don't you ever finish your sentences?
Finish my sentences?
You know, instead of trailing off
or ending sentences with "or something"
or always being so vague,
you should talk without hesitating,
just like you did when you
jumped in to help Hikari today.
That...
That just came naturally.
I see.
So that's the real you.
Huh?
You were really cool right then, Mukaido.
Tsumugu...
I'm sowwy!
Chii, Chii, Chii!
H-Hurry!
Manaka?
What is it?
Tomoebi...
When we were little, you came
and got me for this, remember?
I did?
So when I took too long and was the only one who didn't make it in time,
you got really mad.
So mad that I got really
surprised and started crying.
That doesn't matter anymore.
No, I'm going to finish my thought.
I'm really sorry that I wasn't
able to see this with you that day.
Is this why you brought me here?
Well, I promised!
I said we'd see it together
next time, no matter what.
I hope the Wooden Maiden
never gets completed.
H-How come?
Because that way, it'd always be summer.
And all of us would always be building the Wooden Maiden.
We'd always be together,
playing,
going to school,
and talking.
But...
You know, I always thought
that things didn't need to change.
I didn't want them to change.
You don't want things to change?
But I think it's impossible...
and difficult.
Still, in spite of all that,
I don't want things to change.
I want us all to stay together forever.
It's so pretty.
I wish Hikari and Kaname were here, too.
Yeah.
All of us seeing the same things,
laughing the same way,
and staying friends like this forever.
That's Manaka for you.
Before we even realize it,
she's always jumping ahead,
long before any of us.
Even though she's a scaredy-cat.
Even though she's Manaka.
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
We want to do the Boatdrift Ceremony.
This is what youth's all about!
Break up with that guy.
So careless.
We're not fish, and they're not pigs!
Episode Seven
The Boatdrift
Ceremony
Shakes
The Boatdrift
Ceremony
Shakes