G'morning, Hikari!
You're up early.
Yeah, I was thinking I'd go to work today.
I see.
See you later!
Aww...
And here I was, looking
forward to leaving together.
Are you going there to end things?
Just give up on that guy from the surface.
I guess you're a man of the sea after all...
I know.
Though we are the creation
of the great sea god,
the people of Shioshishio have always carried...
Spirit fire is the soul of the sea god.
Uroko-sama...
The spirit fire is trying to tell us something.
It says the boundaries between land and sea must be made permanent.
Eventually, the surface will...
The saltflake snow is but
a harbinger of what is to come.
The matter with Akari is
entirely up to you, though.
It is not up to me.
Akari will make her own decisions.
Oh?
Throughout the innumerable ages...
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Five
Hey, Sea Slug
Chisaki said she's gonna be late?
Yeah, she said she wasn't feeling well.
She looked a little down
on the way home yesterday, too.
It must be pretty serious.
Serious?!
Nah, I didn't mean it like that.
They say if you tell a red-bellied
sea slug your most private feelings,
it'll tell you what will come of them.
Green...
Manaka's such a good girl.
I, on the other hand...
I've got to do something
about my feelings for Hikari.
You're late.
Look who's talking.
Well, we had a big haul this morning.
We've been lucky enough to get
a lot of golden eye snappers lately.
Where's everyone else?
Since I was running late,
I had them go ahead without me.
I see.
I'm really sorry about yesterday!
For what?
W-Well, for...
Do you like Hikari?
Wh-What are you talk—
Well, I guess I do...
I mean, we've been friends since we
were little, and we're always together,
so he's practically family...
I see.
Can you be my red-bellied
sea slug for a minute?
What?
I actually like him as more than just a friend.
But if I keep on liking him,
I may end up becoming someone I don't like.
I wouldn't be able to forgive myself if—
Stop.
Wait!
Manaka!
I-I'm sorry!
I was worried about you,
so I went back to get you.
But I didn't hear anything, really!
Like about me liking Hii-kun?
Exactly. Like about you liking Hii-kun.
Please forget what you heard, Manaka.
Huh?
Just pretend you never heard it, please?
B-But...
Please!
O-Okay...
I will.
Hey, don't even think
of trying anything funny!
I wasn't!
Now, now. Let's take this more seriously!
We don't want to mess up
during the festival, do we now?
Wh-What's with you?
Well, you smell.
So I don't want to get too close.
That makes two of us!
I don't wanna get close to you either.
Ow!
Hey, sea girl, you're standing on my foot!
Chii-chan...
You're doing it again!
Saya Mart
Akari.
I'd really like you to hear me out.
—
———
Triangle
We should break up.
I don't want to hurt Miuna-chan any more.
That's what was on your mind too, right, Itaru-san?
Well...
I've had it wrong this whole time,
ever since Miori-san died.
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
The whole time...
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Always
Smiling
Saya
Mart
Aka-chan!
Miuna, you're heavy!
Hey, what's for dinner tonight?
Come on now, Miuna.
Thanks for coming by all the time, Akari-chan.
You don't have to trouble yourself, though.
Oh, it's no trouble.
Seeing Miuna-chan brings me a lot of joy.
Joy costs a hundred yen!
What? Now you're charging me?
That wasn't a lie.
Miuna-chan is very precious to me.
I really wish things
could've stayed as they were.
I wonder how it'll go
when we tell her about us.
It'll go fine!
I mean, Miuna loves you, Akari-chan.
And so do I, of course.
Uh, well...
But it was a mistake after all.
Miuna!
"A mistake"?
Please don't put it like that.
I didn't come here to break up with you.
I just think we may have gone too fast.
But Miuna likes you too,
so if we just take our time—
No...
Time has nothing to do with it.
You've known for a while
what needs to be done, right?
Miuna-chan.
Wait.
It's okay.
I'll get lost.
So you don't need to worry anymore.
I'm sorry for putting you through so much pain.
Get l
Hold your horses.
This is the Sakishima resi—
Go and ask Uroko-sama if a little girl fell into the sea earlier today!
What?
Akari?
What are yo—
Miuna-chan hasn't come home yet!
Miuna?!
And her friend hasn't seen her either!
What am I gonna do?!
This is all my fault!
It's my fault that Miuna-chan—
Calm down, Akari!
I'll find her for you!
What are you talking about?!
It's already late.
Just leave the searching to the adults.
You should be—
Quit treating me like a kid!
What?
No matter how much you
try to act all grown-up,
you can't replace our mom!
Huh?
So...
hurry up and go be Miuna's new mom!
Hikari...
I just checked with Uroko-sama.
She didn't fall into the ocean.
It's gonna be okay.
Dad...
Go.
All right, I'm hanging up.
Hikari!
Where the hell is she?
The mountain's the only spot we haven't checked yet.
It's been getting chilly at night, too.
I hope she's okay.
Damn it.
Talk about a problem child.
Nothing less from the daughter of that lecherous old ma—
The hell do you think you're—
Don't say bad things about my dad.
Miuna-chan!
Miuna!
I'm never going home.
B-But
everyone's really worried
about you, especially your dad.
No, they're not.
Of course they're worried!
They're all out looking for you!
I'm alone.
What should we do?
Oh, my family has an extra futon for guests!
Miuna can't go to Shioshishio!
Well, since it's still summer, I guess it isn't all that chilly.
Miuna-chan!
Triangle
Akari!
Akari, they said they found Miuna!
What?
The fishery cooperative got a call from Hikari-kun.
He said he wants us to
leave everything to him for tonight.
He actually found her...
Akari?
Are you all right?
I'm in love with you.
And I love Miuna-chan and Miori-san.
And even though Hikari rejected me, I love him, too.
I love all of you.
Akari?
It's just like Hikari always says.
I'm a child.
I'm greedy.
I'm possessive of everyone I love.
I know what I have to do,
but even so!
I can't bring myself to give up!
I don't wanna give up!
Yeah...
I don't want to give up on
all of us being happy, either.
Look, I caught some!
Oh, good job.
Where'd you get all that stuff?
This place only closed down this spring,
so the pots and plates
and everything were left here.
Cool.
Chisaki, let's see you
make a better meal than me.
I guess we have to gut these.
Chii-chan...
Kaname and I will do that,
so in the meanwhile, could you
take Miuna and go get some more fish?
You too, Hikari.
These two won't be nearly enough.
Yeah, yeah.
Is this edible?
Oh, a sea slug?
Well, I guess you could eat them.
I figured.
I suppose red-bellied ones really are rare.
That one from the other day
must've been special.
Red-bellied ones?
You can eat the ones with green bellies,
but the red-bellied ones are for talking to.
If you tell one your most private feelings,
it'll tell you all sorts of things,
or something like that.
Yeah.
And even if it doesn't,
I guess it can make you feel a little better anyway.
I have something like that, too.
There's something I've been using instead of a sea slug.
Get l
Huh?
If you find a red-bellied one, what will you tell it?
This is my special miso soup, so eat up!
If I find another red-bellied
sea slug, what should I tell it?
You're always making this, Hikari.
Yeah, I'm starting to wonder if it's all you can make.
I wonder what it is that I want answers to...
Then you make something!
Thanks for helping me find her, you guys.
You sure everything's gonna be okay?
Yeah, it'll all work out somehow.
See you later.
Yeah.
S-See you.
The stars tonight are
pretty amazing, aren't they?
You know...
Akari's a really good person.
Though hearing that from her brother probably doesn't count for much.
Anyway, don't hate her, okay?
Nope. I definitely will.
You said you're alone,
and yet, there are all these people who love you.
Are not.
Sure there are. I mean—
No, there aren't!
I wish there weren't!
"Miuna" is written with the characters for "beautiful sea."
Miuna
Mommy loves the sea.
If you love it,
how come you don't live there?
Because I love you way more, Miuna!
I love you too, Mommy!
I love, love, love you!
That tickles!
What the hell do you think you're doing?!
I can't swim!
Why can't I?!
Mommy's from the sea!
So why can't I swim?!
Quit struggling!
You smell like Mommy and Aka-chan.
"Aka-chan"?
You mean Akari?
When Mommy died, I was really, really sad.
It was like I couldn't breathe.
So Aka-chan always stayed with me,
and then I really started to like her.
But when Dad said Aka-chan might be my new mom,
I got scared.
If someone I love went away again,
just like Mommy did, I wouldn't know what to do.
I don't want to be that sad ever again.
If I don't love anyone, I won't be so sad!
That's why... That's why I...
If you don't love them...
If you don't love them, it won't be painful.
You might actually have a point.
Huh?
I'm in no position to talk.
I mean, I guess I also think it might be easier not to love someone.
But even so...
I don't wanna believe it's hopeless or useless to love someone.
Wh-What are you staring at?
Do you have someone you love, too?
Well, yeah... There's lots of people I love.
Lots?
Uh, yeah.
And now I even love you too.
Hey! How long do you plan on holding me?!
Oh, r-right...
Th-There you go.
Are you a dollicon?
Dolly?
I heard that people who like
grade school girls are called "dollicons."
From Sayu.
It's lolicon, not dollicon!
And I'm nothing like that!
There's something I need your help with.
Huh?
My own sea slug...
Saya Mart
You're early, Akari-chan.
Oh, I couldn't sleep.
Man, my jaw hurts.
That was way too much gum.
Akari!
Stupid!
Stupid Miuna!
A-Akari! Calm do—
Of course I'm not going anywhere!
I'm not going anywhere.
I'll always be by your side, Miuna!
I'll always be by your side along with Miori-san!
With... Mommy?
Of course!
Even if I wanted to,
I could never replace Miori-san.
But even so!
I wanna be myself and stay by your side!
Right by your side!
So, Miuna, please just stay as you are,
and let me stay by your side forever...
Don't Get lost
Aka-chan...
Your eyes are so blue,
and your tears look like waves.
They're so pretty.
They're just like the sea.
Miuna...
You know...
I really love the sea.
Good grief.
Which one's the kid here, again?
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
They really are big, Hiradaira-san.
...you're not my type.
...today seemed like the
perfect day for Tomoebi.
He's way too fast.
Episode Six
Beyond Tomoebi