See ya.
S-See you later...
I've never seen something so beautiful.
The scales on this fish are very unique.
Oh, the fish...
And you.
Man, this sake's pretty weak.
It tastes like dog piss.
Perfect timing.
Just the thing to go with my sake.
Um...
What is it?
Take that!
Take that, and that,
and that, and that!
This doesn't taste like
.your grandma made it.
I-I made it.
Oh?
I just did something
.rather rude to you,
and on top of that, I wasted food!
Aren't you going to curse me again?
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Two
Cold Film
Good morning!
U-Um...
Th-Thank you for yesterday.
Feeling better?
Y-Yes! I'm perfectly fine now!
And how about him?
"Him"?
U-Um...
I'm doing great.
I-I mean...
Thanks for taking care
.of Manaka yesterday.
Hii?
But lemme say this.
Surface people have got no business
concerning themselves with the ocean village.
Jeez...
Hii!
Hii! That was really rude of you!
Come on!
I heard all about it! Thanks to him,
you had a rough time, right?
Huh? That's not true.
Didn't the surface people
put you through a lot?
Well, he's guilty by association!
B-But... Tsumugu saved me!
"Tsu-mu-gu"?!
Huh? Wh-Why are you getting so upset?
Why are you acting so
buddy-buddy with him?!
What?
O-Okay, then... Mr. Tsumugu?
W-Well, I don't know his last name!
You've been acting weird lately, Hii!
You're always so angry!
Oh, is that right?
Huh?
What's the matter, Manaka?
I-I messed up!
Messed up what?
Tsumugu saved me.
But even though Hii
.worried about me a lot too,
I got mad at him.
I really messed up!
Yeah.
Hikari was really worried
.about you, Manaka.
Chii.
Really worried.
Even though his Ena was dry
.and he couldn't breathe that well,
he was determined to find you.
Y-Yeah...
Hikari isn't really mad at you,
so try not to act so afraid of him, okay?
That'll only annoy him more.
All right.
Chii, how do you know all this?
About how both of us feel, I mean.
Well... It must be because I've known you since we were really young.
Both you...
and Hikari.
Hey. Hold it right there, you sea slug!
Huh?
You're those kids from the other day...
Do you know that lady?
What lady?
Oh.
So you know her?
She's my older sister.
Liar! You octopus head!
"O-Octopus"?
He was acting real close with her.
They've gotta be boyfriend
.and girlfriend, Miuna.
Uh, I don't really know
.what's going on here,
but shouldn't you two be in school?
Your teacher's gonna get mad—
Don't treat me like a brat, you brat!
I don't need to hear
.that from some brat.
What's the matter?
I see you've brought
backup, you coward!
Seriously, you're one to talk.
Come on, Hikari.
You shouldn't be
.picking on little kids.
Are you okay?
G-Get your fishy-smelly
hands away from me!
Oh, sorry.
Ow!
Sayu!
Serves you rice!
What the hell!
All right. That's it for today.
Oh, that's right.
Who here wants to try
making a Wooden Maiden?
What's a "Wooden Maiden"?
Isn't that the doll we send off
in the Boatdrift Ceremony?
Yes, that's right.
When we first started performing
.the Boatdrift Ceremony,
a girl would be sent off on a boat
.as a sacrifice to the sea god.
Big Catch
Nowadays, instead of an actual girl,
we send off a carved doll
.called a Wooden Maiden.
Why do we gotta make
the Wooden Maidens?
Aren't the adults supposed
to be doing this kinda stuff?
Oh yeah, I heard they're not doing
.the Boatdrift Ceremony this year.
That's correct...
which is why we were thinking of doing something
.like a voluntary Boatdrift Ceremony at our school.
What?
What the heck?
What a pain.
Hikari, calm down.
Isn't there anyone who wants to do it?
All right! Tsumugu.
Why's it gotta be us?
This is something the surface people
are supposed to do!
Well then, you shouldn't have volunteered.
The surface people don't have a clue.
That's why we've gotta
keep an eye on 'em.
Jeez.
So why did you volunteer for this?
My family are fishermen.
We live off the sea, so the Boatdrift Ceremony is my way of giving something back to it.
I heard that Lord Uroko actually exists.
Huh? Yeah.
He's sort of like a
.pervy old man, though.
I'd say he's kind of in between
.an old man and a young guy.
I see. So he does exist.
Then what about saltflake snow?
Like, when salt falls down like snow.
Oh, and if spirit fire
.can burn underwater,
then how do you get it to go out?
Tsumugu, you're really
rather knowledgeable!
About Shioshishio, I mean.
Yeah.
On days when the sun's really bright
and the light refracts in the right way,
you can sometimes catch a glimpse
.of the ocean village.
White roofs reflect
.light between the swells.
And almost like the sound
.of the waves themselves,
I can hear singing drifting up—
.sometimes far, sometimes near.
I like the ocean village.
I'm surprised someone on the surface
cares so much about our village!
Isn't it great?
What are you talking about?!
Oh, it's about time for you sea kiddos
to head home, isn't it?
We can take it from here.
Thank you!
Bye!
Thanks for your hard work!
Get home safely!
Teach.
I have something to ask of you.
Our teacher just called us "sea kiddos"!
I heard! It was actually kind of cute.
I admit he doesn't seem like a bad guy.
But even so...
Hey, isn't that Akari?
Akari?
She k-k-k-ki—
Manaka, shh!
I wonder if that's her boyfriend.
She never even mentioned having one!
And to top it off, it's a
guy from the surface?!
Akari's just about old enough
to get married, huh?
I wonder if she's planning
.to leave the village.
What?
There's no way it'd work out
.with a guy from the surface.
Even if they got married,
she'd end up coming right back.
Huh?
That's not possible.
Not possible? Why not?
Of course it's not possible!
I mean, Akari looks like she's
.going to be a great mom.
So of course she wouldn't
.come right back.
That's not what I meant.
If you get into a relationship
with someone from the surface,
you get permanently
.banished from the village.
"Banished"?
What the hell?! That's awful.
What are you yelling at me for?
I believe that rule's been around
.for quite some time.
Well, this is the first
I've ever heard of it!
But Satsuki from the candy store
and Koji from Hara's family
went up to the surface and never came back, remember?
I always thought that the people who didn't come back
discarded the sea and
.didn't want to come back.
That's so mean!
Manaka?
There's nothing wrong with wanting to be family
.with someone who's precious to you.
It's a wonderful thing!
To chase them out of the sea like that...
Does that mean... you're thinking of
getting with a guy from the surface, too?
Q-Quit it!
I hate it when you say
perverted things, Hii!
And I hate it when you say
perverted things, Manaka!
But I didn't say anything perverted!
You did too!
In fact, you've been
grossing me out a lot lately!
Manaka, wait!
I can understand how you feel,
but don't you think you went too—
What do you mean you "understand"?!
Where do you get off, always
pretending to be so grown-up?
You act like such a know-it-all.
What the hell do you know about me?!
You shouldn't get so angry.
What?
Though I can understand why
.you'd be irritated with Manaka.
See ya.
What the hell is with them?
Repeating that they understand
...like a broken record...
while even I...
don't really understand how I'm feeling.
This saltflake snow is pretty intense...
especially since no one
bothers cleaning it up.
It would've been nice if we could've stayed at Namiji Middle School.
Even you think about things like that sometimes, huh?
Huh?
Things like wanting to
.stay here forever, I mean.
You know, it's not that I don't like
...the people on the surface...
It's just that I want to
.stay in the sea forever.
With Manaka and you... and Hikari.
Don't you just want to stay here because
feeling like that is what's comfortable?
Huh?
Once you long for other places,
life starts to get harder.
I'm surprised.
I'm surprised that Manaka
was the first one of us
to take the first step outta here.
Akiyoshi, Ukita, Kamon...
Kihara Tsumugu!
Kihara, Kihara, Kihara!
All right.
Now Hii won't get angry anymore.
Kihara...
If they got your DNA, it sucks to be them.
You idiot! You saw the footage!
It was super cute!
Oh, man!
H-Hey, Akari...
Today, you—
And this is our baby!
So cute!
My, isn't she cute! Does she
resemble you more?
Aww, it's a girl! I'm so envious.
When I have a kid,
I want it to be a girl, too.
Well, she might have her father's eyes.
Wha—
I wanted a younger sister.
Lately, she started mimicking me.
Have you seen her do it?
I was totally bummed when you came out.
I haven't, but how does she mimic you?
What was that?!
I really am envious...
When I say "me," she says it back, and
when I say "mo," she says that back too!
But if I say "memo"—
If you get into a relationship with
.someone from the surface,
you get permanently
.banished from the village.
And she's only gonna continue
to grow. Isn't that right?
Yes, it's a lot of work,
but every day is a lot of fun!
Spoken like a true mo—
What happened to that girl from Shioshishio?
Oh...
She's fine.
I see.
A guy from the surface, huh?
I just... wanted to protect her.
I wanted to protect her like Ena does.
I wanted to protect her from anything
.and everything that could hurt her.
And yet...
She wants to just discard all that?
To discard everything...
and go to a different world...
I wonder how big the kimono should be.
Oh, um...
Tsumu—
Kihara!
What is it?
U-Um...
We were wondering how wide around
the waist the Wooden Maiden is.
Lemme check.
I wonder why it still sounds perverted
even though I used his last name.
Oh! N-Nothing.
How's he doing today?
He seems to be sleeping...
I see.
Sixty-five centimeters.
Thank you.
So Manaka really does like him...
And besides, if Manaka's
ever out of the picture,
you'll be the one by his side.
I'm terrible!
What am I thinking?!
This is...
Apparently, they used
.to keep carp there.
Oh! I-I'm sorry.
I missed some garbage.
It's a little small for
.four people to get in, though.
"Four people"?
Oh!
I figured it'd get annoying always
.having to worry about the time.
And Teach said it'd be fine to use this.
What? You're going to
make a pond just for us?
Would it be a bother?
N-No, not at all! Thank you!
That's good, then.
That girl with the really round eyes...
You mean Manaka?
I hope her fish is happy about it, too.
Her fish?
Please don't be so
.kind to Manaka anymore.
Manaka already has...
Hikari.
Terrace Road
Shrine Road
Central
Road
Ocean
Bridge
I beg of you, please curse me!
Why is it you wanna be cursed again?
Um, w-well...
Because it hurts to lie.
Why lie, then?
When you put it like that,
I don't really know.
Up till now, you've always had
.someone protecting you.
Hikari, Chisaki, Kaname...
You should've just kept floundering
.along behind them.
But now, you're about to go somewhere
.they can't protect you.
So maybe you need a little lie
.or two to protect yourself.
Huh?
Please let me go!
Stop—
Get over here, Akari.
We're gonna have you explain everything
.in front of Lord Uroko.
Let go of me! I'll tell my dad myself!
What's going on?!
Akari?!
Oh, Hii!
This doesn't concern you two.
Just stay out of—
Wait. It's about time
.they found out too.
They should find out just what happens
.when you break the rules of this village.
What do you mean, "what happens"?
What's going on here?
Dad!
You're finally here, Head Priest.
Akari is seeing a guy on the surface.
Someone saw them!
I'd like you all to leave for today.
But, Head Priest...
I will talk to Akari myself.
But, Head Priest, this is a problem.
If someone from your own family
.leaves for the surface,
it's gonna look really bad.
I'm aware of that.
You guys leave too.
Huh? B-But...
Akari...
My hand floats in warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu te toridasu
I take some string, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning myself into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
My hand floats in warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu te toridasu
I take some string, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning myself for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
into a cocoon that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
You're so cute!
...you've got crappy taste in guys.
You can say that again.
Did Lord Uroko just pass gas?
Akari's crying because of you!
Episode Three
The
Legend
of the Sea
The
Legend
of the Sea
This one's a storm.