By "Dad," you mean him?
Don't tell me he's having an affair, too.
You want me to break them up? How?
You're the one in junior high.
You figure it out, octopus head!
You.
What's your name?
Miuna.
Sayu!
I don't like your dad either.
He's got a kid, and yet he put
the moves on a younger woman!
He's not fit for Akari—for my big sister.
Your sister's the one
who put the moves on him!
But even so...
Hey!
D-Don't touch her!
I don't like playing
dirty like you, Miuna.
See ya.
Wh-What's his problem?!
He won't get away with that!
Miuna, let's just cook him!
We'll turn him into fried octopus!
Miuna?
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Four
Because We're Friends
Wow, that's amazing, Hii!
You're so good at this.
It's no big deal...
You seem to be enjoying
the praise all the same.
You're really good too, Tsumugu.
Where'd you learn how to cook?
I taught myself.
It's always been just
Gramps and me, after all.
I see! That's so responsible of you.
W-We don't need that
much Chinese cabbage.
It's delicious!
Now, why don't we all go around to
the other groups and try their food too?
Okay.
Huh?
Lemme try some of yours.
What is this? The carrot's huge.
What should we do?
I'm not sure...
E-Excuse me!
If you'd like...
please try ours too!
Manaka!
Try yours?
As if sea people could make
anything even remotely edible.
It smells like fish, too.
Right?
B-But there isn't any fish in it.
I don't want any.
But I really think it's fine—
I said I don't want any!
You bastards...
Apologize.
Tsumugu...
What for?
It was just an accident.
Yeah...
Right?
Now, what's going on here?
Sorry...
Aren't you going to eat your lunch?
We just ate.
I'm gonna go work
on the Wooden Maiden.
Oh, I'll come with you!
Hey, don't you think we should
try to get along with them a bit more?
You mean with the guys that waste food?
Wood Shop Room
This is terrible!
Who would do something like this?
It was them.
Wait, Hikari!
Half-arm suplex!
Come on, q-quit it!
Chest!
Hikari!
It was indeed reprehensible that the Wooden Maiden was broken.
We had nothing to do with that!
Quit lying!
Who else would've done it?!
Hey, come on. Please stop.
Hii!
It seems you're too worked up for this to get resolved today.
We should come back to it tomorrow.
Right.
Hikari, you can go home for today.
I'm the only one you're sending home?!
Are you saying I'm
the only one at fault here?
Hikari!
Well, excuse me!
Hikari...
I'm going home too.
You too?
But you can't.
You still have fourth period...
I want to go home,
so I'm going home!
W-Well...
Manaka's so stubborn
when she gets like that.
Man, this isn't coming off at all.
Manaka's so cute.
She may be a scaredy cat,
but she has a strong will,
a really slender body,
and big, round eyes.
And she's always trying so hard.
And you're big.
You're too blunt, Kaname.
There are guys who prefer
taller girls too, you know.
You think so?
And apparently, middle-aged men prefer girls who aren't so skinny.
I saw it on TV.
You could've left that part out.
You should just be honest
with yourself and be happy.
You're right.
I probably should learn to
be more honest, like Manaka.
Sayu wuz heer!
"Sayu wuz heer"?
Sayu?
Do you know her?
Yeah.
She's one of those mysterious grade schoolers who have a grudge against Hikari.
Grade schoolers?
That's a pretty straightforward
admission of guilt.
It wasn't the guys
from our class after all.
Chisaki?
Let's keep this a secret.
Let's pretend we didn't see it, Kaname.
Huh? Why?
Because if everyone else
finds out about this,
Hikari will wind up
looking like the bad guy.
But—
I can't see him get hurt
or blamed any more!
But bad guy or not, the truth is
that it was a misunderstanding.
It's not good to lie.
It'll only isolate you even more.
You're wrong, though!
These are the people who said our food smelled like fish!
They're not bad people
once you get to know them.
The same people who spilled our sushi bowl on purpose?!
I thought you were a
good person, Tsumugu,
but I guess you're just like any other person from the surface.
Don't take it personally.
Chisaki loses her head when it comes to Hikari or Manaka.
I understand.
I love both the sea and
the people of Shishio.
That's why I don't want everyone to misunderstand
Hikari just because he misunderstands all of them.
Sorry, but could you repeat that?
I don't want everyone to misunderstand Hikari
just because he misunderstands all of them.
I see.
Get l
I don't like playing dirty like you, Miuna.
Miuna!
I did it!
I really showed 'em this time!
Huh?
Remember how they were
making a Wooden Maiden?
Well, I totally trashed it!
Trashed it?
Yeah!
I drew all over it, and then
I ripped up its clothes!
Now you can't even tell it's a
Wooden Maiden anymore! Like, at all!
Why would you do that?
Huh?
That's really playing dirty!
M-Miuna?!
I hate playing dirty like that!
Miuna!
Hii, wait!
Why'd you follow me?
An octopus.
Here, boy...
Octopuses are cowards.
You know, you're kind of like an octopus.
Now you're calling me an octopus too?!
Huh? "Too"?
Oh, never mind...
When they get scared by fish
they don't know, they spit out ink.
Like, dark black stuff.
The ink tastes really good, though.
Like when it's in squid ink pasta.
Or should it be "octopus ink" pasta?
I've never made it, so—
What are you trying to say?
Wh-What was it again?
Hey, why'd you ask them to try
our sushi bowl in the first place?
Huh?
You normally don't do stuff like that.
You're usually hiding behind us.
That's because...
Another octopus?
No, look!
That's... Akari's boyfriend!
Hii, the bottom's turning black!
What?
You can't even make
rice porridge by yourself?
I guess we can add some
miso to mask the taste.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I caused you trouble...
Sorry.
There's something else you should be apologizing for, you criminal.
C-Criminal?
You have a kid, and yet you
put the moves on my big sister.
So what the hell were you
drowning yourself for?
I haven't been able to contact Akari.
She won't even come to the supermarket.
So I thought I'd go see her myself.
Go see her? In Shioshishio?
Yeah.
I borrowed some diving
equipment from my friend,
but it kept filling up with water—
Where do you get off
playing the victim?!
S-Stop it, Hii!
You're a criminal! A lowlife!
Having an affair is totally unforgivable—
Lord Uroko, lemme have some spirit fire.
You're quite the sinner,
walking over the servant of a god.
That's fine.
Even though I spent so much time cleaning up around here and doing things for you,
I still ended up miserable.
How long are you gonna
keep ditching work?
I've been thinking about
finding a job down here...
though there aren't that many options.
Are you going to give up on him just because his daughter didn't approve of you?
Despite being cooped up in here all the time,
you sure know a lot of gossip.
It's only been three years
since she lost her mother.
I understand why she
can't approve of me.
Her mother's name was Miori, I believe.
And she lived in a house just off the rocks.
So you remember her.
Indeed.
She was a real beauty with a sweet ass.
Even though Miori had been banished, she wasn't bitter toward me.
Triangle
And Miuna was so cute.
She acted like my baby sister.
Both of them, and Itaru too... They were the perfect family.
They were always smiling.
But then...
at Miori's funeral...
Miuna was bawling.
I had never seen her cry like that.
It somehow reminded me of
Hikari when he was younger.
And right then...
I thought to myself
that I wanted to stay beside them.
I thought I could maybe
fill the hole Miori left behind.
Don't you think you're
sugarcoating it a bit?
This is just forbidden love.
Miori was gone, and you
wanted to take her place.
That's harsh, Lord Uroko.
I could put a curse on you, if you want.
A curse?
A curse to make you forget
the man you fell for.
I don't need you to do that.
I can take care of this on my own.
She's still such a child.
There's only so much
you can do on your own.
I know, Lord Sea God.
We can't hand over the people
of the sea to the surface just yet.
The Wooden Maiden.
Huh?
I did it.
What?
I'm the one who ruined it!
Why?
Why didn't you get mad at her, Hii?
Because it's not like
I don't know how she feels.
Huh?
When my mom died, if some other
woman had tried to come into my house,
I probably wouldn't have liked it either.
Wh-Why are you crying?!
Lord Uroko told me
that I always rely on you and
Chii and Kaname to protect me.
Lord Uroko said that?
And I think it's true.
Lord Uroko says something useful every now and then.
Hii, you're kind.
Really kind.
You put others before
yourself and protect them...
Tomorrow, let's go and
apologize to everyone together!
Yeah.
Though I bet they're gonna have a lot to say in return.
Then they'll have
a lot to say to me, too.
Huh?
I want to protect you from now on, Hii.
I will protect you.
Manaka...
Thanks.
Yup!
Manaka...
I was supposed to be
the one to protect her.
But instead, she protected me,
just like Ena does.
Hey.
Do you two have a sec?
What do you want?
Hikari!
I'm really sorry!
I was wrong!
I thought...
I mean, I'm sorry I thought it was you who destroyed the Wooden Maiden.
Th-That's enough, Hikari.
Dude, he's totally on his knees.
I never saw anyone do that.
Manaka!
Please!
Manaka?
Hii feels really bad.
Please forgive him.
Please!
Manaka...
Forgive them already.
Tsumugu.
You're the ones responsible for their
sushi bowl spilling, so let's just call it even.
But it's not!
It's true you guys
spilled our sushi bowl!
But I blamed you for it,
and then I tackled you!
Huh?
So forgive me,
and then...
come at me!
Hii...
Come on!
Chest!
Ow...
Enough already. This is annoying.
I forgive you.
Do you ever go to school?
Y-You!
You know, you're the one to blame for
Hikari getting down on his knees like that.
Hikari is my best friend.
And as his best friend, I can't let that go.
But I'm... I'm Miuna's friend too!
Huh?
She's my very bestest friend!
When I was in second grade,
everyone used to pick on me.
But Miuna never did.
So then, people started
picking on her instead.
And I was kind of relieved,
since it wasn't me who was getting picked on anymore.
But Miuna...
No matter how much they ignored her,
she was totally fine.
Hey.
How can you be okay with this?
Why are you okay with getting bullied and with people not liking you?
Because it doesn't matter.
They're people I don't care about,
and they have nothing to do with me.
So I don't care what they think of me.
When she said that,
I stopped caring what people
thought about me, too.
I didn't even care if people hated me.
All that mattered was that
Miuna and I were friends!
Can you apologize to Hikari?
Huh?
Since you understand how dear
someone can be to you, you can, right?
Yeah.
Good girl.
I-I-I'm... really sorry!
And so, please forgive her.
It was you?
Hii.
Then why did she...
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
Man, how lame.
You've got snot coming out your nose.
Sh-Shut up, you octopus—
Lord Octopus!
Adding a "Lord" doesn't just make everything better!
I...
I wanted to defend Hikari...
But...
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
...you can't replace our mom!
I guess you're a man of the sea after all...
Can you be my red-bellied
sea slug for a minute?
If you find a red-bellied one, what will you tell it?
Episode Five
Hey, Sea Slug