Once, when we were little,
Manaka and I got lost.
We wanted to go look for coral, so we went to the far edge of the village,
but then we became so preoccupied with our search that we got lost.
When we got hungry and exhausted,
right when we were about to cry,
the person who came to our rescue
was Hikari.
Without saying a word,
he took us by the hands and led us home.
Even now,
I can vividly recall the way his eyes were focused straight ahead
and the way he held my hand.
Which is why
when I heard that Hikari
had found Manaka,
I wasn't all that surprised.
I think I knew somewhere in my heart that it was bound to happen.
And from that same place in my heart,
I knew that if anyone could find her, it would be Hikari.
furitsumoru konayuki ga mau
Little snowflakes dance in the air
akiramekaketa yume ga mata namiutsu
I'd almost given up on my dream, but it washes in again,
ano hi no mama de
like it did so long ago
kawaranai egao mitsumeta
I watched your frozen smile,
somaru hoho ni fureta kaze ga
and the wind turning my cheeks red
sora takaku nuketa
disappeared high into the sky
I was always looking at you, never far away,
and yet you seemed out of my reach.
doushite
Why?
to toikaketa koe mo yureru
Even your voice is rough as it asks me
yurayura minamo ni ukanda
The moon's reflection quivered on the waters,
tsuki wa nanimo kataranai
and it told us nothing about the future
tada no boukansha
The moon merely watched us
onaji ne nigiru te ga itai
We hold hands even though it hurts
Episode Nineteen
The Lost, Lost Little...
Now then...
given her rate of recovery,
taking care of her here should be fine.
Really?!
Hikari!
Well, we've been closely examining her since yesterday,
and in my professional opinion,
she's quite healthy.
Her brain waves are normal too.
Based on you and Isaki waking up recently,
she should wake up soon as well.
Awesome!
Didn't I tell you, Akari?
Nothing at all to worry about!
Her Ena'll probably grow back, too.
Anyway, I'm just glad Manaka's okay.
Aren't you glad too?
Ow!
Akira...
Y-You little—Oh, right.
Doctor, Chisaki... thanks.
Get back here!
They're so lively.
Up your butt!
You fool! Like I'd keep
falling for the same attack!
With these two around,
I'm positive she'll wake up in no time.
Behold my special move,
the Butt Counterattack!
This is so embarrassing.
Wh-What are you...
Seriously.
Butt Counter-Counterattack!!
Hikari must be very happy
now that Manaka is back.
Thank you so much for all your help.
Hiradaira,
feel free to hand in your nurse's log
by tomorrow morning.
Yes, sir.
This is my first time seeing you in your new uniform. It looks good on you.
I almost didn't recognize you.
I haven't gotten used to it yet either.
It still feels like I'm just playing dress-up.
Since you're here,
want to have some tea?
Well, I suppose I could
impose on you a bit more.
Hey...
Manaka,
hurry and wake up, okay?
The Boatdrift Ceremony...
Both Dad and Lord Uroko
had told us it'd be useless,
but I was expecting something the whole time.
I told myself something would happen.
I was sure of it.
But then, something that terrible wound up happening.
Did you save Akari?
What exactly happened that day?
You'd said that, after the Boatdrift Ceremony, you had something to tell me, right?
That day, even though I kept reaching for you, I couldn't get to you.
But never again.
Even if you want me to, I'm never gonna let go of you again.
I see.
So Miuna likes Hikari too.
It's so cute...
The way she puts everything into caring for him and yet can't seem to take the next step.
I always thought of her as just a child,
but now that I think about it,
she's the same age now
that we were back then.
I see.
And I'm almost the age that Akari was.
You worried about that girl
from the sea village?
Yes...
I believe she'll wake up soon, but...
she's lost her Ena.
She lost her Ena?
You mentioned that they found her sleeping in the graveyard of Wooden Maidens, right?
Do you know something about all this?
There's more to the legend about the sea god and the Wooden Maiden.
More to the legend?
Not many like to talk about it.
It's a story with a sad ending.
What?
You haven't said much since you got back from the village.
Is something wrong?
Not really.
More importantly, Chisaki,
how's Manaka doing?
I haven't had the chance to go see her.
Oh, right.
The doctor said that there's
nothing to worry about.
That's good.
Yeah, now you two will have more data to sit on top of.
"Sit on top of"?
It seems that neither Mihashi nor Tsumugu plan to announce their data
about our excursion into Shioshishio or about Miuna's Ena for quite some time.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Mihashi plans to put it all
into one research paper,
at which point, he'll send it to an academic journal,
and officially present it once it's published.
I can't say I agree with that.
Hikari, Miuna, and I didn't swim all the way to Shioshishio and put our lives in danger
just for the sake of your reputation.
Hey, Tsumugu.
You have a good reason for this, don't you?
If the paper isn't acknowledged by our peers,
we'll lose our research grants.
And that will put a stop to everything we've been working on...
finding the link between the weather and Shioshishio,
trying to prevent any more disasters—everything.
By that point, the media will probably get involved and cause Miuna a lot of trouble.
Jeez...
You never explain things without being asked first, Tsumugu.
Come on, Kaname.
Can't you give him a chance?
It's just... there's a lot going on, after all.
You're such an adult, Chisaki.
Thank you for dinner.
Kaname, wai—
Damn it.
"An adult," huh?
Wow!
This brings back memories!
Huh?
What? You've gotta be kidding.
There we go!
Oh no... It's so small.
Chisaki, the bathwater's getting cold.
O-Okay, I'll be right there!
Eek!
What happened?
Chisaki, I'm coming in!
H-Hey, wait!
H-How long do you plan
on staring, you idiots?!
S-Sorry!
Sorry.
Jeez...
Are you hungry?
Oh, it's just you, Tsumugu.
Jeez, don't sneak up on me like that.
Pickled Shallots
Chili Oil
Marinated in Soy
Oh...
Um, well, I was just looking for Grandpa's plum wine.
You're still a minor, you know.
So what!
I can drink some if I want!
After all, I'm this lonely housewife who's suuuch an adult!
Just a minute.
I'll prepare it for you.
Plum Wine
That's not how you're supposed to drink it, you know.
Hmph!
I was told that alcohol tastes better when you're an adult. Apparently it's true!
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
Non-Alcoholic
Plum
Juice
You're saying that after just drinking this...
Even if it's just plum wine,
it's alcohol all the same!
Yeah, it sure is.
Quit trying to act like an adult.
Another!
I feel great.
I wanna go see Shioshishio.
Maybe I'll go after all.
Today,
Hikari was talking to Manaka while she slept.
That didn't come as too much of a shock, of course.
But then...
I doubt I'll have that look in my own eyes ever again.
I may have grown up physically,
but it seems like I still haven't
matured emotionally.
Does becoming an adult mean that you have to lose things?
There probably is a lot you wind up losing.
But that just means you've gotta replace what you lost with something new.
These last five years we've spent together have been like that for me.
You're not planning on doing anything more than that, are you?
I'm not.
We should get her to bed now, though.
Lend me a hand.
R-Right.
I never did tell you, did I?
Tell me what?
How grateful I was that you saved me
at the Boatdrift Ceremony.
Thank you.
There's no reason for you to be grateful.
And just to be clear, I'm not being modest or anything.
At that moment,
it really did cross my mind.
"If I just ignore him,
he'll disappear forever."
"And then, I'll be able to be with Chisaki."
"Don't save him."
"Just abandon him."
But you dove in after me anyway.
Besides, if you had been able to do something like that,
I would never have let you be with Chisaki.
So the truth comes out.
Yeah.
But...
I really am grateful that you guys came back.
Things have been up in the air this whole time.
But now, both Chisaki and I can move forward.
I drank so much, and yet I didn't get a hangover at all.
I guess I'm pretty strong.
So from this point, I have to dive down seven meters...
Directions to Shioshishio
I have to face it...
Then...
This current is really strong.
Um...
What? What's going on?
Chisaki!
Hikari?
Are you okay?
Yeah. Thank you.
You're usually so careful,
but sometimes you wind up
acting totally recklessly.
Huh? You think so?
Anyway, what are you doing here?
What do you mean?
Now that I know we can reach it,
of course I'd come to see the village.
Well, I guess you've got a point there.
When he held me just now, it surprised me.
He didn't feel rugged at all.
He was so different from the men I've had to examine as a nurse.
But of course he would be.
After all, his smile, his body,
and even his heart are...
You're exactly the same as you were five years ago... aren't you?
Huh?
Of course you are.
For you, the Boatdrift Ceremony happened just the other day.
That's true.
But you haven't changed either, you know.
You're the same Chisaki you always were.
Really?
I thought I'd changed quite a bit.
Nah, you haven't changed at all.
You still look like you're listening while you're actually not listening at all.
That's not true!
Also, you still get pissed off
whenever I tease you in the least.
Anyway, what about you, Hikari?
It's pretty early in the morning
for you to be visiting here, isn't it?
Yeah...
I just couldn't stay put.
I couldn't stop wondering why Manaka's Ena disappeared.
So I thought I might be able to figure something out if I went back to where we found her.
I see.
I don't know if this will help or not,
but Tsumugu's grandfather told me a story.
It's the next part of the story about the sea god and the Wooden Maiden.
There's another part?
The girl who married the sea god
eventually had children,
and their descendants flourished.
However, it is said that as time passed,
the girl became more and more depressed.
She was sad that she'd left behind the one she loved on the surface.
And since she could never forget about the man she loved,
she could also never forget the surface.
After learning of her sadness, the sea god tried desperately to make her happy.
But when he saw that she never truly would be,
he had no choice but to let her go back to the surface.
However, he took something in return.
He took something?
I've been thinking about it.
Maybe that "something" was her Ena.
Hikari?
The Wooden Maiden...
Something in return for
going to the surface...
Oh, sorry.
It was just a thought.
Grandpa also said this was passed down orally,
so he can't be sure how true it is.
All right!
I've got it!
What?
Lord Uroko!
I'm gonna find him and catch him.
What do you mean?
I'm positive he knows whether this part of the story is true.
And if it is, he'll probably know what needs to be done too!
To tell you the truth, I was out of ideas,
but now I know what I've gotta do.
Thanks, Chisaki!
But man, the sea god's such a selfish jerk.
I mean, taking people's Ena
just 'cause they don't obey him
and then randomly
..giving other people Ena...
What is he, a kid?
Maybe.
Maybe even after living for
hundreds and thousands of years,
he hasn't changed at all.
Yeah. But I'm sure that's
got nothing to do with it.
It's not about position or age. It's about your feelings.
Feelings?
I can't wait for Manaka to wake up.
I'm gonna get her Ena back no matter what,
and then I'm gonna help
Tsumugu with the surface.
I'm never gonna give up!
Oh... I understand now.
I really do still like Hikari.
And this is how, after Manaka returned,
our time that was frozen for five years finally started moving again.
That's what I thought at the time, at least.
But...
even after another week came and went,
there were still no signs
that Manaka would awaken.
mugon no kotoba de ayatori shite
I play a silent cat's cradle with my words,
jouzu ni dekita to warattemiru
and decide to grin in satisfaction
tokui na no wa dare ni mo kizukarenu you ni
The only thing that I am truly good at
kokoro oshikorosu koto sore hitotsu dake
is stifling my love so others won't find out
demo torimaku kirei na loop wa
It would be nice
yawai chikara de
if the love of those around me
taguriyosetekureru kara
drew me in gently
azayaka ni
Innocently
musunde kono kimochigoto
I tie my feelings into a rope
hanarenai you ni kataku kataku
so that we will never be apart
hitomusubi hito wo musunde
The knots tie us together,
kitai no yamanai saki he asu he yukou
so let us approach the future with hope in our hearts
Manaka!
Isn't that what princes are supposed to do?
Kiss the sleeping princess?
That's too boring.
What do you mean by that?
Maybe they don't want her to wake up?
Episode
Twenty
The
Sleeping
Beauty
The
Sleeping
Beauty