Wood Shop Room
Oh my, this is really...
I know, right?
Doesn't everything look
super awesome?
Ready, and...
We did it!
The light ocean breeze blew the hair from my shoulders
kata wo saratta awai shiokaze
Someone ran a distance away,
kakeru chiisana senaka wo
but all I did was look at their back silently
boku wa damatte tada mitsumeteta
from the immobility of my vantage point
fumidasenai hazama de
Warm sunlight streams into our classroom,
yawakarai hizashi tsutsumu kyoushitsu ni wa
and we are laughing in all the pictures that decorate the wall
kazatta shashintachi ga waratta mama
The future ahead of us is endless
tomedo nai asu ni kawaranai bokutachi wa
and promises us
nagu minamo no saki
calm seas
dokomade mo utsushite
This is all I need
kono mama de ii
In your eyes, I saw
sono hitomi ni yureteta hakanai
a faint love
omoi wo
that I will carry with me
sotto shimatte
Episode Seven
The Boatdrift
Ceremony
Shakes
The Boatdrift
Ceremony
Shakes
All of you did a really great job.
They woulda gotten nowhere without me and Miuna!
That's pretty funny coming from you.
In any case, this is truly amazing.
I'm very impressed.
Right?
We all worked really hard.
It was more fun than I thought it'd be, though.
I see! Well, I'd say this calls for popsicles!
Huh?
My treat!
Do you want Gori-Gori-kun pops or Home Base Bars?
So cheap!
Actually, Sensei, it's too cold for popsicles today anyway.
We even canceled swimming 'cause of it.
Oh, you have a point.
But sadly, they don't sell meat buns around this time of year.
I want to do the Boatdrift Ceremony...
Completely in sync.
Hot damn!
Well, aren't you two close!
They've totally got the hots for each other.
I-It's not like that! You've got it all wrong!
Now, now, no need to play dumb.
I wonder how far they've gone.
Ow!
That hurt...
a lot more than I thought it would.
Well, in a way, we're already doing the ceremony.
No, that's not what I meant.
I want to do it how they did it long ago...
Big Catch
with people from both the sea and the surface working together.
Can't we do it that way?
Hey, that's a great idea!
Yeah, after putting in so much effort, it'd be nice to see a real Boatdrift Ceremony!
But for that to happen, we'd need help from Shioshishio,
and that might be a bit of a problem.
What?
But if we're gonna do it anyway, we should do it right.
Don't you guys agree?
Yeah. I mean, we've already come this far.
Definitely.
I understand. I really do...
but unfortunately,
due to the disagreements between Shioshishio and the Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative,
it's not happening this year.
Let's do it!
We spent so much time and effort making everything,
so let's do it! A real Boatdrift Ceremony!
Wai— Hikari!
Hii-kun...
I'll do something about Shishio.
Tsumugu, you take lead and figure
something out on the Oshiooshi end.
Hikari...
I know you're set on this, but things may get rough.
I know that, but it's just...
I don't wanna do this halfheartedly, you know?
It may be hopeless, but I don't wanna leave behind any regrets just 'cause we didn't try.
All right. Count me in!
Me too!
Tsumugu, you too, right?
I wouldn't mind.
Yeah, me neither.
Yeah, why not!
Oh, this is terrific!
This is gonna be fun!
Yeah!
This is what youth's all about!
Okay! I'll help out as well.
Let's do this, everyone!
Yeah!
That was amazing, Hii-kun!
Everyone's so amazing!
I'll make sure we get to do the Boatdrift Ceremony, no matter what.
Yup!
I'll grant your and Tsumugu's wish.
Association
to Make
the
Boatdrift
Ceremony
a Reality
Association
to Make
the
Boatdrift
Ceremony
a Reality
Please!
Let's make this year's Boatdrift Ceremony a reality!
Please help us by signing one of these forms!
Please help us out!
Please!
Okay! We're definitely not gonna lose!
Right, Miuna?
Let's make this year's Boatdrift Ceremony a reality!
R-Right.
Please help us out!
Please help us o—
You're just gonna scare 'em off like that.
Please help us out!
We're trying to do the Boatdrift Ceremony!
Th-The Boatdrift Ceremony...
Here you go!
Thank you very much!
Much better. Just keep that up.
Please help us out!
We're part of Hama Middle School's Association to Make the Boatdrift Ceremony a Reality.
I heard they weren't doing it this year, though.
We're volunteers from
Hama Middle School.
We wanted to make the ceremony even bigger than last year's!
Are you sure you kids can handle it by yourselves?
Please sign this!
I promise you, we're serious about this.
Please!
Well, since you asked so nicely.
Thank you so much!
Hikari's amazing today.
Thank you!
Why's he so worked up over this?
He's probably going all out in order to distract himself from something.
But to think he had such a competitive side to him.
I guess there's more to people than meets the eye.
Ma'am! Pardon me, Ma'am.
Could you possibly spare me a moment of your time?
W-Well, I suppose if it's just for a moment...
I guess there is more to people than meets the eye.
I've got to work harder, too!
We're doing the Boatdrift Ceremony...
I don't think that suits you.
Huh?
Does that really matter, though?
I think so. I mean, people can
only do what's within their capacity.
When you try too hard to do something that's not in your capacity, you only wind up hurting yourself.
You guys are really going at it, huh?
Pretty impressive.
Dad!
Akari-san, thank you for talking to the manager for us.
Don't even mention it.
Besides, Sayama-kun is the manager's son, and he's helping out too.
Plus, I'd like to see a real Boatdrift Ceremony myself.
In that case, could you put these on display in the store?
Sure. Leave it to me!
If you give me some of those forms,
I'll be sure to get you some signatures, too.
Can you give me some as well?
I'd like to hand them out to some people I know.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I mean, getting the people of the surface and sea to work hand in hand...
It's something that matters to me too.
I want to do the Boatdrift Ceremony...
I'm gonna make it happen.
I look forward to it.
Definitely not.
Why not?!
Look how many signatures we got!
Can't you at least try talking to the fishing association?
Let's Do a Boatdrift Ceremony
This Year!!
Association to Make the Boatdrift Ceremony a Reality
The Boatdrift Ceremony is one of our historical traditions!
Let's Do a Boatdrift Ceremony
This Year!!
Association to Make the Boatdrift Ceremony a Reality
The Boatdrift Ceremony is one of our historical traditions!
I don't care how many you got.
They were the ones who said they wouldn't do it this year in the first place.
B-But...
Come on, Dad.
This is the first time Hikari's ever seriously asked you for anything.
What kind of parent would you be if you didn't at least listen?
I saw them collecting signatures earlier myself.
They were all working so hard.
The people of the surface won't listen.
There's no point in talking to them.
Dad—
I thought the guys on the surface were all pigs at first, too.
I thought there was no point in talking to 'em.
Plus, they thought of us as fish,
which made us even.
But we were all wrong!
We're not fish, and they're not pigs!
We're all people! And we can
communicate with each other!
We're serious about this!
Even if you only try once,
please get everyone together and try talking to them!
So you need my help, do you?
Fine, forget I even asked!
Just stay out of our way, then!
So everything went okay with the fishery cooperative?
It wasn't that hard, actually.
Right?
Yeah.
Although they didn't say much about the Boatdrift Ceremony,
I think it was on their minds the whole time.
So how'd it go on your end?
My stupid dad wouldn't listen,
but the Men's Club heard me out.
If I tell them that the people of the surface have agreed already,
I know it'll work out.
All right! It's finally showtime!
Let's do the Boatdrift Ceremony!
Yeah!
Okay, but first, it's time for food!
I really hope everything works out.
If we don't eat before, there won't be any time to hang out after.
But they all seem so stubborn...
Just watch. I'm gonna make this happen.
Hikari's really putting his all into this, huh?
Yeah.
But at the same time, he seems sort of... um...
different now, don't you think?
Different?
Oh, I mean, I know Hii-kun always does his best,
but, um... it's just that it seems different this time.
Um...
I think
he's trying to change.
Change?
I don't want things to change.
I want us all to stay together forever.
Ch-Change?! That's not good!
We have to try to stop him somehow!
We'll stop him and undo it!
I don't think that'll be possible.
But...
Thank you, Manaka.
Chii-chan...
Some things change whether we want them to or not.
Once someone decides to change and does everything they can to make it happen,
I doubt even the sea god can stop them.
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
Wow, they did a pretty good job.
This is impressive.
Yeah, it's not bad at all.
We may actually be able to use this.
Just look at the detail.
I'm surprised they managed to get Hikari's dad to come with them.
I'm nervous.
Me too. I kinda need to take a piss.
Then go instead of telling us about it!
They even prepared offerings.
We made all that stuff when we were kids, too. Ain't that right, Sakishima?
Why'd you come?
Did you really make all this yourselves?
Yeah.
The four of us and our friends from the surface all worked together.
I see. Well, that explains it.
The Wooden Maiden's kimono is folded wrong.
Huh?
What?!
What are we going to do, Chii-chan?!
We sewed it so that the wrong side's in the front!
The Wooden Maiden's going to die!
Just calm down!
We can fix that in no time.
Hikari...
Talk about a preemptive strike.
No worries!
We're just getting started.
Well then, it seems everyone's ready now.
I'll be the intermediary for today's meeting.
Now, what do all of you think?
The students put a lot of effort into all this.
So as their teacher, I'd really like to see their dream come true.
Well, it's not like we ever objected to doing the Boatdrift Ceremony to begin with.
Yeah.
Besides, festivals shouldn't be disregarded.
And we're not ones to neglect the sea god.
Yeah, that's right.
Hey, Sakishima.
The kids have already done so much.
I know a lot has happened,
but why don't we just let it go?
Yeah.
Okay, you can get started now.
We've already started, though...
Nah, not with that.
I'm saying that we'll hear out your apology now.
What?
Apology?!
We came all the way here.
Feel free to apologize as much as you want.
Our hearts are as great as the sea.
I'm sure it'll be on the rude side, but we'll hear it out anyway.
What the hell do we gotta apologize for?
You're the ones who didn't wanna do the festival in the first place.
Now, just wait a sec.
Don't you even remember the last Boatdrift Ceremony?
You guys kept complainin' about how we didn't have enough money or people,
so you asked us to scale things down, remember?
Yeah, and chances are that your complainin' woulda increased every year.
At that rate,
if we hadn't been the ones to cancel it,
Oh man, this doesn't look too good, does it?
you guys woulda done it yourselves.
What a load of crap!
Please stop!
We're not here to argue about who should apologize or who's at faul—
Butt out, kid!
Regardless, you're the ones who did call it off.
So of course you should apologize!
Not to mention,
the only reason we don't have enough money or people
is 'cause you guys keep stealin' everything!
Yeah, that's right!
Stealin' our fish and our women!
What?
Don't you think the reason your women keep runnin' off is 'cause you guys aren't dependable?
Tryin' to pin the blame on us for that too, are ya?
The hell did you just say?!
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
Looks like it's gonna rain.
Are you sure you want to come in too?
Yeah.
Since Hikari dedicated so much time and effort to this,
I want to do what I can as well.
Plus, I want to show Miuna-chan a real Boatdrift Ceremony.
Maybe it's because of our roots.
But even aside from that, if Miuna-chan ever feels lost,
I thought maybe the memory could be sort of like a beacon of hope in her heart.
Akari...
Thank you.
Thank you for thinking of Miuna.
Okay, let's head in.
What the hell are you sayin', you fish bastard?
Excuse us—
Shut the hell up, you pigs!
Enough of your damn squealing!
Fine, then!
Why don't we settle things once and for all?
What'd you just say?!
Is this a bad time?
Man, this sucks.
Itaru-san...
Talk about bad timing.
You! You're that punk Akari's seeing!
Um...
You damn thief!
Thie—
We've got plenty of things we'd like to say to you!
Get over here!
Hey—
What the heck is going on here? Hikari! Dad!
Will you guys give it a break already?
Aren't you adults?
Why can't you all be civil about this?!
Just stay out of the way!
Are you satisfied now?
Looking for
Part-Timers!
Break up with that guy.
As Hikari said, we can communicate with each other because we're not fish or pigs.
But it's because we can communicate
that we realize there are differences
between us that we can never get over.
People of the sea and people of the surface will never see eye to eye.
I always thought something
felt off when you and I talked.
Now I know what it was.
You know, I've been talking about Itaru-san and myself this whole time.
Yet somehow, you always manage to twist it into being about the sea and the surface.
A long time ago I asked Mom,
"Why'd you marry Dad?"
She told me that the reason was simple.
She married you because she loved you.
That's all there was to it.
When I heard that, I was so happy.
So then I decided to ask her,
"What if he'd been from the surface instead?"
Mom just smiled at me and said,
"Your father and I would've been together, no matter what."
I'm going to be Miuna-chan's mother.
Are you leaving?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Hikari.
You don't need to apologize.
I'm coming with you.
But—
If I stay here alone with Dad,
we can't just sweep our
differences under the rug.
I understand.
I see.
So she said she was leaving, did she?
Look.
The flickering's gotten more pronounced.
There isn't much time left.
What are you gonna do, Tomoru?
Uroko-sama.
Are you leaving?
Yes.
There any chance you'll reconsider?
There is not.
But you're still under my protection, you know.
I'm grateful for all you've done for me,
but I've made up my mind.
I'm going to live on the surface.
Thank you for everything.
I'm not coming back either!
Looks like being stubborn runs in the family.
Good grief.
Akari!
Hikari!
Uroko-sama!
We have to do everything in our power.
Why don't you just give up?
Nothing good's gonna come from you going to the surface.
You're wrong!
There's someone up there who's waiting for me!
Uroko-sama! Why won't you let us leave?!
I made a promise.
A promise?
I must protect the both of you...
because you are his descendants.
Damn it!
Very well, then.
What is this?
The temperature's dropping so rapidly.
This is bad.
We're gonna freeze at this rate.
Like hell I'm gonna give up now!
I won't just be swept along with the current anymore!
My, aren't they persistent.
Uroko-sama!
Please, show them mercy.
Akari, let's go!
R-Right!
Are you certain about this?
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara mayu ni naru
How long did we have
ittai dore kurai mabuta wo
our eyes closed?
tojiteita n darou
We waited and waited
mattemo mattemo bokura zutto
but were still alone together
futarikiri
When I call your name in this finite bowl of water,
koko wa yuugen no suisou de
bubbles rise to foam
namae wo yobeba awa ni naru
Detritus floats in the warm water
atatakai mizu ni oyogu detritus
I take it, and spend a long time
nagai jikan wo kakete
spinning it into a cocoon for you
ito wo tsumuginagara
that will shield you from emotions
odayaka ni nemuru kimi no sotogawa de
as you sleep peacefully
subete no kanjou kara mamoru mayu ni naru
I want a shell from the sea I love so much.
I don't want you to go through the same thing, Akari.
You know, I don't care if I can't go back to the sea.
What's wrong with those two being together?
Episode Eight
Beyond the Wavering Feelings