Naminanakai
Public Hospital
furitsumoru konayuki ga mau
Little snowflakes dance in the air
akiramekaketa yume ga mata namiutsu
I'd almost given up on my dream, but it washes in again,
ano hi no mama de
like it did so long ago
kawaranai egao mitsumete
I watch your frozen smile,
somaru hoho ni fureta kaze ga
and the wind turning my cheeks red
sora takaku muketa
disappears high into the sky
I was always looking at you, never far away,
and yet you seemed out of my reach.
doushite
Why
kou toikaketa koe mo yureru
Even your voice is rough as it asks me
yurayura minamo ni ukanda
The moon's reflection quivered on the waters,
tsuki wa nanimo kataranai
and it told us nothing about the future
tada no boukansha
The moon merely watched us
hora boku nigezu ni tada itai
I want to stay here with you
Episode Fourteen
The Promised Day
Public
Hospital
Oh, Chisaki!
Must be tough
coming here every day.
Not at all. My school is nearby.
KIHARA ISAMU
He didn't finish his food again.
He hasn't had much of an appetite lately.
I see.
Once you finish nursing school, you should come work here!
Having someone as reliable as
you around would be a godsend.
Okay!
South 412
Yamaguchi Youhei
Kihara Isamu
Tanaka Masaru
Kitagawa Kyousuke
Grandpa, you have to eat!
The food here's got no taste.
Well, once you're out of the hospital, you can eat whatever you want.
All right, let me wipe you down now, okay?
Sea Salt
Today's the Tomoebi.
The Tomoebi...
Why can't we all be here for this?
Someone important's coming, right?
Yeah.
A professor from Tsumugu's lab.
Open that.
Since he's from the city,
he probably won't like country food.
Use that to buy some alcohol and meat for him.
Okay.
Oshiooshi  Station
'Sup, Chisaki.
Sayama!
I can give you a lift.
I was just thinking about stopping by Saya Mart on the way home!
Good timing, then.
Egawa's getting married.
What?!
He knocked up some girl.
K-Knoc—
But will he be able to finish college?
Seems the girl's dad
is the president of some company,
so he's gonna quit school and work for him.
I'm in shock.
That's the surprise of the year.
He said he'll be back in January, though.
We all plan on teasing the crap outta him.
Everyone's changed so much,
and it's only been five years.
I think you're the one who's changed the most.
Huh?
Well, there's a rumor going around
that you're, like, some lonely housewife.
It's kinda hot.
Wh-What are you saying?!
You're late, young man!
Tell me you weren't out playing pachinko again!
Just went out for some fresh air.
The boss has been waiting on you, you know.
Chisaki!
Hello!
Here, Akira. I got this for you.
Now, what do we say?
Fanks.
Cut it out, Akira!
He never listens to anyone but Miuna.
It's such a headache!
But...
it's thanks to her that he's here.
The people of the sea can hibernate, right?
Hikari and everyone else
are probably just asleep, then.
Right. They're definitely okay.
So don't—
That's not the problem!
Akari?
There's no way I can have this baby right now.
Having a baby is a blessing.
Please don't talk like that.
Sorry. Just leave me alone.
Akari—
Just go away! Please.
M-Miuna?
Miuna...
It's gonna be a boy.
You can tell?
A boy, huh?
I'm happy.
You know, I'm really happy.
I'm happy that I'm gonna
have a little brother.
Thank you, Mom.
Akari?
Oh, i-it's nothing.
Up your butt.
Come on, Akira!
I'm so sorry!
He's been obsessed with that lately.
I-It's okay...
Ugh, get back here, you dummy!
Don't move!
Oh? You got in one of your
special attacks, did ya?
I said, don't move! Hey!
Run!
Miuna.
Mi-u-na.
Nice try, Sayu.
Good morning, Miss Miuna.
Good morning, Teacher.
You remind me of your uncle, you know.
Huh?
When you sleep, I mean.
Hikari used to sleep in class a lot too.
Oh.
Now then, today's the day
of the long-awaited Tomoebi.
In the past, you couldn't see it
unless you were at the bottom of the sea.
And while it was the sun
back then, it's the moon now.
Tomoebi
Now that the sea is frozen, the ice acts like a prism
and gathers light from all the saltflake snow.
This projects an image onto the night sky,
Tomoebi Before
(Only visible
from under
the sea)
Temperature
Water Temperature
Tidal Current
Sun
Calm Sea Surface
Tidal Current
making an illusory moon.
So the best time to see it is when the moon's at its lowest... at about eight o'clock.
Teach! And before that?
Oh, right!
Dinner!
After this, it's time for rations!
Having a meal by the sea with everyone...
Now, now, kids.
The main event is the Tomoebi.
It's a bit nostalgic, isn't it?
Don't forget that, okay?
Yeah.
Having class at night is pretty exciting.
Ain't that right, Minegishi?
Huh? Oh, um... yeah.
Be on your guard, Miuna!
Why?
I totally found out...
Tonight during the Tomoebi,
Minegishi's planning to ask you out.
Ask me out...
Everyone's so lame.
School's a place for studying!
Sayu, you used to hate studying.
Well, I've decided that I'm
gonna live on my own someday.
I mean, it's not like I'm
gonna find work in Oshiooshi.
So I plan to go to the city
and become an independent woman.
You've planned that far ahead?
More or less. What about you, Miuna?
I'm not really sure yet.
I know I don't plan on leaving, though.
Miuna.
Huh?
Your hair's gotten longer.
Yeah.
Sayu! Miuna!
The teacher's calling you!
Oh, thanks!
Come on, Miuna.
Okay.
Shouldn't you two be in school?
I used to watch from here...
just like this.
Akari!
Mukaido!
Watch out! The bridge pier!
No!
At that moment, I decided I wouldn't cry.
I mean, I knew Hikari and the others were in the sea.
I had faith that they were safe
and that they were still smiling, in a place I couldn't go.
I'm home!
Oh! It smells delicious!
Sorry for being late.
Let me help.
It's okay. It's my turn today!
Your hair's wet.
I went to check under the sea again.
But something's in the way, so I couldn't see.
The sea temperature's gone down, too.
Is your tummy okay?
Of course it is!
Being pregnant underwater is natural for us women of the sea, you know.
Well, it's not all bad.
Huh?
At least he's not alone. Dad's there with him.
Plus, Hikari liked Manaka.
If Manaka and his other friends had been left in the sea and he'd been left alone out here,
I bet he wouldn't know what to do!
Hikari... likes Manaka.
Careful, Miuna! It's about to spill over.
Safe.
He likes Manaka...
Miuna!
What's the matter?
Sorry! I'm coming!
Even now, I'm here watching,
looking out at the sea where Hikari and the others are.
Professor!
Tsumugu!
Why don't you two come
warm up a bit before the Tomoebi?
Delicious!
This stewed golden eye snapper is delicious.
You just can't get food like this in the city!
Is that so...
Huh?
O-Oh, nothing. I'm glad you like it.
The meat's good too.
Sorry to impose on you like this.
Oh, don't be. It's livelier now,
so I'm glad you came.
Thanks to Tsumugu joining our lab,
our research has progressed quite a bit.
I mean, there are only fourteen sea villages in all of Japan.
Not to mention, we can't set foot in any of them right now.
Even when we try diving to investigate,
the tide gets in our way,
and we can't get close.
And now, there are even specialists saying that the sea villages no longer exist.
They're just saying that to get attention.
Hiradaira, I believe there is a close relationship between the surface and the sea.
So in order to make sense of the abnormal weather,
we must research the sea villages as well.
I see.
Let me get you another one.
Oh, that would be wonderful.
She's a great girl.
You sure there's nothing going on?
Of course not.
You guys are at that age, though.
And you're living under the same roof.
Not to mention, she's beautiful, which would usually mean—
There's someone else she's loved for a long time.
Huh?
There we go.
He can put out his futon himself.
He's a guest, though.
I can't let him do that.
Won't you come watch the Tomoebi with us?
No thanks.
There's no point unless we all see the Tomoebi together.
I see.
Since it's cold out, would you like me to make some rice wine?
Sure. That sounds good.
What are we gonna do?
It really did turn into a huge deal.
Oshiooshi Fishery Cooperative
We still haven't found the sea kids that fell in?
Something like this has never happened before.
I can't believe the sea god was this angry.
What are we gonna do about this girl?
She's got no relatives up here...
Chisaki, you can—
You can come live with us.
But...
Your apartment's cramped as it is.
And besides...
I'm from the sea too.
Grandpa! The lady next door
wanted me to give this to you.
Grandp—
Grandpa!
Please, wake up! Grandpa!
In Surgery
If you're a family member,
please wait over here.
No! Don't take Grandpa away!
Chisaki, calm down.
Don't leave me!
Don't take anyone else away from me!
Chisaki!
Chisaki.
Now then, did you pack your underwear?
Don't worry about it.
I'll do it myself.
Absolutely not. You're absent-minded when it comes to stuff like this.
So you're gonna be a college student in the big city...
And an oceanography researcher to boot!
You should be proud!
Sorry that you ended up
having to take care of Gramps.
Don't even mention it.
You two are my other family.
You're both precious to me.
Family, huh?
Huh?
In the course of my research,
I plan to find out more about the sea villages as well as what happened that day.
I'm sure they're somehow linked
to what's gonna happen on the surface.
Tsumugu...
I'm sure they're fine.
And if everything takes a turn for the better,
I'm sure we'll see them again.
Yeah.
So good!
What the hell? Mine's all potatoes!
Let's hurry and finish eating!
The Tomoebi is about to start.
Minegishi, what about Shiodome?
Huh?
Um...
Come on!
Time to prove you're a man.
Seriously, boys are so stupid.
You done? I'll go put our trays to wash.
Oh, thanks.
Look at the currents.
Seems it's about to start.
Yeah.
Ever since that day, the sea has been calm...
and perfectly quiet,
never giving me a single clue
as to what's happening below.
Shiodome!
Um...
Are you asking me out?
Huh?! Wh-Wha—
Sorry, I may have jumped to conclusions. If so, just forget I said anything.
You haven't!
In that case, let me say this first.
I'm in love with someone else.
Huh?
So... I'm sorry.
I can't!
I've always been in love with you!
Ever since grade school!
I can't just give up!
I can't... just give up.
I can't give up!
Who is he?
Please tell me!
Well...
Shiodome!
This is the Tomoebi...
Pretty magnificent, isn't it?
Hey, what is that?
Something big is showing up on the screen.
Is it a fish?
Hey, where are you going?
Miuna, what are you...
Hikari!
He hasn't aged at all since that day.
He's not breathing!
I don't think mouth-to-mouth
will work on someone from the sea.
H-Hika—
Manaka!
Who... are you?
It's Miuna.
What? Miuna?
Tsumugu?
Hikari's eyes
were frozen in sadness...
just like the calm of the sea.
mugon no kotoba de ayatori shite
I play a silent cat's cradle with my words,
jouzu ni dekita to warattemiru
and decide to grin in satisfaction
tokui na no wa dare ni mo kizukarenu you ni
The only thing that I am truly good at
kokoro oshikorosu koto sore hitotsu dake
is stifling my love so others won't find out
demo torimaku kirei na loop wa
It would be nice
yawai chikara de
if the love of those around me
taguriyosetekureru kana
drew me in gently
azayaka ni
and free of blemish
musunde kono kimochigoto
I tie my feelings into a rope
hanarenai you ni kataku kataku aa
so that we will never be apart
hitomusubi hito wo musunde
The knots tie us together,
kitai no iu mama ni saki he asu he yukou
so let us approach the days to come with hope
The reason Hikari came back...
You look like you've seen a monster.
Talk about a turn of events.
I changed from back then?
Hikari... came back.
Episode Fifteen
The Protector of Smiles