dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
What a pity, boy.
Tiger Beetle
You're the same as me.
You, too, will toss her aside once the going gets tough.
No...
He won't.
This is all just some scary dream.
Once I wake up, Onii-chan will be there for me.
And then...
And then you're gonna eat him again?
You know what you did, Yume-chan!
You killed your onii-chan and—
Be quiet!
Please... just leave me alone.
I don't want to remember.
My body is craving flesh.
I'm horrible.
I see people passing me by and can only think about how delicious they look.
I don't want to eat them.
But I'm just so hungry.
I don't think I can control myself!
Yume!
Onii-chan?
Onii-chan, is it really you?
Am I still dreaming?
Don't worry, Yume.
I will protect you.
Out of Order
I'm sorry, Onii-chan.
Don't worry about me, Yume.
I'm basically a monster myself now.
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything