dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
I wish it were all a dream
I'm sooo tired.
How am I ever gonna finish my homework tonight?
Yo, Utsutsu.
Yume-chan's here to see you.
Sprouting Wings
I thought it'd be nice to go home with you today, Onii-chan.
Okay. I'll be done soon, so go wait for me at the park.
'Kay.
Hurry home.
Hurry home lest the red butterflies find you.
Such big butterflies.
They're so beautiful!
Are you hurt?
Hasegawa Yume,
just what the hell are you?
Yume!
Yume...
What's wrong, Yume?!
Your stuffing's spilling out.
That makes two of us.
Why are you looking at me like that, Onii-chan?
What is this?
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything