dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
I've come for you two.
Won't you come with me?
Of course, I'd like to have some fun with you first.
Caterpillar
Something wrong?
Now then, let's have some fun.
Is that all you got?
What a drag.
Damn it...
I was sooo looking forward to meeting you guys.
So c'mon, let's have some more fun...
like this!
Holy shit, man.
It really does take no time for you to heal.
This is awesome.
We can have fun like this forever.
I wonder if you'll grow new eyeballs if I cut these ones out.
Stop...
Hold still.
Get away from him!
Stop doing this... please!
Stop being so mean to Onii-chan!
Shut the fuck up.
Don't you think you're way worse than me?
I mean, don't you eat your own brother when you get hungry?
You're a monster.
Someone should lock you up in a dungeon...
and throw away the key.
What do you think you're doing to my sister?
Here's my thanks.
No...
No!
Yume...
What an idiot.
He should have ended it when he had the chance.
At least he made it easier for us.
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything