dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
Our dad used to beat our mom a lot.
Our mom just used to grit her teeth and bear it.
So when he got tired of beating her, he'd beat us instead.
This is what life will always be like for you.
He'd say that with a smile on his face as he had his fun with us.
My sister and I were just little kids back then,
so we could only wait it out.
Eventually, our parents got divorced,
and our mom started meeting younger men.
Stuck in that empty house,
my little sister would weep bitterly.
Deep Sting
My, my. Would you just look at this mess.
This will prove troublesome to clean up.
Do you have a moment?
I'd like to talk with you about that monster.
My name is Maria.
I'm a researcher.
You needn't worry.
We'll take care of the corpses.
They won't be a problem.
I don't care about that!
Just what the hell is going on?!
It pains me to say this, but...
I'm afraid you'll have to give up on your sister.
We'll take things from here.
What?!
But she's my sister! I love her!
Oh, really?
Well then, why don't you try talking to her?
Who knows whether she will recognize you?
Who knows whether her loving brother's voice will reach her?
Why are the people I killed so very delicious?
What am I supposed to do now?
I don't want Onii-chan to see me like this.
Yume!
Onii-chan!
Yume...
Don't come any closer!
I ate so many people!
But I'm still so hungry!
Don't worry.
You're still my beloved little sister.
No matter what you look like, you'll always be Yume to me.
Come on.
Let's go home now, Yume.
Onii-chan...
Thank you.
Yume...
Onii-chan?!
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything