dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
Inside my belly, that monster grew bigger.
Hasegawa Yume,
just what the hell are you?
What should I do?
I have to get an abortion...
before anything happens to Utsutsu.
Was that the monster's way of saying it won't let me?
Tadpole
Shortly after Utsutsu turned one,
Push, push!
I gave birth to that monster—Yume.
Utsutsu, no!
Stay away from it.
From the moment she was born, she already had all her teeth.
It was as though she was
declaring herself to be a monster.
And the way she would look at me sometimes...
I can't take this.
It feels like she's watching my every move.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry,
but...
You're gonna give birth to my child, aren't you?
Shirou-san...
come back, quick.
What should I do?
And then, one day...
Mom, why are you being so mean to Yume?
After that, I came to like pain.
When I'm in pain, I know I'm not dreaming.
I don't need nice friends or gentle lovers.
So, Shirou-san, please...
won't you hit me again?
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything