dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
Come, now.
A girl must always look her best.
Of course,
given the circumstances, I suppose it is understandable.
Maria-sama,
the cleanup crew has arrived.
I see.
Squirming
Onii-chan!
No need to fret.
We shall take care of his body.
His... body?
That's right. His body.
Remember?
You ate him.
You ate him right as he told you he loved you despite your being a monster.
It gave me such shivers!
He died...
Actually, strictly speaking, he didn't "die."
He was killed. By you.
I did this?
Keep Hasegawa Utsutsu under close observation,
and inform me if anything unusual happens.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh my, how curious.
I'm amazed to see you alive.
This is rather unexpected,
isn't it, Utsutsu-kun?
What the hell have you done with Yume?!
Shit!
It's healing...
It seems that you, too, are infected.
Infected?
With what?
Is it the same thing Yume has?!
Well, aren't you sharp.
You two are now hosts to a mysterious virus.
This virus confers powerful regenerative abilities,
but the price for these abilities is insatiable hunger.
It is called the Pupa virus.
Where's Yume?
She may sprout wings again quite soon.
I'm not gonna let you people toy with my little sister!
Well then, might I offer you a suggestion?
Will you be your dear little sister's sustenance?
Her sustenance?
Can you allow her to eat bits of your body for the rest of your life, boy?
Of course I can.
You and I have got same blood flowing through our veins.
I'm not gonna be like my old man.
I will be there for her.
I will protect our lives.
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything