dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
She's always been like this.
Her sense of morality has
always been somewhat lacking.
She can't seem to understand
why it is that others laugh or cry.
Instead, she brims with curiosity about the material world.
From her perspective, everything is just a guinea pig.
Hotoki?
Yes?
Prepare the sperm we collected from Hasegawa Utsutsu
as well as the egg cells from Hasegawa Yume.
Huh?
I plan to give birth to a monster child.
I could feel my sister's teeth digging into my body.
Parts of me were sliding down her throat, into her stomach.
When I opened my eyes, fighting a pain that may as well have been bliss,
I saw my sister, covered in blood and gorging herself on my flesh.
And yet, for some reason,
she looked so sad as she ate.
I wonder if she's been crying on the inside
ever since that day.
Incubation
There's no need to hide over there.
Why don't you come out now?
Oops, guess you knew I was there.
Your inner sanctum never ceases to amaze me.
We live in different worlds, I guess...
You've got a great sense of style.
You didn't come here just to tell me that, did you?
I came to ask you... to let me fondle your breasts.
I'm just kidding.
Oh? I would have let you.
Someone is after the Hasegawa siblings.
The Imari Ishin Corporation, correct?
Yeah, that sketchy medical company.
By the way, Maria-san,
don't you think you should get dressed?
I don't see the need to do so.
But you somehow see the need for the hat?
Hotoki...
you had better not turn on me.
Come now, Maria-san,
you know I'm your loyal servant.
Now and forever?
If you wish me to, I'll swear to it...
with that monster as witness.
Very nice.
You know, I really think that these children...
are looking forward to
meeting their mom and dad.
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything