dame da yo koko kara saki wa
(dame da yo kono saki he wa ikanaide)
Don't go past this point
(Past here it's dangerous)
ugomeku yami wo kizami sagasu no hikari no sora
(ugomeku yami ni kizamare samayou kieta hikari no sora)
I crawl with my claws through the darkness, in search of the radiant sky
(I crawl through the darkness clawing at me, vainly seeking a radiant sky)
tobitachitai no habatakitai
(tobitatenai yo habatakenai)
I want to fly, I want to beat my wings
(I can't fly, I can't beat my wings)
hirahirahira mau akai chou
(hirahira ochiteku akai chou)
A red butterfly flutters around me
(A red butterfly falls to vice)
nukedashitai yo katai kara wo yaburi kawaru anata no tame ni
(kawarenai watashi)
I want to break open my carapace and change to save you
(I can't change)
Where did they bring me?
What are they going to do to me?
Scalpel.
Specimen
Hey, can't you shut him up already?
Maybe we didn't give him enough anesthesia.
We did, but the virus is neutralizing all of it.
The pupa virus, huh?
An active supervirus is definitely worth investigating.
Look at this.
The organs I removed have already regenerated.
This thing is no longer human.
You bastards are dissecting a teenager you kidnapped...
You're the ones who aren't human.
I think you're under a misunderstanding here.
We didn't kidnap you. We quarantined you.
Onii-chan...
Calm down.
We're not like that woman.
We'll be using the data we gather from you for the good of humanity.
So you say, but seems like you're having fun doing this to me.
You freaks!
While it's nice to see you so spirited, you should consider your situation.
Onii-chan!
yasashiku sareru to setsunaku naru
When you're nice to me, I grow sad,
tsumetaku sareru to nakitaku naru
and when you're cold to me, I want to cry,
dare yori suki nano ni
even though I love you more than anything