My heart beats like crazy, this is the first time I've felt like this, don't mess with my feelings
dokidoki harahara konna no hajimete doko made watashi no kimochi wo moteasobu no
I can't do it, it's too much, this is so sudden, you just want to startle me
mushi mushi murimuri totsuzen hajimaru dai spectacle atto iwasetai tame ni
My Neighbor Seki
That's what all your antics are for
subete wo kaketeru no
Every day I have to deal with your eccentricities
mainichi daimeiwaku okiraku my pace otoko no ko
waku
pace
o
to
ko
no
I can tell you're doing this on purpose, don't try to hide it
toboketa kao shitemo dame da yo
You're no end of trouble, but I can't help but glance over
zettai daimeiwaku dakedo tsui micchau no kimi no koto
waku
You intrigue me
ki ni natte
ki
ni
na
tte
What are you up to this time?
kondo wa nani suru no
Stop it
yamete
ya
me
te
We began looking at "Run, Melos!" last time.
Today, we'll read some of the text
and get a feel for the world it occurs in.
Oh?
So you're doing needlework during class today?
A boy, doing needlework...
And in the middle of class, no less.
Not to mention,
he's doing it right next to me, someone with a Grade 2 certification in knitting,
Knitting
Certification
Grade 2
which makes me qualified to act as an instructor's aide.
You've got some nerve.
9th Period
Needlework
Needlework.
Since I started knitting in first grade,
I've continued to hone it,
my one and only talent, over the years.
I've knit things for my family
and friends' birthdays, of course,
as well as for Valentine's, Christmas, and anniversaries.
I've made all kinds of gifts for many people.
Though eventually, I got so good that they stopped believing my gifts were hand-knit.
But that's exactly it!
That's why needlework's not something you can easily do during class!
I won't let you get away with any half-hearted efforts!
He's fast!
That's way beyond beginner level!
Not bad, Seki-kun.
What he's doing is the most basic of basics, though:
crocheting!
Skilled needlework is all about precision and variation.
Speed is secondary.
Still...
if he's crocheting something with stitches that small, it can't be any kind of clothing.
Oh! He's got stuffing ready.
Which means...
He's crocheting a stuffed toy?
And judging by the color... maybe a frog?
Though when you take the shape into account, it could be a snake.
I wouldn't put it past him.
What?!
That's no ordinary crochet hook!
That's a double-ended afghan hook!
Th-That's Seki-kun for you. He's done his homework.
The tool you can only get at specialty shops
that's all the rage in the crochet world,
the double-ended afghan hook...
But...
should you really be using that
just because it's in fashion, Seki-kun?
Needlework is an extremely deep art.
Each tool has its own special purpose.
You're making a mistake!
The afghan stitch is known for its
unique thickness and its soft fluffiness.
The finished product, though simple,
can be just as expressive as woven fabrics.
Its texture is best suited to clothing, such as hats and sweaters.
Ah, it warms me right through to my heart.
Each stitch firmly emphasizes its presence,
as if to warmly embrace both body and soul.
And yet!
Crochet                                              Afghan Stitch
The most important rule of crocheting
stuffed toys is to pull every stitch tight
Crochet                                              Afghan Stitch
so that the surface is smooth.
If the surface is bumpy, the cuteness is lost.
Crochet                                              Afghan Stitch
That's why...
Stuffed toys are not where the afghan stitch excels!
What you are making can only end in failure!
Hmph.
I was wondering what he was making.
A cactus?
Isn't that a bit dull for a stuffed toy?
Quality hardly matters if the shape is no good.
But...
I wonder why...
I can't take my eyes off of that crocheted toy.
Something about it resonates with my heart.
What is this feeling?
Yes, far in the distance...
A hint of green barely visible in a land of scorched sand.
The cactus that stands firm
in the piercing sunlight and arid winds.
The toughness, and yet gentleness, of its skin.
The characteristics of the afghan stitch should have worked against it.
But instead, the thickness of the surface
and its texture have breathed life into the cactus!
I've lost, Seki-kun.
I've never seen such an amazing crocheted toy.
I have to admit it, even with my Grade 2 certification.
I'm sorry for treating you like a beginner.
I apologize.
So please...
let me cuddle that cute li'l cactus too!
Huh? Hey...
Hey, Seki-kun... What?
Wh-Wh-What?
What?!
Evidence Destroyed
Make it... one more time.
Hurry up...
Japanese
Yokoi-san's wish did not reach him.
Hurry up...
Japanese
Under her piercing gaze,
Seki-kun was rooted to the spot,
frozen with his textbook in hand.
Japanese
Tonari no Seki-kun.