My heart beats like crazy, this is the first time I've felt like this, don't mess with my feelings
dokidoki harahara konna no hajimete doko made watashi no kimochi wo moteasobu no
I can't do it, it's too much, this is so sudden, you just want to startle me
mushi mushi murimuri totsuzen hajimaru dai spectacle atto iwasetai tame ni
My Neighbor Seki
That's what all your antics are for
subete wo kaketeru no
Every day I have to deal with your eccentricities
mainichi daimeiwaku okiraku my pace otoko no ko
waku
pace
o
to
ko
no
I can tell you're doing this on purpose, don't try to hide it
toboketa kao shitemo dame da yo
You're no end of trouble, but I can't help but glance over
zettai daimeiwaku dakedo tsui micchau no kimi no koto
waku
You intrigue me
ki ni natte
ki
ni
na
tte
What are you up to this time?
kondo wa nani suru no
Stop it
yamete
ya
me
te
As we see here, expressing one's future actions
is done using "to" plus the verb's base form.
This is called the infinitive.
Huh?
This usage is...
Seki-kun's playing shogi again.
He was playing that just the other day.
But that's just as well.
If it's the same game,
there won't be any new surprises,
so I'll be able to concentrate on the lesson.
Hm?
What?!
Why is it a single pawn versus everything else?!
8th Period
Shogi 2
Shogi 2.
There's no way a shogi game
that biased will ever go anywhere!
What's going on?
What did that pawn do?
Princess
P-Princess?!
That piece doesn't even exist in shogi!
Don't just make up weird stuff!
Pawn
Princess
The pawn and the princess are together.
And the king and his whole army are against them?
Could this be...
that scenario you see in foreign movies all the time?
You know...
Pawn
Forbidden love between...
Princess
a soldier and a princess!
And the king who stands in their way!
Everyone's turned against them, so they're eloping!
What a dramatic game of shogi!
What's going to happen to them?
I can't miss a single move of this game!
Whoa!
They're all attacking at once!
Pawn
Oh no, the pawn got all beat up!
There's no way he can win now!
Pawn
Princess
Princess?
Pawn
Princess
Husband
Wife
They flipped over?!
Pawn
Oh, "pawn" became "husband,"
Husband
Princess
and "princess" became "wife."
Wife
Husband
and
Wife
Husband and wife!
Despite the hopeless situation,
they're reaffirming their undying love for each other!
So that's what's going on?!
Wow! The husband's strong!
The power of love powered up that pawn!
That's it! Now just take out anyone who gets in your way!
Huh? What's wrong?
Whoa!
Wife
The princess has been captured!
What underhanded tactics!
Now he can't fight!
Husband
So cruel! That's just cruel!
It's like they're beating him
to death in front of the princess!
No! I can't watch any longer!
I'll just study. I can't take any more of this.
This is... the enemy gold general who got blown away earlier.
Gold    General
But... on the inside...
Father
"Father"?! Is he that pawn's father?!
Was he brainwashed
into fighting his own son or something?
Seeing his son in danger
brings the father back to his senses,
so he shows up to save him!
That's a pretty natural turn of events, isn't it?
Wha—
He made a wall with his textbook!
Seki-kun, you cheater!
How... How can he get past this enormous wall?
If he doesn't hurry, his son's life will be in danger!
Now, onto the next page.
Seki, read it out loud for us.
This is my chance!
You have to pick up your book to read it!
An unexpected intervention from a higher power, eh?
The heavens are on my side.
Things won't go the way you're planning, Seki-kun!
Now, open the gates!
They're open! Now's my chance!
Pawn
Huh?! What's with that barricade?!
When did you make that?
You built it behind your textbook in that short amount of time?
Not bad, Seki-kun.
I see... So the final wall to overcome is a wall of people.
But that cannot...
defeat...
the bond...
Father
between parent and child!
Yippee!
What's wrong, Seki?
You don't know where to start?
Um...
Page 35! Seki-kun, it's page 35!
Page 35!
Tonari no Seki-kun.