Fire!
What happened?
How's Bellows' crew?
What about the pirates?
There were no casualties
.on the defense vessel.
The enemy forces
.have been eliminated.
Eliminated?
You killed all the pirates?
Affirmative.
The enemy forces
.have been eliminated.
Stupid Ledo!
I don't understand.
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru yozora
The night sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
The Ruffian Queen
The pirates were eliminated?
Their fleet was destroyed, and those who
.came on board my ship were vaporized.
They won't let this pass now
.that blood has been shed.
His actions were excessive.
Commodore, this boy
.cannot remain here.
Shall we hand him over to the pirates?
If only that would appease them...
And what if he joins forces with them?
What would you have us do?
Just take his Yunboro and throw him—
What we should do for now
is see how the pirates react and find appropriate countermeasures.
We can deal with the boy later.
I didn't think he'd go that far.
He was telling the truth
.about being a soldier in space.
I shouldn't have asked for his help...
There you are, Amy!
I need you for a little something.
They seem to detest me.
I have trouble finding
.logic in their response.
I thought they'd be
..indebted to me, but—
Flying object ahead!
It's Amy and Bellows!
Lower your guns!
Hey...
Sorry for shouting at you earlier.
I hope you're not mad.
Not at all.
No need to apologize.
Really? Okay, good.
I'm Bellows.
I wanted to talk to you.
I brought you something.
She requests that you consume that animal carcass.
This again?
Your name's Ledo, right?
Why'd you kill all the pirates?
Why not? They are the enemy.
I don't know about space,
but murder is the
.greatest taboo here.
Yet you have no problem with killing and eating animals?
It's true that we kill
.and eat fish and birds,
but only enough for us to survive.
We don't kill unless we have to.
Not to mention,
the pirates are human!
The same as us!
It's wrong to take lives thoughtlessly.
If killing humans is forbidden,
then why do you arm yourselves?
The pirates make others obey them by
.demonstrating their willingness to kill,
so we arm ourselves to show them
.we won't go down without a fight.
Pointing our guns at each other
.is just a form of negotiation.
We have a saying that goes, "if someone catches
.fish for you, give them water to drink."
Advocacy for the collectivization of goods?
Yeah.
If we don't pool our
.resources, we won't survive.
But the pirates don't
.play by the same rules.
We obviously can't accept that.
Our lives and possessions
belong to us, not the pirates!
We need a way to show them
.it's not worth attacking us.
We just want them to understand that.
But the game's changed now
.that blood has been spilled.
They'll have to claim even more
.lives to regain their position.
I understand the situation.
Good!
Anyway, despite what
.others have to say,
we need your strength
.to face the pirates.
Here's a communicator.
It'd be nice if you talked
.with the others too.
You still saved me, after all.
That bird is my way
.of saying thanks.
See you.
Hey, Ledo.
If you've got nowhere to go,
you could just stay here with us.
I'm sure we'll all get along somehow!
She wants me to live
on this ship? Is she serious?
Should we refuse?
No, don't refuse.
I'll consider it.
Really?
Consider it real seriously, okay?
Well then, I'll be going too.
Ledo, thank you for
protecting Bellows' ship!
Later!
Really, thank you so much!
What a peculiar phrase.
I see.
You may go now.
I've never really
liked them to begin with,
but I never thought they'd deride me so.
Captain, I'm a bit worried
..about that flying Yunbo—
Marocchi!
Their derision will only
.increase if you fear them.
I'm sorry.
Shouldn't we teach them a lesson?
Whatever secret weapon they have, they're no match for me!
Captain! Ships at three o'clock!
A whole bunch of them!
What?
Those are... pirates!
Captain Worm! We just got word from the freighter Atui.
A huge pirate fleet has been spotted.
Here they come.
They request emergency
.permission to join our fleet.
That is all.
At least thirty pirate
.ships have congregated.
Thirty ships?!
That's pretty much all
the pirates in the area!
The crest of the Lobster
.has been spotted as well.
The great pirate Rackage...
Their bearings?
They were spotted here.
They were seen heading
.east by southeast.
We can safely conclude
.we are their targets.
We'll encounter them by the evening.
We should change course.
It'd be pointless.
We can't outrun them.
But there are thirty
heavily-armed pirate ships!
We only have fifteen defence ships, and that includes patrol boats!
We are severely outmatched!
Let us attempt negotiations.
They're coming for revenge.
They won't leave until
.the price in blood is paid.
Commodore.
We should ask for that boy's help.
H-How can you say that?
Can you hear me, Ledo?
What is it that you want?
The pirates are coming our way.
We will have to fight them tonight.
I have already identified
.the approaching fleet.
I am willing to assist you.
Do you wish for my help?
Commodore, you should
.try talking to him.
That's insane!
It's his fault in the first place that—
Hold on!
Consider the tactical advantage his Yunboro represents.
Ridget.
Yes, sir.
My name is Ridget.
I speak on behalf of the Commodore.
Is that acceptable?
No problem.
Let me confirm.
You offered to help us,
but are you aware that you're the one to blame for this mess to begin with?
I am aware.
I offer an apology for killing the pirates.
Then one more thing.
In light of your immense firepower,
would you be able to
eliminate us as well?
Affirmative.
I could destroy your
.entire fleet by myself.
Then why offer to
help our paltry fleet?
I want to trade.
Trade?
Bellows told me that you offer water to those who catch fish for you
and that the pirates ignore this rule.
Therefore, I judged that negotiating with you would be more beneficial.
rebis oueko kartra
I wish to stay here for the time being.
I need your support for that.
Commodore,
I think it might be wise
.to agree to his deal.
Wh-What?
We can't let someone who
.brought us fish leave thirsty.
Let me confirm.
My job will be to act as a diversion in the upcoming battle. Is that correct?
Yes.
Just draw the pirates' attention away.
Refrain from excessive violence.
Your request is understood.
I'll try to keep human loss to a minimum.
So that's what it looks like inside.
Do not enter the cockpit
.without permission.
What do you think
you're doing, metalhead?!
I don't believe this.
We know nothing about that boy.
How can we trust him
with defending the fleet?
It's the Commodore's decision.
Pretty reasonable, all in all.
But still...
Marocchi.
Nothing from Gargantia yet?
They noticed us, so it's
.only a matter of time.
The night is dark; they might
even stand a chance.
That's in poor taste, milady!
The night is our domain!
Oh my, you think so?
What?
Visual on enemy fleet.
Initiating battle.
Shoot that thing down!
All ships ready to fire.
All ships, commence attack!
Oh look, they actually made the first move in a night battle.
What's with that Yunboro?
It's flying all over the place!
Get moving! Time to fire back!
All ships! Retaliate against
the enemy fleet!
The Chezy and the Nephilim got hit!
The Chezy is out of commission!
Have them retreat!
The rest of the ships should—
The Marcus got hit!
Continue firing!
Do not falter!
Additional allied ships have been hit.
Allied fleet operative period is expected to end in approximately seventeen minutes.
That settles it.
I'm joining the fray!
Keep casualties to a minimum.
Disable the enemy's weaponry and engines.
Understood.
No signs of life.
No casualties.
Good.
It's coming!
The Crocodile's on fire!
The Grach turned around!
They're trying to run away!
Our boys should be here by now.
We should get ready too.
Aye, sir!
Something's there!
Lights, please!
It's the pirates!
It's a sneak attack!
Civilians, evacuate to starboard!
Fire!
Get the Yunboros out there!
Give 'em some love from above!
Warning: mechanized enemy units have infiltrated Gargantia.
What?
You're not the only one
with a special Yunboroid!
Lady Rackage is on the move!
It's been a while
.since I've seen her fight!
It's the Surfing Lobster!
She's heading straight for Gargantia!
Target the large incoming Yunboroid!
She broke through!
Dammit!
What happened?
Rackage crashed into the hull!
What?!
She's climbing her way up!
Send reinforcements to deck one!
Get out of here, now.
She's coming for me.
Commodore...
Where is Commodore Fairlock?
I can't wait to blow his brains out.
Oh, my. It's rude to approach
a lady from behind.
But I do like my men aggressive.
What is she doing?
Gung-ho!
Semper fi!
Here we come!
You may rule the skies,
but how will you fare in the sea?
Wha—
No way!
What's going on?!
To all enemy personnel:
surrender immediately.
Surrender?!
Me, Rackage?!
I did warn them.
I repeat: surrender immediately.
We guarantee you won't be harmed.
I don't care! It doesn't matter! I'll never—
Surrender. Surrender.
Surrender immediately.
I repeat: surrender.
Never...
I'd rather die than surrender...
Crap! Let's get out of here!
W-Wait for me!
He did it.
The boy did it.
Thanks!
I keep hearing that phrase.
It is an idiom to express gratitude.
Gratitude, huh?
I see.
He did well.
How do you intend to deal with the boy?
I wonder what Chevron would've done.
My father?
I'll let you decide.
Good work!
We brought you dinner!
Th... Tha... Than...
Thank you.
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo
Art: Shimotsuki Eito