This is... the Earth?
It's flying!
Amended crisis assessment up by
.two hundred and twenty percent.
A preemptive attack is recommended.
Wait, Chamber.
Tell them in their language
.that we mean no harm.
Stop attack.
I-It spoke!
We no enemy.
Is there someone inside?
Request you put away weapons.
I am Ridget, the aide
.representative of this fleet.
Who are you?
They request your name and attachment.
All right.
Pilot of the Anti-Hideauze Extermination Weapon, Chamber: Second Lieutenant Ledo.
Ledo...
Extermination Weapon?
What are the Hideauze?
Enemy. Coexistence impossible.
You are fellow humans.
Join the Alliance.
Request dialogue.
Who is the commander?
Chamber, what did you say?
In their language,
I requested a dialogue
and offered the standard
.invitation to join the Alliance.
Good.
But why the hostility?
Drop your weapon, and you, come out of that thing!
What's she saying?
Unknown.
No person inside.
What?
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru yozora
The night sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
The Planet of the Beginning
You sure took your time, Amy.
I had to make up for
.the deliveries I delayed.
So, what is it?
Tell me your impressions of that boy.
Didn't you speak to him too?
Right?
You've had the closest
.interaction with him.
What do you think?
Nothing special?
Hmm...
He was all, "Whoa, what do I do?" like it was his first time here.
I don't think he wanted to hurt me.
He did touch my butt a little, though.
He what?!
The person in the Yunboro seemed
.to understand what we were saying.
Why don't we ask him directly?
You've gotta be kidding!
What if they get violent?
They destroyed the hangar in one hit!
Pinion.
You had a look at that Yunboroid, right?
Yeah, and I have no idea how
.it works or what it's made of.
Couldn't even stick a knife
.between the joints.
It's a tough one, all right.
What about you, Bellows?
Notice anything strange
when you retrieved it?
I dunno.
I just pick up stuff that might be
..worth something, like I was told to—
That reminds me,
the crane's broken now!
No one told me that
Yunboro would be so heavy!
I expect compensation.
What? Not my fault
.you're bad at your job.
What'd you say?
Commodore Fairlock, are you there?
I've been listening.
I believe that Yunboroid to be the
.product of advanced technology.
I think we should disassemble
.and reverse engineer it.
Yeah!
That mech's nothing like the stuff we pulled up so far!
Let's take it apart!
We can drag the pilot out and
..throw him into the sea with the boy—
That won't do.
They may not be alone.
They could pose a
.threat to the fleet later.
I see what you're getting at, but...
Geez, what a spoilsport.
You'd best listen to the Commodore.
We can't risk facing their vengeance.
I cannot identify any logic
.behind your actions.
Explain the reason why you
.maintain this stalemate.
My present armament is sufficient to resolve this situation.
This is for the best at the moment.
My suggestion is as follows.
One, overwhelm and
.stifle their armed forces.
Two, suppress their leader
.to prevent rebellion.
Chamber, our top priority is to get in contact with our allies
and identify our location.
Since your analysis has failed,
we're forced to rely on the
.historical records of these people.
Conditionally agreed.
The most important fact
.is that the Earth is alive.
We thought that the Sun's abnormal activity had turned it into a frozen wasteland,
yet look around us.
I agree.
The Alliance has always been on the lookout for habitable planets.
This planet is rich in
.both water and air.
It could replace Avalon
.as our new homeworld.
Remark: Your rank is not high enough to make that kind of decision.
I guess.
Did you manage to
contact the Alliance?
Distress signals were continuously sent, but there has been no response.
If you persist with autonomous actions, you will run out of supplies,
and that will impede your metabolism.
Suggestion number three.
You should consider withdrawing from this
.situation and returning to artificial hibernation.
Hey!
Hey, Pinion!
Who's gonna fix my ship now?!
Who cares, moron?!
Bye!
Thank you!
Amy!
How was the merman?
M-Merman?
I heard he took you hostage.
How old is he?
Is he handsome?
It has the whole fleet abuzz!
Gosh, just let me work!
Hey, Amy!
Open the wings before you jump!
And don't skip the safety check!
It's a rare piece of treasure.
Like I'd let Ridget's crew nick it!
Let's take a fine-toothed
comb to that place!
Heya, Bevel!
Hi, Sis.
Sorry for running late.
Are you all right?
I heard you were taken hostage.
Yeah, no worries.
Luckily, he didn't mean any harm.
He's called Ledo, apparently.
Ledo?
What's he like?
I'd say he's about as old as I am.
His arms are really slim,
and he's kinda effeminate.
There's another guy in his Yunboro.
He talks weird, but at least he speaks our language.
Then we can get along if we just keep talking to them!
I know, right?
That's what I said.
I got you a present.
Thanks!
Can you use it?
Yeah.
It's perfect!
Thanks a lot!
My pleasure!
I wanna talk with Ledo too.
Hmm?
He might've come
.from the sky, after all.
The sky? Ledo?
Yeah.
Don't you know the stories
about the people who escaped to the stars when the planet froze?
Oh, that?
That's just a legend!
And we found that
.Yunboro under the sea.
No, they've come from space.
I'm sure of it.
The people who escaped to space ages ago have come back!
Space, huh?
Why'd they bother
coming all the way here?
Dr. Ordum told me.
If ships could sail straight upwards,
we could make it to
.space in just half a day!
I see.
Someone is approaching.
Is she gonna be okay?
The Commodore was right to tell us not to
.provoke them, but they can't stay there forever.
But why her?
We had no other volunteers.
Want to go instead?
I'm good.
Conjecture: She poses little threat.
She might be an envoy sent for negotiations.
An envoy? She's just a kid!
Should I intercept?
No need for that.
Understood.
It is the carcass of a marine creature.
A carcass?!
What does she want?
It is presumed to be harmless food.
She wants me to eat it?!
It can be deduced to be
.a ceremony of friendship.
But it's a carcass!
The decision is yours.
Chamber, inquire about her purpose.
ik ek royto spulp
haue kesma
She requests dialogue.
Well then.
He ate it!
hweh amy
osey dewo ekuek
She calls herself Amy.
She asks where you hail from.
The sky?
So you're soldiers who
fight the "Hideauze"?
Yes.
Then you're stronger than those?
Super strong.
They're really from space.
I guess Bevel was right.
The present state of the Earth
.contradicts our records.
We demand explanation.
Your speech is getting better and better.
Translating everything must be tough.
Why don't you at least show us your face?
What do you mean by
"show us your face"?
I mean you, the person inside.
There is nobody inside.
Huh?
It really is empty!
I am an interface system that supports
.and oversees the development of pilots.
A system?
So it's a machine that's talking?
Chamber is an AI that offers the pilot combat and survival support.
Whoa...
Incredible!
That's unbelievable!
There's really no one
.inside! It's a machine!
I reiterate: Tell us about
.the current state of the Earth.
Oh my gosh!
They say it used to be a planet of ice.
Then the ice melted, and it
.became a planet of water.
Supposedly, long ago they had this place called "land" too,
but I'm not sure what that is.
Now we live like this,
by connecting our ships into fleets.
There's still old ships and resources at the bottom of the sea,
and we pull those back up.
Gargantia—oh, that's the name of this fleet—is no exception.
Gargantia?
Yes, Gargantia.
Are there others?
Huh?
Oh, there's other fleets too.
They come in all sizes.
All you need to do is chain
.a couple ships together.
There's also pesky ones, like pirates.
Are these "pirates" the enemy?
Yeah, kinda.
Oh, don't worry about that.
That's a galaxy current.
Some call it a "sea galaxy."
It's really pretty,
so keep watching.
That's good.
Now we'll get a
.new galaxy current.
Define "galaxy current."
Shining currents on the sea.
We can only live on those,
so we sail on,
following the currents,
but they don't go on forever.
Eventually we need to find a new galaxy current to switch to.
The sea galaxy shines
.because of lightbugs.
They're tiny creatures
.that store electricity.
We get our power
.from this strip of light.
It's so pretty!
What?
Did you ascertain our coordinates?
Due to atmospheric interference, the lack of information,
and the limits of optical analysis,
continued observation is required to
successfully determine our current position.
I'm telling you, it's true!
I think.
You're not even trying
.to make it sound realistic.
In the small chance that indeed was a talking machine—
It really is!
But still, waging war
against space creatures?
That's a load of bull!
What we should do is take it apart
and see for ourselves if it can really talk!
The kid can just sleep with the fishes.
Are you serious?
They've got no place to go!
They need help!
You should listen to
.what Ledo's telling us!
Extensive contact with the abnormal is profitable to no one.
This applies to both sea and space.
Location identified.
This is definitely where
.we found that Yunboro.
Okay then! Leave no stone unturned!
Supplies are plentiful here, and
.the locals pose little to no threat.
Conditionally agreed.
If we can't return to the
.battlefront by ourselves,
we'll just have to wait for our allies to notice our distress signal.
Building a cooperative relationship here is probably the best choice.
Agreed.
Words like "battlefront" and "allies" are completely foreign to the people of this planet.
Our life-and-death struggle against
.the Hideauze doesn't concern them.
What's that? What happened?
What's going on?
Pirates are attacking the salvagers!
Bellows' ship!
Bellows' people...
Shoot!
The cocky bastards are attacking.
Guard Captain!
No chance! There's too many of them!
Salvagers, stay underwater!
Multiple engine sounds detected.
Confirm it!
Ledo!
Amy?
They have kites?
They have nine ships
.and several small boats.
They are attacking with kites.
Where are the reinforcements?
They might not make it in time.
An enemy attack?
Aren't you guys strong?
Isn't that a super-strong Yunboro?
Help us! Please!
She requests assistance.
Let's do it. We can use it
.as a bargaining chip later.
Activate floater.
The weird Yunboro's moving!
What?!
What is he planning to do?
Launch.
So you're Bellows of Gargantia?
Take what you can and get lost!
Why are you sticking
with this shitty fleet?
Come with us.
Lady Rackage thinks very highly of you.
Dream on, pathetic pirates!
What do you think you're doing?!
You'd better not try to piss us off.
Damn you!
Friend-or-foe identification
.of the larger units complete.
Requesting permission
.to identify smaller targets.
Do it.
Identification complete.
Deflector beam on standby.
Eliminate them.
What's going on?!
What's going on here?
What the hell...
What was that?
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo