Okay!
Let's try suspending it!
Thank you.
You've completed the linking procedures.
Fantastic.
This is one hell of a fleet you've got.
Thank you for warning
.us about the pirates.
We welcome you.
Our pleasure!
We'll be in your care.
Commodore, we've completed
.the linking procedures.
Good.
And what about him?
Well...
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru yozora
The night sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Flute of Memories
Okay! Tighten the wires!
Boss!
Move 'em! They're in the way!
Hey! Don't just put those anywhere!
Where... do I put?
Over there!
Where the other cargo is!
Okay, move them over there.
Roger.
What the...
I said no flying around!
Ch-Chamber!
Hey, are you okay?!
Fool! Don't just cut the rope!
Can't you do something
about this yourself?
We haven't yet decided how to manage your residency rights,
so could you live here
for the time being?
Here?!
Is there a problem?
This place is so inconvenient!
This is okay.
Chamber close. Convenient.
Is that what matters?
No problem.
And one more thing...
The invoice.
Invoice?
They demand that you work to repay
.the damage you caused to the hangar.
Come on, Ridget!
Ledo's the one who chased off the pirates!
The damage of the hangar
.is a separate matter.
But he just arrived here!
He doesn't know anything yet!
We will not charge him for water or electricity during his stay,
and we will waive the freight
.tax for this giant payload.
It's not simply a one-sided agreement.
Ledo, are you sure
you're okay with this?
Tell me about the details.
Hey, your Yunboro's in the way!
Move to where?
Take the next load of cargo
and drop 'em off at the same place!
Chamber, take them away.
Roger.
What did I say about flying?!
That's quite a Yunboro you've got there.
Does it understand people besides you?
It does.
Will it listen to me?
The transfer of command rights is permitted to the degree allowed by army regulations.
Meaning?
It will.
I see. Excellent!
Hey, boss! I got a great idea!
Okay, that'll do!
Something for you!
Thanks!
Ah, hard at work I see.
Huh?
What's the matter with him?
He's slacking off while the
.metalhead does all the work.
What happened?
That frickin' dolt.
We really oughta feed him to the fish—
He might be just taking a break!
There we go!
I cannot identify any logic
.behind your actions.
It's just a way to focus my mind.
I'm surprised these people can
.move about so much in this heat.
There's no discipline here.
What are their instructors up to?
It can be conjectured that instructors
.do not oversee the training of children here.
Then how can they grow into
productive members of society?
Awaiting further orders.
Just hold on a sec!
I'm first!
Not fair!
Say something!
C'mon! Fly!
Completion of mission is currently hindered.
Requesting permission to dispose of obstacles.
Permission granted.
Be mindful not to cause any damages.
Understood.
Ledo.
How's it going?
I am standing by.
Standing by? I see.
What's that? Are you making something?
I don't know.
You're making something you don't know?
That's weird.
What a strange material.
Hideauze claw.
Cannot find on this planet.
It's really pretty!
You can have it.
You sure?
Hey, you got time for a walk?
I'm sure my little brother will love it!
"Little brother"?
Yeah. His name's Bevel.
He's really good at making stuff.
What does "little brother" mean?
"Little brother" means a sibling.
A younger sibling.
Uh... Family?
"Family"?
A societal unit found in
antiquated communities
centered around a male-female
.couple based on genetic relation.
I've never heard of that custom.
You don't have a family?
Inefficient. Unnecessary.
Inefficient?
The place you come
.from sounds really harsh.
Bevel wants to ask you about space.
About space?
Yeah. He's really interested in stars, and ships that can go to space.
But his body's really frail, so he
.can't exactly be out and about.
Frail?
He's got this... chest disease.
In the Galactic Alliance, weak individuals
.are removed and disposed of.
Individuals incapable of combat
.are considered unnecessary.
Unnecessary? And you
just let that happen?
I understand not the question.
I see...
Will talking to this person
lead me to useful intel?
Intel?
You should probably talk
.to Dr. Ordum for that.
Ordum?
He's a doctor, but we call him
.the wise man of the fleet.
He's the most knowledgeable
person on Gargantia!
This way!
Good morning, Dr. Ordum!
Oh, Amy!
Doctor! Amy's here!
Good morning! Oh, Doctor!
Well, if it isn't Amy.
I brought a guest today!
Are you the famous Ledo, by any chance?
He said he'd like to ask you something.
That so?
Anyway, I still have
.work to do, so I gotta go.
You must be busy.
Ledo, I'll come pick you up,
so wait for me downstairs later!
I would like information from you.
I heard the rumors,
but is that the voice of the machine that can understand our language?
Correct.
We've lost that technology.
I never thought I'd see it for myself.
Can ask more questions?
I'll answer to the best of my knowledge.
Sit down.
What would you like to know?
Do you know of a way to return to the Galactic Alliance?
Sadly, I don't know nearly
.enough to answer that.
As you can see, most of the ancient
.knowledge has been lost.
In particular, that pertaining
.to interstellar travel.
This is all the knowledge
.we have left about the sky.
I doubt this is what you're looking for.
I'm sorry I couldn't help you.
Not your fault.
Can ask another question?
Sure, go right ahead.
I request your explanation regarding
.the organization of this fleet.
Explanation?
This fleet is inefficient.
The chain of command and the
.training process are imperfect.
The behavior of the civilians is disorganized.
I also cannot understand
.why you protect the weak.
I see... So that's what it looks
.like to a visitor from space.
Ah, forgive me.
It seems that you have a very narrow
.interpretation of what "efficiency" means.
Let's see...
Maybe you should talk
.with Bevel sometime.
Will this person provide
me with useful intel?
It's up to you to decide how useful it is.
I see... So not even Doc knew.
Hey, Bevel! I'm back!
Welcome back, Sis.
Is this Ledo?
He really is your friend!
You're awesome!
Nice to meet you.
I'm Bevel.
So this is Amy's "little brother"?
Please take a seat.
Ledo said he wanted to see you.
Really?
Yes.
I request information from you.
Wait, was that...
Yep! Chamber talks
.through this transmitter.
Amazing! It really can talk!
Chamber...
I am an AI whose purpose
.is to assist my pilot.
That's so cool!
You can even understand our language!
Amy, you there?
We need a hand. Can you fill in?
Huh?
Whoa, look at this cutie!
Since when did you two...
You've got it all wrong!
Sorry, I gotta work again.
See you later.
Man, I was looking forward to this, too...
Looking forward to what?
Will you cut that out?!
Bevel, take care of Ledo for me!
Try not to rush and fall over this time!
Sure, I'll—
Amy!
Sorry my sister's so busy all the time.
I do not mind.
Ledo, are you really from space?
I've always wondered what life in space would be like!
In the Galactic Alliance, our main task
.is to defend against the Hideauze.
What's a Hideauze?
Alien lifeforms that threaten humankind.
Are you constantly fighting them?
The conflict has lasted since the founding of
.the Galactic Alliance up until the present day.
That's totally different
.from how we live here.
Don't you ever get tired?
Those who tire, die.
Die...
I see. It must be tough.
Are you used to this place yet?
I cannot comprehend the
.organization of Gargantia.
Organization?
Explain to me the reason behind your
.inefficient and unprofitable actions.
The fleet isn't an organization.
We all just kind of gathered together here.
Sometimes we fight, and
.other times we help each other.
That's just how we live.
What is the purpose of that?
It doesn't matter if we can live without worrying, right?
Your answer is questionable.
The purpose of mankind is to subjugate the enemy, the Hideauze.
Otherwise, the steady progress of
.mankind cannot be guaranteed.
You think so?
In the Galactic Alliance, people like you
.would be weeded out immediately.
Weeded out?
But then, what'll happen to the Galactic Alliance once you defeat all the Hideauze?
What will you do, Ledo?
I will be on standby,
.awaiting my next orders.
Then, what if no more come?
I will remain on standby.
That's what we're doing!
Is it?
Doesn't standing by mean
that you're "living on"?
Hey, Ledo!
I hear Joe took your Yunboro.
Now you've ruined your
.hard-earned hero image.
Ledo?
Were my actions beneficial?
Yours?
Well, you got rid of the pirates for us.
At the moment, all I do
.is oversee Chamber.
You're just not used to it yet.
I cannot determine which actions I am supposed to take.
Supposed to, huh?
How about leaving that
soldier mentality behind?
Leaving behind...
Yep. You could just let yourself—
It's raining!
Collect the rain!
What's this? What's going on?!
It is a weather phenomenon.
It is not poisonous.
This is an emergency!
Go collect the rain with your Yunboro!
Fresh water is precious!
What should I do?
There's some sailcloth over there!
Spread it out and collect the water!
Chamber!
Roger!
Okay, that's good!
I detect changes in your brainwaves.
I was just wondering if the army
.made any progress in the war.
At present, such thoughts are illogical.
I know.
Cutie spotted!
He's sooo cool!
But, you know, I kinda
.feel sorry for him.
He's all alone in some
.completely foreign place.
Don't worry. A cute guy
like him will be just fine!
Right?
Oh, come on! I know
you're worried about him!
Just go already!
Ledo, you're soaked.
You're gonna catch a cold like that.
Come to my place to dry off.
I heard the squall was pretty intense.
It was the first time I observed the
.phenomenon of concentrated rain.
Does it rain in space?
No.
Are there any seas?
And sick people like me?
They do not exist.
But I don't think I'm not needed.
I...
I've got my sister.
Amy?
She needs me.
You managed to live on till now
because someone needed you too, right?
Only the lives of those who are fit for battle are deemed to be worth preserving.
Well then, is there anyone out there that you need?
My sister and I need each other.
And most of all, I need myself.
So I live on.
I...
The Alliance sees no point in allowing
.unneeded individuals to survive.
Then, what is this to you?
That...
My sister told me that you made it
.without even knowing what it was.
It's gotta be a flute.
Definitely not something you need in battle.
A flute?
Yeah. I learned how to play it, too.
Ledo, what's wrong?
Why are you crying?
I...
Did I do something wrong?
No. I do not know.
Why?
You must've remembered
.something very sad.
I did?
Bevel?
Yes?
Can I have that again?
Of course.
I brought you tea!
Saya says it's good!
It's really tasty!
Chamber, do you still not
know our coordinates?
Observational data is insufficient.
More time is required.
I see.
Looks like I have a lot more to learn about this planet.
It is not necessary.
You will eventually be
.reunited with the army.
Yeah, I know.
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo