Stop! That's a whalesquid!
Don't attack it!
Interference from the seawater
.is disrupting accurate targeting.
I'll hit it next time!
Leave it be, Ledo!
It'll just get more violent if you provoke it!
Dammit!
Take this!
Charge the next shot!
Warning: beam weapons deemed ineffective underwater.
Possibility of damaging allied vessels.
In that case...
Stop!
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
A Soldier's Duty
Hey! Looking good!
Not now. I'm not in the mood.
The space guy came flying back earlier.
I heard he killed a whalesquid.
He did what?!
Whalesquids have been considered
.sacred creatures since ancient times.
And he killed it for no reason...
What in the world were
you thinking, Ledo?
Folk are already starting to feel uneasy.
Rumors are going around that this'll bring about a curse.
Considering who did it,
people will obviously be shocked.
Are you serious?
What's going on?
It's all just superstition.
For sailors, however, he just
.committed the greatest taboo.
I can only hope nothing bad will happen...
Analyze this.
How long will it take?
Amplification and analysis of the DNA is estimated to take four hours.
Get to it.
Understood.
However, the probability of a result contradicting the unique wave signature is minimal.
I know.
I want to find out if the Hideauze
.on Earth have any unique traits.
Roger.
So the Hideauze have reached even Earth?
Could I have brought it here
with me from space?
No, that's impossible...
Lieutenant.
While I can complete a biological analysis,
I cannot retrieve any information
.regarding their invasion strategy.
I'll gather intel from the fleet.
I need to know their numbers and territory.
Someone is approaching.
All right, that's it.
How have you been feeling?
Pretty well these days, thanks to you.
Try to take it easy,
and take a few days off every now and then.
You ought to move to the main ship
..where it's a little more pastoral and—
I like it here.
Though I may not be
.able to walk anymore,
my legs still remember
.just how great this fleet is.
My eyes and ears still remember
.the people sailing along with us.
I want to continue to protect the smiles
.and laughter of those who live here.
That's the proof that I'm alive.
I can't argue with that.
Just when you need to stay in bed,
it seems the fleet got
.involved with a whalesquid.
For heaven's sake...
No matter how old you get,
life will always be full of new experiences.
So you say you're not afraid?
Whatever reality gives us,
it is our privilege to accept it while we live.
Privilege, huh?
Of course, should I become unable to lead,
I must pass the torch to my successor.
Is that so?
Have you guys heard about this?
The whalesquids' territory is full of treasures no one's ever seen before!
And we'll be the ones taking 'em!
Riches as far as the eye can see!
So?
No one's ever dared brave a whalesquid nest!
Well, that's the thing!
How can you say there's a load of treasure if no one's been there?
But someone did go there.
He told me about it before he died.
We're mechanics, not salvagers!
Show me someone fool enough to take on a whalesquid!
Right here! That metalhead!
Those monsters stand no chance against him!
Huh? You already have him on board?
Well... I'm working on it.
What?
You don't even have the basics covered?
Come back once you got the space boy and his metalhead convinced!
Let's get going.
How could you let this
happen under your watch?
You let him attack a whalesquid!
All of the ships' captains are feeling uneasy.
I have a whole list of people waiting for action to be taken.
I'm not going to make excuses.
It was my fault for not telling him beforehand.
That means there are lots more?
Then, I will do the same in
.the future and do my duty.
Do you even understand
what you're saying?!
The Hideauze are a
.threat to all of Mankind.
Annihilating them is the
.only possible option.
That is nothing but your opinion.
We have no reason whatsoever to kill whalesquids.
Real peace and prosperity cannot be achieved without eliminating every threat!
Where do you think you are right now?
This is Gargantia!
The Commodore wants to hear the details.
Perfect. They're here too.
Do you really want to continue arguing in front of the Commodore?
Very well.
I'll report to him, then.
You two may leave.
Hey, Flange!
What?!
Hush...
Ledo...
Tell me more about the Hideauze... The whalesquids!
How many are there?
What are their strengths?
What are their weaknesses?
H-Hold on a second, Ledo.
Are you still planning on doing something?
You can't!
The whalesquids get really scary if you're aggressive towards them,
but they won't attack unless provoked.
That's right!
Don't you feel sorry for them?
Impossible.
They are enemies.
They must be annihilated.
Why do you not understand?!
Why do you want to keep up
your stupid war here on Earth?
Your fight's got nothing to do with us! Don't drag us into it!
Your civilization is very—
I don't understand what you're saying!
Your civilization is so primitive that the Hideauze simply ignore you.
Confrontation is but a matter of time.
When the time comes, how do you intend to stand against them?
Uh, well...
You neither have a specific plan of action,
nor do you even think about the betterment of your civilization as a whole.
Instead, you fight amongst yourselves despite being fellow humans.
When they attack,
it will be too late to plan.
I will kill them before that.
Ledo...
You won't listen?
I live to kill them.
You don't have to do that to be yourself...
Pinion, if you're planning anything stupid, give up now.
What do you mean?
You wanna use Ledo and Chamber, and loot the whalesquids' territory.
Something wrong with that?
He wants to fight the whalesquids anyway.
We'll just be there to grab the treasures!
Even if that means putting the fleet at risk?
Whatever you find might as well be trash if it doesn't help Gargantia in some way!
Why wouldn't it?
No one's even explored the place!
It's all uncharted!
Prizes beyond your wildest dreams are waiting for us!
So, what do you say?
You should come too!
Can't you feel your salvager blood boiling?
Sorry, but I'm not interested
.in your childish expedition.
What was that?!
All you want to do is
.inflate that ego of yours.
You can't even do it yourself,
.so you get someone else to do it.
And you're content with that.
Screw you, Bellows!
Dammit.
What if I said I wanted
to avenge my brother?
That, too, is nothing but a pipe dream.
Any word from the Alliance?
No response so far.
Could you determine our coordinates?
Further parallax measurements
.of the planet's orbit are required.
Dammit.
The analysis of the biological
.sample is complete.
What's the result?
The exoskeleton has adapted
.to the different environment,
but the genetic data is indistinguishable from the Hideauze.
It is the same species.
I knew it!
So, I'm correct to try and annihilate them.
I must do this for the people of Earth.
Why won't they understand that?
Based on linguistic analysis,
I hypothesize that the
Earthian survival strategy
is fundamentally different
.from that of the Alliance.
What do you mean?
The answer for that question is not included in the standard dictionary of the Alliance.
However, it exists in the Earthian language.
What is it?
Coexistence and mutual prosperity.
The galaxy current's shining like crazy!
I've never seen anything like it!
What?!
Hey, isn't that the whalesquids?
Stand back!
Multiple underwater objects approaching.
Judging from their noise signature, they are likely to be Hideauze.
Come, Chamber!
Please, don't go!
Sonar ping at 10 o'clock.
There's a ton of them!
Depth at about thirty!
Thirty?!
Double the patrols!
Have the defense vessels on standby beside the main fleet!
This can't be...
To have so many come in such
.shallow waters is unheard of.
What are we supposed to do about this?
Their trajectory will intersect with ours!
The whalesquids!
A whole shoal's coming!
Get it up! Get it up!
This is all because we let that alien stay here!
Dammit!
Forgive us!
Calm your anger!
Commodore!
Stop the siren.
Yes, sir!
I will take command. Understood?
Of course, sir.
But...
This is Commodore Fairlock.
I want everyone to listen carefully.
A group of whalesquids is approaching the fleet.
Though they may be numerous,
no harm will come to us
.if we prepare accordingly.
In order to minimize provocation,
we will now stop all of Gargantia's engines.
Ridget, relay that to all the ships.
I don't want any light or sound.
Roger.
Once we halt the engines, citizens
.are to remain wherever they are.
Keep noise to a minimum!
Help us!
Cut the main power supply!
Move out of the way.
No!
Fine.
You can't! Don't go!
Please!
Let me go!
Why?
My fight has nothing to do with you!
It does!
You mean with the fleet?
Then I will not cause you any more trouble. I will leave!
I will fight alone!
That's not it!
I just don't want you doing something that dangerous!
I—
Ridget?
I warned you before.
You must follow our directives.
I refuse.
That is not an option.
If the whalesquids attack the fleet, you are free to do as you please.
But until that time, you'll do as I say!
They are right under the fleet.
Ledo...
Do not touch me.
I cannot do my duty as long as I am here.
I am a soldier.
Ledo, you can't...
I'm taking Ledo and Chamber with me.
We'll head out to the whalesquids' territory and do some salvaging.
Are you serious?
Who'd joke about this?
Here's a list of people who've
.signed up to come with me.
We're leaving Gargantia.
Come on. Just approve it.
Commodore, I'd also like to ask for
.permission to leave with my ships.
Flange?
You too? But why?
You own so many ships.
If you left, Gargantia's defenses
would be left bare!
The seabed holds the glorious
.heritage of a bygone era.
I hope I can retrieve even a bit of it.
Please don't hold it against me.
But...
No. I will never agree to put all of Gargantia in danger
for the personal gain
..of a few narrow-minded—
Commodore!
Oh no! Call Dr. Ordum!
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo