Bellows!
Got a delivery for you!
Thanks.
Keep up the good work.
Will do!
I'm glad to see you've cheered up.
Well, there's no point in feeling depressed forever.
We got word that Flange's fleet is in the Sea of Fog.
The galaxy current seems to be flowing that way,
so we might end up sailing in the same area.
There's a chance that we'll find out what's going on.
I hope Pinion didn't do anything too stupid.
Well, all that matters to me is that they're safe.
Later!
Huh? What's that?!
That thing's huge! Is it pirates?
Commodore!
Put the whole fleet on emergency alert!
But don't make any careless moves.
Call Pinion.
Actually, I'll call him myself.
Ledo?
Colonel? Is that you, Colonel Kugel?
Long time no see, Ledo.
I'm glad to see you're doing well.
Likewise, Colonel.
I picked up your distress signal.
However, I was on the other side of this planet.
If you contacted me, I would've come to you, sir.
I had to keep radio silence.
Can you come over here?
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant Ledo will now return to the Kugel squadron.
What's that?
Are they pirates?
It's gigantic! This ain't good!
Shouldn't we retreat, Pinion?
Retreat? To where?
Don't worry! We got this cannon and the Metalhead!
How about we give them a nice, warm welcome?
Aye-aye.
Target aligned!
Ready to fire!
Fire!
How d'you like that? Go run to momma!
Huh?
What was that?!
It was like a lightning bolt!
Look at what you've done to my treasure!
Huh? The Metalhead?
No...
Hey, Ledo! Ledo, where are you?
This is Lt. Ledo.
I shall now return to the ranks of the Galactic Alliance of Mankind.
Huh? What are you saying?!
Ledo! Metalhead!
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Ruler of Fear
Guiding signal acknowledged. Commencing landing.
What are they doing?
Unknown.
I hypothesize it is a collective action to demonstrate the unity of their group.
So he took command of the locals?
We welcome you,
O herald of the skies, clad in a thunder giant's form.
In the name of Providence, we wish you peace and prosperity.
What is she saying?
I believe those are idiosyncrasies referring to Machine Calibers and their pilots.
Where is Colonel Kugel?
Follow me.
Come.
Please wait here.
Excuse my use of a hologram.
Colonel Kugel! I'm happy to see you alive and well and on this planet!
If only.
A endemic disease got the best of me.
I'm unable to leave my sterilized cockpit.
How are you yourself?
No such problems, sir.
That's good. Having to issue orders from here is (such/quite) a nuisance
I understand.
Having you around will help a lot.
What do you say? Will you follow me once more?
But of course, Colonel!
Chamber K6821 to Striker X3752:
I request information about the aforementioned endemic disease.
Striker X3752 to Chamber K6821.
Request acknowledged. Transmitting data.
Hey, we're surrounded.
This ain't good.
We got the treasures!
Is it really gonna be fine?
Don't panic.
If things turn sour, the Metalhead—
Didn't they just leave?
We're done for.
C-Come on now, calm down.
We don't know what they want either.
What else could they want
but the ancient treasures?
How would they know about it?
You broadcast it for the whole world to hear!
What now?
Uh... sorry.
I doubt you have the time for this.
Don't butt in.
Look around you!
Get back to your positions immediately!
Thanks for that.
I heard that the weapon's in the hands of one of Ledo's comrades.
Yeah.
So there was more than one visitor from the skies?
But what could he possibly want from us?
Urgent message!
The fleet just got hailed.
Flange speaking. What is it?
They demand the presence of our representative.
Why?
They haven't specified a reason.
They must be here for the relics.
I'll go.
Wait!
I'm responsible for this mess.
I'll see to it that it gets cleaned up.
I've no time for your delusions of grandeur. I can't trust you with diplomatic negotiations.
Um, sir...
They demanded Pinion of the Sea of Fog as our representative.
See? I'm up.
Are you out of your mind?
If you were taken hostage, who'd keep this fleet together?
But still...
It's okay. Even if I stayed here, no one would follow me after I screwed up this badly.
You reap what you sow.
Fine. Just be careful.
Sure thing. Off I go.
Pinion!
Yeah?
Just wait here. They said they're gonna send a ship.
Right.
"No one would follow me after screwing up this badly."
Oh, shut up.
You're overthinking it.
It's not true at all.
That so?
You've always been a loser. No one's gonna leave over this.
Thanks, I guess.
Here they come.
Huh? Look!
That's the...
Surfing Lobster!
You're Pinion of the Sea of Fog, right?
Yeah. What a surprise to see Rackage, the great queen of pirates herself, here.
Just "Rackage" will do fine.
Also...
You'd do well to mind that mouth of yours.
Right, gotcha.
Times look hard. Are they eating at all?
The weak serve the strong.
Such is the God's Providence, apparently.
Your "God" being... that?
That's a thunder giant.
A servant of God that supposedly hands down divine judgment.
While the humans of this planet do get to live in such a luxuriant environment,
they must do so under the constant oppression of the Hideauze.
Our duty is to teach them to defend themselves and become missionaries of mankind's glory.
As for that, sir...
The Hideauze...
They're humans!
Former humans.
You knew, sir?!
It was not something that was discussed, even in the upper echelons.
For those of us fighting on the front-line, it is only unnecessary information.
Unnecessary, sir?
The Hideauze are driven by hunger and base instincts.
They cannot be called humans.
Yes, sir.
Both the strong and the weak support each other with reason.
They contribute in their own way to the formation of society.
That is what it means to be human.
Yes, that may be true, but...
I have brought order to this fleet.
As a result, the average well-being of the people here has risen.
I request the definition of "well-being" in this context.
Based on the principles of the Galactic Alliance,
"well-being" is defined as the state in which the cost-benefit performance
of the individual's contribution to the community is maximized.
Therefore, well-being correlates directly with the stability of command.
I agree with this definition and conclusion.
Is that... right?
Say, Ledo. Won't you help me change this planet?
Here.
Huh, no one's here.
What's this?
Pretty neat!
What about this then?
Gotcha.
Pinion of the Sea of Fog, we welcome you as our distinguished guest.
The heck? It was a transmitter?
It is necessary for the technology of the humans on Earth to improve.
This was a test to measure the skills of Pinion of the Sea of Fog.
Your aptitude is judged to be promising.
You sound familiar. Are you a relative of the Metalhead?
I am the pilot support system Striker X3752.
And what might you want from me, Striker?
We commend you on restoring a cannon retrieved from the sea floor to operational capacity.
However, it is but a temporary measure that lacks an understanding of the underlying structure.
What am I to do, then?
I got no idea how that ancient machinery stuff works.
We are willing to provide you with information on that matter.
Whoa...
With your skills, repairing weaponry would only be the first step.
Designing and manufacturing new weapons are within your capabilities.
You sure think highly of me.
You have been deemed to be capable of handling such technology.
Our final demand is that you display leadership as an engineer officer.
"Officer"?
I ain't no soldier!
More importantly, can you guarantee the safety of our fleet?
Valuable human resources are not to be expended without a rational cause.
"Expended"?
Well, if you can guarantee our safety, I'm willing to cooperate.
I expect great things from you.
Read this before you eat.
The sooner you speak, the sooner we'll be done.
Aren't you a stuck-up one...
Sit still, and it'll be over soon.
This is Pinion of the Sea of Fog addressing you.
Devotion and cooperation are at the essence of people.
By joining the Kugel fleet, the Flange fleet will attain even greater prosperity.
I trust you to make the wise decision.
That's what it says.
This is nothing but a well-phrased demand to surrender.
Commodore?
Yet we have no choice but to accept.
I take it you are the leader of this fleet.
Indeed I am.
You have made the right decision.
I wish to resolve this peacefully.
What are you trying to do?
They want to tear our fleet apart!
What?!
Ships will be selected according to their ability.
I can't have that.
Our fleet is like our family.
Only together does it function.
From now on, you are to contribute to an even greater family.
But—
Happiness shall come to those who follow Providence.
However, the judgment of God shall fall upon those who oppose it.
I see...
Then kneel. We shall grant you the Blessing.
May you devote your life and ability to work in the name of Providence.
This looks pretty different from the other place.
These guys must be rich.
There's no money here.
How do you live without money?
People receive rations based on their contributions to the fleet.
It's a very fair community.
Fair, huh?
Your living quarters are this way. I'll show you to your room.
What's with these guys?
Where are my people?
Your ships are splitting up and joining the fleet as we speak.
"Splitting up"?!
But of course. Did you expect us to be so naive as to keep potential insurgents in one place?
You ask us to join then you treat us like insurgents?!
Either way, it would be most wise if you refrained from contacting your friends for now.
It's all over...
Virus data analysis complete.
Commencing medical examination.
Medical examination complete.
No abnormalities.
The Colonel commanded a fleet from such cramped a spot?
I can't measure up to that.
I conjecture that Colonel Kugel's withdrawal to his cockpit had the effect
of turning his figure into a symbol and provoke sentiments of awe among fleet members.
It appears to have led to his current strong authority.
You fear what you can't see, huh?
But is keeping these people perpetually afraid the right path?
Fear is the most primal animal reaction.
While those who oppose him see fear as the root of his authority,
it nevertheless provides peace and safety to those who obey him.
That's true, but still...
It has been concluded that rule through force is effective in the fight against the Hideauze.
It enables the mobilization of a large number of personnel
and the maintenance of a stable and responsive community.
Furthermore—
Enough.
Maybe... I shouldn't have left the cockpit either.
Welcome back, milady.
Good evening.
I have returned.
How was the man called Pinion?
Vulgar.
Oh my!
Should we dispose of him?
It's too early for that.
His skills are genuine.
Besides, idling around all day has gotten boring.
Waking process complete.
Transmission from Colonel Kugel.
How are you feeling?
Fine, sir.
I'm in need of your help.
Is it the Hideauze, sir?
No. It's missionary work among the folk of this planet.
As you command, sir.
Good answer.
Now that you're here and we've got two Machine Calibers at our disposal,
I can proceed with the large-scale missionary work I've been planning for a while.
This is the target.
That's...
Gargantia...
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo