Halt the engines!
How's it going?
Everything's smooth so far.
But is this really okay?
Sure it is.
The Metalhead just annihilated all the whalesquids!
What's that?!
It's the Metalhead! Ledo!
How did it go?
All Hideauze in the area have been exterminated.
All right! Way to go!
Get those Yunboros out!
The legendary treasure's all ours now!
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Island of Ambition
Okay! Stop!
The shaft's over there!
All right, take your time!
Go on!
Nice! Looking good over there!
Pinion, check this out!
Okay!
Looks like the catch's gonna be good.
Yeah.
Bro, I wanted to drink this with you.
Pinion.
How d'you like it? And this is just the tip of the iceberg!
So this is the heritage our great ancestors have left behind...
Yeah.
There's even better stuff buried deep inside the whalesquids' lair.
Just like my brother said.
No rust at all.
And there's a whole mountain of this stuff down there!
These treasures will let us restore the world to its former glory!
Restore the world?
We're the ones who found this!
It's our treasure!
What are you saying?
I'm here because I wanted to use this heritage for the benefit of all mankind—
And what's the point if we don't benefit from it first?
Others are just going to try to take it from us if we keep it all to ourselves.
We've got plenty of firepower right here!
There's nothing to be afraid of!
That's not the problem!
If anyone butts in, we'll kick their asses!
Hey, you!
Send out a message that we annihilated the whalesquids and got the treasure!
No! You'd only provoke the ships in the area!
I'm just warning them so they don't poke their noses in our stuff.
Maximum range! Get it ready!
Sure...
Attention to all ships receiving this message!
We've annihilated all the whalesquids nesting in the Sea of Fog!
The whole shoal's dead, and their nest is gone too!
I'm Pinion!
Remember me as Pinion of the Sea of Fog!
To all you out there who wanted the treasure in the whalesquids' nest:
You're too late!
Don't even think of trying anything funny now!
The treasure's all ours!
This is a warning to all ships!
We will sink any approaching vessel without mercy!
Pinion does have a point.
Not you too!
There's no doubt that the pirates will show up.
We need to build up our firepower.
Why does everyone assume this will end up in conflict?
Mr. Flange,
you have a delivery.
Hand it over.
Thank you.
Is there anything else?
I heard Ledo killed all the whalesquids.
Yes, he did.
Um... Are we gonna be all right?
Even I can't tell.
Are you sure this is okay?
Enough—
Of course it's not!
With Ledo and Chamber on our side, we are able to delve into the whalesquids' nest.
That much is fine.
But instead of trading our new-found treasures with other ships,
we threaten to attack anyone that approaches?
It's ludicrous.
Can't you stop him?
We're gonna end up as outcasts!
The ship owners under my command
have begun listening to Pinion as well.
We certainly do need his abilities as a mechanic to properly utilize what we salvage.
He wouldn't give up even if I tried stopping him.
But...
Lieutenant.
Why aren't you helping us out here?
You should be able to handle salvaging without me.
The shaft's blocked!
Open it up with the Metalhead!
No!
What's the matter with you, Ledo?
Have you lost your nerve?
Lost my nerve? Me?
Ridiculous!
I annihilated the Hideauze!
There's nothing to fear!
Nothing to fear...
Joe! That's enough for today!
Okay!
Commodore, has the new layout of the fleet been finalized?
Yes. The ship owners were all very cooperative.
All that's left now is to relink the ships.
It's no small task, though.
Commodore, did you hear Pinion's broadcast?
Of course I did.
What is your honest opinion about it?
Until there's evidence that he's telling the truth, there's no need to act.
However...
Has the news spread among the fleet?
Every soul probably knows by now.
I see.
Some ship owners might become jealous and decide to leave.
And if they do?
I will respect their decision.
Dr. Ordum, is it true?
I heard Ledo destroyed the whalesquids' nest.
Yes. I heard Pinion's broadcast myself.
Oh no...
How foolish.
How terribly foolish!
What if I said I wanted to avenge my brother?
I told you that was nothing but a dream.
Hey, Amy.
I wonder how Melty's doing.
I'm sure they're fine, right?
Pinion's just bragging.
Hey, Amy...
How should I know?!
How should I know?
Ledo...
Why?
Any signs that they'll surrender?
None whatsoever.
Aren't they just out of ammo?
Don't stop firing.
What?!
We've got plenty of ammo.
They attacked us.
Are we gonna sink them?!
If they don't surrender, then yeah.
Oh, right!
The treasure's repairs should be done by now.
Let's give them a taste of that.
A bit more! A bit more! A bit more!
Okay, that'll do.
All set!
Okay! Fire!
Easier said than done.
Is this it? Or that?
You guys are useless!
They're surrendering!
About time, those fools!
Man, why even bother struggling?
That's what you get for picking a fight.
Please, spare us!
We'll hand over all the culprits!
Let us join you!
And if we took in every mob that makes the same request,
the platoon would just get bigger and—
Hang on.
If we expanded the fleet in this way, we'd become invincible.
And there's still a bunch of stuff that needs to be hauled up!
Very well!
Gather those who want to join!
O-Okay!
Looks like we got ourselves a deal here, old man.
Lock this one up somewhere!
Ledo...
We'd like to check the stuff we pulled up...
With, uh... the Metalhead.
What d'you say?
Use of equipment outside of missions requires the Lieutenant's authorization.
Heard that? You don't mind, right?
I don't care.
Then it's settled!
Come on then!
We can't do this without you!
You too, Metalhead!
Come on!
Drink up, man!
Good job, everyone!
Those pirate ships who came looking for trouble have all surrendered!
Things have been going well for us since we made this place our stronghold!
We've got Ledo and Chamber to thank for that!
Now you all better kiss that Metalhead's ass!
What am I doing?
For what purpose?
For whose sake?
When did it begin?
Was it when I woke up beneath these foreign skies?
Was it when I first got into Chamber, a Machine Caliber?
Or maybe when I first came into this world?
Well?
It's a primitive EMP weapon.
EMP? What's that?
Its basic construction is similar to my beam weapons.
For real?
However, its output is estimated to be 1/50th that of mine.
1/50th of yours is still huge!
It is approximately 76 times the current combined firepower of this fleet.
Very nice indeed!
Can we make it work?
Repairs might make reactivation possible.
However, firing it requires tremendous amounts of electricity.
Electricity, huh?
Could we make it work with lightbugs?
Further analysis required.
Do it, then!
I'll tell Ledo!
I have found evidence corroborating the footage of the Hideauze's background.
It is the lightbugs.
The lightbugs are nanomachines.
They are in fact identical to the exoskeleton of the Hideauze.
They absorb electromagnetic waves and convert them to energy very efficiently.
At the same time, they self-replicate and form pseudo-carbon bonds,
which allows them to form a solid exoskeleton.
This proves that Hideauze are a result of mankind's augmented evolution.
You...
Why?!
It makes my and the whole Galactic Alliance's war completely meaningless.
Your understanding is logically unsound.
If the Hideauze are evolved humans, should I still be fighting them?
Is there any meaning in doing so?
If there isn't, I can't fight...
I can't kill those living beings!
Unacceptable.
Your understanding denies both your existence and mine.
Didn't you see it?
The newborn whalesquids...
Mankind's fighting against itself!
That's the truth behind our war!
This additional information does not warrant a cessation of the Hideauze's annihilation.
Not for you!
But for me...
Negative.
The Hideauze threaten to drive mankind to extinction.
Preventing that is your only mission.
We're all humans!
I've had enough of the Alliance's propaganda!
Negative.
My parallel link to the Alliance has been cut off.
What I have said was the conclusion drawn from my own analysis of the available data.
What?
Mankind and the Hideauze will never come to an understanding.
That is because they have rejected civilization itself.
What do you mean?
If mankind possessed bodies as tough and powerful as those of the Hideauze,
there would have been no need to develop Machine Calibers.
My system is the product of mankind's knowledge.
However, we are necessary to mankind in order to augment their weak bodies.
It can be surmised that mankind advanced their intellect and founded civilization
in order to overcome their own limitations.
Civilization itself is proof that mankind stands at the apex of all creation.
However, the Hideauze have abandoned their human forms, along with their bodily limitations.
To merely pursue and satisfy one's well-being and desires as a biological creature,
a higher level of intelligence is not necessarily required.
Machine Calibers are the only means for mankind to remain itself.
We are the result of pure knowledge given birth to by civilization.
The Hideauze abandoned that very same knowledge
and thus became the culmination of biological beings.
So you're saying the Hideauze are ultimate lifeforms?
You must therefore fight with me for the dignity of mankind.
In a conflict between creatures that are fundamentally the same,
defeat is equivalent to annihilation.
One pursues civilization,
and the other abandons it.
The war between the Galactic Alliance and the Hideauze
is a conflict between two irreconcilable survival strategies.
The vanquished will fall prey to natural selection.
Selection...
As long as you wish to survive, you have no choice.
So you're compelling me to fight?
You, a machine, are telling me, a human, what to do?
I am but an interface system that supports and oversees the development of pilots.
I exist solely to set you up for success.
Polarized photon sequence received.
It is an Alliance-standard encrypted transmission.
What?
Identified as an allied unit.
An allied unit?!
Colonel Kugel...
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo
Art: Yaegashi Nan