But then, what'll happen to the Galactic Alliance once you defeat all the Hideauze?
What will you do, Ledo?
Chamber, search for a job I can do here.
Search complete.
No results.
My database is limited.
I have no data regarding
.Gargantia's labor market.
If there's a job for you,
there's gotta be one for me too!
Your comparison with
.me is not applicable.
You have close to no aptitude for non-combat tasks.
I recommend maintaining
.the current situation.
So the best option
for me is to stand by?
Good morning, Ledo!
Good morning.
I agree that it is morning.
Ah, Chamber.
I saw you working
.on my way here.
What're you building?
Part of a hull-connecting machine.
They sure rely on you a lot.
Ah, you're still working on that?
Bevel told me it's a flute!
Show me!
Is it not done yet?
It doesn't make any sound.
Even with sound, it is useless.
Come on! You're working
.so hard to make it.
It is useless. Meaningless.
Here, this is yours.
What's this?
Your wage.
It's for loading the
.freight the other day.
Don't waste it.
Say, is there no money in space?
The Galactic Alliance does not allow soldiers
.to own private goods during their service.
Not very motivating.
Amy, I want to work by myself.
Sure, that sounds good!
Give it a try!
What work is there?
Well, I'm a delivery girl, for instance.
It'd be a drag if everyone had to walk around
.to hand over letters and packages themselves.
So I deliver stuff for them,
and in exchange, I get paid.
That's how we support each other.
Support each other.
I would support someone?
Yeah!
So first, you should think
about what you wanna do!
What I want to do...
I don't know.
I guess it's not an easy question...
You're not familiar with
.how we live, after all.
What can I do? Please tell me!
Okay!
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru yozora
The night sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Day of Calm
You have a delivery!
Oh, thanks.
Here you go. Sign here, please.
All right.
How's work? Do you have enough people?
This guy here's looking for work.
Ah, you're that boy from space.
Ain't that something?
One of my men retired last month.
Oh, then—
But I already got someone to replace him.
Don't worry about it! There's always fishing!
Huh? Not a chance.
Look around.
It's been like this ever since
we missed the last riptide.
I'll let you know if
.things get busy again.
Okay.
As you can see, we're busy trying
.to organize all of these invoices.
It's not something we
.can let a newbie handle.
What about treasure hunting?
We found a nice target,
but it'll take three more
.days until we get there.
I see.
Sorry to let you down.
It is okay.
I gotta do my deliveries soon.
I will try searching alone.
All right! All right! All right!
All right! A bit higher...
Dumbass! I told you to go higher!
No! Left here! Left!
Sorry! I can't do this!
I never thought the requirements
.for work would be so strict.
Chamber, how's your database update coming along?
There are still no jobs
.that match your skill set.
What's the status?
The fleet's engines are stopping.
What's going on?
Hey!
Pinion...
Whatcha sulking about?
It's time to cheer up!
Pinion, the fleet stopped.
What is happening?
It's the calm!
Come on, let's get together! Follow me!
Check out this huge chunk of meat!
It's gonna fill us up!
I'm impressed you got
.your hands on that.
I can't wait!
But can you really
afford to throw a party?
It's been ages since our last calm.
Isn't there a bunch of stuff
that needs repairing?
Once you get to where I'm at,
your employees do all the work for you.
Oh really?
We'll start with Flange's ship.
What?
Has the power been shut down yet?
Yeah, it's down.
All right, this way for the party!
Hey, that was your job
they were talking about, Pinion!
Geez.
What is going on?
Well, on days of calm, when the wind dies off and the sea quiets down,
we do maintenance on the ships.
We get out of the galaxy current and cut the electricity,
so all that's left to do is repair work.
We all get a break.
I see.
You okay, Bevel?
I'm fine.
Not bad, eh?
This is the best spot!
It's so pretty!
Ledo, this is what the sea's like
when there's no wind.
Heya!
Saya! Melty!
You're late!
Come on!
Oh, doesn't that look nice?
Wanna swim?
You bet I do!
You too, Ledo!
I-I...
It'll feel good!
Let's get rid of these lame clothes!
Wow.
That's a pretty nice body.
It's a real scorcher today, isn't it?
Dr. Ordum!
Don't mind me.
Not at all.
It's finally time!
It wasn't easy getting this meat!
It's gonna be great!
Huh?
Damn, still no power?
Hey, how about putting that
.metalhead over there to work?
You need them fried?
That's right!
Target incinerated.
What the heck was that for?!
Man, seriously...
Crap, I forgot!
Forgot what?
Hey, Ledo!
I got some work for you.
Work?
That's right!
Go to that smelter granny's place and fetch me some stuff!
It's a fitting job for you—
No, it's a job only you can do!
Wait, you're seriously
sending Ledo there?
Of course! He wasted all that meat!
I'm counting on ya.
Do my back next!
I wonder if Ledo'll be all right...
Hey, that tickles!
I knew it!
Geez...
I'll probably get even fatter
.if I have some of that barbecue.
Even fatter?
You of all people shouldn't have to worry about that, Melty.
Everyone has their own standards. Right?
I don't care about those things.
Lots of guys like girls
.with rounder figures.
Aren't we naïve?
Keep believing that, and
.you're bound to get hurt.
Maybe I should start exercising...
I-I guess...
This is Ridget. Amy, are you there?
Yes?
You know about the
crane tower's sprinklers, right?
The power's back up,
but they won't work.
Huh? Again?
Could you get up there with your surfkite to start the pump?
But we're about to
..have a barbecue party—
Ah, whatever! I'm on it!
Barbecue?
Huh?
Never mind. I'm counting on you.
Time for a race!
Okay! I'm not gonna lose!
Now I don't need to
worry about getting fat!
If they are so enthusiastic about eating,
why do they worry so much
about maintaining their figures?
That's just how girls think.
I do not understand.
No surprises there.
But what do we do now?
Hey, metalhead. You sure are black.
Is this the right place?
Why hello there, lonely boy.
Your face is so sweet.
And such a juicy body!
What's this over here?
The finish line's the top
of the crane tower!
Okay!
Ready...
Go!
Hey! Watch your takeoff!
I question the necessity of this action.
Don't move.
Pinion!
When are you gonna
fix my ship's winch?
I'll get to it eventually!
Isn't this when you're
.supposed to be the busiest?
Stop worrying about the little details!
You should join us for some meat!
We're about to start!
Hey, wait!
Wanna work at my place?
Chamber!
The lieutenant is in
.a state of emergency.
I said no moving!
He can learn something about society.
I agree.
Pinion!
What are you doing there?
Wh-Who's that?
Ridget?
What's with the diving suits?
I was overseeing the inspection
.and repair work of the ship's bilge.
Oh, okay.
Hey, when's the power coming back on?
The repairs are taking longer than expected, so probably not before sunset.
Let's take a break.
You haven't started yet, have you?
No...
I see.
Excuse me.
Sure—
Something wrong?
It's just... your swimsuit's...
pretty revealing.
It is?
Newcomers don't need
to work night shifts!
Wait!
What's going on?
What did I do wrong?!
I'm gonna win this!
It's not over yet!
I won't lose!
I'm sure you'll become our number one!
Your butt is simply perfect!
So fresh! So much stamina!
Amy?
You okay?
Man, why is it always Amy?
But the race is still on!
Hey, wait!
Hold on tight!
Huh? Oh no!
Yay, I won!
There we go.
Phew, that was close.
What were you doing there anyway?
I... do not really understand.
Anyway, it must've been rough.
Here it comes!
Come look!
Yay!
Well, I have to get back to work now.
What the—?!
It's right down this street!
This is the place.
Phew, that was some good exercise.
I know, right?
Now I can eat as much as I want!
I question the necessity of this action.
I repeat: I question the
.necessity of this action.
I told ya, no moving!
It's just about time.
This.
Young'un, what do you
intend to do with this?
Well, doesn't matter.
Just take it.
If it'll settle things, why not?
Um—
Are these parts for something?
So I have to go back the way I came?
What is this...
Dammit! Who told everyone
about the barbecue?
Welcome back!
Good work, space boy!
Gotta have something
better than salt for this!
You're just in time!
All right! Who wants some?
Me!
Dang, that granny's
sauce really is the best!
You should get some
.before it's all gone, Ledo.
O-Okay.
Here.
Is it good?
And now, taste the
fruit of your hard work!
Here.
This... This is...
The wind...
Time to get back to work.
You got enough to eat?
I think so.
I was worried, since
.you got back late.
Sorry. It was supposed to
.be a party for you too.
Huh? You didn't know?
Pinion came up with the idea to cheer you up
because you couldn't find work.
I did not know.
Thanks for working so hard for everyone!
Me... For everyone?
Yeah!
We had a great barbecue thanks to you!
Well, let's go!
I'll tag along while you search for a job!
What would be the best for him?
Manual labor, maybe?
No cows, please.
What do you mean?
Ah, Pinion!
So this is where
you were slacking off!
This is proper work—
I'm sorry!
I question the necessity of this action.
I repeat: I question—
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo