Ridget...
Yes, Commodore?
Take this.
But...
Take good care of the fleet.
Commodore Fairlock,
Gargantia needs you!
I have faith in you.
I don't think...
You've grown so much...
I can hold my head high when
.I give my report to your father.
Commodore!
No...
Earth coordinates confirmed.
Current Galactic Alliance
standard coordinates confirmed.
Really?
Can we go back?
Returning would necessitate faster-than-light travel.
I am incapable of such actions.
What?
What about the distress beacon?
The estimated time of arrival of the first signals sent out upon crash-landing on Earth
is 6582 years, 16 hours,
and 20 minutes.
That... can't be...
Returning to the fleet is
.realistically unfeasible.
I can't go back...
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Separation
Ridget?
Are you serious?
That little girl?
The Commodore himself appointed her.
I should just join Flange instead.
Ship commanders!
I'm glad you're all here.
We need to discuss Flange's request to split off from the fleet.
Oh, please.
This isn't the time for that!
Commodore Fairlock's
.funeral is about to begin.
I know, but still—
He thought of you as his own daughter.
How could missing his funeral even cross your mind?
He took you under his wing
after Chevron died!
What are all of you doing?
You should be heading towards the bow.
Sorry.
Let's go.
Opposition will always exist.
I know. I'll be fine.
You can't go back?
Yeah...
I'm... sorry about that.
But you know,
if you can't go back, you'd
.better make up your mind.
You wanna kick some whalesquid ass, right?
Killing them is my duty.
So I guess you'd be interested
in knowing the location of their nest?
There is a nest?!
Calm down.
There's treasures down
.in the whalesquids' nest.
They're worth a lot.
Money does not interest me.
You kill the whalesquids,
and I grab myself some treasure.
How about it?
I only care about killing them.
Looks like we've got ourselves a deal.
To release all the ships that want to leave, we'll have to unfasten thirty connectors.
It's a lot of work.
Get to it!
Flange, I beg you to reconsider.
I've already made my decision.
A huge fleet with weak leadership is the perfect target for pirates.
But still...
The heritage Pinion talked about
might become the foundation of our future.
Besides, many people wish
.to leave with my ships.
Protecting the peaceful lives
of those on my ships
is my duty, you know.
Thanks!
Anytime!
Melty!
Amy? Saya?
Melty, are you really leaving?
Yeah.
Why don't you let Flange's ships go,
and stay here with us?
I can't just leave my granddad alone.
I see...
Who would've thought my home ship
would ever leave Gargantia?
I was the most surprised.
But who knows? It could be fun!
I might even meet a nice guy out there!
You wanna be Cinderella?
Yeah!
Not to mention that cutie's coming with us!
Ledo?
Pinion's been bragging about it.
"With that flying Yunboro on our side,
we won't have to be afraid of any whalesquid!"
I see...
I wanted you to succeed him, Krown.
I don't have much time left myself.
I must guide the next generation, while I'm still of this world.
Train her as best you can.
Commodore Fairlock,
I thank you for the journey we underwent together.
May the green waves be with you.
Not putting on your mourning gown?
Pinion!
Can you sign my parting request?
How many times do I have to repeat myself?
Then, show me why staying here
is worth my while.
I just—
Don't stop people from leaving if you're
.not confident you can protect them.
Later.
What's wrong?
Saya!
Oh, nothing.
You're worrying about Ledo, aren't you?
No, I'm not!
You know, you could go with him.
Just go with Melty on Mr. Flange's ships.
With Melty?
I'd miss you for sure,
but seeing you like this is even worse.
Huh?
One look at your face, and you'd
.think the world was ending.
Although that's probably
.how it feels to you right now.
Nothing even started between us...
Then—
No!
I have to stay here.
Are you sure?
I can't leave Bevel behind.
He has to stay here with Dr. Ordum.
Besides, I couldn't live without Bevel.
I see.
Yeah...
That's a relief.
I'd miss you if you left, Amy!
Thanks.
Notice of ship separation
I hereby declare our intent to cancel the contract
of aggregation of ships undersigned on            .
Furthermore, you are not to disclose our numbers, position, course,
or any other information to other members of your fleet.
Names of concerned ships
Representative
A long-time member of Mr. Fairlock's fleet
You look kinda troubled.
I'm fine.
How about taking a break?
Yeah, what a great example that would set!
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
With the Commodore gone, I can't afford to look weak.
I know how hard you're working.
You're doing more than enough.
If I were, we wouldn't be in such a mess.
There's a difference between "enough" and "perfect."
I went through a period
.like this too, you know.
Back when my old man
.left me the business,
I tried to do everything myself.
One day, I found a huge catch.
I tried to show off all the skills I'd learned,
but I was swept away by the current,
and my Yunboro got stuck
.underneath my target.
I thought I was going to die there.
Pinion made fun of me, saying I couldn't keep track of my surroundings.
He said what I did was the same
.as not trusting my shipmates.
You don't have to do everything by yourself.
So...
But Commodore Fairlock did just that!
That old man relied on you a lot!
Your job is figuring out who
to entrust with what, isn't it?
Entrust?
You use the stuff I salvage
.for the sake of the entire fleet.
I'd consider myself lucky if my ships were
.under the command of someone like that.
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Sorry I'm late.
I'll start dinner right away!
Hey, is it true that Ledo's leaving?
Where'd you hear that, Bevel?
I overheard the neighbors saying Pinion was talking about it.
Yeah. It's a shame, huh?
We were just starting to get along, too.
I wonder why he'd want to do something so dangerous.
Good question...
What an idiot!
Amy...
Why doesn't he value his life?
It looked like he was having
...so much fun at the festival...
He was laughing!
But now,
he seems to be suffering even more than when we first met!
I'm sure the real Ledo is the one I saw at the festival!
Some chose to stay here, too.
How do you intend to deal with the boy?
I'll trust you with that decision.
Trust...
Bevel?
You're leaving?
Yeah, I am.
Do you have to?
Yes.
Is that really what you want to do, Ledo?
It's for the sake of mankind.
And Amy's as well.
But she never asked you to do that!
I want you to have this.
But...
Isn't this important to you?
It was made by a child
.who looked just like I did.
Just like you?
Thinking back, he might
.have been my little brother.
But then...
In the Galactic Alliance, a child
.who cannot fight cannot survive.
The Hideauze constantly
.encroach on our territory.
But...
The same goes for the Earthian Hideauze.
If they one day decide
.to expand their territory,
a clash with mankind will be inevitable.
But the whalesquids—
Those are Hideauze.
If a similar situation to the Galactic Alliance arises here, you will not survive.
I do not want Amy to
.experience such a loss.
No! You're wrong, Ledo!
It won't come to that!
I don't want to make Amy sad.
That's why I'll destroy
.every last Hideauze.
Please wait!
I humbly apologize for my tardiness.
Thank you... so much.
There is something we must all discuss.
Gargantia has been entrusted to me
by Commodore Fairlock.
The future of the fleet occupied his thoughts until his very last moments.
I want to live up to his expectations.
I want to protect the Gargantia
.that the Commodore so loved.
I want to protect this fleet
.that we all live on.
By myself, I was helpless to even
.stop those who wanted to leave.
I... am powerless.
That is why I'm turning to you for help!
If you want to protect this fleet,
Gargantia, the stronghold harboring our lives,
then I implore you, please help me!
Who do you think we are?
We're veterans.
Yeah!
You can count on us to get things done!
No point in crying over the jerks who left!
Just stand in the middle,
.and rebuild the fleet around you.
Ridget...
That'll do.
You all have my heartfelt gratitude.
Ledo...
What are you doing down there?
I'm about to leave.
I see.
So, Ledo...
You're really leaving?
Yeah.
But listen!
I'm just holding onto this for you!
Be sure to come back!
Thank you for everything.
May the green waves be with you.
There's nothing you could've done.
They've already made up their minds.
Fools, the lot of them...
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo
Art: Kikurage