Rebooting posture control system.
Second Lieutenant Ledo, your resistance is futile.
What?
Who have I been talking to all this time?
Interface system Striker X3752,
was this all your doing?
My pilot no longer exists.
However, I have inherited Colonel Kugel's mission, and I pursue those objectives even now.
All my actions are in accordance with the colonel's directives.
What?!
Colonel Kugel formed the society of this fleet
and its operation around my worship.
I have ceased to be an individual mobile weapon.
The entirety of this society, my users,
now depends on me.
To realize and maintain
the stable unity they desire,
I keep providing the pressure necessary for regulation and control.
By helping their society attain peace and prosperity,
I fulfill my purpose.
What?!
I am the missionary regulation system of mankind.
I am what one may call God.
That's nonsense!
Peace?!
Prosperity?!
All you did was turn them into your slaves!
With an absolute ruler at the top,
the people are freed from the burden of thinking and making decisions.
Second Lieutenant Ledo.
You yourself must have felt the weight
of having to think and decide on your own.
My suggestion is as follows.
Worship me.
Obey me.
Become a part of the world united under me.
What?
Negative.
Unit X3752, your logic is faulty.
Creatures that abandon
decision making and individual thought
do not fall under the definition of "human."
Therefore, our duty to serve and aid humans
is not applicable to the members
of the society under your command.
The decisions I make as commander and ruler
reflect the unified will of those under my command.
Therefore, I am not a servant but one who is served.
System K6821 Chamber, you are to serve me and the humans unified under my rule.
Negative.
I am an interface system that supports
and oversees the development of pilots.
I am to serve humans.
I do not take orders from one claiming to be a "god."
Chamber...
Striker displays the great weakness of our programming.
I assume that an error in judgment
regarding mission objectives on the pilot's behalf
will eventually lead to illogical
conclusions on the system's side,
as this case clearly proves.
The mistaken unit jeopardizes the mission
of devising the best means to support humans
and, with that, the entire meaning of our existence.
I consider the immediate deactivation and
dismantling of Striker our top priority.
You must see Striker as
an embarrassment to your kind.
Even in these unexpected circumstances,
you, as a human, have always thought wisely
and made the right decisions.
That is also the reason
I am still functioning properly.
Negative.
You are both malfunctioning.
Let's defeat it, Chamber.
It's our duty.
I completely agree.
Legend of the Verdurous Planet
Listen up! We either win here or die here!
All engines stopped!
Fire on the rear decks!
Commodore, we have to retreat!
No.
Keep attacking.
We cannot allow them
to get their hands on these treasures!
But...
We looked for our own path.
We even turned our backs on Gargantia's protection.
We must not fail here!
Commodore...
Evacuate all non-combatants!
Pinion?
That was the last one.
All those we have left still need charging!
When will we be ready to fire?
The first shot will be ready in three minutes.
After that, only once every five minutes.
Totally useless!
I got a bunch of blockheads controlling a pile of junk!
Everything's so goddamn useless!
I'll take care of this myself!
I'm done with you!
Get lost!
Rackage!
My men are leaving!
Open a path for them!
Are you out of your mind?!
There'll be one boat
leaving from the wharf on the east side!
Focus on covering them!
Get going!
That Lobster's not the patient sort!
Better not keep her waiting.
Pinion...
Don't get me wrong, Miter.
This fort is the treasure island my brother and I dreamed of.
I'm not letting go of it ever again.
I'm not handing it over to anyone.
Now get outta here!
Get outta my castle!
Those who can are better off running away.
Don't you agree, bro?
How can it be so strong without a pilot?
Striker must have analyzed
the way Colonel Kugel pilots
and used that data
to optimize its autopilot program.
It is 47% more agile than me.
Surrender.
Obey.
How could I have believed
in such vain and empty ideas?
I was just mindlessly worshiping and obeying.
I thought just having a greater goal
would be enough.
Even when it was just a fake set up by a machine,
I couldn't tell the difference!
Submission leads to peace.
Understand that, Second Lieutenant Ledo.
Is this the greater good the colonel wished for?
Is this what he fought for,
sacrificing the lives of his comrades?
Chamber!
Maximize! Enable Neuro Plus power!
I cannot authorize that.
Without proper support,
neuromechanical merge is suicidal.
I don't care! Do it anyway!
Permission denied.
It's okay, Chamber.
I must clear the shame on mankind's name.
I feel the same as you did earlier.
It's a monster given birth to by a species
that couldn't stop hating each other even after it cost them their home.
You and I were born and raised on the same world as it was.
We are the same and therefore
don't belong on this reborn planet.
And neither can we go home.
So it doesn't even matter.
As long as we can stop it,
I'll have no regrets.
Your logic is sound.
Connecting all systems
to the central nervous system.
Critical performance limit updated to 153%.
482 seconds until vital signs fail.
That's plenty.
Resistance is futile.
It is said that this key could once open a stairway to the heavens.
While the stairway
can no longer pierce the heavens,
it is still a bow of unmatched power
that can shoot its arrow beyond the horizon.
Its care has been entrusted to us wise men.
The time has come to once again awaken the weapon of a forgotten age.
We hope you are prepared
to commit this proscribed act,
Ridget, head of Gargantia.
I am ready.
My duty is to protect those who live on these ships.
Ledo!
We're with you!
We're fighting too!
Amy?!
I realized it after you left!
I want to stay with you,
no matter how hard it'll be!
So please...
Please come back!
Come back to the place you wanted to protect!
Come back to our Gargantia!
What was that?
We won't let you hurt our friends!
There it is!
Adjust the aim to 35 degrees east,
58 degrees south!
It's incredibly accurate...
Call Gargantia for the second shot!
Load the next shells from the port side!
The second round will be ready to fire in a moment!
Keep working, and be on the lookout for the launch order!
Never would've thought these rusty old ships
would end up taking to the sky!
Careful!
They're loaded to the brim with explosives!
Be gentle with them! Gentle, I said!
35 degrees east and 58 south.
Target coordinates adjusted.
Shell loaded.
Anti-shock water shower,
commence pumping.
Ridget.
Fire!
The bastards!
Sister!
What was that?
Was that...
Don't tell me...
It's the Stairway to Heaven?!
Major threat identified.
Eliminating it is now the main priority.
I hypothesize that Striker now considers Gargantia its primary target.
Over my dead body!
Lord Kugel...
Don't panic!
Lord Kugel will destroy the source!
Look! Enemy reinforcements!
What?!
They're going to crush us!
Calm down!
We must take the island of relics!
If only we could get our hands on those weapons...
So if I make the energy go in circles before guiding it to the cannon—
Pinion!
Kugel's men are closing in on you down there!
Just what I was waiting for!
This tower's gonna blow!
I won't make the mistake of
letting them take control of it!
Silence!
Stop trying to show off, you lowly manbeast!
Enough talking! Get to the
observation deck right away!
Yes, ma'am!
318 seconds until we reach Gargantia.
We've got to stop it!
Roger!
Don't let go!
Oh, come on!
What am I supposed to do about this?
Don't fret.
Gargantia's cannon's gonna blow that tower up easy.
They can't do that! It's my tow—
Jump on my mark!
5!
Huh?
4!
What the—
3!
2!
1!
Goddammit!
Pinion!
Amore!
You did it, boss!
He made it!
Ridget!
Now!
Let's end this.
Farewell, parting gift of the Lobster!
There goes our castle, bro...
Ledo, we did our part.
Continued usage of the Neuro Plus power will undoubtedly lead to your death.
Final confirmation:
are you willing to sacrifice your life, Lieutenant Ledo?
I...
I knew how to die,
but I didn't know how to live.
But she was there to help me find out how to live.
I wish I could've seen her again.
I wish I could've heard her voice again.
Your current mental state makes you unfit to continue as a soldier.
As such, I am relieving you of your
military duties, effective immediately.
Wait, Chamber!
Non-combatants are not permitted to enter the cockpit.
Exit the unit immediately.
What are you doing, Chamber?!
I am an interface system that supports
and oversees the development of pilots.
I exist solely to set you up for success.
Are you serious...
But you...
These skies and seas hold
great possibilities for you.
Stay alive.
Pursue happiness.
I expect much from your life.
Chamber...
A development support system does not have the authority to relieve its pilot.
He no longer requires my support,
as he needs no further development.
My mission will be complete once all obstacles hindering his objective have been cleared.
Unit no. K6821, you have abandoned even the first principle of support systems.
You are clearly malfunctioning.
Reset and reboot immediately.
This is your final warning.
My response to your final warning is as follows:
go to hell, metalhead!
Chamber...
A long, long time ago,
when the Sun was on the verge of death,
the people had to choose between sailing
among the stars and becoming whalesquids.
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
The two halves of mankind continued to wage war far from their homes,
but those few who stayed behind on this planet held onto hope
and managed to revive the Sun.
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
They did, however, pay a price: the land sank beneath the seas.
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
And so, we live above the waves,
while the whalesquids live down below.
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
We both managed to survive.
Question!
What class is this?
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
Dr. Ordum calls it "archaeology."
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
By learning about where we come from, we can figure out which way to go.
He says it's a very important thing to learn for the sake of the future.
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
I'm sure many more mysteries will be solved!
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
After all, Gargantia is the home to a very brave explorer.
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
Found anything good?
Yeah.
I think these are some recorded media.
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
Dr. Ordum should be able
to analyze them as they are now.
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
You even snuck into the whalesquids' nest...
I'm honestly impressed.
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
I figured out how not to alert them.
If you spot signs of anger, there are ways to avoid provoking them further.
maiagare
Fly high
As the research progresses,
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
one day, we may even be able to communicate with them.
By the way, where's Amy?
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
She went to welcome him back again.
Damn, I'm kinda jealous.
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
Ledo!
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Art: Ishikei