So, I can buy one meal
using this token,
and that piece of paper
.is worth 100 tokens.
Did I get it right?
An analogy with the Galactic Alliance's ration tickets is most suitable.
It's too much.
It is assumed that the tickets can be exchanged for provisions not limited to food.
We couldn't use up all the oxygen here,
even if we wanted to.
What other provisions could possibly be necessary?
What if...
What if they gave me
more than I deserved?!
Ledo!
What's wrong, Ledo?
I do not know how to use salary.
Huh?!
Ah, that's right.
You said you didn't
.have money in space.
Well, you're in luck.
You'll get to use your money to have all sorts of fun!
The carnival's coming up!
"Carnival"?
Yeah.
We'll be able to catch lots of fish,
so we're all going to
.have a little celebration.
Oh, right!
There'll be some fishing jobs this time!
You can use your Yunboro to fish with us.
Guild Chief! You have a delivery!
Cool.
It's the chief navigator letting you know about our route.
Gotcha.
And some manpower too!
I heard you wanna join us fishermen.
Yeah. I want to try fish catch work.
Got fed up with being called a slacker?
But what about your flying Yunboro?
No need Chamber.
I work myself.
I reiterate my objection: inefficient action.
That's a galaxy loop.
Lightbugs. A kind of nanomachine.
Heritage of an ancient culture.
When sea galaxies merge due to ocean currents, rings can form.
The fish are trapped there.
It's basically a huge fishing pond.
Now, let's get this party started!
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Carnival
Ya know how it works?
Controls easy.
No problem.
Oh, really?
Just don't break it!
Try lifting an arm first.
I understand the controls.
Where is the information support system?
The heck's that?
Computer that analyzes combat situation.
There ain't anything fancy like that!
Use your own eyes!
Understood.
Okay! Now move to the galaxy loop.
But do it quietly.
Ya don't wanna open
.a hole in the ring.
Display current location.
Set target coordinates.
What's wrong, Chamber?
What are ya doing?
Get it straight!
Information support!
It's the same as swimming!
You'll float if ya relax.
I can't swim!
Ledo!
Geez.
Ya shoulda told us up
.front ya couldn't swim.
I did not think the machine would obey me very little.
Well, there's no sea in space, I suppose.
You tried.
So, wanna get lunch?
Here's your Young Lady set
.and your sea mustard bread.
Thank you.
Hey, Ledo, is that really enough?
They have a bunch of
.yummy stuff on the menu.
No problem.
Man, you soldiers have it rough.
Don't worry about the
.job thing too much.
I screw up all the time myself!
You should take it easy too.
How can I do that?
Maybe you should just
.go and have some fun.
Check out the carnival today!
But first... Let's eat!
Okay.
How is it, Ledo?
It is good.
Oh, okay.
Then, you should let it
.show on your face.
Let it show?
How can I do that?
Hey-my! You haven't changed yet?
Oh no!
If you don't hurry, all the
hot guys will be taken!
Oh wait, there's a cutie right here!
My, she's right!
Hey, Amy, you gonna keep keep him all to yourself?!
Sorry, gotta go! Let's go to the carnival together later!
Okay...
Hurry up!
Proposal:
I carry out a mission
.to secure fish alone.
I suggest you stand by, Lt. Ledo.
Just do whatever.
Oh, so you came with your own Yunboro this time?
Correction number one:
I am not a Yunboro.
My identification is
.Machine Caliber K6821.
I request to be assigned
.on a fishing mission.
I see.
Correction number two: my pilot,
Lt. Ledo, is inspecting the carnival.
Huh? The kid's not here?
I will now commence
.capturing sea life-forms.
Hey, take a net with ya!
'Sup, Ledo!
I heard about your lil'
"underwater excursion."
No problem.
Chamber is doing it for me.
Hey, cheer up now.
C'mon, I'll show you around.
I hear you don't know how to use money.
I'm feeling generous today,
so I'll treat you just this once.
Watch and learn.
Hey, waitress, over here!
Whatcha want?
Sea mustard bread.
Waitress! Two special dinners!
Roger! Two specials coming right up!
What's wrong? You homesick?
You wanna go back to space?
But no map. Can't return.
I see. That's tough.
How's your life here?
Not bad.
But distance with people big.
What d'you expect, when all you do is eat sea mustard bread?
Sea mustard bread unacceptable?
That's not it.
We just don't get you at all.
Do not get me?
Say, isn't there anything you wanna do?
I want to return to the Alliance frontlines.
Not that kind of stuff.
Something you can do right now,
here on this ship.
I do not know.
How are you supposed to trust someone who doesn't even know what he wants?
Good!
You should come salvaging with me.
"Salvaging"? Is that work?
Yeah!
With your metalhead, we could go after the big treasures.
Already have much money.
Then eat the good stuff
if you can afford it!
If you make even more, you could get yourself a nice ship.
What's the point of money if you're just sitting on it?
And while you're at it,
figure out what you want.
Figure out what I want...
Hey, don't try and pull a fast one here!
What d'you mean?
If you're gonna team up with someone, it should be with me, the pro.
I'll turn you into a top-grade salvager.
I do not know much about salvaging.
It's real easy.
I'll teach you.
If there's something you
don't understand, just ask.
And if you don't know
how to do it, follow my lead.
Don't listen to her.
If you team up with me,
you'll eat great food every day!
I'll teach you how to read the tide.
You have potential. It'll be easy.
Team up with me, and you'll get to drink all the booze you want!
Swimming will come
.early in the curriculum.
And you'll get to fondle
girls' asses all day long!
Pinion, you've been getting
more and more vulgar!
Oh, get lost, stone-butt!
Big words from someone
who can't even swim!
I can swim perfectly fine!
I just can't dive!
Sorry for the wait!
Here's your main dish.
Oh man, it's finally here!
What'd you get?
Hideauze!
Whoa there, what's the matter?!
The enemy of mankind!
To be eliminated!
That's just an octopus.
It's delicious.
Seriously, if this tiny octopus freaked you out,
then I can't wait to see your reaction once a whalesquid shows up.
Octopus.
Eat.
Delicious?
I request the assistance
.of my pilot, Lt. Ledo.
Commencing capture.
Deploying gravity waver. Activate.
Capture complete.
I ain't got a clue what goes
.on in your or Ledo's head.
Nutritional values remain identical.
That ain't the problem!
Unable to control current situation.
Requesting the support of Lt. Ledo.
He minced 'em all?
Just use a net, 'kay?
Watch how the others do it!
I need the biggest net possible,
as well as the help of the Yunboros.
There we go!
See?
Don't act like you
.taught him anything.
That was so good!
I'm stuffed.
Chamber, search for the enemy.
Measuring local changes
.in energy distribution.
Danger rating: minimal.
It's okay.
Just look over there.
What is that?
Veils of light.
They form when galaxy loops dissolve.
You should practice
.playing some more.
"Practice"?
Amy practiced dance?
I want see you dance.
Okay then, as a token
...of my appreciation...
"Appreciation"?
Hey! I brought you a present!
Welcome back!
Hello, Amy.
Hi, Doc.
I'm home. How've you been?
Oh, Ledo!
Present.
Thanks, Ledo!
I got and gave money,
and everyone eat good food.
The payment you received
is proof that you supported someone.
I supported someone?
That is work.
Someone invited me to job.
Really? What?
Salvaging with Chamber.
That's great!
It is?
Well, the bottom of
the sea's full of stuff!
You can find out what was on this planet in ancient times!
I want try salvaging.
You sure are a lot of help.
I was afraid you'd go with Pinion.
Something I want learn from Bellows.
With a Yunboro like that, I'm gonna run
.out of things to teach you pretty fast.
Not true. I want to learn a lot.
All right, we got another one here.
It's a treasure. Careful, now.
Hostile unit detected.
Preparing to intercept.
Double-check it.
Unique waveform analysis complete.
99.97% probability.
Target recognized to be Hideauze.
Initiating combat.
Annihilate the Hideauze.
Roger.
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo
Art: Tsuji Santa