After eons of wandering,
we humans have found ourselves a
.flourishing world in this wide galaxy.
Its name is Avalon—a beautiful utopia.
Behold the Edenic light of this paradise built atop
the shoulders of science and the pursuit of progress.
This is your homeland.
Its 470 million inhabitants praise your courage and devotion,
and your names, glorious heroes,
will forever remain in their hearts.
Praise be to the eternal future promised to the Galactic Alliance of Humankind.
Here is where the endless challenges awaiting mankind shall begin.
And yet, you must never forget.
In the cruel and heartless abyss of space,
merciless evil lurks, ever present.
The rampaging of the Hideauze threatens our future.
It is our duty to stop them!
We cannot allow such despicable creatures to endanger the advance of Man!
Heroes, rise to these countless challenges.
Forget neither the innumerable sacrifices of this tragedy
nor your fellow countrymen whose very future teeters on the brink of oblivion!
All units, cease coordinated REM sleep.
Pilot of unit no. K6821,
Second Lieutenant Ledo, awaken.
No irregularities in brainwaves or body rhythms.
Blood lactate and adrenaline
.secretion levels all nominal.
Waking process complete.
Where's the enemy?
All units in the Krüger squadron.
Sleep development time is over.
I hope you're all wide awake.
Phew. We haven't started yet.
The entire fleet will enter the ergosphere
.of the wormhole in three hundred seconds.
After swinging out, we'll exit right in front of the Hideauze's nest.
This is a surprise attack deploying every single unit the Galactic Alliance of Humankind has to offer.
It's do or die.
Please note.
At this moment, the service time of Second Lieutenant Ledo has exceeded 145,000 hours.
After this operation,
you will be granted permission to apply for limited
citizenship rights and four weeks' leave on Avalon.
Right...
No change in adrenaline secretion.
Your reaction is below expected levels.
Avalon, huh?
There was a time when I
.wanted to see it for myself,
but I'm not sure I want to now that I have the opportunity.
Homeland? What is it exactly?
It is a place where citizens'
rights are guaranteed.
You will be granted the freedoms of
sleep, food, and reproduction.
Right.
That's all too complicated for me.
You have proven yourself a human
.worthy of living and reproducing.
It is an honor and an achievement you should treasure.
Are you happy about it, Chamber?
I am but an interface system that supports and oversees the development of pilots.
I exist solely to set you up for success.
Yeah. I appreciate it.
No complaints on that front.
Enough chitchat, Second Lieutenant Ledo.
Focus on the mission ahead of you.
Understood, Colonel.
All units, assume anti-shock formation.
Launch immediately after the Telemocy Swing.
Best of luck to you all.
All fleet ships, prepare to enter!
Commencing Telemocy Swing.
Swing in!
Drifters
All units have successfully traversed the wormhole.
All carriers and attack
reinforcement units, attack!
All attack reinforcement units,
proceed to designated coordinates.
Klauserpass quantum reaction
.warhead carrier squadron, launch.
Vanguard squadrons!
Once you get a visual on the Blossom Sail,
aim at the mouth of the enemy's fortified super-cannon, and fire!
Sudden energy increase detected in the Blossom Sail's fortified super-cannon.
All units, prepare to fire...
Fire!
Hits confirmed on target cannon mouth!
Vanguard squadrons annihilated!
Remaining units heavily damaged!
Follow-up fire has hit the target!
Target cannon firing area destroyed!
All enemy fortified super-cannons disabled.
Good!
Hexiler squadron, prepare to fire the Dimenström!
Machine Caliber squadron, launch!
The Hideauze's nest is right above the
.dark side of the hot, Jupiter-type planet.
The Blossom Sail defensive platform,
powered by the photon pressure of a star, protects this impregnable fortress.
The extreme radiation of the star prevents us from attacking from the starlit side.
We must attack from the planet's shadow and bring down the nest!
Dimenström, fire!
Fire!
We will disable the fortified super-cannon on the Blossom Sail protecting the planet's dark side
using the newly deployed Dimenström,
which will expose the nest and clear the way.
Our mission as the Machine Caliber squadron
is to protect the squadron in charge of positioning the
Klauserpass quantum reaction warhead in the nest
and destroy all interfering enemy units!
First line, fire!
Phalanx squadron, focus fire
on the enemy units!
Several enemy attack-type carriers are emerging from the nest.
Numbers increasing!
When was the last time I felt afraid?
I ceased being a soldier-in-training once I learned how to forget everything unnecessary.
I know where victory lies.
Everything is clear, and no doubt clouds my mind.
What I want, and what is wanted from me—all of those are here.
Klauserpass positioning squadron moving ahead and approaching the Hideauze's nest!
Multicore cannon squadron, take attack formation!
The Blossom Sail is regenerating too quickly!
Is the Dimenström ready to fire again?!
120 seconds to reach the critical point!
We won't make it!
No!
The enemy's fortified super-cannon has fired on the main fleet!
Hexiler squadron annihilated!
Dimenström formation destroyed!
Operation unsustainable!
All units, retreat immediately!
We threw everything we had at it and it wasn't enough.
Colonel Kugel.
The wormhole stabilizer will cease supply of exotic matter in four minutes.
All Klauserpass positioning units are to
.immediately return to Carrier Labrac.
All units! You heard it!
Abandon the Klauserpass and retreat,
or they'll leave us behind!
Roger.
Delta team, disengage from the Klauserpass!
Abandon all quantum reaction warheads!
Follow Colonel Kugel's orders and retreat!
Hurry! Go, go, go!
Set the Klauserpass to destructive mode!
Leave it after disabling the safety!
They're going to eat the Klauserpass along with the energy core?!
Ledo?!
I'll hold them back!
What?
Very well.
200 seconds will do.
Don't overdo it!
Affirmative!
Limiter Release order—maximize!
I don't care if they all burn up!
Roger.
Help requested!
I'm caught! I can't move!
Help her!
Roger! Hang in there!
Wait for me.
Ledo!
It's time.
Return, Ledo!
But, Colonel Kugel, they're still...
They're done for.
Give up!
Don't waste any more energy!
Help! Help!
We're completely surrounded!
The enemy is trying to consume the Klauserpass's quantum energy!
We can't last any longer...
Maximize Limiter Release complete.
Ensuring safe operation.
Refrain from reengaging.
Maintain passage connection.
Commence Telemocy Swing!
Forty seconds until Labrac Telemocy Swing.
------------------------------------------------------------
Thirty-nine.
Thirty-eight.
------------------------------------------------------------
Thirty-seven.
Damn it.
We can't let the Hideauze go back with us.
------------------------------------------------------------
Ledo, you dock in by yourself.
I'll hold them off.
------------------------------------------------------------
Colonel Kugel, that's against regulations!
You're still young.
------------------------------------------------------------
Your future holds more dead enemies than mine.
That's a soldier's decision.
------------------------------------------------------------
Glory to the Galactic Alliance of Humankind!
Farewell.
------------------------------------------------------------
Sir!
Connection to the guidance beacon complete.
Commencing docking sequence.
Damn the Hideauze...
Sorry!
Wow! It's so big!
Bellows!
Yo, Amy!
Message from Ridget!
If you'll take on liability for it, you can use this place until tomorrow night.
Here's the contract.
Geez, what a stingy woman.
By the way, what's this?
That's what we'd like to know.
We're dying to see what's inside,
but we can't even put a scratch on it.
No idea how this was built.
And look at this.
What?
I've never seen writing like this.
Well, writing or not, it's still strange.
We figured this was an odd one the minute we found it.
No signs of rusting or rotting whatsoever.
It's completely different from the treasures we normally dig up.
Who cares if it's treasure
if you can't even open it?
I'm not budging from
.the agreed price, Pinion.
You're the one who said to
pick it up, no matter what it was.
Damn shark.
This thing looks like it could move any minute.
Don't get your hopes up. It's busted.
It won't move no matter what I—
Ow!
Well, we wouldn't be way out here if we weren't trying to be careful.
If anything goes wrong,
we can always bail out.
This is our home, damn you!
Like we'd just let you leave like that!
Yeah, yeah. I'll let Ridget know.
That's basically it, Amy.
Nothing fun to see here.
Just go back to your delivery job.
Okay, I'll be back tomorrow morning.
Hopefully by then you'll have opened it up a bit!
If it's even possible!
Easier said than done.
No irregularities in brainwaves or body rhythms.
Lieutenant Ledo confirmed conscious.
Waking successful.
Your bodily functions have been preserved via
artificial hibernation as per the emergency program.
Elapsed time: 266,815 minutes.
All systems on this unit had been frozen,
but external stimuli triggered
.reactivation twelve minutes ago.
We've been sleeping for six months?!
The current situation requires your, the pilot's, decision.
It is why the waking process was initiated.
Who are these people?
What are they saying?
They speak an unknown tongue.
It bears similarities to
.some ancient languages.
Analysis is underway,
but data is insufficient.
They aren't part of the
Galactic Alliance of Humankind.
Are they Drifters, people who haven't joined the Alliance?
They've never seen a
Machine Caliber before?
My observations lead me to believe they are attempting to damage the unit,
but they seem unable to do so.
Thus, it can be deduced that the level of civilization possessed by these people is low.
It doesn't look like they
.can even open the hatch.
Where are we?
Unable to confirm coordinates.
No points of reference can be found.
What?
Conjecture—after we were separated from Carrier Labrac
during the Telemocy Swing through metric spacetime,
synchronization occurred with normal space at randomly selected coordinates.
That's ridiculous...
Distress signals were continuously sent while maintaining your hibernation,
but the situation now requires your action.
Let us discuss what to do.
I don't know about that...
They look human enough on the outside,
but we can't decide anything until we know exactly who they are.
The walls of this structure appear quite weak.
Even with what's left of this unit's
.power reserve, we can still escape.
No.
The outside may not be pressurized.
These people aren't wearing airtight suits.
More importantly, I need to
evaluate the situation.
I want to see what
...it's like outside, but...
Screw you.
Ow!
The gravity is exactly 1G.
Pretty well controlled, for Drifters.
What about the air?
The main components are nitrogen, oxygen, and carbon dioxide.
Their respective proportions
are perfect for life.
There are minute concentrations of other constituents,
but no harmful ones can be detected.
If it's breathable air, I'll take it.
I need to preserve what oxygen I have left.
What is this smell?
What's with this place?
That's beyond ancient!
Who are these people?
I did tell you to come
.back in the morning,
but the sun's not even up yet.
I couldn't go back to sleep.
I just kept thinking about it.
And I didn't even get to sleep.
But I can't get through the
locked doors without you, Pinion!
We're crossing a galaxy
right now, y'know.
Ridget'll have my head if
.we waste the electricity.
Huh?
What is it?
This thing ain't gonna move.
Amy, get away from it.
Get over here!
Now!
O-Okay.
Amy!
You little...
What the hell are you saying?!
Hey, who are you?
What are you doing?
You little bastard!
Stop, damn it!
You jerk!
Put me down, I say!
I cannot identify any logic
.behind your actions.
They won't attack me with a hostage.
At least, I hope not.
hagoinasain hagsen
We'll start by mapping
.the layout of this place.
I can't start you up until then.
Understood.
Recording video. Beginning analysis.
Try to explore this place
.as much as possible.
dete dete dete
Still can't figure out
what this girl's saying?
Analysis is estimated to be
.forty percent complete.
Additional vocabulary samples required.
You heard him.
Come on, talk some more.
todisio efef
Not a fire? What do you mean?
Ridget, it's an intruder!
He's got this weird weapon,
and he took Amy!
An intruder?
Where from?
Hell if I know!
He just appeared in the hangar—
abeganush taisho
nemaida okenehka tomelakse
What she just said relates to
.reproducing with your mother,
as well as fresh excrement.
Terrible people, as I thought.
That's why I can't stand Drifters!
Proposal of doubt—we cannot assume these people are Drifters.
Why not, Chamber?
According to all the
video data collected so far,
there is absolutely no evidence of gravity changes, radiation,
or devices and building layouts designed to be airtight.
It can be deduced that this building was designed without
any considerations for vacuum space or weightlessness.
Ridiculous!
That's impossible!
I agree.
However, there is one such exception in my records.
Wh-What is this?
doshi doi sois
What is this?
Where the heck am I?
gurecce
Well, that's that.
Chamber!
Seriously, what's going on here, Chamber?
It can be deduced that we stand on a planet with a breathable atmosphere.
No way.
That's impossible.
Commencing exhaustive search of the observable skies.
Result: only one matching entry.
The Earth, third planet of the Solar System.
Up until now, its existence has
.only been hinted at in records.
It is the planet where humanity originated.
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Art: Naruko Hanaharu