I'll be damned...
This is where we stored all the sacred relics recovered from the seafloor
that are suspected to be weapons.
Wh-What a heap of treasure!
Your sacred duty is to repair these.
Easier said than done!
I don't even know where to sta—
What's this?
This lets me look inside them?
Damn, that's awesome!
Any item that does not add to
.our armament is yours to keep.
What?
Cool!
I'll hold you to that!
I'll leave the rest to you.
Look at that!
What a shallow man.
What was that?
I was remarking on how easily bought you are.
Huh?
You seem so satisfied with
.what you've been given.
I took you for a more
.willful man than that.
Huh? What's your point?
The flying Yunboro...
What about the metalhead?
Provided we can make use of it,
I might be willing to aid you.
I still don't see your point.
As a matter of fact, I am quite disgusted
.with the ways of this fleet.
Huh?
I'm going back to being a pirate.
After I sink this fleet, that is.
Colonel.
Could you refrain from attacking Gargantia?
Why?
Because...
If you wish to help them, then hasten our missionary work.
Let us turn them into useful human resources
for the sake of mankind's prosperity!
But...
Ledo, it is our duty to bring
.a new order to this planet.
That's no different from
...the Galactic Alliance...
Should we be unable to
.reunite with the fleet,
we will transform this planet, Earth,
into our own utopia—a second Avalon.
Our legitimacy remains unchanged.
Falter not.
Yes, sir.
Moment of Decision
This baby's pretty awesome too!
Lord Pinion, you have a visitor.
Ah, let 'em through.
Lord Pinion?
Like some nobleman!
Oh, it's just you?
So you can inspect all the goods you like?
When did you become such a big shot?
Hey, I never asked for this.
Here.
Avalon.
Utopia.
...we will transform this planet, Earth,
into our own utopia—a second Avalon!
Falter not.
Grace?!
H-Hey!
Oh, right.
Grace is on Gargantia.
With Amy.
Amy...
He's here!
Pinion!
Keep it short.
What's with the members of this fleet?
Huh?
They might as well be ghosts!
It's like they're possessed.
It's weird!
I guess.
If this goes on, the people on my ships
.are bound to end up the same way.
And then, what would have been the point of leaving Gargantia?!
Are you going to let that happen?
Someone's planning a revolt.
What?
Really?
It's the Red Lobster who greeted me.
The great pirate Rackage?
Th-Then, if you pair up with the Lobster and—
She wants the metalhead, though.
Can't see Ledo agreeing to that one.
No...
Are we gonna have to
live like this forever?
Spread it out and collect the water!
You're soaked.
You're gonna catch a cold like that.
Hey!
Huh?
What the hell?
Chamber, what's going on?
This is the natural phenomenon
we observed earlier called "rain."
I do not detect anything
.out of the ordinary.
What... is that?
What?
The gift bestowed by the great God
.in the skies is a wonderful blessing.
Their journey to stand by
.God's side begins here.
As a manifestation of our fervent gratitude,
they shall die for the sake of those who live!
What?
Stop! What are you doing?!
They receive this eternal glory
.for the salvation of mankind.
People...
Those are people, right?
I didn't come here to witness this.
They're insane.
Indeed, they are.
And this insane fleet's next target is...
Gargantia.
What?!
Guess this ain't gonna
.work out after all.
I came here to protect them
.all from the Hideauze.
Amy.
Bevel.
I want to protect all those people!
I...
Orders received from Colonel Kugel:
"Second Lieutenant Ledo is
to prepare for combat."
"To me, soldier."
I await your decision.
My decision, huh?
I decide, and you execute.
That's how it's always been.
The truth is, I've never made a
.single real decision in my life.
The meaning of your words is unclear.
The Colonel's orders—
Chamber!
How is your combat potential
compared to Striker's?
Cannot be determined
.due to lack of data.
The intent of your query is unclear.
Can you fight Striker?
Tell me.
Striker X3752 is currently operating
.without orders from the Galactic Alliance.
It can be considered a
.possible combat opponent.
I see.
In that case,
can I fight the colonel?
Chamber!
Answering that is beyond my
.capabilities as a pilot support system.
Decisions regarding combat objectives
.are left to you under all circumstances.
Please.
Radio transmissions would be intercepted.
We must warn them directly.
We're out of time!
But you can't leave such an
...important mission to me...
You're the only one here who can
.fly all the way to Gargantia.
Please! Save them all!
You owe me one, okay?
Chamber. Stand by for combat.
Roger.
Gargantia...
Melty!
It really was you!
Amy... Amy!
They're gonna attack Gargantia...
Melty?!
What a crazy girl.
She flew all the way here
.by herself on a surfkite.
Melty!
Saya... Amy...
To protect Gargantia,
our only option is to follow Melty's instruction:
.change our course and attempt to flee.
As commodore, I have to agree—
Wait!
Amy?
Melty told me that Ledo wants to
take them on while we escape!
What?!
He's gonna fight! By himself!
In our place!
He'll even go against his own comrade, just to protect Gargantia!
And you still want to run away?!
Are you sure about that?!
But...
He made his choice.
We must make ours too.
Dr. Ordum...
Ridget.
I think it is high time we used the key.
The Stairway to Heaven?
Are you serious?
Such is my advice to the Commodore
as the wise man of this fleet.
The time has come.
Amy.
I want you to help too.
Hear my almighty will.
To demonstrate God's
.boundless might to the world,
I hereby announce the beginning
of a new crusade!
We shall be victorious
and bring absolute order to this planet.
We shall build a glorious and prosperous
.utopia on this planet.
Obey me. Nothing more is required.
I will lead you to eternal well-being.
Ledo.
Second Lieutenant Ledo,
explain your absurd behavior.
You're the one being absurd!
Such words hardly befit
.a soldier of the Alliance.
This is Earth, not the Galactic Alliance!
Nevertheless, it is a planet
.inhabited by mankind.
It is our duty to enlighten them.
Duty?!
No!
The people of this planet have
built their own world here!
Nothing can justify destroying that!
Our legitimacy remains unchanged.
Falter not.
Keep your distance!
This is a battle of the gods!
How is it so powerful?!
I hypothesize that it is not
limited to its own generator
but has been able to draw power
.from an external energy source.
So he was charging up?
Ledo.
It is our duty to bring a
new order to this planet.
Pinion?
Pinon, withdraw!
This is my battle!
Can it!
You space boys sure get on my nerves,
but that's nothin' compared
to those religious nutjobs!
Next shot charged and ready!
Kill them!
What is the meaning of this?!
All civilians not participating in the attack,
take shelter in the cargo hangars!
Prepare the rescue pods!
That vessel is the fleet's main ship!
Seize control of it at all costs!
Quell the revolt!
All who oppose us are enemies!
H-Her?!
Please pardon my uncomely entrance.
Actually acting like a man for once?
My opinion of you has improved.
Shut up!
Get rid of those guys,
and get over here!
Don't mind if I do.
Unable to establish tactical dominance.
A temporary retreat is suggested.
Focus fire on the enemy cockpit.
I don't want to kill the colonel!
Warning: enemy unit on collision course.
Both the strong and the weak
.support each other with reason.
That is what it means to be human.
Am I wrong?
Ledo!
Now!
Take this!
Pinion?
Hell yeah!
Generator at maximum output!
Say, Ledo. Won't you help
me change this planet?
Going in.
Send emergency release signal.
Having you around will help a lot.
What do you say?
Will you follow me... once more...
Colonel...
Rebooting posture control system.
Second Lieutenant Ledo,
your resistance is futile.
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara da ne
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo
Art: Izumi Tsubasu