This is the infamous Sea of Fog.
Is it true that no one's gone inside and lived to tell the tale?
It's a pretty famous story.
Here they come!
Man, there's a lot of them!
All ships, halt engines!
Now then, General Metalhead, show us what you've got!
Commencing combat.
A group of Hideauze approaching.
They clearly have the edge in terms of numbers.
Affirmative.
However, I hypothesize that their combat capabilities are inferior.
I suggest taking individual action.
That's just what I intended to do.
All right!
Preparing for coordinated attack.
That'd save us some effort.
Too slow!
I could keep this up forever.
Affirmative.
The Earthian Hideauze appear to be significantly inferior to those previously encountered.
Their combat capabilities are 1/120th of mine.
With current armaments, continuing to repel them will pose no difficulty.
Then that's what I'll do.
I'll kill them all.
maiagare yume no hate ni
Fly high, to the far reaches of your dreams
mirai ga aru sa
That's where our future lies
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
afuredasu hontou no negai
My true wishes can no longer be contained
omoi no mama ni susumou
We'll proceed as we please
kimi to nara doko made mo ikeru
No place is beyond our reach if you're with me
kakenukeru yo kokoro wa jiyuu
We'll run past it all, for our hearts are free
motomeru chikara boku no naka ni aru no o
The power I wish for lies within me
oshiete kureta no wa kimi no hohoemi
Your smile told me that
maiagare
Fly high
kagayaki e to chikadzuite miseru
We'll approach the light, just you see
kibou ga moeru oozora
The vast sky burns with hope
itsuka mita yume no hate ni
At the far reaches of the dream I once had
mirai ga aru sa
We can find our future
kono sekai wa bokura o matteita
This world has been waiting for us
Deep Sea Secret
Okay! Just maintain the course now!
And keep an eye on the depth gauge!
Is this really the right way?
Man, I do not wanna get lost in the middle of a bunch of whalesquids.
I heard they can put curses on you, too!
Cut that out!
We'll be fine!
Nothing to worry about if we just follow the plan!
I'm not gonna screw up again.
Bro, this is bad!
I've never seen so many whalesquids in one place!
No need to panic.
We'll be fine as long as we don't provoke them.
Let's go around and cut towards 10 o'clock.
10 o'clock. Roger.
Hey, is that...
Yeah.
A real treasure island, just like I thought.
Was something this awesome really built by humans?
I'm gonna take a look around.
You keep watch here.
Be careful, Bro!
Hey now, I'll be back before you know it.
I'm inside.
There are these stupidly huge machines all over the place.
This wasn't some residential building.
It was an industrial facility.
A whalesquid!
This is seriously incredible!
These aren't lousy parts
but true relics of the ancient civilization!
Hey, don't you think it's about time to head back?
We can't pull up everything by ourselves anyway.
Well, I need to get an idea of the place for when we come back.
Right now, I'm opening the gate.
Huh? What's this huge thing?
Crap! This is a whalesquid—
What's wrong?!
Dammit!
Screw you all!
Pinion! Run!
Bro!
Bro, I'm back.
Warning: 23% of my total energy has been depleted from using Maximize.
Its usage underwater is highly inefficient.
I know.
That's why I brought this melee weapon.
What?
Is that the main force?
Activating proximity fuse. Launching.
Roger.
Oh, wow.
So they really can be killed.
Yeah, looks like they aren't demons or anything!
Didn't I tell you guys?
Ledo, how's it going down there?
No problems.
Good going!
Now, just lure them out of their nest!
We'll be ready for them in five minutes.
Understood.
Right ahead, huh?
Warning: density of enemy units increasing.
Their numbers are too high to engage simultaneously.
Recommending retreat.
We're good up here! Anytime you're ready!
Roger.
Okay! Now!
Gotcha.
Launch!
Activating anti-shock shield.
No damage. Deactivating shield.
Status?
Currently, 67% of detected enemy forces have been annihilated.
Percentage increasing.
All right.
Heave-ho!
I see.
When you're done with that, move on to the next step of the plan.
It's working perfectly!
Keep throwing them in!
Aye!
Fair enough, but is that Yunboro gonna be okay?
He'll be fine.
That metalhead's really something else.
No reason to hold back, then!
Look at all those lightbugs! That blast of water was glowing!
So, fish can't survive here, but the whalesquids can?
Where do I go next?
The enemy forces appear to be retreating.
I hypothesize that they have shifted to defense of their base.
Their base...
Is that the nest Pinion mentioned?
Echolocation analysis complete.
Displaying.
I see.
What is... that?
Warning: overall fatigue levels reaching dangerous levels.
Recommending retreat and a later assault at full power.
There's no way I'm passing up this chance.
Roger. Proceeding with current mission.
Ion concentration rising.
Ongoing electrolytic reaction detected.
Powerful electromagnetic field discharge from inside the target confirmed.
What?!
Activating anti-shock shield.
The hell is that?
Could that be the curse?
This is Pinion.
Do you copy, Ledo?
Hey, Ledo! Metalhead!
What's going on? Respond!
This is Ledo.
You had us worried.
Okay! Let's get a move on ourselves!
Aye!
I may have been too careless.
In any case, they're much more vulnerable than they seem.
I hypothesize that a lack of natural enemies has resulted in their devolution.
The analysis can wait.
Energy remaining?
Fifty-three percent.
All right.
Great!
Ledo and the metalhead did it!
That treasure is as good as ours!
Hurray!
Everyone, prepare to drop the anchors!
Watch this, Bro.
Can you see anything?
Not a thing! This fog is way too thick!
I wonder if the cutie's okay,
Pinion being the one in charge and all...
They could at least report on their progress so far.
All we can do now is put our faith in Pinion.
What are those?
They appear to be fledgling Hideauze.
These are... Hideauze children?
Much is unknown regarding the Hideauze life cycle.
This is valuable information.
Are these really Hideauze?
Analysis of biological signatures complete.
All patterns match those of Hideauze.
Organisms now designated as Hideauze larva.
Is this their spawning ground?
Proceeding with the mission.
What's that?
It appears to be this facility's administration block.
And these?
I hypothesize that this is a type of recording medium used in extreme environments.
Can you salvage the data?
Records successfully accessed.
Scanning for known data formats.
Compatible format detected.
Launching inference engine.
Attempting recovery and translation.
Recovery complete.
Good. Now open it.
Display of data prohibited.
Prohibited?
This facility is confirmed to be a research institute of the ancient civilization.
However, further details are marked as classified by the Galactic Alliance of Humankind.
Classified?
Is that even relevant now?
It is military protocol.
Take a look at our situation!
When unable to contact the main forces,
the highest-ranking officer present has authority to command.
Isn't that right?
Affirmative.
And just who is the highest-ranking officer present here?
Lieutenant Ledo.
I, Lieutenant Ledo, demand the display of the classified data
from pilot support and development interface system Chamber.
Roger.
Executing command.
Don't get ahead of yourselves.
We need to scout the place first.
Survey the area, and secure a foothold!
Yeah, we know.
I'm counting on you, Ledo.
Now is the time for mankind to walk using its own two feet.
And the volunteer who'll be taking the first step is our guest, Ryan Matsumoto.
This mission seems rather dangerous...
Well, nothing like this has ever been attempted before,
but I've got the best staff out there backing me up.
With their aid, this missi—
Now that the fifth ice age is closer than ever,
our research is becoming more and more crucial.
However, many fear that such rapid scientific progress
will destroy traditional values and will be detrimental to people's happiness and well-being.
But religion and traditions have changed alongside the progress of science.
Continuous research may make happiness attainable for the first time.
I hereby announce the birth of a stronghold of free science!
The advocates of augmented evolution,
commonly known as the Evolvers, are facing opposition all over the world.
I think that's truly unfortunate.
And what about your human genome experiments,
which violate international regulations?
To overcome the crisis we are facing,
it is necessary to be more flexible.
In my opinion, current international regulations are outdat—
In response to the worsening global cooling,
there are calls to expedite the development of space.
Led by the Continental Union,
space stations and interstellar migration vessels are being developed.
Such space development is essential,
but that alone may not be enough.
After all, it is not machines that will be going into space
but we humans.
Since last week's shocking leak of inside information,
the opposition against the Evolvers has been getting fiercer.
The Continental Union dispatched a multinational fleet
without waiting for the UN's decree.
On the other hand, there are also a number of countries siding with the Evolvers' cause.
It is expected that the crisis will only worsen.
Limited as we are,
finding planets suitable for colonization
would take at least dozens of years, if not centuries.
There is but one solution to this problem.
We must utilize and combine mechanical engineering and biology.
By evolving the human body itself,
we can adapt to the vacuum of space
and to the astronomical distance and time requirements of interstellar travel.
The symbiont is a wonderful invention.
It can respire using the oxygen in seawater and endure the pressure of ocean depths.
I'm sure they'll eventually adapt to the absolute-zero vacuum as well.
Symbiotic nanomachines provide their nutrition.
The method resembles photosynthesis but is far more efficient.
Daddy!
Wave good-bye to Daddy.
Is Daddy going away?
No, we'll—
Last week, the highly criticized Evolvers were under fire again
due to a leak of their internal recruitment materials,
which demonstrated that they had carried out atrocious human experiments
in violation of international law.
With global cooling rapidly decreasing the area habitable on Earth,
the conflict over the escape from the planet
between the Continental Union and the Evolvers is intensifying.
Currently, the frontlines are limited to outer space and to the launch sites on the surface,
but the hostilities are expected to increase in scale.
We have discovered that the Continental Union is developing a large-scale wormhole drive.
The platforms are all equipped with self-destruct devices.
It is clear that they intend to destroy the drive
upon their escape of the Solar System, thus stranding us on Earth!
This is our chance!
By attacking and taking control of the wormhole drive,
we Evolvers can extend our habitat to unknown galaxies!
We shall conquer the infinity of space and achieve eternal prosperity!
That concludes the playable data.
Multiple contradictions with information released by the Galactic Alliance exist.
Its credibility is extremely low.
Then, what was that?!
Who made it, and why?
It is highly likely to be information manipulated by the enemy.
The enemy? What exactly is the enemy?
Weren't the Hideauze supposed to be lower life forms?!
Surviving Hideauze identified.
Commencing extermination.
Stop!
Get all the equipment to starboard!
The hell is Ledo doing?
I wonder what this world
kimi no hitomi ni kono sekai wa
Looks like to you
donna fuu ni utsutterun darou
What are you going to find on the sea?
kono umi de nani wo mitsuketeku no kana
With fumbling hands, little by little
bukiyou na te de sukoshi zutsu
You try to find out where the wind blows
kaze no yukue wo tsukamu you ni
You move ahead by your own efforts
jibun no chikara de susunde yukun da
So I'm sure the day will come
kitto itsuka sono toki wa kuru yo
It just pains me a little
sukoshi sabishii no wa
That your sky is too bright for me
kimi no sora ga mabushii kara dake
But I'm so happy, so happy to see you try your best
ganbatteru sugata ga ureshikute ureshikute
That's why I decided I've got to change myself as well
dakara watashi datte kawaranakuchatte kimeta no
Let me tell you everything's all right, forever and ever
daijoubutte iwasete itsumademo itsumademo
I'm by your side watching
soba de miteru yo
And on this day so reminiscent of you
kimi rashii kyou no naka he
I'll be seeing you
ai ni yuku yo
Art: Kasukabe Akira