Countless endangered species have gone extinct throughout history.
One such example would be the humans who possessed the special power known as "ISH."
And frankly speaking, for a power like that to die off in obscurity is the best possible outcome.
That way, everyone can live more peaceful lives.
Anyone who would consider using such a power for the purpose of mere entertainment
is a fool.
That about sums it up.
Zetsumetsu kigu shoujo
Endangerously foolish girls
Shuraba ni uchiatare
Dive into conflict
Zenryoku gushoujo
Airheads to the max
Chaos ni tsukkome
Plunge into chaos
Zetsumetsu kigu shoujo
Endangerously foolish girls
Genkai made kamitsuke
Push yourselves to the limit
Zenryoku gushoujo
Airheads to the max
Tonde hi ni haire
Fly like a moth to the flame
Itami wo kanjiru yo
I can feel your pain
Kokoro no
So let's yell out
Sakebi wo kikasete
What's in our hearts
Tsunagarou
And come together
Chikyuu wo marugoto
We have the power
Ugokaseru hazu dakara
To shake the world to its very core
(Shinjite)
(So believe)
ISH for wish sora ni donna michi demo
ISH for wish, no matter how turbulent your flight
Futatsu tamashii awase tsukiyabure
Combine your two souls and blaze through it
Donnani namida tsubusareru yoru mo
Even the darkest night that takes your tears away
Zettai ni no nante iwanai
Won't tell you that it's impossible
Too slow!
What?!
You're so weak.
Far too weak!
Shit...
I'll send you straight to Hell.
Messiah Chain!
Are you okay, Captain Japan?
Yeah. Thanks,
Messiah Lady.
Die, Messiah Lady!
You'd better be dead.
Huh? What?!
I will not die!
You shall repent!
Episode
Welcome to Our Show!
Hear me, foolish humans.
I am the queen of the demon world—
a messenger from the realm of darkness!
You're a queen and a messenger?
The heinous ESPer Idol,
Todoroki Amane!
Don't twirl so excitedly, or...
Huh?
I feel... dizzy...
Yes, exactly.
Charged to the max!
Lilianne!
Okay, okay.
Whoopsie-daisie!
Heinous and cruel, I am on the prowl!
Thanks for your continued support!
That's too drastic a personality shift.
Next up:
my evil underling,
Cat Man!
This premise really is pushing it...
But as long as we're doing this,
we've gotta do it right!
As bland as ever, I see.
What a bland cat.
Cat Man ESP:
Big Bang!
There it is!
Teleportation magic!
Ow...
Here I go!
You shall repent!
I'm beat.
Huh? Hey!
Hey, Lilianne! Don't do this to me!
Allow me to take it from here, then.
Here's the cutey-lovely Hironacchi!
Go for it!
'Kay!
Huh?
That is all.
Magic  Show
Evil
ESPer
Idol
Amanel
and
Her
super
merry
Friends!
Cast
Amanel
KAZUKI
Hironacchi
Cast
Amanel
KAZUKI
Hironacchi
Cast
Amanel
KAZUKI
Hironacchi
Cast
Amanel
KAZUKI
Hironacchi
That was weird.
Didn't it look much better on TV?
Thank you very much!
This was the "ESPer Idol Amanel" magic show!
We look forward to seeing you again!
She wasn't the least bit special, Hasudou.
While she might have been weak, she was capable of using multiple abilities, right?
That sets her apart from
normal ESPers like you, Aya.
Plus, take a look at this.
The estimated value of her potential abilities is abnormally high.
Much higher than anything I've seen before.
Are you sure it's accurate?
And what's with this stuffed toy that supplies her with power?
I want to know.
Todoroki Amane, you're irresistible.
Aya, let's use test subject number fourteen in the special show we're inviting her to.
She might die, you know?
We'll cross that bridge when we come to it.
I wanna eat that too...
You never can use it without my help, can you?
If you know that already, then don't bail on me partway through, Lilianne!
That aside, we need to discuss the steady decline in attendance.
I knew the whole "heinous"
thing was a bad idea.
Do we need to discuss how the "wicked idol" idea went?
I think the "idol" part's the problem here.
Actually, why don't you take the stage with us, Nanae-san?
"Esperanza Magic" was a really cool name.
Stop!
Geez!
N-No way! What is that, Amane-chan?!
Um, well... that was...
Isn't she kinda freaky?
It was me.
I stopped the car using my powers.
Do we have a problem?
Thank you...
She possesses a power
similar to ours, doesn't she?
That's why she covered for us.
Yep.
This power tends to scare people,
so I should try not to use it too much.
But it felt different today.
Back then,
I was one with you, Amane.
Huh?
I was a part of you.
It felt a little good,
but if we do that again,
you'll lose all your friends.
I knew you'd be better off
without me around.
That's not true.
You're my little sister.
We're twins!
Amane?
Can I really stay with you?
Of course!
I love you, Lilianne.
I love you too.
Let's stay together forever.
When I found out that the lady who saved me was using her powers to hold magic shows,
I thought it was awesome!
I was amazed that these powers could be used like that!
But now...
All right! Time for special training!
I'm going to learn some crazy technique.
Maybe I'll learn to fly like Messiah Lady, even!
H-Hey!
Stop!
And then we'll be overnight sensations!
I don't think it'll be that easy.
You're too naïve, Amane-kun.
There he goes again.
Kazukicchi and his "Nope-Nope" disease.
Well, am I wrong?
We can totally do this!
We have your bird-calling abilities
and Hironacchi's superhuman strength.
We'll do our best, too!
But Lilianne's...
Oh, so it's Lilianne you're worried about?
Have you fallen for her?
Of course not!
Anyway, once we put on shows
that are a lot more fun
and convince people that they don't need to be afraid of ISH,
we won't have to keep a low profile anymore.
I'd love for that to happen too.
But first, we have to capture the
audience's hearts by using proper magic.
Oh, right!
You get it now?
This really does call for special training!
Let's go, Lilianne.
We'll see you later!
She's not even listening to me...
All right! Now I'm all fired up!
Shut up and walk.
Sentiment Takagi
Hello!
You reek of booze.
Are you here for training advice again?
That's right!
Are there any special
training methods for flying?
That's a tough one.
Five thousand yen.
What? Make it five hundred
and you've got a deal.
Sure.
Hang on a second.
I'll contact Gaia right away.
Huh?
I will now convey to you Gaia's will.
This should do the trick!
No, it won't.
Yeah...
I give up.
Belief is the key to your ISH abilities.
Sentiment Takagi
For someone like you, foolish enough to believe the most barefaced of lies, anything is possible.
Amane may be a fool,
but this is really pushing it.
That sounds hard.
Hang in there, foolish girl.
Okay.
That'll be five hundred yen.
What? You're still going to charge?!
CROQUETTES
Guess we should do some
teleportation training.
Yeah. We only ever use it unconsciously.
Three-second rule...
Three-second rule.
You're Todoroki Amane from the
performing troupe "Nought," right?
Yes, but who are you?
Wait, could you be a fan of mine?
What? No way!
Thought as much.
Then who are—
Your magic's bogus, isn't it?
Don't call it bogus!
Of course it isn't—
It's ISH...
Right?
I'm the same as you.
Huh? Are you saying you're an ESPer too?
Right. Also...
I-A-M.
Wait, I.A.M?!
Oh, you've heard of it?
Obviously!
Their popularity has gone
through the roof recently.
I.A.M's Cruel Illusion:
a spectacle of bloodshed and insanity!
Can you handle this spectacle
of bloodshed and insanity?
Oh, but I haven't seen it,
since I can't stand scary stuff.
Not for the faint of heart!
Oh!
Could you be Aya-chan,
I.A.M's masked magician?!
Bingo.
Really?
Hey, could you tag along with me?
Huh?
I'll take you to a special show.
Amanel, Amanel...
Amanel, Amanel, Amanel, Amanel...
Amanel!
She left for the day already.
Sennokura-sensei?!
She worked so hard on the manuscripts this week
because she was looking forward to seeing Amane-san.
Date!
Horror movie!
Haunted house!
Amane finds that kind of stuff...
...so scary she could cry, right?
But she can't turn down my requests since I'm her patron! So cute!
By the way, did you
check out I.A.M's show?
No, not yet.
I took a look.
That Aya girl has an ISH ability.
Not to mention, she seems a tad dangerous.
Dangerous?
It's like she's somewhat murderous, bloodthirsty, and bewitching!
Probably best not to get involved.
Well, I guess you have nothing in common,
including popularity.
Sorry about that.
This is kinda scary...
What do you think Aya-chan's ISH ability is?
Remember that weird thing that showed up out of your croquette earlier?
Twilight, which brings out the devil in men.
The onset of a sinister night.
I'm scared already!
Love is deception, and everything is false.
Fear is the only reality.
Hey—
What?!
What the heck is this?!
Today's first sacrificial lamb—
Give her back!
Take her back.
Maximize your ISH output and do it.
If not, I'll rip your precious bear to shreds.
Stop...
Stop it!
Looks like you don't mind.
Then I won't hold back.
Blood drops keep falling on my head,
falling on my head...
It's so much fun to stab and chop with a knife...
Chop, chop, mush, mush, la la la!
Lilianne!
Your ability sucks!
You really are utterly pathetic
without your stuffed toy, aren't you?
Anyway, my ability primarily deals in visual interference.
What you're seeing right now
is an illusion I created.
The same goes for that thing at the back.
But your poor teddy bear's fate...
was also an illusion!
I'll give her back.
Lilianne!
Now, will you show me your ISH ability at full strength?
I refuse.
The only thing I want to use ISH for
is to entertain people.
Huh?
What?
I want everyone to realize that ISH is an
amazing power that can be used for fun things!
I want them to understand that it's nothing to be afraid of!
Are you stupid?
Scaring the non-ESPers to death is where the real fun lies!
They're completely powerless, but they act like they're better
just because they outnumber us!
When they find out about our powers,
they get all scared and attack us
even if we've done nothing at all.
Keep up that carefree attitude,
and you'll wind up dead one day.
I don't care what you say.
That is my dream.
Hey, it's Amane-chan!
Mana-chan?
Yoohoo!
Why are you here?
Sacrificial lamb number two!
Hey, you can't leave what
few fans you have to die!
I hope for your sake that
the next one's an illusion too.
Kozu-chan?!
Your opponent's over there.
A non-ESPer who's had
his ISH forcibly awakened.
Thing is, the only way to find out what abilities someone will have, or their potency, is to try it!
So this is ISH, huh?!
Amazing!
Two other teensy problems are mental instability and the powers going out of control.
Whoa, this is seriously awesome!
Now, number fourteen.
Your prey is this girl right here.
Maximize your ISH output
and get your hands on her.
The same goes for you.
There are no rules.
I don't even care if one of you dies.
The laws we have right now can't touch an ISH ESPer, anyway.
My prey's a high school girl?
You really know where it's at.
Have you come to, princess?
Lilianne!
Okay.
Stop that!
Don't you dare lay a finger on Kozu-chan!
Amanel?
Oh, yeah. I was told I'd get to see a
...special show of Amanel's, and then...
The hell is this?
Whoa, it's so tough!
I didn't know you could
do this kinda shit too!
This power is just so damn amusing!
Amanel!
Kozu-chan...
Run away!
Take that!
Amane, are you okay?
Yeah.
What's going on?
Isn't it a magic show?
She really is nothing special.
Hurry up and run away!
No!
Warp!
Dammit!
Warp! Warp!
Believe in yourself, Amane.
Okay!
Remember all those days you spent training.
That's how it goes.
Best of luck with your training.
That'll be two hundred yen.
This time, I'll warp for sure!
I did it, Lilia—
HERE
Warp, warp, warp, warp...
Warp!
It worked!
Wait, wha—
Catch me if you can!
Please, let me go!
This is good.
This is so much fun!
Are you okay, Lilianne?
I'm fine.
This feels great!
Is he going berserk?
Amane, let's become one.
Become one?
Yeah, like we did back then.
I'll give you all of my power.
Lilianne...
Keep Kozu-chan safe at all costs.
Got it.
I can't hear her voice, but I can feel it.
I can feel every last bit of Lilianne.
So I won't lose!
Bring it on!
That's... Amanel?
Hey, what the heck is that?
This is the best!
Fighting to the death is the best!
Knock it off already!
Let me go!
Kozu-chan!
How could he jump all the way
up here with the car?!
Sorry to put you through
such a harrowing experience.
Don't worry.
I'll save you, no matter what!
I'll make sure you reach the end of the show
with a smile on your face!
The sea.
I'll have to teleport to the sea.
That's my only option.
With Liliane's help, I can do this!
Combine both of our powers into one...
Warp!
To the sea!
Lilianne?
I'm okay.
Thank goodness.
Hang in there...
Hang in there for just a little longer.
It's all righ—
I'm... saved.
What's going on?
I don't get it at all!
Wasn't Amanel's show a
simple magic performance?
Kozu-chan,
stay calm and hear me out.
It talk—
Please don't come to hate Amane.
She's doing all of this for my sake.
I'm Amane's twin sister,
but I don't have a body.
You don't have a body?
Apparently I lost it while I was still in my mother's womb.
The only thing I have
is this strange power.
Even so, Amane wants me to feel like I belong in this world.
She wants to give my life
a meaning—a purpose.
That's why she puts on those magic shows.
What's happening?
Please believe me.
Amane would never use
this power for herself.
She may be a fool,
but she's a really honest one.
So...
So please believe in Amane!
Please, please don't come to hate her!
I beg of you!
Don't worry.
I'll save you, no matter what!
I'll make sure you reach the end of the show
with a smile on your face!
Honest and foolish...
Now I get why Amanel's shows are so fun.
It's all right.
Forget coming to hate her,
I'm an even bigger fan of hers now!
Thank you.
Oh... I hear laughter.
That, and this restless noise...
Is it the waves?
Or could it be applause?
Just look at this power.
I knew it!
Todoroki Amane is an Archetype—
beings that were said to have gone extinct!
No, I don't know.
I have no idea where she is
or what she's up to.
Hasudou did?!
Massugu na omoi dake ga
If only the most honest of emotions
Hikari ni nareru nara
Can become the shining light
Taisetsu na hito no tame
Then I'll become a shadow
Kage ni naru yo
For the ones I hold dear
Onaji katachi no heart mottetemo
While our hearts may all look the same
Kokoro asymmetry
Our souls are asymmetrical
Namida de barasu no
Once we break free of our tears
Kusari hodokeba
And the shackles they bind to us
Mou daijoubu kanashimi wo
We will be just fine
Chikara ni kawaru
Our sorrow will give us strength
Sono egao ga motto
I want your smile
Kagayaku youni
To keep shining brighter than ever
Zutto soba ni iru kara
So I'll always be with you
Tsuyoku tsunagaru yo
And hold you tight