It is well known that our bloodline dates back
.to the long-past Heian period.
Just because we're tanuki
doesn't mean we pop out of a nook in a
.camphor tree like a hairy ball of candy.
The wildly branching bloodline we inherit
binds us for reasons unknown.
Even a bohemian tanuki like me
cannot abandon his blood ties so easily.
As you might expect,
even the most tenuous familial bonds
.can allow grudges to be held,
turning quarrels that should be water
.under the bridge into long-lasting feuds.
They say that blood is thicker than water,
but I think that proverb
.is more than I can handle.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Seven
Bathhouse Rules
Akegarasu
Did you find what you were looking for?
I don't have the slightest of leads.
I gotta say, I thought you'd
.already ended up in a stew.
Well, I'm sure it's only a matter of time.
With all due respect, what the hell?
Drink up while you still can.
You gotta seize the day, you know.
Big bro, you gotta help me!
He hates baths. To an extreme degree.
These days, even the tanuki
who live out in Shimogamo Forest
worry about split ends
.and use hair conditioner,
but this guy can't even stand to
.wipe his body with a damp cloth.
Oh, that explains a lot.
Whenever I say "Let's go
.to the bathhouse," he's like,
"The weather's bad."
"My butt itches."
"My back hurts."
"I don't like the look on your face!"
Didn't you try dragging him out anyway?
I did! Then he threw a
.huge daruma doll at me.
Anyway, the whole room smells
.like something died in there,
so I tried to do something about it, but...
But he's been spraying so much air freshener
around that you can't even breathe?
Yeah.
I'm so useless, big bro.
I can't even get Master
.Akadama to take a bath.
Don't cry, Yashirou.
Herding seniors isn't the
.most sought-after of talents.
You've got better things
.to put your energy into.
He's been letting loose
.with his tengu winds, too.
Oh, he still has enough energy to do that?
It's messing up my hair.
Any more, and I'll end up with an afro.
If he wants to show off what's left of his power,
he should pick on someone his own size.
He's a disgrace to all tengu.
I'll plunge him into the
steaming bathwater of repentance!
You shouldn't bully him too much, big bro.
I know.
I just wanted to say that.
Hey, your tail's out.
That you, Yasaburou?
I haven't seen you since the
.night of the Fire Festival.
Where have you been loafing about?
You're a rambunctious lowlife who's
.forgotten how to act toward his mentor.
I wasn't exactly loafing around, but...
Anyway, I apologize for not visiting sooner.
I have no need of your visits.
In fact, it was one less thing to worry about.
Oh, you're always saying stuff like that.
Why don't you just admit you were lonely?
As if!
Why does someone like me have to
go take a bath with you tanuki?
You don't want to go with us?
Is that it?
So you'd go if it were with Benten?
That goes without saying.
That's exactly what I want.
You lecherous tengu.
In that case, how about
I transform into Benten?
It'll be nice and sexy.
Just you try it.
I'll pulverize you!
Do it if you can, you stubborn old tengu!
You asked for it.
The likes of you don't stand a
chance against my tengu wind!
Bring it!
Moo!
Moo.
Mooo...
...o.
Moo.
Moo!
Yasaburou, what are you
playing at over there?
Please, no moo-re.
Enough with the mooing already.
Master, might you be
sweating with righteous fury?
Eh.
It's not so bad to have a bath
every now and then, you know?
Eh.
Master, it's been quite some time.
It's pretty chilly tonight, isn't it, Yaichirou?
Yes, Master.
Must be a pain coming
all the way out here, huh?
Not at all.
Say what you really think.
I'm speaking from the heart.
Well, whatever.
Okay, let's go!
What are we dawdling around for?
Bathhouse
What a bother. Such a bother.
Wo
men
This bath's cold, big bro!
Yashirou, that one's supposed to be cold.
Why do I have to take a
bath with you hairballs?
We're in human form,
so shedding is not a concern.
Still, I wish Benten were here
.to wash my back.
I want to take a bath with Benten.
Ahh, I wanna take a bath with Benten!
Master, must you express your
indecent desires so openly?
Please try to retain at least a little dignity.
I'm ashamed to call myself your disciple.
Even if Benten came, you think you'd be
allowed to join her in the women's bath?
Quiet, you.
Yasaburou,
I hear you were out the other day
.with Benten and the Friday Fellows.
You certainly seem to be obsessed
.with following her around.
There's no way a hairball like you would
be carrying a torch for her... is there?
Don't be ridiculous!
What'd be the point of a
tanuki falling for a human?
The allure of forbidden love?
Like you give a damn
.about what tanuki forbid.
Who knows what a twisted guy
.like you might be plotting.
Your expectations of me
.are always so warped.
I'm only trying to look out for you.
If you view her as just some human girl,
you'll get eaten up.
Master!
It's about time to get out.
First you drag me all the way here,
and now you won't even let me
take my time in the bath?
He says he hates baths,
but once he gets in,
you can't get him out.
It's sweet.
Sure is.
Big bro, coffee and milk both taste bad,
so why does coffee milk taste so good?
It must be the multiplier effect.
The multiplier effect?
Like a fateful encounter.
Once they meet, everything goes smoothly.
You know, Master says a lot of things,
but he really does like you.
Yeah. I knew that already.
And you like Master too, right?
Hey, keep that between us, okay?
My dignity is at stake here.
While you were in Osaka,
he kept asking me,
"How is Yasaburou doing?
Did Benten eat him yet?"
That's good to hear.
What's all this?
Are the tanuki acting like idiots again?
The Ebisugawa Elite Guard?
Togetsukyou
Bridge
The Ebisugawa Elite Guard?
Elite Guard?
Just some hoodlums that were
.lured in with free fake Denki Bran.
As if getting Master Akadama to
.take a bath wasn't enough of a hassle,
now these numbskull
.brothers show up as well.
This is what you'd call
.the anti-multiplier effect.
Did you do something?
Uncle probably ordered them to come here
.and convince me to drop out of the race.
The next Nise-emon
.will be selected this month,
and there's no telling
.whether it'll be Uncle or me.
I'm runnin' around all by myself
'cause nobody ever helps me out!
Seriously, you brothers of mine are such—
This again?
You just up and left for Osaka without
a single thought for your own brother!
What could I do? My life was in danger.
But you're the one who got into this—
Wait, bro. Look.
It's Kinkaku!
And Ginkaku!
Yeah, we know.
You don't have to announce it.
Then I'm sure you also
.know what we came to say.
And you think I'm just gonna
do you a favor and drop out?
We thought you might say that.
But according to my carefully
.composed calculations,
your chances of winning
.are infinitesimal.
You may not know this, but Yoshidayama
.has promised to back the Ebisugawa family.
Moreover... Let's see.
Takaragaike is backing us too.
We even have a significant
.amount of support from Yase.
Gosho will back me,
and Nanzenji would never take your side.
If Nanzenji's with me,
then Ginkakuji will be too.
Koudaiji and Rokuhara will
.undoubtedly support me as well.
That may be the case...
Wait, really? That many?
That's not what I'd heard.
This is earth-shattering.
Big bro, don't give up now! Go for the kill!
We have an ace in the hole, remember?
That's right. Our ace in the hole!
And what would that be?
I just said it was our ace in the hole.
You don't expect me to come out
and tell you, do you?
Because I certainly won't.
But I will tell you that
.you should drop out now.
The only one who can unite
.all tanuki-kind is our dad,
and one day I'll follow in his footsteps.
The world has no further use for the pathetic
.young masters of the Shimogamo family.
Quite right!
Fragile
False Advertising
You might have a mind to bite our butts again,
but it's not gonna happen.
Fragile
False Advertising
An artisan blacksmith residing in Nagahama
.reluctantly made us this iron underwear.
Fragile
False Advertising
If you try to bite us again,
you'll only chip those fangs of yours.
Fragile
False Advertising
How's that for an idea?
My big bro sure is clever, isn't he?
And trying to use force
.will get you nowhere.
We have trouble taking
.them off ourselves.
Thanks to you, my big bro and I have caught a chill
.and are in considerable distress.
Quite right!
In fact, I'm now more aware of
.that crisis than ever, big bro.
I guess you could say I'm about to be
.yelling "Oh crap!" quite literally.
Now that you mention it, me too.
So, come on. Just tell us you'll
.drop out of the Nise-emon race.
Otherwise, things are about
.to get real messy in here.
Like we care.
Damn you guys!
Cease that infernal racket!
Kinkaku, don't you know the bathhouse rules?
Rule one: no towels in the bathtub.
Rule two: no washing clothes in the water.
And finally, rule three: you have to
.rinse off before getting in the bath.
You can't just hop in like that.
You think a fool who can't even
follow the bathhouse rules
could ever become the leader
of all Kyoto's tanuki?
But you're the one who threw me in.
It's not like I did it myself.
Well, whatever.
What's this "ace in the hole" of yours?
I said I wasn't telling.
I see.
Lips still sealed, huh?
If you don't tell me, I'll throw you in
.and seal the lid on this.
Then you'll really catch a chill.
Okay, fine! I'll talk.
My stomach hurts, sheesh!
It's about your old man.
Do you know how he died?
Why bring that up now?
He was cooked in a stew.
Don't you find that suspicious?
How were they able to catch
such a great tanuki so easily?
Bath
Cold
I happen to be quite sharp,
so I found this rather curious.
So I decided to do some
.investigating with Ginkaku.
And we figured it out.
What did you figure out?
A truth that, should it be exposed,
would deal a fatal blow
.to the Shimogamo family.
Are you sure you want to know?
What are you saying?!
As it turns out, the day Uncle Shimogamo Souichirou
.was caught by the Friday Fellows,
he was out late drinking with someone.
He got so drunk that he became careless.
And that cost him his life.
So?
Well, you see,
the one he went drinking with that night has
.remained utterly quiet about it ever since.
Isn't that unforgivable?
Anyone decent would feel some responsibility
and apologize to everyone, right?
To their fellow tanuki!
After all, Uncle was a leader
to us all, was he not?
Who was it, then?
Spit it out!
Cold
Bath
Your useless little brother—
Our well-dwelling friend, Yajirou!
Cold! It's cooold!
Big bro, what's going on?
Bathhouse
Go home to the forest, Yashirou.
Stay with Mother.
Why'd you leave him behind?
I didn't have the heart to bring him.
You're so easy on Yashirou.
No.
This is for Yajirou's sake.
The
Six
Paths
Yasaburou, huh?
Oh, and a rare appearance by Yaichirou.
How have you been, big bro?
Not much happens in a
.small world like this, I'm afraid.
It's the bottom of a well, after all.
By the way, I heard all the leaves
.in Arashiyama fell in one night.
You're quite well informed for
.someone living in such a small world.
Kaisei told me about it when
.she was here yesterday.
Hey, big bro...
What's up?
Yajirou.
Oh, big bro.
You sound like you're in a bad mood.
Have you come to
lecture me about something?
I can't guarantee I'll be able to
.take your lesson to heart, though.
After all, I'm just a frog.
Yajirou.
I remember the last time
.I saw Father very clearly.
That day, I went out with him
.to visit the elders.
Afterward, he said he had
.some important appointment,
so he told me to
.go home without him.
That was nothing unusual, though.
I mean, Father was always so busy.
So he accompanied me as far as Higashioji
and waited until I caught the bus.
I still remember the way he looked, even now.
Because that was the last time I ever saw him.
Big bro...
What I want to ask you is:
exactly where and when
did you last see Father?
Were you...
Were you drinking with him that night?
Did you get drunk?
What about him?
Did you leave Father by himself,
even though he was drunk?
Please tell me that's not what happened.
Big bro, that's exactly what happened.
I'm the one who sent Father to his death.
How could you?!
You idiot!
What was I doing that day?
I was but a newborn pup, taking my
.first steps around Tadasu no Mori,
when I saw Dad wave good-bye to me.
Our dad, Shimogamo Souichirou,
was a great tanuki who united our society
and thus was extremely busy.
He was always going out,
bidding farewell to the forest
.where his wife and children waited.
That's just the way it was.
That winter,
when we found out that he had been
.cooked in a year-end stew,
we had great difficulty understanding that
.his last parting had been a true farewell.
As long as you still draw breath,
there is no way to escape
.having to bid others farewell.
It doesn't matter if you're
.human, tengu, or tanuki.
We all have to say good-bye.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
If not a frog, I wonder what else
.I might have transformed into.
A newt? A salamander?
I'd probably be at the bottom of a well either way.
Next Time:
The Day of Dad's Departure