Ever since Dad died,
the tanuki living in Kyoto have called us brothers from Tadasu no Mori
“fools who failed to inherit
their great father's blood.”
And sure, those gossipy tanuki
might be right every once in a while
with the stuff they talk
.about behind our backs,
but saying it as if our father's blood
just disappeared into thin air
really pisses me off.
For one thing, all tanuki are
.fools to some extent as it is.
To take it a step further,
I'd say that very idiocy is the best proof there is that his blood flows through our veins.
After reaching the apex of tanuki society,
Dad's own foolishness caught up to him,
and he ascended to the state of stew.
Episode Eleven
Back in the Game
Would you be so good as to just give up and come with us, Yasaburou?
What are you doing, Ebisugawa?
Such tiresome rain.
I'm happy to find you in
.good humor, Miss Benten.
Do I look good-humored to you?
I was waiting out the rain up there
.when I saw you, Yasaburou.
Then I thought I'd have you transform
.into an umbrella for me.
I'd transform into anything for you,
Benten—umbrellas included.
But...
What is it, Ebisugawa?
Is there a problem with that?
We were just about to head
.to a reconciliation banquet.
If you were to take him away,
we would be left in
.quite the predicament.
Remind me again: how does your
predicament concern me in the slightest?
Are you suggesting I should walk home
like this, soaked to the bone?
Of course not. I wouldn't dream of it.
Then I'll just borrow him for a bit.
Awful weather, huh?
You saved me. Thank you.
Did I do something?
No need to thank me.
I went to Master's room the day
.before yesterday, on Christmas Eve.
What for?
I'd had a few drinks for
.the first time in a while,
so I thought it wouldn't be
.so bad to check in on him.
He was sleeping like a log, though,
so I went home right away.
You gave him that cane, did you not?
No present for me?
No.
Why not?
There's nothing you'd
need from me, is there?
You already get whatever you want.
That's a terrible thing to say.
I haven't gotten a single
.thing I've ever wanted.
You're pretty quiet today, aren't you?
I know you put Father in a
.cage for the Ebisugawas.
Why didn't you ever say anything?
Huh?
You never asked!
I can't believe how much you
.humans like to twist words.
I'll have you know I'm a tengu.
Nope. You're a human,
and you'll always be a human.
Is that why you're giving
me the cold shoulder?
It's not just that.
It seems my brothers have been
.captured by the Ebisugawas.
You know how today is the
Friday Fellows' year-end bash?
They might end up making
.my big brother into stew.
Good heavens!
So I'll be eating your big brother tonight?
How terrible!
Would you be able to save him for me?
Don't count on it.
Why? You won't save him
just because he's a tanuki?
I'm only human, you know.
In that case, I'll do something
.about it on my own.
Where are the Friday Fellows
having their get-together?
Chitose-ya in Pontochou.
Do me a favor and try not to charge
.in there with your fists flying.
You're always so quick to
.resort to violence. I hate it.
Professor Yodogawa was saying he would
.go pick up the tanuki this afternoon.
He said he was in touch with someone who
.caught one, and they'd made an agreement.
Oh, right. Professor Yodogawa.
You can figure the rest out by yourself.
I'm human, so I just eat whatever
.tanuki ends up in the stew.
I couldn't care less who it is.
Professor Yodogawa?
It's like he just fell into my lap.
This is it! Divine providence!
Chikurintei Soba Noodles
Excuse me!
I'll have an egg bowl.
Let me out of here!
Dammit!
Yaichirou?
Mother?
Mother!
Yaichirou, they got you too?
I'll save you, Mother!
Dammit, I can't get out!
Once you're put in a cage, there's
.nothing you can do, Yaichirou.
You tried to get to me because Raijin
brought his storms, didn't you?
It's my fault.
This all happened because
.of my fear of thunder.
None of that matters!
I wonder what happened to
.Yasaburou and Yashirou.
I hope they're not having
.too rough of a time.
This is an Ebisugawa conspiracy!
How can they do this as fellow tanuki?
Drop dead!
Are you okay, Mother?
I'm just a bit cold.
That's strange.
“Back in the game, you know my name.”
Yashirou?
We're back in the game!
Back in the Game
You drugged the egg bowl?
We tricked him good, didn't we, big bro?
Well done, Ginkaku.
Drop d—
Gentlemen,
the day of vindication has arrived!
Yay!
Chikurintei
Demachi
shopping arcade
Masugata Co-op
We have some ready for you in here.
How many do you need, Juroujin?
Benten will be there,
so we'll need to prepare
.enough for ten people.
Oh my,
if it isn't the tanuki. Here, of all places.
Yes. I made an agreement to turn
.him over for tonight's banquet.
Ah, so Hotei asked someone
.else to get one for him.
How pathetic.
This soft spot for tanuki that
.Hotei has is really no good.
That's where I come in.
So you run this kind of
racket as well, Ebisugawa?
What an utterly wicked fellow you are.
Please, you flatter me.
So there'll be two tanuki tonight?
Splendid!
Oh, I'm sorry. This one isn't available.
Just one, then?
I'm afraid I can't give up
.this tanuki, Juroujin.
Not even to you yourself.
You're fond of that one, I take it?
It is as you say.
Well, that's fine.
Bring these to Chitose-ya.
Understood.
Dammit!
I won't let them make you into stew!
But there's nothing we
.can do at the moment.
If there's anyone who could
.save us, it'd be Yasaburou,
but he's probably been
.captured already.
If he hadn't been, there's no way Soun
.would have been that laid back.
We can't give up.
Yasaburou is sharp and fearless,
so I'm sure he'll be okay.
Hey, Kinkaku, let me outta here!
Why doesn't a pro like you
just transform his way out?
Oh, you mean you can't 'cause
you're locked up in a cage?
That's right, big bro.
To transform, you gotta have "inner calm."
Right, right.
And at the moment, he doesn't have the
slightest bit of inner calm, does he?
Too bad!
You rotten jerks are a disgrace
to all of tanuki-kind!
Goodness me, could it be that
you're just a plain old fool?
No doubt about it, big bro.
Clearly, a fool like you is too foolish
.to know where he went wrong.
So I'll tell you.
I predicted you would follow Professor
.Yodogawa to try to save Yaichirou.
Predicted!
Even so, no matter how
.brilliant my transformation,
you must have been blind as a bat
.not to pick him out as a fake.
Aren't you supposed to be friends with him?
Kinkaku, Ginkaku! When I get outta this cage,
I'm gonna bust your asses into eight cheeks each!
That makes sixteen between you!
Who cares about your powers of addition?
It might be multiplication, big bro.
Hmm? Two times eight is sixt—
Well, either way,
we're wearing our iron underwear made reluctantly
.by an artisan blacksmith in Nagahama,
so we're cool as cucumbers!
Cool as cucumbers!
We even stuck hand warmers in 'em
.so our butts wouldn't get cold.
Such a bulletproof plan must
be the work of a genius!
Heaven's vengeance is slow but sure!
My big bro came up with all of this himself.
Meticulous planning!
Ready to throw in the towel, Yasaburou?
What, already? Not on your life!
You stubborn jackass!
This is a plan that I've been
carefully putting together
in my brilliant mind since last year!
Our father's already turning that pitiful Yaichirou
over to Professor Yodogawa, you know?
Your tail-popping little brother is in a
.warehouse at the Fake Denki Bran factory,
but we slapped on a padlock as big as his head,
so he's not getting out any time soon.
We've also got your mother.
And you're here, crammed in a
.cage inside Ginkaku's stomach.
So where's that white flag, huh?
Who's gonna save you, and how?
Yajirou is still out there!
You're so stupid!
What do you think that
frog in a well can do?
The Shimogamo family is over.
All we have to do now is
.wait for the sun to go down.
Rest in peace.
May Yaichirou reach enlightenment
.right after he reaches the stew pot.
Rest in peace, rest in peace.
Damn you!
We may be stupid tanuki, but
there are lines we mustn't cross!
I won't be lectured by a dope like you.
As Yaichirou ascends to the stew pot,
so shall our father ascend to Nise-emon.
And then somewhere down
.the line, I'll inherit that title.
I'll be the clever, strong, young ray of hope
that will shoulder the future of all tanuki-kind!
Quite right!
Let's talk 'til the battery runs out.
Oh, Kaisei?
It's your big bro.
Hold tight 'til tonight, okay?
No, you can't now.
We're at Chikurintei teaching
Yasaburou a lesso—
Please don't talk like that.
You're wounding your big brother terribly.
Then I hope you drop dead
from those wounds!
C'mon, don't be like that.
You're an unmarried girl.
Right?
So take better care of yourself.
Then quit screwing aro—
I'm just looking out for her...
Your little sister doesn't have
any respect for either of you!
Who asked you?
Yeah, who?
Mother!
Mother, are you all right?
Are you feeling cold?
Mother!
I'm all right.
I'm not cold.
You didn't move a muscle, so I got worried.
I'm conserving energy.
If you try to struggle,
you'll just hurt your bottom.
The professor has arrived.
Once I turn you over, I'm going to Sensuiro.
Just leave the future of tanuki-kind to me.
Farewell, Yaichirou.
Please go gentle into that good stew.
Drop dead!
You think I'm gonna just
let you have your way?
I'm not gonna cheerfully dive
into your damned stewpot!
I've got your mother in
.the palm of my hand.
If you were to run, what do you
think would happen to her?
How low must you stoop
before you're satisfied?!
No matter what you say, your
.words will never reach me.
Mr. Ebisugawa.
You really have changed so much.
I think it's a dreadful shame.
I'm sure Sou would say the same.
If he knew his little brother had become such
.a horrible tanuki, he would be crushed.
"Sou," huh? He was fully aware of it.
Tanuki don't do such
.horrible things to each other.
This is something a tengu or a human
would do, Mr. Ebisugawa!
Mr. Ebisugawa,
I'm begging you, please
.stop bullying my children.
And yet, you call me “Ebisugawa."
But that's who you are.
Then what do the children you had
with my brother have to do with me?
If you get the chance to escape,
take it! Don't worry about me!
Mother!
Hello there.
So this is the one.
Indeed. Here he is, as promised.
What a magnificent li'l guy.
But you know, tonight
.we're gonna eat you up.
That's...
Yashirou!
Kaisei, get me outta here!
I can't. It's locked.
But I gotta hurry!
I know. Calm down.
There's a hidden hatch in the corner
.of the warehouse. Find that.
If you undo the latch from
.inside, you can get out.
Thanks!
Where are my brothers?
Yaichirou was taken
.by the Friday Fellows.
Kinkaku said on the phone earlier that he and
.Ginkaku were teaching Yasaburou a lesson.
And Mother? Is Mother here, too?
They got her as well, but
.she's not here at the factory.
My dad must have her
.locked up somewhere else.
Probably at the Fake Denki Bran shop.
How can they be so cruel?!
If we can save Yasaburou,
it'll all work out somehow.
This won't do, young mistress.
Please return to your room.
We'll be scolded by Master Soun!
Run.
Young mistress!
Go to Chikurintei!
If I go by myself, Kinkaku and Ginkaku
.will beat me to a pulp.
Come with me and tell them to stop!
If I go with you, all of these
.guys will be after us.
You're going alone!
Put your tail away and run for it!
We take pride in our position
as lords of the realm of idiocy.
As reflections of the idiot blood that
.flowed through the veins of our father,
his father, and generations
.of the Shimogamo family,
sometimes we trick humans,
sometimes we harass tengu,
and sometimes we wind up as stew.
These aren't things to be ashamed of,
but things of which we should be proud.
Know that we brothers hold our
.heads high with that pride,
even—and especially—when our
.eyes are brimming with tears.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
Being in a tiny cage makes you feel helpless,
but if anyone can get through this, it's our kids!
Right, Sou?
Next Time:
The False Eizan Electric Railway