1,200 years since Emperor Kammu
.settled on a location for his palace,
the city of Kyoto is now
.home to 1.5 million humans.
But wait just one moment.
"Humans are naught but an
accompaniment to our history."
"We were the ones who built this city
and the history surrounding it."
Or so say a few big-talking tanuki.
But wait just one moment.
"The skies above the palace have been
our territory since ancient times."
"Fear and respect us
who dwell in the heavens!"
Or so they arrogantly declare.
The tengu, that is.
Humans live in the city,
tanuki crawl the earth,
and tengu fly through the air.
Since the city's establishment,
humans, tanuki, and tengu have
.maintained a delicate balance.
That's what keeps the great wheel
.of this city turning round and round.
And watching that wheel spin
.is more fun than anything else.
I'm what you'd call a tanuki
but too proud to be a mere tanuki.
I admire tengu from afar,
and I love imitating humans.
That's why my daily life is busy enough
.to make your head spin.
In fact, there's no time
.to be bored at all.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode One
Goddess of the Noryoyuka
25th
Shimogamo Summer
Used Book
Fair
August
11th (Sun.)
- 16 (Fri.)
August
11th (Sun.)
- 16 (Fri.)
Big bro!
You're using that form again?
If you keep changing your
.appearance all the time,
you'll get another earful from Yaichirou.
Tanuki societal norms
.can eat dirt for all I care.
But hey, did you need something?
You're going to Master Akadama's place, right?
Mom said to use this.
Demachi shopping arcade
Masugata
She said she found it on the ground
.near the ticket counters at the station.
Don't tell me this is actually a leaf...
See you later.
Demachi shopping arcade
Masugata
What's with you?!
I'm gonna scream!
Pervert!
Quit messing around!
What are you even supposed to be?
Just looking at you is embarrassing.
Then don't look.
Don't get smart with me!
Just think of it as a favor to Master Akadama—
Shut up!
As it is, we're already branded
as the pitiful children who failed to inherit
.the blood of Shimogamo Souichirou.
Tenkura
Just behave yourself until
.the Nise-emon election.
Got it?
Your daughter?
My kid brother.
You airhead!
Did you really think such a cheap
trick would make me happy?
Master, I'm doing this because you
just sit here wasting away every day!
I'm trying to breathe some
fresh air into your stale lif—
I have no interest in seeing
your alluring figure!
Can't you comprehend the degree of artistry
achieved in this transformation?
Behold! This perfect swelling of the chest,
these slender hips, and these firm, pert—
Stop it. You're creeping me out.
Sounds like you're just mad at
.yourself for getting turned on.
There's no point taking it out on me, then.
I won't be bewitched by the likes of you.
Of all the impuden—
I bought you some food.
Please eat up.
Have you seen Benten lately?
Nope. Haven't seen her in a while.
She hasn't come by in a long time.
I wonder how she's doing,
wherever she is.
There's no way she'd want to
.come back to a place like this.
Is that so?
I'm afraid I still can't.
What's all this, then?
Greetings.
I am Yasaburou, third son
.of Shimogawa Souichirou.
I come bearing a gift for
.Nyoigatake Yakushibou.
My thanks.
You needn't have gone to such trouble.
What are you wearing?
Is it strange?
So, you're not human either, huh?
I guess that remains to be seen.
And you?
I am but Suzuki Satomi.
Don't tease. Just leave him be.
He's sly, that one.
A real nasty fellow.
He seems interesting!
Him, interesting?
He's a clever one, for sure.
He's capable, but he knows
.nothing of self-improvement.
He'll never amount to anything.
He seems quite fond of you.
Don't be absurd.
Would you like to see the flowers?
I've never seen such a splendid
.cherry blossom tree.
Hey.
Why don't you try doing
what I taught you?
Goodness. You know I can't yet.
Just give it a try.
I did it!
We soar through the heavens
.wherever we please.
That's what it means to be a tengu.
Disgusting.
This rubbish isn't remotely edible.
Let's get one from the
.same place next time.
You ate half of it, so it must
.have been good enough.
Is that any way to treat your master?
Whatever's cheap, as long
as it's "good enough"?
Today is Friday.
I daresay Benten is out
.with the Friday Fellows.
She must be living the good life.
What's so fun about hanging
out with those humans?
Benten's human too, you know.
Or had you forgotten?
She's always out partying late at night.
If I don't keep an eye on her,
she immediately strays from the right path.
She's hopeless.
Don't you think "strays from the right path"
is a strange way to put—
Quiet, you.
This place has better ventilation
.than you'd expect.
The only visitors I get these days
.are you and the bugs.
How depressing,
You could stand to be a little
.more appreciative, you know.
Oh? Who even asked you to come?
You were such a troublesome student.
I thought I'd finally gotten rid of you,
and now you expect me to be happy
when you nonchalantly drop by?
I'm fresh out of lectures!
Don't they say that the worse the student,
the more the teacher loves them?
Who would say that?
What nonsense.
Since you clearly have nothing better to do,
why don't you go find Benten,
and bring her here?
No way.
She won't come here, and there's
.no way I could convince her.
Besides, I can't stand Benten
.or the Friday Fellows.
Also, while you're out,
pick up a few cotton swabs.
When my ears itch,
my mood grows stormy.
There's a fresh package
.on the washstand already.
And besides, didn't I
just say I wasn't going?
Hold on a minute.
I think I'll write a letter.
Hmm, ben, ben, ten, ten...
You stubborn old tengu!
Pipe down, clean out your ears,
and get to bed!
Err, it'd be better to use her real name here...
What was it again?
Satomi
To Suzuki Satomi
Make sure you deliver this
.to Benten tonight.
Consider it your honorable duty.
I, Shimogamo Yasaburou,
accept this mission.
Very well!
This bow's just the thing
.for playing Cupid.
Demachi
shopping arcade
Chikurintei
Masugata Co-op
Seven Lucky Gods,
..Seven Lucky Gods...
Looks like this is the place.
But I don't see the target...
There she is!
Nyoigatake Yakushibou,
..of all people...
Who is he, some dumb high schooler
with his head in the clouds?
One shot!
Like a modern-day Nasu-no-Yoichi!
Wh-Who was that?
Are you okay?
That was close.
How awful!
Akegarasu
This is no place for a young la—
It's me.
Oh, you. Sheesh.
You're using that form again?
These powers were
.granted exclusively to us,
so what's wrong with
using them however I like?
If you're so good at shape-shifting,
you could at least turn into
.someone fit to be here.
One fake Denki Bran, please.
I'll have an aka and shochu.
What was all that about earlier?
You startled me.
Master told me to deliver
.his love letter, so I did.
You were all the way across the river,
so I took the liberty
.of sending it by arrow.
Are you looking for a fight?
I guess you could call it a token
.of our love-hate relationship.
Well, I enjoy making sure people
.looking for fights find them.
Please don't.
You ruined my precious fan,
and the Friday Fellows are in an uproar.
I said I wasn't feeling well
.and excused myself.
If I had really wanted to
.hit you, I would have.
I bet!
Thwack, right in the eye.
I apologize for the fan.
If you like, I can—
No thanks.
I'll be holding on to this.
Did you read the love letter?
Of course.
I suppose Master is
throwing another tantrum?
All he does is gripe and moan.
He's so grumpy right now.
Sounds about right.
Well, it's been ages
.since I last stopped by.
Couldn't you at least try
to show up once a week?
That's not really any
of your business, is it?
I have no intention of sticking
.my nose where it doesn't belong.
And even a dog would
.hesitate to sniff at this mess.
Funny hearing that from a "raccoon dog."
Do you have a problem with tanuki?
What can I say? I'm only human.
But if you're looking for a fight,
I'd be happy to find you one.
Of course not.
And then I'd catch you and make you
.into a stew for our year-end bash.
You're always so unreasonable.
It's a Friday Fellows custom.
At the end of each year,
we stew a tanuki and eat it.
Bartender, another round.
By the way,
what's with the cutesy look today?
I wanted to add a bit of spice
.to Master's daily life.
What do you think?
Pretty cute, right?
A beautiful display of
.master-disciple love.
You'd think, but he just
.yelled at me instead.
That selfish old tengu.
You should just leave him be.
I can't do that.
Is the Demonic Cedar
incident getting to you?
It doesn't bother you, I take it.
Why should it?
It's our fault Master
.can't fly anymore.
No, it's yours for transforming
.into the cedar tree.
That was why Master
.fell and hurt his back.
But you were the one who
came up with the plan!
So what?
This is why I can't stand humans.
You guys are way worse than tengu.
Sorry to say it,
but you don't understand
.Master's feelings one bit.
Minamiza.
That's where Master is.
I don't recall saying
.I was going to see him.
I-I'm sorry for my presum—
How you managed to stay
alive this long is beyond—
This is what makes life worth living.
Shijou Bridge
Master...
You sure have some nerve.
Wait a second.
I'm about to stand up, and if you don't mind,
I'd like to wrap my arms around you.
And then, if you don't mind, well, I think the two
.of us might take a leisurely mid-air stroll.
You shouldn't offer to do things
you clearly can't, Master.
Ah.
Oh, Master.
What are you doing here?
Oh, it's you.
Drunk, huh?
I may have had a few.
You're always screwing around.
Well, I'm going to call it a night.
W-Wait. I'm going home too,
so hail us a taxi.
Wouldn't it be faster to fly
there than to take a taxi?
No need to be spiteful.
This is pathetic.
My back hurts so much
.that I can't even move.
You idiot.
Didn't I tell you to
drop the maidenly look?
I probably look like a girl who came
.to pick up her grandfather.
You still haven't told me what
.you were doing over there.
Yes, well, sometimes I like
.to have a drink in Gion.
Is that so?
Soaring through the heavens whenever we please
is what it means to be a tengu, right?
There's nothing wrong with taking
.a taxi every now and then.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Even we tanuki get sick of
transforming sometimes.
Ha! Think you can lump me
together with you hairballs?
Once, I wrestled with the difficult question
.of how one should live as a tanuki.
I felt I understood how to
.live an interesting life,
but it was unclear what
.else I needed to do.
And then, somewhere along the
.line, as I idled away my time,
I realized that living an interesting life
.was all I needed to do.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
We're in trouble, big bro!
The God of Thunder is coming!
We have to hurry and let Mom know!
Back in
the Game
Next Time:
Mom and Raijin, God of Thunder