I can't even fly where I please now.
But this, too, shall pass.
One day, when my back stops hurting and I get back in shape,
I'll teach you all kinds of things.
If I put my mind to it,
I can move the very mountains
and topple buildings with naught but the power of the wind.
Yeah. I know you can.
What a pitiful state to be in.
But one day, everything under the heavens will once again be within my reach.
Master, you should really get some sleep.
I know, I know.
You should stay the night every now and then.
This is so sad.
It's been 1,200 years since Emperor Kammu settled on a location for his palace.
Humans live in the city,
tanuki crawl the earth,
and tengu fly the skies.
Since Kyoto's establishment,
humans, tanuki, and tengu
have maintained a delicate balance.
That's what keeps the great wheel of this city
turning round and round.
And watching that wheel spin
is more fun than anything else.
I'm what you'd call a tanuki
but too proud to be a mere tanuki.
I admire tengu from afar,
and I love imitating humans.
That's why my daily life is busy enough to make your head spin.
In fact, there's no time to be bored at all.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso hontou ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
is an idiotic reaction we all tend to
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Two
Mom and Raijin, God of Thunder
Looks like we ended up here again.
Come on in, Prince.
I see you're with a fine young lady today.
If I'd known you were coming,
I would've had those folk wait for you.
Who do you mean?
Some men from a TV station.
They wanted to interview the "Prince in Black" that the whole town's talking about.
Seems like I couldn't live
a quiet life even if I wanted to.
Wherever I go, towns buzz
with gossip in my wake.
Right. Then I'll give them
the go-ahead next time I see them.
Yashirou told me earlier that
you were out again yesterday—
You can talk normally, Mother.
No one's listening.
Did you go to meet with Benten again yesterday?
Yeah. Kinda.
Must you act so recklessly?
No need to worry.
That woman isn't right in the head.
You'll end up in her stew pot if you aren't careful.
Though tanuki have always been cursed with that fate...
The point is, humans are even more cunning, sly, and wicked than tengu or foxes.
It was a personal request from Master Akadama.
I had no choice.
His infatuations are always so unbefitting of his age.
People like him are
the most troublesome to deal with.
Ah, it's the Prince!
Well, if it isn't Andy!
The name's Ando.
Ready for our rematch?
I was born ready, Andy!
I'm going to visit Yajirou.
Are you?
Check if he's still alive for me, will you?
You could just go see him yourself, you know.
Have you ever been to his place?
I don't think he'd like that.
He's living there because
that's what he believes in,
but he'd be embarrassed
if I saw him like that.
The weather isn't good today,
so don't stay out too long, Mother.
Yasaburou, could you drop by the
Ebisugawa power plant on your way home?
I need you to pick up Yashirou.
Prince, which table should we use?
That one right there!
I'm sorry!
Shimogamo Yashirou,
how many times does that make?
You don't even have enough left
for it to come out of your pay.
You're in debt now. In the red!
But he bumped into me!
So now you're trying to pin
the blame on someone else?
Brother, I hope you'll show him
the error of his ways.
Meiwaku-senban!
Huh?
It means "great nuisance."
It's an old idiom you can use
to scold people who accuse others based on flimsy pretexts.
You're amazing, Brother.
That deserves a round of applause.
You can work on cleaning that up until we get back.
Yes, clean it all up.
This is why I can't stand those Shimogamo folk.
Indeed, neither can I.
Meiwaku-senban...
Well, this is just another part of my training.
The
Six
Paths
May
All
Rest
In
Peace
Brother?
Is that you, Yasaburou?
I can't see you.
Oh, whatever.
I'll eat my dinner here. It's a beef bowl.
That sounds delicious.
It's a real tragedy you got so used to that form
that you can't shape-shift anymore.
Have you been trying, at least?
I got pretty depressed the first night I realized I was stuck like this,
but I've resigned myself to it since then.
Besides, I never intended to go back to being a tanuki in the first place.
So I just got what I wanted, really.
Do many people still come here?
It's a lot quieter than it was last year.
Back when I was a tanuki,
even the youngest pups made fun of me,
but now so many people come to me
that I'd actually like some time to myself.
In fact, there's no time to be lonely at all.
You wanna bury me alive under your troubles?!
On one hand, most people probably feel pretty dumb talking into a well,
but on the other hand, having someone listen to their troubles makes them feel a little better.
I'm an almost-forgotten almost-tanuki almost-outcast by my kin.
I can never change my form again.
And I'm always here at the
bottom of the well, waiting.
I guess the convenience of those three factors is what makes my well so popular.
Do you give advice and stuff too?
Well, I don't really care about their problems.
Sometimes it's better if the listener stays detached, anyway.
I'm just a small frog in a big well.
I know nothing of the great wide world.
So, you don't care about Mother or the rest of us, either?
Give me a little credit.
I'm not rotten to the core.
But you see, I'm a frog now.
By the way, Yaichirou stopped by the other day.
He did? What for?
Something must've been troubling him.
He left without so much as a word, though.
Maybe he came to lecture you
but gave up and left?
Didn't seem that way to me.
He has his share of troubles too, you know.
Yeah, I know.
I pity him sometimes.
He's trying so hard to be a worthy successor to our great father, Shimogamo Souichirou,
but his brothers are a frog,
an idiot, and a kid.
We're utterly useless.
I can't argue with that, nor do I want to.
You know, Yasaburou...
You were always our father's favorite.
He even told Master Akadama
to pay special attention to you.
"He's the most like me," he said.
That's the first I've heard of it.
Do you remember his last words to you?
No.
I can't remember his last words,
no matter how much I try.
It still bothers me, even now.
Hey, where's Mother?
At the billiards saloon as always.
Why do you ask?
There's a big one coming.
I can feel it in my butt.
Raijin, God of Thunder,
has made his appearance.
Tokusei Bridge
I gotta pick up Yashirou.
Yashirou...
Redouble
Efforts
Shimogamo Yasaburou...
joins the fray!
Bro!
Redouble
Efforts
Well, well. Yasaburou's here too.
Redouble
Efforts
Higuchi
Ichiyou
Redouble
Efforts
Fake Denki Bran factory
Ebisugawa power plant
Yasaburou, your brother abandoned his work
and ran away from our factory.
That's not true!
It's just that our mother
can't stand thunder, so I had to—
We were kind enough to let you work for us
because you said you wanted training.
That's been quite a bit of trouble in itself.
We can't just let you leave your work half-finished.
Indeed. It's just as you say, Brother.
We can't.
When you can carry out the work that's given to you prop—
Drop dead!
...properly, only then will you be an adult.
I really don't want to poke my nose in your bus—
Drop dead!
...business, but I'm worried about
the future of the Shimogamo family.
The Shimogamos are all so undisciplined.
The second-eldest brother is a frog,
the third is an idiot, and the
youngest brother is who you see before you.
We Ebisugawas should try
and set a good example for them.
If we don't, the future of all
tanuki-kind could be in danger.
Higuchi
Ichiyou
As long as you're here, Brother,
we've got nothing to worry about.
You are like a beacon of hope to us.
Ginkaku...
"Higuchi Ichiyou" is a person's name,
not an idiom.
Higuchi
Ichiyou
You can't fool me.
You just don't know this idiom!
Brother, is he right?
No, don't listen to him.
Higuchi-ichiyou means "a fallen leaf,
caught in the rain gutter."
It's an old idiom that expresses the solemnity of autumn.
I read it once in a book.
You're so knowledgeable, Brother!
I knew it was something like that.
Now, let us take care of your brother.
We'll teach him an important lesson.
Our father has given us total authority.
It's our job to teach him about
the hardships of labor.
And we take our job very seriously.
So let us...
Not a chance.
You're as headstrong as always.
People like you who thumb their noses at tanuki societal norms are a constant thorn in my side.
And I've long thought that people like you are the least qualified to preach to me.
Believe me, we're qualified.
After all, we're great.
Bro, Mother's in trouble.
I know. We should retreat for now,
and come back with a perfectly crafted revenge plan
that'll really make them regret this.
Kinkaku! Ginkaku!
Yaichirou!
He bit my butt!
I'm flying! Someone catch me!
Damn you, tanuki tiger.
I mean, Shimogamo Yaichirou.
Not there!
Please don't bite me there!
What are you waiting for?! Get on!
Why did you just let those Ebisugawas walk all over you like that?!
Didn't you think for one moment
about defending the honor of our family?!
Remind me, what exactly is the "honor of our family"?
I can't quite recall.
I guess I shouldn't have expected someone
who only cares about having fun to understand.
You bring shame to our parents' names!
Our father must be spinning in his grave!
He wasn't the kind of tanuki who
cared about family honor and stuff.
But I told them to drop dead!
Where's the Prince in Black?
As soon as the thunder began,
the prince freaked out and split.
I dunno where to, because of all that commotion with the tanuki.
What commotion?
A tanuki showed up over there.
What happened to it?
Not sure. Guess it disappeared at some point.
Thank you very much.
Mother! This is what happens
when you poke balls with sticks!
We should send out word immediately
and get all the tanuki in the area to form a search party!
Isn't that overreacting a little?
Then what should we do?
You want her to get hit by a car again?!
Why would she run all the way to Gojo or Shijo?
We should split up and look here, around the bridge.
Right! Maybe that'd be best.
I'll take command!
Yaichirou, you go and search near Doshisha University!
Oh wait, I'm Yaichirou.
Okay! I'll search near Doshisha University!
Yasaburou, search the north bank of the Kamogawa!
Yashirou, you can check the other side of the bridge.
As for the south...
Yasaburou, you go that way!
I can't go north and south at the same time.
Then, Yajirou!
He's still in the well.
Also, he's a frog.
How damn useless can a tanuki get?!
Why do I have to put up with such
utterly useless brothers? Is this my fate?!
Calm down, Brother.
I'm most worried about you at this point.
For now, let's just split up and look for her.
Found her yet?
No.
Where could she have gone?
Mother!
Thank goodness.
Oh no!
Were you under that bridge all this time?
The Ebisugawa girl was with me.
She saved me when I was about to fall into the river.
Mother! Come on!
Is that you, Kaisei?
How long are you gonna stand there?
Hurry up and get out of here.
I just wanted to say thanks.
Don't waste your time.
Your mother's gonna catch a cold, stupid.
Thank you.
Say hi to your stupid brothers,
Kinkaku and Ginkaku, for me,
though they might not be home for a while.
Take care on the way home.
What took you so long?
I had to say thanks.
The world would be a better place without those damn Ebisugawas,
but that girl is different.
I'm so happy I have you.
Your father may have left us,
but you three are still here for me.
Our father was a great tanuki
who was known far and wide across the city.
Respected by many,
he united local tanuki society.
Sadly, a few years ago,
he didn't come back home.
He was eaten.
Made into stew.
When we got word of our father's death,
the three of us were in such shock that it was half a day before we could even start to cry.
Any one of us tanuki could wind up in a stew.
It's just a normal part of life.
You must all become wonderful tanuki
that wouldn't bat an eyelid at becoming stew!
But don't ever try that yourselves.
Please, promise me none of you will ever end up in a stew!
We grew up into great tanuki,
just like you asked, Mother,
but the three of us are utterly useless.
And the other one is a frog.
I don't mind what you become,
be it a frog or anything else.
It's enough for me to have you here in this world.
Not to mention, you really have become great tanuki.
Your mother knows.
Our mother doesn't think for one moment that
her sons are famous losers among tanuki society.
She still solidly believes that we are all
perfectly fit to succeed our great father.
Our father was great indeed,
but, you know, so is our mother.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what this place will be like in the future,
mirai no koko wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
Benten did what?!
How shameless! How inappropriate!
Don't look!
Next Time:
Yakushibou's Inner Parlor
None other than me may look!