Yaichirou was taken
by the Friday Fellows.
Kinkaku said on the phone earlier that he and
Ginkaku were teaching Yasaburou a lesson.
They got your mother as well,
but I don't know where she is.
Just leave him be.
It's not like he can do anything.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Twelve
The False Eizan Electric Railway
Big bro!
Yashirou? What are you doing here?
Raijin's going crazy out there.
Why aren't you with Mother?
They were all caught by
the Ebisugawas, big bro!
They were what?!
You're our last hope!
But you know,
I'm just a frog in a well.
What could I possibly do?
I've got an idea!
Look up this way and open your mouth!
Sheesh. I doubt this is the time
to be gulping down rainwater.
Just do it!
Big bro?
I'm back in the game!
Chikurintei Soba Noodles
Your brother was such a good tanuki.
It's a crying shame.
Drop the act!
It's not an act.
I can still feel the pain in
my butt where he bit me.
He almost turned my two
butt cheeks into four.
I must admit that he
was an earnest tanuki.
Then help him!
Not happening, sorry.
We have to follow our father's orders.
It's not easy being a tanu—
What's wrong, Ginkaku?
Why's the place shaking like this?
I don't know, big bro!
I think I'm moving really
fast for some reason!
It's making my butt twitch!
I'm scared!
Calm down, Ginkaku!
Your transformation is falling apart!
I'm too scared, big bro!
I can't hold on anymore!
No!
Don't do this to me!
What's going on?
Big bro... we're moving.
We're here for you, big bro!
Yashirou!
What on Earth—
Hey, Yasaburou!
How's the ride?
Yajirou?!
You two are gonna pay now!
Quit it, you perv!
That's our underwear you're manhandling!
You'll regret this! You really will!
Stop!
Well, this is cozy.
Yasaburou! Don't be so rough!
I should be the one saying that!
It's the Fuujin Raijin fan!
So you had this!
We just found it at Aoi Bridge!
It's not like we stole it!
Enough excuses!
This fan belongs to Master Akadama.
I'll be returning it to him.
Outta the way!
The Ei Train's honoring
you with its presence!
Yahoo!
What should I do, Yasaburou?
The head of our family,
my dear brother, is in mortal danger,
but I'm feeling strangely excited
as I tear nonstop through the streets!
I must have a few screws loose.
Don't worry! Just keep going!
There's no better fuel
than our idiot blood!
What's fun is good!
What happened?
Are you okay?
Those were our father's final words...
He told me that on his last night.
I never remembered it during
all that time I spent in the well,
but now it's finally
come back to me.
What's fun is good!
Are we gonna keep going this way?
What? I can't hear you!
Pontochou! We've gotta go to Pontochou!
Where is that, even?
Pedestrians only
No bicycles allowed
Can you turn left at Sanjou?
Not a chance.
I feel bad about this.
Shouldn't we stop the train
and continue running on foot?
Sorry, Yasaburou, but I can't do that.
Oh well.
Let's take Shijou Street for a bit.
Big bro, we're running around in circles!
Something's wrong! Slow down a bit!
Yasaburou, you're asking for
some pretty complicated stuff.
I'm trying, you know.
Is your idiot blood boiling
too hotly to be quelled?
Seems like it.
This is a fake Teramachi Street!
You?!
That's my phone!
How's this, Yasaburou?
Have you heard the saying
"out of the frying pan and into the fire"?
I called the Ebisugawa Elite Guard
and told them to intercept us.
That he did!
Damn you!
Just how many traps are you
gonna set up in one day?!
Have you learned your place now?
Yeah, have you?
Send them flying into the Kamo River!
Big bro, this is bad!
You've got that right.
My phone!
Big bro, we're gonna end up taking
a dive if we don't do something!
The Kamo River's cold in winter!
Be sure to warm up beforehand!
Gotcha, suckers!
We're back in the game!
Back in the game!
Hey, if we end up swimming
in the river, so will you guys!
That's right. We swim
together or sink together.
We're enemies in the
same boat. The same boat!
Hang on, Yashirou!
Chitose-ya
Minamiza
Teramachi
shopping street
Gotcha, suckers!
You guys are the real suckers!
It's the Flying Eizan
Electric Railway! False, too!
I'm glad we managed
to stay out of the drink.
Victory!
Ah, there!
Damn!
Ah, b-but you fell for it, Yasaburou.
Big bro?
What are you saying, big bro?!
We don't—
Y-You see, I actually considered
this possibility as well,
so there's a giant beckoning cat statue
under the river surface that—
Hey, wait! Wait, please!
Give us a break! Come on, time out!
No can do.
We're out of time.
You can drift all the way to
Osaka Bay for all I care!
I don't wanna end up
in the river again!
It's too cold!
We'll freeze to death! Seriously!
Hey, guys!
Did you know the Friday Fellows are
having their year-end bash over there?
Which would you rather:
the ice cold river or the burning hot stew—
It feels so weird to be flying.
Big bro!
The Friday Fellows are over there!
Can you land on the roof of that building?
You keep making all these
difficult requests, huh?
I've never tried to do
something like this before.
I'll try stirring up a bit of wind
with the Fuujin Raijin fan.
Be gentle, okay?
Easy does it. Easy...
My nose hurts.
Yashirou!
Hurry to Sensuiro and
disrupt the elders' meeting!
Okay.
Delay them as long as you can!
If all else fails,
just fan them a little!
Give it back to Master Akadama
when you're done.
He should be at Sensuiro too.
What about you?
I'll rescue Yaichirou
and catch up with you.
Hurry up!
If you hang around here
in that form, you'll get eaten!
Is that you, Yasaburou?
Dammit! Dammit!
You must think I'm a total idiot!
I've been playing human, getting all
involved in this election nonsense,
and yet look at me now!
How could someone as pathetic as me
shoulder the future of tanuki-kind?!
I might as well just get eaten here!
That's taking it a bit far, big bro.
Do you want Mother to cry again?
But I'm a failure of a tanuki.
That's just a reflection of our idiot blood.
And what's wrong with playing human?
You're just following in
our father's footsteps.
I guess...
Kick Ebisugawa's ass.
Avenge our father.
What?!
Soun was the one who handed
him over to the Friday Fellows.
It's me, big bro.
Yajirou?
Hurry up, bro!
I sent Yashirou ahead to Sensuiro,
so you can still make it.
Maybe we can make Mother happy too.
Oh right, Mother!
Did you save her too?
Not yet. I don't know where she is.
At the fake Denki Bran
store in Kamiyama.
We must hurry!
Calm down, bro!
I'll go.
Who's there?
Hurry! Leave Mother to me!
My, oh my.
Who are you?
I heard a loud sound and
came to see what had happened.
So you're just passing by?
Do you two know each other?
That's right, Juroujin.
He's a really fun guy.
Is that so?
Well, fun is always good.
What could have happened?
An earthquake? Or a tornado?
My tanuki escaped!
You! What in the world happened here?
Something huge crashed into us
from the direction of the Kamo River...
I have no idea what's going on anymore!
Just look!
The room's in shambles,
and my tanuki's gone!
Calm down, Hotei.
You have no idea how much trouble I went through
to get my hands on this tanuki!
And what good would
complaining to a bystander do?
Strange things just happen
every now and then in this city.
If you stress yourself over each one,
you'll go grey before your time.
Don't worry.
Just earlier I happened by the
fake Denki Bran shop in Kamiyama.
I saw another tanuki caged there.
My acquaintance wanted
to keep it for himself,
but I made arrangements
in case something like this happened.
Let's have that one for tonight's stew.
My, what a way to begin the evening.
We need a change of venue.
But where to, I wonder?
Oh? Will we get a chance to
ride your famous private train?
Sadly, it's currently under repair.
In terms of a replacement venue,
how about a nice restaurant
I know called Sensuiro?
I made a reservation for tonight
in case something like this happened.
E-E-Excuse me!
May I join you as well?
Hm? You?
I've always wanted to try eating tanuki.
But before that,
I'd love to see one alive,
since I've never had the chance
to see a real, live tanuki before.
I don't have a problem with it.
What do you say?
Well, if you're okay with it,
Benten, then so am I.
But since our guest is young and strong,
I'd appreciate a bit of help with some heavy lifting.
We have some fake Denki
Bran here in the kitchens.
I'd like it carried all
the way to Sensuiro.
It would be my pleasure!
It seems Yaichirou has lost his nerve
and abandoned us.
Let us forget about that coward.
Well, he is indeed absent.
Silence!
How dare you engage in such revelry
before the guest of honor has even arrived!
We are terribly sorry.
The room was struck by a sudden whirlwind.
Was it your doing, Master?
What are you insinuating?
Who do you think you're talking to?!
Well done.
I was gracious enough to come
all this way on your request, furballs!
It's time for me to take the stage.
Give the fan back to Master,
and have him stay out of this.
My humblest apologies
for keeping you waiting.
However, please allow me to explain
the extenuating circumstances.
Until recently, I had been held
captive by the Friday Fellows.
And how did I end up
in such mortal danger?
It was due to the scheming of none other than
Ebisugawa Soun, sitting right over there.
In order to win the title
of Nise-emon by force,
he not only captured every member of
the Shimogamo family, including myself,
but also handed me over to
the Friday Fellows in a cage.
His conduct ill befits a tanuki of his stature,
or indeed any tanuki at all.
Is this true?
It is entirely false.
How could a tanuki plot to make
one of its own kind into stew?
I am no tengu or human, and I
doubt there is any tanuki so cruel.
He is merely trying to excuse his own
lateness to this important meeting
while besmirching my
good name in the process.
What an underhanded tactic.
It is baseless slander.
I am not lying!
Then where is your proof?
He is telling the truth.
What an ugly mess that was.
Well, if it isn't Shimogamo Yajirou!
It's been a while since we last saw you.
You call this proof?
He's a fellow member
of the Shimogamo family!
They could easily have
conspired to frame me!
Your accusation is
fundamentally nonsensical!
If I'd handed you over to the Friday Fellows,
then how are you here
instead of in their stew pot?
Some people have entered the next room!
Tanuki are peace-loving creatures.
But what is "peace" to a tanuki?
It's being able to lie on the banks of the Kamo River
and idly gaze at the blue sky above.
Such peace should be easy to attain.
But then,
what is this maelstrom of events that has engulfed us?
Though it may be another
reflection of our idiot blood,
is this really what we
tanuki should strive for?
Sensuiro
Tanuki, humans, and tengu.
Will this tale end on the note of
"What's fun is good"?
Next Time:
The Ecstatic Family