You're saying I should hitch a ride on a boat with you hairballs and watch the Fire Festival?
Me?
You sure can be cheeky sometimes.
Mom's going to treat us to
.bowls of sushi and stuff.
Sushi made by a tanuki?
The hair will get stuck in my throat!
Anyway, if you feel like it, please come to
.Tadasu-no-Mori tomorrow evening at seven.
I might stop by if I remember. Who knows.
Wait, but don't count on me showing up.
He'll be there.
Imitating the various beauties of
.nature is nice and sophisticated,
but imitating humans is
.probably the most fun of all.
For some reason, it's always entertaining to
.mingle in at their events and enjoy ourselves.
"It's just another reflection of our idiot blood."
Dad used to say that with a smile
whenever my brothers or I caused mischief
or got into a mess of some kind.
The night of the Gozan Fire Festival
.is the highlight of summer.
We tanuki would get caught up in the humans'
.merriment and throw our own parties,
though this, too, is probably another
.reflection of our idiot blood.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso hontou ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
is an idiotic reaction we all tend to
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Four
The Daimonji Leisure Cruiser Battle
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
For Master
Akadama
Is Master really going to come?
Why don't you guys transform into a couple
of the Seven Lucky Gods yourselves?
Sorry, big bro. I can't do it.
Father would always transform
into Hotei. In his memory—
No tanuki likes transforming under someone
.else's orders. That's just how we are,
big bro.
Yo!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Father must be grieving in
.the afterlife by this point.
As long as we're all smiling,
I'm sure Father's smiling too.
You're just overthinking things.
See? Here he is.
Why isn't he coming over?
What a piece of work.
Huh? Oh, Master!
Well, if it isn't Yasaburou.
What a coincidence!
Are you taking a walk?
Indeed. It's such a nice, cool evening.
That's wonderful.
By the way, Master, are you aware
that tonight is the Gozan Fire Festival?
Oh, is it?
We were just planning to fly out in the inner parlor
.we borrowed from you and watch the fires.
If you're not too busy,
would you like to come with us?
It's not much, but we've
.prepared food and drink.
That's right. You did mention
something about that, didn't you?
I was just thinking I'd like to take a break.
I suppose it wouldn't hurt
.to join you for a little while.
Is that you, Yaichirou?
What's with that form?
I'm abandoning formality this
.evening, Master Yakushibou.
I like to have some fun now and then, too.
By the way, when is Ben—
Welcome, Master!
It's such a waste to give such
fine port to the teakettle!
For Master
Akadama
By the way, when is Ben—
Master, over there is Mount Nyoigatake.
Can you see Daimonji?
I can. I can indeed.
By the way, when is Benten coming?
For Master
Akadama
Teakettle energy
I believe she knows about the
.party today, so she might come.
Teakettle energy
It sure is great that you're giving that
blasted teakettle so much to drink!
But, Master,
if we don't let the teakettle drink too,
it'll get upset and we'll fall.
That might be a problem
for you fur-brains, but—
Now, now, Master.
Don't be so stubborn.
Don't get too close to
.the edge, or you'll fall.
I know!
The Ebisugawas are here.
Look, there's Soun.
Boom!
Those jerks! Do they
wanna go again this year?
Let's just call the Manpukumaru incident
.an unfortunate accident.
The fireworks they set off just
happened to start a fire. Okay?
Like hell it's okay!
The Nise-emon election is coming up.
Please don't cause trouble.
Besides, relatives shouldn't
.squabble amongst themselves.
Just dropping by.
Oh, it's you.
Well, hello to you too.
Were you expecting some
other tengu besides me?
Quiet, you.
Welcome. It's good to see you.
How dull. So this is what it's like
.to see it from down here.
You don't want to go back there?
At this point, I don't even care.
It would only spell more trouble.
The False Nyoigatake Incident
was really something, wasn't it?
Shimogamo Souichirou.
Now he was a real tanuki.
It sure has been a while since then.
I guess it was right around the time
.Shimogamo Yasaburou was born.
Back then I was a little fuzzball
.the size of a dandelion head.
Souichirou was already
Nise-emon by then, I think?
Yes, he was the leader who kept
.peace in Kyoto tanuki society.
Atago                Shrine
The start of the the whole incident
was a fight between Nyoigatake Yakushibou here
.and the Kurama tengu.
Those bumpkins were just trying to act cool.
After making a total mess of the mountain,
both Yakushibou and the Kurama tengu
got a good scolding from
.Atagoyama Taroubou.
The Kurama whipped up
.their tengu winds first.
You went and picked an unnecessary fight,
so it caused no end of trouble later on.
Later on?
Those Kurama tengu who were
the root of the quarrel
took turns creeping onto Mount Nyoigatake
and throwing "Give Yakushibou Hell" parties
.day in and day out, tormenting him.
And who was it who, unable to bear Yakushibou's
suffering, decided to stand up for him?
The tanuki known as
.Shimogamo Souichirou.
Finally, reduced to a state of pure,
instinctive fear, the Kurama tengu
prostrated themselves before
.Yakushibou and apologized.
In a feat of extraordinary magnificence,
the tanuki Souichirou transformed into
.Mount Nyoigatake itself for an entire week.
That's where the name
."False Nyoigatake Incident" comes from.
Father sure was amazing, wasn't he?
Teakettle energy
Amazingly foolish, yes.
You tanuki sure have it easy, lazily
.sleeping your days away like that.
I've gone and done something a little bit foolish.
It was awfully entertaining but a bit
.too much excitement for one like me.
You shouldn't push yourself too hard.
Take care.
Thank you.
Teakettle energy
Benten is on the boat over there...
Why?! Why does she spurn
the inner parlor I gave her
only to ride on a boat with
those damned hairballs?!
Why won't she stay by my side?
Don't ask me.
They always go overboard.
I'm going to give Uncle a piece of my mind.
Cease this racket!
Mother, please have some patience.
Dammit, they're always making fools of us!
We absolutely cannot retaliate!
There will be all kinds of troub—
Let's hit them right between the eyes!
Take careful aim!
Why are you all just standing around?!
Yashiro!
Right!
How can you do that?!
True forbearance is tolerating the intolerable!
Drop dead!
It's about time we got out of here.
Goodness! That would have killed me!
There we go. Now reel 'er in.
Enemies in the same boat!
There are only a handful of 'em! Pull it in
real close, and fire everything we've got!
Isn't there anything we can use?
There's nothing here at all!
Bring out Yaichirou, the heir!
That's not the heir at all!
.It's just the third son.
What happened to Yaichirou?
Is he curled up in a ball
at the back of the room?
"You will have heard of me by now,
and here I am, before your very eyes:"
The third son of Shimogamo
Souichirou, Yasaburou!
We know that already!
Hurry up and bring out
.that big brother of yours.
We gotta thank him for chewing on
.our rear ends the other day, too.
My butt nearly got an extra crack in it!
By the way, Yasaburou, how can you
persist in calling that a leisure cruiser?
That's not a boat, it's a tearoom!
Being flamboyant is indeed the tanuki way,
but moderation is important as well.
As a tanuki who upholds
the teachings of my father
and lives purely and justly in this era of peace and tranquility,
there is no doubt it is my duty
.to punish such out-of-line tanuki,
who ruined what should have
.been an enjoyable event.
Are you okay?
Who cares? Just go for it.
Well then, Uncle, I wish you well!
Farewell, Ebisugawa!
Isn't it grand to entrust yourself to the wind
and let yourself fall wherever it takes you?
Tanuki truly are irredeemable fools.
All right, let's take a photo to commemorate.
What a great family! I'm sure
.your father must be proud.
The fuel is...
Teakettle energy
...gone!
There's none here!
None here either!
How could this be?!
At this rate, instead of being Nise-emon,
I'll end up a fallen tanuki!
If we had just a little bit of port left...
Master, that's—
Why should I have to go
without my precious port
just for the sake of that blasted teakettle?!
I am your special guest this evening!
I'm greater than tanuki!
Greater than that teakettle!
I will drink as much as I want,
of whatever I want!
What is soaring freely through the sky in one's
dreams, if not a tengu's natural right?!
I am Nyoigatake Yakushibou!
Ow...
Is everyone okay?
I'm so sorry, but there was no way
.I could've carried all three of you.
I'm all right, but... where's Master?
Though... this really isn't good.
It's not here! Or here! Or here!
What isn't?
The Fujin Raijin fan!
I like you so much I could just eat you up.
If she actually liked me, that would be great.
But I really would not like to be eaten.
When all else fails, retreat!
Being the resourceful guy that
I am, I fled with such skill
that from the end of summer into autumn,
I became renowned throughout Kyoto
as "Yasaburou the Fugitive."
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what this place will be like in the future,
mirai no koko wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
I don't care whether you tell me
.the moon looks nice or not.
On nights when the moon is full,
my response will always be the same.
So, come with me!
Next Time:
The Friday Fellows