Obon season's closing in.
We'll have to get a leisure cruiser ready.
I hope Yaichirou's making the arrangements.
Did you hear anything about it?
No. He doesn't tell me anything.
I hope everything's going okay.
The Manpukumaru's gone too.
He should just ask for your help
instead of trying to take everything on himself.
I guess he just hates asking for help from his brothers.
You should try to get along with him better.
I love him, you know.
He's a great guy.
Must you be so sarcastic all the time?
The night of the Gozan Fire Festival is the highlight of summer.
Just as the humans celebrate on the ground,
we tanuki throw a wild party in the sky.
This irresistible habit has, without a doubt,
been passed down from generation to generation since the reign of Emperor Kammu.
Manpukumaru
My late father used to call this our "idiot blood."
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso hontou ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
is an idiotic reaction we all tend to
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Three
Yakushibou's Inner Parlor
Could you please help?
I need you to arrange a leisure cruiser.
I thought you'd decided to borrow one
from an acquaintance in Nara.
It crashed on the way here.
This time, it was Yaichirou's fault.
You're our last hope.
If you're willing to beg for it, I'll see what I can do.
Cut this out already!
Your brother is in trouble!
Why would you kick him when he's down like that?
The
Six
Paths
And that's how I ended up having to wipe my dear brother's hairy ass.
You seem pretty relaxed about the whole thing.
I've got an idea.
By the way, I heard what happened.
The other day, when the God of Thunder showed up,
Kaisei saved our mother, right?
Yeah.
How are things going with her?
Who cares?
Don't try to hide it.
You can tell this reliable brother of yours anything...
even though I'm just a frog.
Our engagement was just something Father decided on his own.
But don't you two still see each other
from time to time?
Yeah. I have no idea what she thinks about it all.
I've never even seen her face-to-face.
Aren't we innocent?
It's enough to make this green frog turn red.
Well, you can come up with
all the perverted fantasies you like,
but I'm sorry to say it's not the
star-crossed romance you're imagining.
For one thing, if I ended up
with in-laws like Uncle Ebisugawa
and the dynamic dumbass duo, Kikaku and Ginkaku,
my life would go straight to hell.
Yeah.
If that happened to me,
I'd just hide in a well and never come out.
You'd hide in a well either way.
It might be tough on you,
but this was Father's decision.
So what? Why should I care?
I'm sure Father had his reasons.
Or maybe he just wanted to get some fake Denki Bran on the sly.
That's ridiculous.
He might've loved his booze,
but he wouldn't do something like that.
Either way, Ebisugawa already broke off the engagement.
Get out!
Don't ever show your face here again!
Drop dead! Drop dead!
Drop dead!
I'd never seen Mother so furious.
She really liked Kaisei.
I wonder how long this feud will last.
If Father were still alive,
he'd have knocked Uncle down a peg or two.
That's true. Father could probably have handled this a bit better.
Well, just take it easy, okay?
Father would just laugh it off and move on.
Port
Wine
Look, big bro!
Port
Wine
I can charge cell phones now!
Charging
Who would you even call with that thing?
Mother, of course.
But aren't you always with her anyway?
No way!
What about when I go to the factory?
Kyoto
Gozan
Fire Festival
Will Master Akadama let us borrow his ship?
Well, he does hate to depend on vehicles.
But since he hurt his back,
he can hardly move around.
Why doesn't he use it himself?
Maybe he doesn't want to make it too obvious
that he's dealing with a tengu identity crisis.
Not to mention that.
The inner parlor needs to be fueled by booze to fly.
Why would he pour his wine into a vehicle
when he can drink it himself
and soar the skies freely in his dreams?
So you're Shimogamo Yasaburou?
You've grown into a splendid young man.
Such nonsense.
What use is splendor to a tanuki?
You're far too nice to them.
That's why those damn furballs cling to you like lice.
I heard you passed on the position of Mt. Iwaya's tengu to another.
Yeah.
I'm now running a used camera shop
in Osaka. It's like a hobby.
How could a tengu get so obsessed with cameras?
Yakushibou said he doesn't want any of these, so help yourselves.
Don't mind if we do.
And you even came here from Osaka by train.
Some tengu you are.
Hey, you try flying around in the middle of summer.
You'll cook your brains in an instant.
The Keihan trains are nice and cool.
Pathetic.
You really surprised me, you know.
When I got to Demachi,
I thought I'd fly to Nyoigatake to see you,
but I only found Kurama tengu there.
You're the last tengu I'd expect to move to the Demachi shopping district.
I just got fed up with it all,
so I let those folks take care of Nyoigatake.
Is it really okay for Yakushibou of Nyoigatake to do something like that?
I just can't bring myself to like those Kurama folk.
They're as pale as bean sprouts. It gives me the chills.
If you want to get rid of them,
I'll have my successor help you out.
I'll pass.
The Fire Festival's right around the corner.
It must be so sad not being able to perch atop your own mountain.
For the festival? It's much more fun
watching the fires from the town below.
You can't see anything from the mountain itself, you know.
There you are with your excuses.
Master, about the Fire Festival...
You're aware that my family traditionally goes out on a leisure cruiser every year, right?
I am.
You tanuki really are hopeless fools.
Would you let us borrow your inner parlor?
My inner parlor? What's that?
You know, Master.
That little tea-room-like thing.
It flies.
Ah, that?
Now that you mention it, where did I put that?
Oh, right!
I gave it to Benten!
Gimme a break!
Why do you give everything to her?
First you give her your Fuujin Raijin fan,
and now your parlor too?!
You can't fly!
You can't even cause the slightest breeze!
What kind of tengu—
Do you still not get it, you moron?!
I just want to make her smile!
Nishizaki Gen'emon
Rokkakudou
Cafe Tsutaya
Oike Av.
Sakaimachi
Yanagi-banba
Tomi-no-kouji
Fuyachou
Gokoumachi
Museum
Seichin-in
Ikebou-Chouhou
Temple Hall
That was all I had.
It sounds like you take care of Yakushibou a lot.
It's really good of you to do so.
I just got stuck with this duty because I was careless.
His other students don't even visit him anymore.
He might complain a lot,
but I'm sure he's grateful.
That's easy to say,
but it doesn't make me feel any better.
Sorry. I guess I should think
before opening my big mouth.
I'd say the biggest problem is how he
hurt his back when he fell from the Demonic Cedar.
Is that so?
If not for that, he could have
remained active, even at his age.
He wouldn't have let those Kuramas get so uppity either.
By the way,
I heard that this human girl, Benten,
is on good terms with the Kurama too.
That's right.
My gut tells me she might have been involved in the Demonic Cedar incident too.
If at least your father was still around,
why, things would be very different around here.
You think so?
The Nyoigatake incident...
Now that was certainly something.
Transforming into a mountain like that was no mean feat.
The Kurama didn't even know what hit them.
Never before or since then has a tanuki gotten the better of tengu.
Dad sure was awesome, huh, big bro?
For a tanuki, he was a great one indeed.
Will you take Yakushibou on your cruise?
I'd love to tag along.
We'll make the necessary arrangements.
Take care, then.
And make sure you don't let
your guard down around Benten.
You can go home now if you want.
I'll come too!
Mother's always saying I should try to be more brave.
Let's be off, then.
Nishizaki Gen'emon
Nishizaki
Gen'emon
Mixed Udon    Stir-fried Udon
Tempura Udon   Egg Udon   Kitsune Udon
Curry Rice    Fried Tofu Sushi    Tempura Don   Oyako Don   Tamago Don   Katsu Don                            Chilled Noodles
Is Benten at the clock tower?
Indeed she is.
The water has been quite rough as of late,
but it's a lovely day today.
You can't do it, huh?
Sorry, big bro.
I'm so scared that I can't stay transformed.
It's not like she eats nothing but tanuki stew, you know.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of everything.
Peer   less
Aww, you're so cute.
You must be his little brother.
Thank you.
You two must be hot in those clothes.
Couldn't you transform into something more breezy?
What's with that shirt anyway?
It's not like you to brag so tastelessly.
I got it from the Ebisugawa tanuki.
You mean Kinkaku and Ginkaku?
Yes.
They brought me some fake Denki Bran as well.
So? What brings you here today?
I would like to borrow the inner parlor.
This is no laughing matter.
You know, Kinkaku and Ginkaku came by yesterday,
saying you were bound to show up here asking that very thing.
They cautioned me not to get involved in feuds between tanuki
and left this lame shirt and the fake Denki Bran here.
That's a pretty pathetic attempt at bribery.
Indeed.
I can take any of these things whenever I want.
Their schemes are as foolish as they themselves are.
Do you want the inner parlor?
I don't think I've ever wanted anything more.
I wonder what I should do, then.
If I were to let you borrow it, what would be in it for me?
What are you doing today?
Waiting for a whale.
There are whales here?
One shows up every now and then.
Over there.
When I woke up this morning,
I felt like pulling on a whale's tail.
That's why I'm here.
But naturally, now that I'm waiting for one,
there's not a whale in sight.
That's the way of the world.
Big bro!
What is that?
Take a look.
I asked Gen'eimon to fix the fan.
You tore a hole in it when you decided to play Nasu-no-Yoichi.
Did you forget?
It's not my style to dwell on the past.
You're such a bad tanuki.
You should reflect on your actions.
I've made up my mind.
Since you're the one asking, I'll let you use the parlor.
Thank you very much.
But goodness me,
what if you ruin it like you did my fan?
You're such an unruly boy.
I'll take good care of it.
Oh, I know!
If you manage to wreck the parlor,
I'll have you perform for the Friday Fellows!
They had just been asking me to get someone in.
And if your performance isn't entertaining enough,
we'll just make a stew out of you instead.
I don't think I'd taste very good.
I don't mind.
I like you so much I could just eat you up.
Look at that!
Port
Wine
Pay attention.
This is how you make it fly.
Even after our father's untimely departure to the next world,
our mother and we, her tanuki sons,
still take a leisure cruise
on the night of the festival each year.
The thought of celebrating our
legendary Shimogamo ancestors
never even crosses our minds.
Sometimes we remember our father, of course,
but mostly we just set the summer sky alight
with our wild celebrations.
That's just how we tanuki are.
Just another reflection of our idiot blood.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what this place will be like in the future,
mirai no koko wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
It's the Gozan Fire Festival!
The Daimonji, huh?
We can take on a thousand foes!
Enemies in the same boat!
Next Time:
The Daimonji Leisure Cruiser Battle