Until recently, I had been held captive by the Friday Fellows.
It was due to the scheming of none other than Ebisugawa Soun, sitting right over there.
How could a tanuki plot to make one of its own kind into stew?
I am no tengu or human,
and I doubt there is any tanuki so cruel.
He is telling the truth.
He's a fellow member of the Shimogamo family!
Some people have entered the next room!
It's been 1,200 years since Emperor Kammu settled on a location for his palace.
Humans live in the city, tanuki crawl the earth,
and tengu fly the skies.
Since Kyoto's establishment,
humans, tanuki, and tengu have maintained a delicate balance.
That's what keeps the great wheel
of this city turning round and round.
And watching that wheel spin
is more fun than anything else.
I'm what you'd call a tanuki
but too proud to be a mere tanuki.
I admire tengu from afar,
and I love imitating humans.
That's why my daily life is busy enough to make your head spin.
Sensuiro
In fact, there's no time to be bored at all.
Episode Thirteen
The Ecstatic Family
It's a bit cramped compared to Chitose-ya.
Is this really the biggest room you had for seven?
I am terribly sorry.
Can't we use the next room?
There are a great number of guests over there.
Really? I don't hear a sound.
It's as though it were empty.
Indeed, they are quite quiet.
So, why don't you let me know what you're plotting?
I'm afraid I cannot.
I wouldn't mind tagging along, as long as it's fun.
Just don't get too rough.
Your delivery has arrived.
That's a rather beautiful tanuki.
Unusually so. What do you think, Daikoku?
This is a fine tanuki, wouldn't you say, Hotei?
What's wrong, Hotei?
We've had enough of your
absurd fabrications, Yaichirou!
It's pathetic.
I'm amazed.
I'm amazed you have the guts to lie like that, you slimeball!
Is that any way to talk to your uncle?
Learn some manners!
Uncle, my ass! You put Father into a stew pot!
He cooked Souichirou?
Hold on.
Calm down.
That is just another one of his baseless accusations.
None of his lies have worked so far,
so he appears to have dragged in this
sad story about his father out of desperation.
But of course, he has no proof of that story either.
Who can corroborate this wild tale?
Kaisei is our witness! Your daughter!
She's at precisely the age
where young girls often dream up such tragedies.
Aren't you embarrassed to have taken my daughter's fantasies seriously?
Do you really believe I sent Souichirou to the stew pot?
How long are you gonna keep playing dumb?
Well, you guys keep spouting
the most outrageous nonsense.
What tanuki would believe such a horrible story?
How about it?
Do you think I would do such a thing?
Indeed, it is still not clear how Souichirou ended up in the Friday Fellows' stew.
It's strange that a tanuki so great
could so easily fall into those humans' hands.
However, it would be a different story
if he had been inebriated.
Rumor has it
that on the night Souichirou was captured by the Friday Fellows,
there was another tanuki
drinking with him until the end, was there not?
I daresay that's the reason Souichirou was captured by those hateful humans.
But even now,
the concerned party has not stepped forward.
Though he was responsible for the leader of tanuki society ending up in a stew,
he remains tight-lipped about his own involvement.
I heard a rumor that, ashamed of his base actions,
he now spends his days
hiding in the well of some temple.
I won't let you get away with this!
I don't care if you're my uncle or anyone else!
I'll crush you into paste myself!
If you think you can bite me, give it your best shot!
You'll just be chewing up your own chances of ever becoming Nise-emon!
Sounds like they're getting
down to business next door.
Calm down, Yaichirou! Order! Order!
Are they holding some sporting event in there?
A tiger!
Good heavens, it's a tiger!
B-Benten!
My, it certainly is rowdy tonight.
Oh, Ebisugawa?
What? Why do you have that tanuki?!
I thought I'd left her in the storeroom.
It's a long story, but in short, we'll be borrowing her.
Borrowing her for what?
To cook her in a stew.
That's not borrowing!
I clearly stated that this one was not to be cooked!
That's my tanuki!
And what if she is "your" tanuki?
You can cook anyone else but her!
I won't allow this!
I won't provide you with any more Fake Denki Bran!
Then all I have to do is take it by force.
Isn't that right, Benten?
It is indeed.
This is it!
This is why humans are so despicable!
What's the matter, Hotei?
This is the one!
The one I took care of!
I won't let you have her!
This is your fault for letting the first one get away.
That's why I went to such great pains to get her!
Are you suggesting we steer clear of tanuki this year?
What of the Friday Fellows tradition?
You'll be kicked out of the club, Hotei!
I don't care where you kick me!
So these are your true colors, are they?
I was the wrong person for the job after all.
This is defeat. Ideological defeat.
But that's fine!
I mean, why do we still eat tanuki stew for kicks in these enlightened times?
To hell with the Friday Fellows!
To hell with tradition!
You've eaten a ton of them too, you know.
I thought you said, "To eat is to love." What happened to your pet theory?
Indeed, to eat is to love.
But to refrain from eating is also love!
You're just making it up as you go along, aren't you? And with such conviction!
This is sophistry! Pure sophistry!
I'm fine with sophistry! Your opinion is irrelevant!
I've decided on a complete about-face!
Feel free to about-face all you like,
but the tanuki stays here.
Th-The Friday Fellows!
What a marvelous sight!
We can make all the stew we can eat.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Shut it!
Shut up!
Good grief, what a mess.
Are you injured?
Master, I beg of you, please quell your rage!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
Congratulations
to     the
new
Nise-emon!
How long—
How long do you intend to keep me waiting?!
If you continue with this tomfoolery, I'll blow you all away!
Nyoigatake Yakushibou!
We've caught their infidelity red-handed!
Wh-What are you saying?!
This is a misunderstanding!
A complete misunderstanding!
You!
For human scum like you to lay his hands on Benten is completely inexcusable.
But it's not just you!
Every last schmuck here is guilty!
Hear me now! Behold this tengu!
Don't you understand? I despise the lot of you!
For I am a tengu!
All of you, without exception, need to learn your place!
Minamiza
Sensuiro
Here he comes!
Master, why don't we call it a night
and show some mercy?
He still has some fight in him, I see.
Yasaburou, do something!
Can't you see I'm trying?
Big bro, he's taking a break.
Here's our chance!
We're gonna die!
He's such a hooligan, isn't he?
Nice work.
I'll take it from here.
Master.
Benten?
I think everyone understands
the terror you represent well enough now.
How about we leave it at that?
But...
I bought some cotton swabs.
I'll clean your ears for you
with your head in my lap, just like old times.
Master, could you do me a favor and let them be?
Let's go home.
Are you lot up to no good again?
You'd better get yourselves back to the forest.
Hairballs who get cocky
and stay out late wind up eaten!
By the way, Yajirou,
how long do you plan on staying a frog?
Isn't it a bother?
Well, I haven't quite got the knack back yet.
For the time being, I'll just have to remain as a frog.
Who'll be Nise-emon?
Well, I committed assault in front of the elders.
But so many of Soun's misdeeds were exposed that there's no way it'll be him either.
I guess Yasaka will continue on as deputy for a while in that Hawaiian shirt of his.
Oh right, Mother!
Right, right. I told her to go
to Akegarasu ahead of us, but...
I wonder if she made it okay.
Please charge
Isn't the battery dead?
No problem!
I just arrived at Akegarasu.
You're all okay, right?
Yup, we're all here. I'll put on Yasaburou.
Hello, Mother. I'm still kicking.
Yasaburou? You did a great job.
Oh, it was nothing. Well, here's Yaichirou.
Mother, today was a complete mess.
I can't apologize enough.
On top of that, I'm sorry to say it,
but I doubt I'll become Nise-emon.
That's fine.
As long as you're still with us, you'll get another chance.
I'm sorry.
I'll give the phone to Yajirou.
Calling
Hold
End
Calling
Hold
End
Yajirou? Why aren't you saying anything?
Are you all right?
It's been a long time, Mother.
I'm sorry I haven't been in touch for so long.
Please forgive me.
It's okay.
Calling
Hold
End
I understand how you feel.
So no more crying, okay?
Well, it's certainly been quite the night.
We're all waiting for you to get here!
Shall we kick things off together with a belly strike?
Those always upset my stomach, though.
Yasaburou.
Big bro!
Well then!
This sure is some crowd.
Wouldn't want to get crushed, would we?
I have the most to worry about.
After all, I'm just a frog.
Please don't drop me, Yasaburou.
I'll get trampled.
Oh, hello.
Happy new year.
Hello, and a happy new year to you as well.
Might I inquire after your health?
I'm doing just fine.
But you know, no matter
how many times I go over it in my head,
I have no idea what happened that night.
I went through hell, though.
They expelled me from the Friday Fellows.
But if you're doing well,
isn't that more than enough?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Come visit me at my office again sometime!
Hey, take a look at that.
Kurama tengu?
There's no telling how many of these people are actually tengu or tanuki.
Well, in this day and age, even a frog can visit a shrine for New Year's.
Even tengu make New Year's wishes, huh?
And just what's wrong with a tengu making a New Year's wish?
Well, if it isn't Nyoigatake Yakushibou!
Happy new year!
Indeed.
Are you on your way to the shrine?
That was the plan, but I can't be bothered anymore.
Oh, come now. Let's visit the shrine.
Right, Master? It's only once a year.
I guess you're right.
It's not so bad every now and then.
Yaichirou.
Yes?
You should try to just take things as they come once in a while.
U-Understood.
Yajirou.
For starters, you should quit being a frog.
Okay.
Yashirou.
For now, you should hurry up and grow!
Got it!
Well, there's no reason for us
to keep standing around here.
Shall we go?
Hey there, Kinkaku, Ginkaku.
Happy new year.
Getting a head start on your idiocy this year, I see.
You got us pretty good that night, Yasaburou.
We caught a horrible cold,
and we've been bedridden until yesterday!
I thought I was gonna die.
They say that stupidity keeps the common cold away,
but I guess idiocy is a whole other story.
What'd you say?!
Hey!
Can my idiot brothers not even
give a proper New Year's greeting?
"Idiot"?
You too?
Kaisei?
Don't worry. Just go.
Kaisei!
I've never seen her, so I wouldn't know who to look for anyway...
Did Uncle come back?
No. He said he was going
to a hot spring, and that was it.
He might never come back.
Why don't you give this whole thing a rest and let me see you?
Not if I see you first!
I have so many things to wish for this year.
That's just because you're greedy.
Am I really that greedy?
If you don't narrow down your goals,
even wishes that could come true won't.
Hmm, in that case...
I'll wish to meet the one I'm destined for.
There you go, acting like a cute little girl again.
So what will you wish for, Yasaburou?
Huh. I thought about it,
but I don't have any wishes in particular.
As long as we're all living, and as long as
we're all having fun, that should do it, right?
We're tanuki.
If someone were to ask me how tanuki
should live their lives, this is how I would answer:
"The tanuki crawling the streets of Kyoto should abandon all lofty ambitions."
"There's nothing else we have to do besides lead an interesting life."
Yasaburou?
There's nothing in particular I need to ask for.
Just a little glory for my family and our friends.
You just have to make
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
this dull world more interesting
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
Some people love to claim
that something is boring
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
That habit is the most boring thing of all
sore koso hontou ni tsumaranai
It's easy to complain about stuff
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
but it doesn't do any good at all
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
That sort of useless waste of time
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
runs in our idiot blood
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
Just party on and on,
and the more you do
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
the more awesome will be your days
nanto subarashiki hibi
You just have to make
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
this dull world more interesting
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
The things you find
for yourself in this world
jibun de mitsukerya
quickly turn it into a little paradise
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
Before you know it,
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
you live a life of pure ecstasy
uchouten jinsei da
Thank you so much
for  watching!
Deep
gratitude!