Benten is neither tengu nor tanuki, but simply a human.
In her younger days, Benten aimlessly walked the shores of Lake Biwako
bearing the human name of Suzuki Satomi—
one that befit the cute country girl she was.
Master Akadama, who happened to be
.at Lake Biwako on a New Year's visit,
took the girl home with him.
He took great care in
.giving her a tengu education,
and she enthusiastically raced up
.the ladder from human to tengu.
Once she reached the top,
she kicked her kidnapper-turned-master to
.the curb with one flash of her gorgeous legs.
Oh, Professor.
You came after us, huh?
The current Benten bears little
.resemblance to her former self.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Six
Taking in Fall Colors
You're one active lady, Benten.
And you're pretty nimble
.yourself. For your age.
Now, just a little further.
Sheesh. You're like a tengu.
I am but Suzuki Satomi.
She bears little resemblance
.to her former self.
Hey.
I was thinking about the day I first met you.
Oh, please.
Feel free to forget it.
I would never!
It was at one of our year-end parties.
I heard the tanuki cage was in the inner parlor,
so I went to check on it.
And you were lying next to it, sleeping peacefully.
You had piled up some
floor cushions to make a pillow
and were curled up like a child.
Was I really?
I thought, "Who could that be?"
I didn't know the new Friday Fellow
.was a young lady.
The tanuki in the cage was
.a splendid one, and so dignified.
He didn't have the slightest hint of fear.
Anyway, the tanuki and I
were staring at each other
when you woke up, came over to me,
and started talking to him.
Are you Hotei?
I'll be meeting you officially this evening.
Oh, I see!
You're the one Juroujin was talking about.
I didn't know he meant a girl.
I'm Benten.
He looks like he's sleeping well.
I feel bad that you're going to be eaten,
but I'm still going to eat you up.
That all happened so long ago that I'd forgotten.
That's when I fell for you.
I fell in love.
I could understand just how you felt,
and I thought, "Now here's a
girl after my own heart!"
That's your own misunderstanding.
I don't remember saying anything like that.
Really? I could've sworn you did.
Benten?
What are you doing?
Stay back, or I'll eat you.
I'm serious.
I don't mean to presume,
but is something the matter?
The moon is pretty,
but I feel sad all the same.
I want to take a bath.
I'm going home.
Just thinking about yourself, huh?
Are you just gonna leave us on the roof?
Yasaburou,
please make sure the professor
.gets home safe and sound.
Where did Benten go?
I'm feeling hungry.
How about you?
Um...
Have a few of these with me.
I'm pretty good at making rice balls.
Tasty, right?
You know, I've always liked rice balls.
They're good cold,
they're good grilled,
and you can eat them
.anytime, anywhere.
We call it "Benten's Early Exit."
She always disappears without warning partway through.
You just can't make head or tail of her.
You're a student, right?
How do you know her?
We both studied under the same master.
Master? Master of what?
Oh, is that where you learned
your act from the dinner party?
Something like that.
So Benten can perform as well?
Yeah. I'm nowhere even close to her level.
She's even surpassed our master.
There's no one in Kyoto who can match her.
At any rate, she sure is an eccentric beauty.
You're a bit of a strange one
.yourself, Professor.
I'm not that strange.
Your passion for eating is no joke.
I guess you're right there.
I've eaten so many things,
some of it for research.
You eat tanuki too.
Not just tanuki!
I've traveled all over the world eating everything I can, be it bug, plant, beast, or fish.
Are they tasty?
If you're going to eat something,
you have to eat it like it's tasty.
That's our duty as people who eat.
To tell the truth, though,
eating a life should be
.delicious all on its own.
That's the way it's gotta be.
That's the state of mind I'm aiming for,
and that's why I eat so many things.
Well, nothing poisonous, of course.
I wouldn't live to tell the tale.
I'm just a frog in a well, though.
If you open your eyes to the world,
you'll find humans eat
.anything and everything.
It's amazing how much of a
.passion for eating we have.
Whenever I think of it,
I'm filled with admiration.
To eat is to love.
We eat so many things!
And we love so many things!
Hooray for humanity!
That's how you start to feel.
I don't think the ones being eaten
.are quite so exuberant about it.
Oh, I'm sure they must hate it, of course.
I wouldn't like to have a bear or
.a wolf bite my head off either.
No one would.
But if they're going to be eaten anyway,
I'd like to be the one to eat them.
I feel bad for them, but I like tanuki
.so much I want to eat them up.
Not just tanuki, either.
We'll eat all the cute li'l critters out there.
It's a shame, but they're just so delicious.
A fine contradiction, wouldn't you say?
Just like love!
I'm not entirely sure,
but it's probably love, right?
Yeah, must be.
Humans don't have to worry about being eaten,
so they can afford to be nonchalant about it.
You're firmly on the side of the eaten, I see.
But that's a good point.
You're right that we humans don't
.have to worry about being eaten.
No natural enemies.
We die, get burned, turn to ashes,
get eaten by microbes,
and return to dust. That's about it.
But thinking about it that way makes me sad.
It's a bit pitiful just being
eaten by microbes, right?
If I'm gonna die one day anyway—
well, as long as it doesn't hurt too much—
I'd rather be eaten by a tanuki.
I'd rather be a tanuki's dinner
.than die all wrinkly in a hospital.
Dying in a hospital doesn't nourish anyone.
That's so sad.
I'd much rather fill a tanuki's stomach, at least.
I think any tanuki who ate you would be
.biting off more than he could chew.
Guess so.
Not to mention, I bet I would taste horrible.
What a pity.
Isn't it sad that someone would just
assume that they'd taste bad to a tanuki?
I've never heard of any human
.getting sad about something like that.
There was a tanuki who said something like that to me back then, too.
I can remember it even now.
Kyoto Newspaper HQ
Town Welfare Hall
Dotemachi St.
It was the night Benten first
.joined the Friday Fellows.
You're really something, huh?
You must have really made a name
.for yourself among tanuki-kind.
This evening, we'll be eating you.
You're probably a bit reluctant,
but we always have tanuki stew
.at our year-end party.
Being born as a tanuki means there may come
.a time when you'll be eaten by humans.
This may be selfish of me,
but I'm happy I get to eat you.
It gives meaning to the fact that we met.
How can you be so calm?
Aren't you anxious?
I've done everything I wanted to do.
My children have grown up.
The youngest is still small,
but he has his brothers,
so I suppose all that remains is for them to
.help each other out and live decent lives.
I sowed my seeds and nurtured them, to an extent.
I've fulfilled my role as a tanuki.
The rest of my days are a blessing,
or in other words, a lucky break.
Therefore, at this point,
I don't mind being eaten by you at all.
If you want to eat me, you should.
This is kind of weird.
I get the feeling you're talking,
but it must be my imagination.
I really am talking.
Well, I'll be!
You shouldn't surprise people like that.
I just figured it wouldn't matter
.if I said something to you.
Call it the last trick of my life.
A reflection of my idiot blood.
And then we talked for a bit
about where we lived, what kinds of
.things we ate, that kind of stuff.
But there was one thing.
The tanuki was worried he might taste bad.
Don't worry.
I'll be certain to make a delicious stew out of you.
Please see it through from beginning to end.
I would feel terrible if I ruined
.an otherwise tasty stew.
You're a magnificent tanuki,
so I'm sure you'll taste great.
Don't worry.
As a last request, mind telling me your name?
I'm Yodogawa Choutarou.
Just as I thought. It is you.
Oh?
You know me?
You helped out one of my family members.
Would you tell me your name in return?
I'm the Nise-emon, Shimogamo Souichirou.
Who's there?
Huh?
Wasn't he just...
You probably find it hard to believe
a weird story like that, right?
I think I can manage.
I'm glad to hear it.
I told you because I felt this
.connection between us.
Uh, we just met for the first time tonight.
But I feel like we're destined
.to really know each other.
A chance meeting is a meeting
.brought about by fate, after all.
Let's drink to this evening's encounter! A toast!
Is it okay for a supposed
college professor like you
to be drinking in a place like this
in the middle of the night?
Don't you worry about that.
It's just a reflection of my idiot blood!
Hey, you!
What do you know? A ladder!
We can get down this way.
Phew. That was lucky.
Kaisei, is that you?
Go home and get some sleep, you blockhead.
Next time, you're on your own.
Hey, Teramachi Street is this way, right?
Thanks.
The
Six
Paths
It's me, big bro.
Oh geez, Yasaburou?
So you're still alive, then. I was worried.
Surprisingly enough, yeah.
You gonna abandon the world and become a frog too?
If two of her sons ended up
.as frogs, Mother would cry.
I'm just gonna crash for the night.
That's fine.
I thought you might have been
.worrying about something.
You've had trouble talking about things
.that bother you ever since you were little.
I'll have you know I never worry.
My life is far too interesting
.and amusing for that.
Are you drunk?
Yep.
Come visit me at my office sometime.
Kyoto University
Yodogawa Choutarou
Well then, be seeing you.
He said it was a "reflection"
of his "idiot blood."
This university professor, Yodogawa,
said the same thing Father used to.
Even if we owe him for saving Mother,
by rights, we should hate him as an enemy.
But for some reason,
I think of him affectionately,
as strange as that may be.
I find it utterly bizarre.
Why don't I hate him?
To be honest, I like him a lot.
And why do I have such a crush on Benten,
when she ate Father in a stew?
It's obviously another
.reflection of our idiot blood.
Besides, we're tanuki.
We just get eaten every now and then.
It's not wrong for a human to eat a tanuki.
I admire you, big bro.
You're enlightened.
Not at all.
To tell the truth,
I just act like I know it all.
I'm just a frog in a well, after all.
You always use that
convenient excuse, huh?
Not at all. I still have a lot to learn.
Even now, I tear up when I think of Father.
Is someone here to talk to you
about their troubles?
No. That's Benten.
What?
She never says anything.
She just sits there like that,
crying all alone.
The well water is gonna get all salty.
I wonder why she cries.
I wonder what she's sad about.
Could it be because the moon's so pretty?
Children don't have to cry
.for a reason. They just do.
Back then, in the heart of the city,
my big brother Yaichirou
and my uncle Ebisugawa Soun
were starting up the unsightly battle
.over who would be the next Nise-emon.
But as for me,
I knew nothing of the outside world.
I was just a frog in a well.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what this place will be like in the future,
mirai no koko wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
Argh, none of these schmucks have any manners!
Like that! Don't wear a towel in the bathtub!
Next Time:
Bathhouse Rules