In Kyoto, there is a secret society that has existed since the Taishou era.
There are always seven seats,
and the humans who occupy them each take on the name of one of the Seven Lucky Gods.
They are our natural enemies, those who
.paralyze children with fear: the Friday Fellows.
And why are they our
natural enemies, you ask?
Because they stew and eat a tanuki
.at their year-end bash.
Though our daily life may be tranquil,
their stew is a regularly scheduled
.nightmare we have once a year.
Even our father, the great
.Shimogamo Souichirou,
met his end all too soon
.in the Friday Fellows' stew.
Thus we are reminded
that the ones on top of the
.food chain are the humans.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso hontou ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
is an idiotic reaction we all tend to
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Five
The Friday Fellows
So, you're still alive.
Wouldn't be here otherwise.
Still on the run, by the looks of it?
I'm helping out at a secondhand camera
.shop in Osaka's Nipponbashi district.
Are you going to be okay?
Benten likes to hang out in Osaka too.
Just don't tell her about me.
Think I can promise that?
Whenever I'm threatened, I tend to
babble things I didn't mean to—
Is she gone?
Yeah.
There really is something
.irresistible about this thrill.
Well then.
So, about this whole Benten affair.
Yaichirou went to ask
.Master Akadama to intercede,
but he came back fuming,
saying, "I'm through with bowing
my head to Master!"
He was bristling mad!
He needs to learn a bit of tolerance.
Well, maybe it's already water under the bridge,
and I won't need my brother's help at all.
Maybe so. Benten might be dangerous,
but she's fickle and capricious, after all.
But what'll you do if it's not
water under the bridge?
I like you so much I could just eat you up.
Ugh, humans are even nastier than tengu.
But you know, most of them are good people.
You can say that because
.you owe your life to one.
It's also thanks to Mr. Yodogawa that you
.were brought into this world, you know.
I still remember the taste of the
.rice balls he gave me that night.
We need to be thankful.
Mamiana Antiques
Man, I demolished that.
You sure do eat like a pig.
Kaisei?
Why are you in that dresser?
Shut up! Who cares?
So, what's been happening?
Is Yajirou doing okay?
Yeah, he's doing fine at the bottom of his well.
And he's giving people advice with their lives.
I... like Yajirou.
I go for advice sometimes, too.
There's a rumor that Benten visits him as well.
What kind of worries could the peerless Benten have?
How would I know?
Maybe she can't decide which tanuki to eat at the end of the year.
There's a rumor that you're headed for the stew pot this time.
That so?
Not if I can help it.
This is all because a mere tanuki like you
got involved with that wannabe tengu!
Go back to Osaka as soon as you can.
If you hang around here for too long,
you'll end up in that stew pot for real.
That is a risk we all face as tanuki.
When the time comes, I'm ready to plunge
.into that pot with a smile on my face.
You sure talk big for a guy with no balls.
Just in case I get caught,
I'd like you to hang onto this for me.
What is it? A keepsake?
Tengu cigars.
Please take them to Master Akadama for me.
I asked Yashirou to take care of him in my absence,
but I hear Master's been making all kinds of unreasonable demands.
A cigar in his mouth should shut him up.
No good. I can't see it.
How could you see anything in there?
Just come out already.
No way. I refuse.
I don't get it.
What's the point?
To the valued customer on the second floor,
Benten has arrived.
Is that Yasaburou character here?
Well, they do call him
"Yasaburou the Fugitive,"
so I suspect he may have already run away.
What would you like to do?
I can take you to the Friday Fellows.
I'm a little tired.
I'll rest here for a bit.
Hey, Teikinbou.
There are two daruma dolls here.
Isn't that strange?
The burn marks, dirt, and other
.scuff marks are exactly identical.
I see.
That certainly is mysterious.
Yasaburou has always been
.good at shape-shifting.
Long time no see, Yasaburou.
How'd you know I was here?
Kinkaku and Ginkaku came to me for advice.
Apparently, their little sister had been
.going out alone from time to time.
They suspected she might have gotten
.sweet-talked by some nasty male tanuki.
Those two are always meddling
.in the most troublesome ways.
They take such good care of their little sister.
You're cute when you're round,
so you can stay as a daruma for a bit.
Where are we going?
Not only did you wreck my inner parlor,
but you also lost my beloved fan.
You promised you'd entertain
the Friday Fellows, did you not?
I won't take "I forgot" for an answer.
There are no words that can express my regret
.for what happened during the Fire Festival.
But—
I don't need apologies.
If we don't enjoy your performance,
we'll eat you, and that will be that.
Do you like beef sukiyaki?
I have no beef with any food.
Except tanuki stew.
Personally, I find tanuki stew
.to be far better than sukiyaki.
How befuddling.
Beef is much tastier.
Your father ended up in a stew pot.
I wonder how many years it's been since then.
You say that like you weren't
.sitting there eating it.
That was right after I was welcomed
.into the Friday Fellows.
It was the first time I had ever eaten tanuki.
A truly delicious stew.
Professor!
Hey.
Here's our entertainment for the evening.
I'm Shimogamo Yasaburou.
Juroujin and Fukurokuju will be absent.
I let the restaurant know in advance.
Well then, since all of today's attendees
are here, shall we begin?
The sound and smell are more than enough
.to put me in a beer-drinking mood.
Then you can just stick to drinking beer, Ebisu.
I'll help myself to your share of the food.
No, no. Appetizers have no meaning
.unless there's a main course.
Tasty meat is poison for your body.
The guy who's smiling and laughing
.over there is Ebisu.
The big one is Bishamon.
Ebisu works in upper management
.at a bank in Osaka.
Bishamon is the president
.of the Sengyoukaku Hotel.
An intellectual once said,
"Cows eat straw, so this isn't
beef stew, but straw stew."
And there's no cholesterol in straw, right?
Daikoku is the young proprietor of the
Kyoto-style restaurant "Chitose-ya."
Wouldn't you agree, Professor?
I wonder if cows these days even eat straw.
Hotei is a university professor.
Cows these days drink beer while listening to Mozart.
There are two others, but they're absent today.
I wanted to see Juroujin, too.
So that means we're eating beer while drinking beer?
What kind of person is Juroujin?
That's like eating rice with a side of rice.
He's a shark.
A shark?
You mean like a card shark?
A loan shark.
We're lucky Hotei is at
.the other pot today.
He doesn't care if the
.meat's not cooked at all,
so if you're not paying attention,
you won't get to eat.
Seriously.
What do you say?
Those three don't seem to be taking this seriously,
sitting there without a care in the world.
Quite so.
Let's teach them the harshness of reality!
It's about time we headed into the
.entertainment portion of the evening.
We've been waiting!
That idiot.
Nishizaki Genemon's shop
Sukiyaki
restaurant
Teramachi
shopping district
And now, presenting the secret ceremony passed
down in the Shimogamo family since long ago:
Bang, Bang! The Seven
Rapid-Fire Transformations!
Shall we begin?
Here we go!
And again!
We're just getting started!
One more!
And even this!
Keep going, keep going!
If you get too carried away,
you'll get devoured.
Thank you very much.
Bravo!
Amazing! I'd expect nothing less
.from a guest of Benten's.
I have no idea what the trick could be.
Are you, by any chance, a tanuki?
That's right. I'm a tanuki.
Indeed he is.
He's a tanuki I know.
Doesn't he look tasty?
No, it would be a waste to eat
.someone with so much talent.
I just couldn't!
I've taken a real liking to you!
You're fantastic!
And so interesting!
Come again next time!
Here, please eat.
Eat as much as you want!
I guess I can let you off the hook for one night.
You mean you won't cook me in a stew?
Well, I can't say the same about tomorrow.
Next month's year-end bash is tanuki stew, huh?
We'll borrow Chitose-ya as usual.
Of course. My doors are always open to you.
I doubt there are other restaurants
.that'd let you make tanuki stew.
Why is it that we have to eat
tanuki every year, anyway?
I prefer beef.
If you keep saying things like that,
you'll be expelled from the club.
It's a rule, that's why.
Wasn't it Tanizaki Jun'ichirou
who made that rule?
Is that true?
I heard from Juroujin that Tanizaki
.Jun'ichirou was once a member.
I find that hard to believe.
Would Tanizaki eat tanuki, though?
Wasn't he into eel?
But eel's a summer food.
The next one who has to bring
a tanuki is Hotei, right?
Hotei, you like tanuki, don't you?
Tanuki are cute, aren't they?
.They sure are cute.
They're all short and stout.
Isn't it charming?
Not to mention the way their
.eyes look at you blankly,
the way their butts wiggle as
...they timidly scurry away...
I see.
It was many years ago when I fell
.head over heels for tanuki.
She was such a cute little thing.
It happened when I was walking
.alone in Kitashirakawa.
You poor thing. Are you hurt?
Okay, c'mere.
It might have been because her leg
.was injured and she was in pain,
but she didn't struggle or make a fuss when
.I picked her up and took her to my place.
Then I dressed her wound
.and made some rice balls.
That tanuki would gobble up anything.
She really loved to eat.
Just like me!
She was terribly scared
.whenever it thundered.
Huh?
She was scared of... thunder?
Sure was.
She would run around whimpering, the poor thing.
On nights when it thundered, I covered her with
.a blanket and stayed with her the whole time.
She got better, so I took her
.back to the mountains,
but as she was leaving, she
looked me right in the eyes!
She kept looking back as she walked away.
Ah, Bishamon, you don't believe me, do you?
But you weren't there, were you?
You didn't see how cute she was!
She understood that I'd done
.her a favor by saving her.
Uh huh.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
They're clever, tanuki are.
Sure, sure. Yep.
Ever since then, I've been
.in love with tanuki.
That's why it's so weird!
Hotei, we all know you
.have a thing for tanuki.
But don't you happily scarf down
tanuki stew every year?
Isn't that kinda messed up?
Liking tanuki and eating tanuki
.are not contradictory.
There will always be guys like
.you who eat it reluctantly,
but I'm always happy to.
Eating it and thinking how delicious it is
.is the least bit of courtesy you can show.
But hold on.
You don't need to go out of your
way to eat tanuki, do you?
There are so many other
.tasty things in the world.
Well, I like them so much
.I could just eat them up.
I've known you for a long time, Hotei,
but I still don't understand you.
But I want you to understand!
It's love!
You get it, right?
Not at all!
And I don't understand how you can't.
You know, tanuki are cute,
but there's someone here
who is just as cute as them!
This is no good.
Hotei's wasted again.
I know how you feel,
but control yourself!
Impossible!
Hey. This is getting kind of boring.
Let's go outside.
Hey, Benten!
Come back!
There's a huge moon out!
I like round things.
Is that so?
I want the moon for myself.
Hey, why don't you go
fetch it for me, Yasaburou?
I'd love to do you a favor,
but that's asking way too much.
Yeah, you're a good-for-nothing.
Can't do anything at all.
You're such a pitiful tanuki.
Call me whatever you want.
When the moon is this pretty,
I get kind of sad.
You're just drunk.
Hardly. It'd take more than this.
What are you so upset about?
You, my dear. Because you're
.going to be eaten by me.
But couldn't you just not eat me?
At some point, I'm definitely
.going to eat you up.
I have issues with the fact that you can
.say "I'll eat you up" so casually.
It's a matter of life or death for me, you know.
I just like you so much I could eat you up.
But if you eat the thing you like,
then it'll be gone!
Obviously! You can't have
.your tanuki and eat it too.
Despite my better judgment, I ended up
.joining the Friday Fellows,
the guys responsible for the death of our dad, for sukiyaki.
That night, Benten and I toasted
.the moon at a secret bar.
I don't know why, but as she sipped
.from the cocktail in her hand,
the words "It's sad. It's so sad"
.escaped her lips.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what this place will be like in the future,
mirai no koko wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
Yodogawa here. Autumn's in
full bloom now, isn't it?
The season brings clear skies
.and a healthy appetite.
Huh? It's the middle of summer?
Next Time:
Taking in Fall Colors
That so?