omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Eight
The Day of Dad's Departure
Yajirou.
Oh, big bro.
You sound like you're in a bad mood.
Have you come to
lecture me about something?
I can't guarantee I'll be able to
.take your lesson to heart, though.
After all, I'm just a frog.
Yajirou.
I remember the last time
.I saw Father very clearly.
That day, I went out with him
.to visit the elders.
Afterward, he said he had
.some important appointment,
so he told me to go home without him.
That was nothing unusual, though.
I mean, Father was always so busy.
So he accompanied me as far as Higashioji
and waited until I caught the bus.
I still remember the way he looked, even now.
Because that was the last time I ever saw him.
Big bro...
What I want to ask you is:
exactly where and when
did you last see Father?
Were you...
Were you drinking with him that night?
Did you get drunk?
What about him?
Did you leave Father by himself,
even though he was drunk?
Please tell me that's not what happened.
Big bro, that's exactly what happened.
I'm the one who sent Father to his death.
How could you?!
You idiot!
I was renowned throughout Kyoto as
.the least motivated tanuki there was.
Never paid any respect by anyone,
I sat around like a daruma doll,
being totally useless,
and the only time I displayed
the will to do anything
was when drinking was involved.
Father's "important appointment" that day
was actually a secret consultation with me.
At the time, I had a really
.troublesome problem on my hands.
I was greatly tormented,
and I opened up to Father to get his advice.
I had fallen into an unrequitable love.
Why was it unrequitable?
Well, the tanuki I loved was awfully young,
and on top of that, she had a fiancé.
That fiancé was my own
.little brother, Yasaburou.
Yes, the one I fell in love with was
betroth
Ebisugawa
Kaisei
to
Shimogamo
Yasaburou
betroth
Ebisugawa
Kaisei
to
Shimogamo
Yasaburou
Ebisugawa Kaisei.
I had told Dad many times that I wanted
.to part with the family and leave Kyoto.
But that day, he was still against it.
Our dad, who had tricked even the tengu,
had nothing in this world to be afraid of.
Or so I thought.
However, even he had one thing he feared:
that his sons would separate
.or come to hate each other.
It was Dad's earnest wish
that we would not end up
like him and his younger
.brother, Ebisugawa Soun,
who unfortunately detested each other.
I split my blood between the four of you,
so you're each indispensable in your own way.
Even if people say
.the most terrible things about you,
you must maintain the balance.
You're one of the four pillars
.of the Shimogamo family.
Anyone who doesn't understand that
.isn't worth the time of day.
You can't grow apart from your brothers.
But, Father,
does that mean I have no choice
but to endure this?
I'll see what I can do.
I don't know if this will work or not,
but for the time being,
leave everything to me.
Be patient for a bit.
Then Father and I decided to forget our worries
and drink like we'd never drunk before.
Let's do that thing we do!
I transformed into the
False Eizan Electric Railway
that had been terrorizing the town back then,
had Father climb aboard, and ran
.through the Shijou neighborhood.
Father and I had done
.this any number of times.
It was our favorite game.
That night, I transformed into my specialty,
the False Eizan Electric Railway,
for the last time.
Father didn't come home that night.
Oww.
You haven't seen Father?
And he didn't come home the next day either.
The Nise-emon...
was eaten by the Friday Fellows!
I deserted Father in the middle
.of town when he was drunk.
That's how he fell into the hands
.of the Friday Fellows.
Yajirou!
Big bro.
Even breathing is too much of a hassle.
That's enough!
Swimming is too much of a hassle as well.
I killed Father.
I felt like all those terrible things
.people were saying were true.
I've been an absolute failure of a tanuki.
Rather than simply being useless,
I ended up causing irreparable damage.
But how could I say that
to your grieving faces?
And yet, I couldn't just act
like nothing happened
and live with the family.
That's why I decided to
lock everything up inside
and become a frog in a well.
I quit being a tanuki.
I can't show my face to Mother.
I no longer have the right
.to call myself her son.
Oh, we forgot about Master Akadama.
We have to go get him.
It's okay. You can go home.
I'll get him.
Rokudou-Chinnouji Temple
How could you neglect your master so?
Did you mean for me to walk home alone?!
My most sincere apologies.
Hm?
I bet you're jealous.
Kaisei brought me this gift.
What was the occasion?
It was when you were in Osaka,
busy ignoring me.
Kaisei visited me a number of times.
One time, she said,
"It'll be getting cold soon," and gave me this.
That girl may have a foul mouth,
but she's quite attentive.
I guess it doesn't matter
.if it's a tanuki or a human.
You have a soft spot
.for girls of all kinds.
Quiet, you.
That's because they're basically
.all I have left to look forward to.
I killed Father.
I felt like all those terrible things
.people were saying were true.
I've been an absolute failure of a tanuki.
It's cold!
Yasaburou.
You're unusually quiet.
I was just lost in memories of my father.
Mammaries? What nonsense are you spouting?
Not mammaries. Memories.
I see. Memories, not mammaries.
So what about Souichirou?
No matter how much you think about someone
.who's passed on, it won't bring them back.
It just makes you an idiot.
We just found out that the last one
.to see Father was Yajirou.
Dad went drinking with him,
got blind drunk, and fell into
.the hands of those humans.
I thought he fell into a stew pot.
Well, yeah.
You know, as long as they're alive,
both tengu and tanuki
.are bound to fall one day.
Even a tengu who flies
freely through the sky
will one day fall onto the roof
.of some human's house.
In a tanuki's case, a stew pot is as
.natural a place to land as any other.
Souichirou made no mistake about
.his own landing place, believe me.
I know that!
The last person who saw
.Souichirou wasn't Yajirou.
Well, if it isn't Master
.Akadama! Good evening.
Is that you, Souichirou?
It's chilly tonight, huh?
Want a drink?
Don't mind if I do.
Why are you here as a hairball?
I'm past the point where I can transform.
So this is my final drink.
Souichirou, are you dead?
I'm afraid I've just been cooked in a stew.
Of all the idiotic things to do!
Oh, don't say that.
We all walk down this road at some point.
But I told you, didn't I?
Didn't I say to go easy
on the screwing around?!
I'm a tanuki, you know.
It's a hard urge for me to resist.
Just another reflection of my idiot blood.
Master,
please continue to look after Yasaburou.
He's a weird one.
He really takes after you,
as far as idiocy goes.
Though, isn't he a bit too idiotic?
He truly is.
But that's what I like about him.
I know he'll cause trouble for you, but anything
.you can do would be most appreciated.
Someday, I'm sure he'll
.make himself useful to you.
Okay.
Well, I've got to be going.
Souichirou.
It's a shame we have to part.
Keep that between you and me, though.
That's great to hear.
Now I can rest well.
Well then, Shimogamo Souichirou
.shall be retiring early. Do excuse me.
Though it had no shortage
.of bothersome matters,
it was, more or less, a pleasant life.
I sincerely appreciate the kindness you've
.shown me all these years, Nyoigatake Yakushibou.
Did that really happen?
He was an idiot to the last.
He was too good to be a tanuki.
Well, good night, Master.
Big bro...
Father...
Did something happen?
We went to Yajirou's place.
Did you have a fight or something?
Mother...
We were talking about the night
.that Father didn't come home,
and...
He was so troubled, you know.
And he was in love with Kaisei.
Yeah.
And then he went to see Sou about it.
Hey, Mother is worried.
Say something.
Mother.
What is it?
You knew?
Knew what?
Why Yajirou holed himself up in a well.
I'm his mother.
If I didn't understand him, who would?
So, Yaichirou,
please, please don't blame him too much.
I understand him.
I understand him very well.
You're his big brother,
so please try to understand him too.
Of course I do, Mother.
He's my little brother.
Of course I understand him.
It's because I understand him
that this hurts so much.
When saying good-bye to this world,
our great father split his blood into four:
the eldest inherited only
.his sense of responsibility,
the second eldest inherited only
.his easygoing personality,
the youngest inherited only his innocence,
and me, well, I inherited only his idiocy.
What held us diverse brothers together
was the love of our mother,
deeper than the sea,
and the farewell we bid our great father.
Sometimes, one profound separation
can unite the ones left behind.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
There's something I'd want to
.ask Uncle if he were still alive.
Why is my name "Kaisei"?
Next Time:
Kaisei, Daughter of Ebisugawa