Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
In this modern tanuki society,
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
who would genuinely aspire to the title of Nise-emon?
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
Shimogamo
Yai
chirou
There is a huge gap between the unfettered,
carefree life of a tanuki
and the responsibility of the Nise-emon,
who must take charge whenever
.duty calls, be it day or night.
Weighing these two options,
any normal tanuki would ask themselves,
"While the traditional title of the
.Nise-emon is certainly a great honor,
is it worth sacrificing my comfortable,
free lifestyle for?"
The day the Nise-emon is decided,
which also happens to be the
anniversary of my father's death
as well as the day of the Friday Fellows'
.detestable year-end bash, has come.
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Ten
The Strings Pulled by Ebisugawa Soun
Yasaburou? I see there are still many
.inexplicable wonders in this world.
You're up crazy early as well.
You fool.
I wake up early every day
.to focus on mental training.
You just don't know about it,
since you're usually sleeping like a log.
The Nise-emon must be ready
.to shoulder the future of tanuki-kind.
That's a rather serious topic to
.discuss first thing in the morning.
Only one ready for that duty
.should be chosen as Nise-emon.
I've done all in my power to be worthy.
Your determination is impressive.
You should always dream big.
But—
No need to say any more.
I know what's on your mind.
I'm sure you can figure out
.what I'm thinking as well.
Maybe I'm just a fool.
Maybe I'm just trying to
.follow in Father's footsteps.
Our dear uncle may
.be right about that.
Tanuki society might not even care about the Nise-emon anymore.
But my dream is to become like Father.
How could I accomplish that
besides becoming Nise-emon?
You wake up this early every day
to think about things like that?
You oughta just sleep in
.every now and then.
Maybe so.
Are you going to see the elders today?
Yes.
If I don't pay them a visit,
they'll think I've given
.up my candidacy.
By the way, Kaisei said
.something weird the other night.
What was it?
"I'm sorry."
What's that supposed to be about?
The Ebisugawa family might
.be scheming something.
How stupid.
If those idiot brothers try anything,
it'll end with me chomping their butts and
.hurling them into the cold Kamo River again.
Well, I'm glad to see
.you're so confident,
but when the going gets tough,
your courage tends to get going.
Don't get smart with me!
I'm just worried about you!
No fighting!
I'm going to Nanzenji
.to meet with the chief,
and then I'll head to Sensuiro
.in the evening with my sponsors.
We'll get the banquet ready at Akegarasu,
so stop by once the election is over.
Okay.
What will you be doing, Yasaburou?
I think I'll go over to Yajirou's.
Today's the anniversary of Dad's death,
so I'd feel bad about
.leaving him on his own.
In that case, Yasaburou,
could you also remind the owner
of Akegarasu that we're coming?
Okay.
Well then, I'll be going.
Don't forget.
You're Shimogamo Souichirou's son!
Believe in yourself.
I know, Mother.
But in the end, it all
.comes down to chance.
Yeah.
Okay, Mother, I'm off.
Look forward to good news!
Hey, big bro.
Be careful.
Fake Denki Bran
Organize and pack up the old switchboards
.piled in Old Warehouse No. 1.
Don't cut any corners,
'cause we'll be checking your work.
Old Warehouse No. 1
All right, then. We'll need you
.to begin immediately.
Old Warehouse No. 1
We need to get started on the preparations
.for tonight, so we'll be rather busy.
And we can't head off until we've made sure
.you're doing the job properly.
Old Warehouse No. 1
Sometimes cell phone signals can cause the
.old machinery here to inadvertently activate.
We wouldn't want you to get hurt.
So you should leave
.your phone outside.
I knew it! The Shimogamo
.kids are such idiots.
There's a saying,
"Carelessness is one's greatest enemy."
Can I use it now?
Can I make it buzz?
Stay cool, Ginkaku.
Let's save it until we figure
.out where Yaichirou is.
Not to mention,
wherever did Kaisei go?
If she interferes,
our plan could fall to pieces.
Once we nab Yaichirou and his mom,
that just leaves Yasaburou, right?
He's gonna be a pain.
Don't be a baby.
Father will take care of him for us.
If he should fail,
I'll figure out something.
You're really in your element, huh?
So much so that
.you're freaking me out.
By the way, what should we do
about the frog in the well?
Just leave him be.
It's not like he can do anything.
Hey!
Old Warehouse No. 1
Hey, somebody! Open the door!
What's going on?
.Something smells amazing.
Heyo!
It's your share of the
.Christmas Eve fried chicken.
Oh, Yasaburou!
Chicken? Isn't this fancy.
It's tender!
Eating insects all the time
.must be rough on your mouth.
To think even a frog in a well like me
.gets to eat fried chicken.
I really appreciate it!
I'm convinced a little brother
.is something everyone should have.
Tonight's the night, big bro.
They're going to decide
.the next Nise-emon.
I hope things calm down after that.
I feel bad for Yaichirou, saying this,
but I feel like I don't really care
.who becomes Nise-emon.
As long as things calm down in
tanuki society, isn't that what matters?
It's been years since
Father died, you know?
Yeah.
My head's been filled with thoughts
.of him since this morning.
Same with all of us.
Yeah, I guess this is the day for it.
I've tried so hard to remember
what Dad's last words were.
But no matter how many times I relive the
.events of that night, my memory cuts out partway.
Even as a frog, it's painful to think that I might
.go on living my whole life without remembering.
Big bro.
Have you seen Kaisei lately?
Now that you mention it,
she hasn't come this way in a while.
Did you two have a fight or something?
Well, we're always fighting,
but she's being a bit weird.
What do you mean, "weird"?
She said "I'm sorry."
.Kaisei, of all people.
Don't you think that's strange?
Yeah, it does seem a bit odd.
Right? There's something
.creepy about it.
Now that you mention it,
Kaisei's done that before.
She's taken that kind of humble tone
.when talking to me.
After talking for a bit,
she'll suddenly clam up.
It's like she's got
.something on her mind.
I wonder what it could be.
I never know what
.Kaisei is thinking.
She's a strange one.
She certainly is.
But when she found out
.I was unable to change back,
she cried by the edge of
.the well for a long time.
She has a kind side to her, you know.
Are you still stuck on her?
That's not something you
.should ask a frog in a well.
I'll just get depressed.
Sorry, big bro.
But Kaisei sure is acting strange.
The view from the bottom
.of a well may not be much,
but you can see the sky
.and the stars really well.
My world is small, but since I'm
.looking up at space night after night,
you could say I'm a frog
.on a universal scale.
When you gaze up at space all alone like that,
the back of your mind goes quiet,
and you feel as though you've gained
.an extraordinary amount of wisdom.
If I were to give you my
.opinion as a wise frog,
it seems like something
.awful is gonna happen.
What the hell?
This wind is insane!
Can't feel it down here, but...
Raijin, God of Thunder, has arrived.
This is bizarre.
Seems like someone used
.the Fuujin Raijin fan.
Damn, where did they
find that thing?
Take care of Mother, Yasaburou.
This again?
How useless do I have to be
before I'm happy?
A frog in a well can't do
.anything about anything.
Well, I guess I can't do
.anything about that either.
It's okay, big bro.
Leave it to me!
Be careful, Yasaburou.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Will do.
Mother...
Shimogamo Shrine
Mother!
She's not here?
Mother?
It's me, stupid.
You? What are you doing here?
I've been looking for you all this time!
My brothers have been keeping watch,
so I was hiding behind Kiyomizu Temple.
You can wait here as long as you like,
but no one else is gonna come.
My big brothers summoned Raijin,
and the Ebisugawa Elite Guard
.carried off your mom a little while ago.
Yashirou is probably at the factory.
Yaichirou will have been
.captured by now.
My dad means for him
to be made into stew!
Just like Uncle.
That's right.
The one who sent Uncle
...to the stew pot was...
my dad.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Brother!
I trust Master Akadama is in good health?
Sorry to say, but I haven't seen him lately.
Even though you got along so well?
Is there some kind of problem?
Hmm.
If there's a problem,
I guess we should say it's mine.
Is that so?
But I have some great memories of the time
.we spent learning from Master Akadama.
Yeah, we were both so young.
And then we both fell
.for the same tanuki.
Ah, now that I remember it,
that was pretty cute.
Cute?
That sure was something, though.
You got married in a flash.
Really? It didn't feel that way to me.
But I joined the Ebisugawa family right
.after that, so it's all been a bit of a blur.
And that's when our relationship
.began to fray at the seams.
Right. Then I lost the
.Nise-emon election.
I wonder why.
I made a vow back then, you know.
Did you make good on it?
Not yet, but I expect to soon.
Ah. Well, that's what really counts.
It's all thanks to you, Brother.
I must have made things difficult for you.
It's no problem.
That's ancient history now, right?
It's hardly an exaggeration to say that I have also
.become a great tanuki, with children of my own.
I'm not hung up on the little things.
I'm happy to hear you say that.
You certainly have made
.something of yourself.
Now, now, so have you.
Hm? What's that over there?
Looks like a cage.
It does indeed.
Should I have them take it away?
No, it's not that big of a deal.
Just a strange thing to have lying around.
You're drunk, aren't you, Brother?
No need to worry about me.
I don't get dead drunk.
If you say so.
But before we continue,
I'd like to have a reconciliation ceremony.
I even invited a witness.
Once we've officially made up,
we can drink without a care.
You're really blowing this
.out of proportion.
Can't we just settle things on our own?
I don't think so.
We're pillars of tanuki society.
That's why I'd like to get this
.sorted out once and for all.
Very well. I understand
.where you're coming from.
The witness!
We shall be graced with the presence
.of Suzuki Satomi as a witness.
Miss Suzuki, what brings you here?
Well, you never come to see me.
But I don't understand.
What's the purpose of this?
I'm joining the Friday Fellows.
I see. And you need me for that, huh?
I'm glad you're so quick on the uptake.
A seat has opened up
.among the Friday Fellows,
and in order to fill it, I need to
.procure ingredients for their stew.
Does Master Akadama know of this?
Oh, how pitiful you are.
Master doesn't know a thing.
Farewell, Brother.
I don't expect I'll be seeing you again.
My little brother.
Is this really what you want?
I'm sorry.
I thought it was something like that.
I've been under that assumption for so long
.that it's actually surprising to hear it confirmed.
Let me go, you!
What happened?
Yasaburou.
Ebisu
gawa
Don't worry about what Kaisei said.
When she's half asleep, she loses track
.of the line between dreams and reality.
I may have been a tad overprotective
.during her upbringing, so she's a little delicate.
Whatever tonight's outcome,
I'd been meaning to hold a banquet with
.the Shimogamo family as the guests of honor.
All the members of both
.families are there already.
You're the only one we
.haven't been able to find.
I appreciate the kind gesture,
but we've already booked
.Akegarasu for tonight.
You just don't get it, do you?
That plan has long since been scrapped.
I'm far too wet for good manners,
so I think I'll pass on attending
.your auspicious gathering.
You're coming with us,
whether you want to or not.
Only a fool would get
.themselves hurt by resisting.
Don't make us waste our time.
Stay away from me!
Anybody who comes near me gets my
teeth through one side of their ass!
There are all sorts of good-byes.
Some good-byes are sad,
and some good-byes are blessings in disguise
.that take a load off of one's mind.
It often happens that someone who bid farewell
.unexpectedly returns, all embarrassed.
And then there are times when someone
.makes it seem like only a temporary parting,
only to not return for a long time.
And then there are
.good-byes that last forever.
True good-byes that we
.make only once in a lifetime.
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
and find something,
tashika na mono
something permanent
te ni ireyou
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
Oh no! It doesn't seem
like I'm gonna be rescued!
This sucks, but there's nothing
I can do from inside this cage!
What fate doth await our dear family?
Next Time:
Back in the Game